The O
Doc- O

Event O
and O
story O
or O
: O

Albrecht B-PER
Lehmann I-PER
speaks O
to O
refugees O
and O
displaced O
persons O
in O
West B-LOC
Germany I-LOC
, O
1945 O
- O
1990 O
. O

Discussions O
on O
asylum O
seekers O
, O
displaced O
persons O
and O
immigration O
issues O
have O
dominated O
politics O
and O
the O
media O
in O
Germany B-LOC
in O
recent O
months O
. O

It O
is O
therefore O
not O
difficult O
at O
the O
moment O
to O
attract O
attention O
with O
the O
publication O
of O
a O
book O
on O
refugees O
and O
displaced O
persons O
in O
West B-LOC
Germany I-LOC
from O
1945 O
to O
1990 O
. O

And O
indeed O
, O
there O
are O
hardly O
any O
serious O
scientific O
discussions O
that O
have O
taken O
on O
this O
topic O
so O
far O
. O

It O
is O
questionable O
, O
however O
, O
whether O
such O
an O
actuality O
must O
necessarily O
lead O
to O
an O
undoubtedly O
upcoming O
debate O
to O
deprive O
it O
of O
its O
actual O
core O
in O
favor O
of O
a O
distortion O
of O
the O
difference O
between O
past O
and O
present O
problem O
constellations O
. O

In O
his O
book B-MISC
I I-MISC
m O
Fremden O
unwillend O
zu O
Hause O
, O
Albrecht O
Lehmann O
attempts O
to O
take O
a O
neutral O
perspective O
, O
free O
from O
blame O
and O
innocence O
, O
on O
a O
policy O
and O
its O
consequences O
that O
led O
to O
the O
12 O
million O
people O
fleeing O
or O
displaced O
from O
East B-LOC
Germany I-LOC
and O
the O
German B-MISC
settlements O
in O
Eastern B-LOC
Europe I-LOC
at O
the O
end O
of O
World O
War O
II O
. O

In O
what O
way O
the O
" O
refugees O
" O
- O
as O
it O
was O
called O
immediately O
after O
the O
war O
with O
a O
pejorative O
taste O
- O
or O
" O
districted O
" O
- O
has O
been O
the O
common O
term O
since O
about O
. O

In O
1948 O
- O
found O
in O
their O
new O
conditions O
and O
how O
these O
experiences O
have O
traded O
over O
the O
next O
decades O
in O
the O
different O
generations O
to O
the O
present O
day O
, O
Lehmann B-PER
demonstrates O
by O
means O
of O
a O
series O
of O
stories O
, O
personal O
records O
, O
diaries O
and O
documents O
of O
the O
displaced O
press O
. O

Nowadays O
a O
picture O
is O
promoted O
which O
, O
although O
not O
surprisingly O
, O
yet O
in O
its O
composition O
convincingly O
allows O
readers O
to O
follow O
up O
on O
a O
specific O
type O
of O
foreign O
experience O
. O

The O
respective O
experiences O
and O
their O
handling O
are O
presented O
very O
differently O
. O

However O
, O
certain O
issues O
are O
repeatedly O
raised O
: O

Thus O
, O
the O
rape O
of O
German B-MISC
women O
by O
members O
of O
the O
Red B-ORG
Army I-ORG
not O
only O
led O
to O
irreparable O
mental O
disorders O
in O
the O
women O
themselves O
, O
but O
also O
to O
complicated O
marital O
relationships O
that O
often O
ruled O
the O
lives O
of O
entire O
families O
for O
years O
after O
these O
events O
. O

The O
detachment O
from O
the O
old O
homeland O
produced O
in O
many O
cases O
forms O
of O
social O
over O
- O
adaptation O
, O
which O
especially O
in O
narrow O
village O
communities O
caused O
difficulties O
with O
the O
elderly O
population O
. O

A O
" O
sentimental O
insistence O
" O
on O
ancient O
traditions O
and O
customs O
expressed O
how O
incapable O
the O
displaced O
were O
to O
forget O
the O
old O
homeland O
. O

In O
all O
the O
narratives O
it O
becomes O
evident O
that O
the O
pursuit O
of O
social O
harmony O
has O
long O
been O
the O
guiding O
factor O
of O
action O
. O

Creating O
a O
new O
sense O
of O
community O
should O
compensate O
for O
the O
loss O
mostly O
experienced O
as O
cruel O
. O

In O
addition O
to O
showing O
such O
typical O
difficulties O
, O
one O
of O
the O
strengths O
of O
the O
book O
is O
to O
highlight O
the O
differences O
in O
the O
experiences O
of O
different O
generations O
. O

So O
it O
becomes O
plausible O
that O
the O
generation O
that O
grew O
up O
in O
the O
sixties O
and O
seventies O
wanted O
little O
to O
do O
with O
the O
past O
of O
their O
parents O
who O
had O
been O
displaced O
. O

A O
consciousness O
of O
the O
“ O
lost O
homeland O
” O
existed O
; O
however O
, O
it O
was O
no O
longer O
sentimentally O
occupied O
. O

This O
changed O
only O
again O
in O
the O
eighties O
, O
when O
in O
Germany B-LOC
a O
Renaissance O
of O
the O
concept O
of O
homeland O
allowed O
a O
stronger O
reference O
to O
the O
former O
German B-MISC
settlement O
areas O
. O

In O
describing O
and O
reproducing O
the O
stories O
of O
the O
displaced O
, O
Lehmann B-PER
will O
not O
tire O
of O
repeatedly O
pointing O
out O
that O
, O
despite O
long O
- O
held O
prejudices O
, O
they O
do O
not O
adhere O
to O
revenge O
. O

One O
can O
believe O
the O
author O
who O
understands O
his O
book O
as O
a O
contribution O
to O
understanding O
different O
nations O
, O
when O
he O
in O
this O
sense O
calls O
to O
conceive O
of O
the O
old O
homeland O
only O
as O
a O
“ O
homeland O
in O
the O
head O
” O
. O

However O
, O
despite O
this O
praiseful O
attitude O
and O
programmatic O
, O
the O
many O
reports O
and O
narratives O
leave O
a O
delicate O
aftertaste O
, O
which O
is O
primarily O
due O
to O
the O
methodology O
of O
German B-MISC
folk O
science O
. O

History O
, O
as O
it O
is O
written O
in O
this O
book O
, O
is O
reproduced O
primarily O
from O
the O
perspective O
of O
those O
involved O
in O
it O
. O

The O
one O
story O
breaks O
down O
into O
many O
stories O
, O
which O
in O
turn O
can O
be O
scientifically O
accurately O
classified O
by O
different O
genres O
. O

Thus O
, O
success O
stories O
, O
slums O
, O
and O
overthrow O
stories O
are O
typical O
forms O
of O
telling O
a O
particular O
group O
that O
today O
still O
wants O
to O
forget O
their O
initial O
difficulties O
in O
the O
new O
home O
. O

A O
suppressive O
form O
of O
storytelling O
, O
on O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
is O
to O
find O
out O
among O
women O
who O
have O
become O
victims O
of O
rape O
. O

Nevertheless O
, O
this O
scientifically O
derived O
classification O
of O
narrative O
types O
remains O
only O
external O
. O

The O
narratives O
themselves O
are O
central O
in O
the O
present O
form O
of O
presentation O
; O
a O
reflection O
on O
them O
and O
therefore O
a O
possibility O
for O
evaluation O
and O
classification O
remains O
out O
. O

However O
, O
this O
circumstance O
leads O
too O
easily O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
compassionate O
understanding O
or O
sympathetic O
identification O
with O
those O
affected O
will O
make O
those O
constellations O
of O
history O
forgotten O
, O
in O
the O
framework O
of O
which O
the O
undoubtedly O
cruel O
individual O
events O
must O
be O
presented O
. O

For O
example O
, O
it O
appears O
quite O
irritating O
when O
the O
" O
double O
fortune O
" O
of O
Anton B-PER
K. I-PER
from O
Siebenbürgen B-LOC
is O
, O
who O
as O
a O
Volksdeutscher B-MISC
was O
not O
allowed O
to O
join O
the O
Wehrmacht B-ORG
, O
but O
had O
to O
join O
the O
Waffen B-ORG
- I-ORG
SS I-ORG
; O
who O
was O
therefore O
able O
to O
save O
himself O
over O
the O
war O
years O
and O
at O
the O
same O
time O
was O
spared O
from O
the O
captivity O
. O

Considering O
the O
fortune O
of O
an O
Anton B-PER
K. I-PER
is O
one O
side O
. O

The O
other O
must O
be O
to O
classify O
the O
individual O
fates O
in O
such O
a O
way O
in O
the O
history O
of O
the O
Second B-MISC
World I-MISC
War I-MISC
and O
the O
years O
thereafter O
that O
an O
objective O
perspective O
can O
be O
taken O
. O

It O
is O
a O
mistake O
to O
assume O
that O
the O
mere O
reproduction O
of O
authentic O
accounts O
must O
inevitably O
lead O
to O
an O
adequate O
view O
of O
history O
. O

Rather O
, O
it O
carries O
the O
danger O
of O
a O
look O
at O
history O
that O
stylizes O
all O
involved O
to O
their O
victims O
. O

It O
is O
undoubtedly O
necessary O
to O
deal O
also O
with O
the O
victims O
of O
history O
who O
stood O
on O
the O
side O
of O
the O
perpetrators O
. O

It O
should O
be O
avoided O
, O
however O
, O
to O
make O
a O
push O
for O
a O
relativization O
of O
history O
, O
which O
seeks O
to O
blur O
all O
differences O
in O
favor O
of O
a O
" O
recomprehensible O
understanding O
" O
. O

In O
this O
context O
, O
it O
is O
not O
enough O
to O
issue O
programmatic O
slogans O
for O
the O
" O
reconciliation O
of O
all O
cultures O
" O
. O

Rather O
, O
this O
leads O
to O
other O
fundamental O
misunderstandings O
that O
contribute O
to O
blurring O
crucial O
differences O
. O

This O
distortion O
is O
most O
clearly O
seen O
in O
Lehmann B-PER
at O
the O
point O
where O
he O
advocates O
a O
“ O
post O
- O
national O
Europe B-LOC
” O
and O
declares O
this O
as O
a O
perspective O
that O
should O
arise O
from O
a O
non O
- O
revanchist O
expatriate O
perspective O
, O
so O
that O
the O
German B-MISC
solution O
to O
the O
expatriate O
problem O
becomes O
a O
model O
for O
those O
questions O
and O
problems O
that O
arise O
as O
a O
result O
of O
the O
immigration O
movements O
: O

The O
topic O
of O
this O
book O
remains O
current O
: O

The O
question O
of O
how O
individuals O
and O
families O
with O
their O
children O
and O
grandchildren O
find O
a O
new O
homeland O
in O
our O
country O
, O
in O
what O
memories O
they O
carry O
and O
tradite O
the O
old O
homeland O
and O
the O
culture O
of O
the O
region O
of O
origin O
, O
in O
what O
way O
they O
nurture O
the O
contact O
with O
the O
first O
homeland O
. O

In O
the O
equalization O
of O
the O
problems O
of O
displaced O
persons O
and O
asylum O
- O
seekers O
and O
their O
respective O
experiences O
in O
foreign O
affairs O
, O
the O
fundamental O
difference O
between O
these O
groups O
is O
turned O
under O
the O
table O
. O

A O
post O
- O
national O
Europe B-LOC
consists O
in O
the O
coexistence O
of O
the O
most O
diverse O
ethnic O
groups O
, O
which O
it O
has O
forcibly O
or O
intentionally O
pushed O
to O
Germany B-LOC
or O
other O
countries O
of O
Europe B-LOC
. O

However O
, O
the O
alienation O
experiences O
of O
these O
groups O
are O
likely O
to O
be O
fundamentally O
different O
from O
those O
of O
the O
expats O
in O
the O
1940s O
or O
their O
children O
decades O
later O
. O

The O
latter O
have O
proven O
to O
identify O
with O
Germany B-LOC
despite O
the O
losses O
of O
the O
" O
old O
homeland O
in O
the O
east O
" O
, O
have O
built O
up O
a O
national O
consciousness O
due O
to O
their O
ethnicity O
. O

Such O
identification O
is O
neither O
possible O
nor O
desirable O
for O
immigrants O
. O

While O
for O
the O
expats O
the O
idea O
of O
a O
homogeneous O
national O
state O
was O
determining O
, O
for O
asylum O
seekers O
and O
immigrants O
today O
it O
is O
the O
idea O
of O
a O
heterogeneous O
national O
state O
. O

A O
focus O
on O
subjective O
sensitivities O
, O
as O
done O
in O
this O
volume O
, O
should O
not O
lead O
to O
neglecting O
fundamental O
, O
objective O
differences O
. O

This O
is O
neither O
useful O
to O
a O
scientific O
context O
, O
nor O
does O
it O
help O
the O
author O
’s O
desire O
to O
“ O
build O
” O
a O
Europe B-LOC
in O
which O
differences O
are O
overcome O
without O
denying O
them O
. O

The O
Doc- O

It O
is O
often O
the O
small O
problems O
at O
the O
front O
door O
that O
cause O
great O
trouble O
to O
the O
citizens O
of O
Frankfurt B-MISC
. O

The O
reading O
phone O
of O
the O
districtRundschau B-LOC
has O
repeatedly O
been O
able O
to O
help O
to O
find O
ways O
out O
of O
the O
mess O
of O
the O
authorities O
and O
to O
find O
solutions O
to O
some O
problems O
. O

Even O
if O
in O
the O
case O
of O
everyday O
difficulties O
the O
quick O
success O
did O
not O
always O
settle O
( O
hardy O
long O
- O
lasting O
false O
- O
parks O
can O
not O
be O
impressed O
either O
by O
penalty O
notes O
or O
newspaper O
articles O
) O
, O
the O
direct O
thread O
into O
the O
editorial O
office O
continually O
contributes O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
an O
ass O
bridge O
can O
be O
stretched O
over O
some O
seemingly O
unbeatable O
caves O
. O

The O
reader O
’s O
phone O
of O
the O
district O
- O
Rundschau O
( O
telephone O
number O
21 O
99 O
- O
3 O
60 O
) O
is O
occupied O
: O

Every O
Thursday O
from O
14h O
to O
17h O
, O
Friday O
from O
10h O
to O
13h O
. O

The O
Doc- O

When O
the O
weight O
of O
112 O
kilograms O
indicated O
Andrea B-PER
, O
27 O
years O
old O
: O

Pregnancy O
after O
pregnancy O

She O
has O
always O
been O
overweight O
. O

The O
man O
she O
has O
been O
married O
to O
for O
ten O
years O
has O
never O
made O
any O
difference O
. O

The O
marriage O
seemed O
happy O
, O
Andrea B-PER
was O
happy O
. O

When O
she O
was O
24 O
years O
old O
, O
she O
was O
pregnant O
for O
the O
second O
time O
. O

She O
always O
wanted O
to O
have O
many O
children O
. O

However O
, O
after O
Mirjam B-PER
’s O
birth O
, O
she O
felt O
overwhelmed O
. O

Andrea B-PER
began O
to O
eat O
more O
and O
more O
. O

It O
was O
no O
longer O
the O
healthy O
appetite O
that O
drew O
her O
to O
the O
refrigerator O
: O

She O
suddenly O
put O
a O
lot O
of O
food O
in O
her O
. O

And O
at O
some O
point O
, O
the O
scale O
shows O
112 O
kilos O
. O

Andrea B-PER
had O
become O
addicted O
, O
addicted O
to O
the O
feeling O
of O
fullness O
. O

Hunger O
was O
a O
stranger O
to O
her O
, O
her O
whole O
body O
was O
a O
stranger O
to O
her O
. O

That O
she O
was O
sick O
, O
she O
did O
not O
know O
at O
the O
time O
. O

Only O
when O
she O
read O
a O
diet O
book O
one O
day O
, O
she O
noticed O
it O
. O

It O
was O
described O
as O
an O
addicted O
woman O
- O
and O
in O
that O
story O
Andrea B-PER
recognized O
herself O
again O
. O

At O
that O
moment O
she O
realized O
that O
she O
had O
to O
do O
something O
against O
her O
suffering O
. O

Andrea B-PER
took O
the O
initiative O
and O
registered O
at O
a O
clinic O
for O
addicts O
in O
Allgäu B-LOC
. O

A O
few O
weeks O
later O
, O
she O
left O
her O
husband O
and O
children O
for O
a O
three O
- O
month O
therapy O
. O

Her O
relatives O
accused O
her O
of O
being O
a O
rabbit O
mother O
. O

It O
was O
clear O
to O
Andrea B-PER
: O

“ O
I O
can O
only O
be O
a O
good O
mother O
if O
I O
am O
well O
. O
” O

When O
Andrea B-PER
introduced O
herself O
on O
the O
first O
day O
in O
the O
group O
, O
she O
said O
: O

" O
My O
name O
is O
Andrea B-PER
, O
I O
eat O
too O
much O
, O
but O
I O
have O
no O
other O
problems O
. O
" O

Everyone O
laughed O
, O
and O
soon O
she O
knew O
why O
. O
” O

I O
had O
supplanted O
my O
problems O
until O
therapy O
. O
” O

It O
turned O
out O
that O
Andrea B-PER
was O
not O
so O
satisfied O
with O
her O
existence O
as O
a O
young O
mother O
and O
wife O
. O

Today O
she O
admits O
: O

“ O
I O
still O
feel O
like O
I O
missed O
something O
in O
my O
youth O
. O
” O

Through O
therapy O
, O
however O
, O
she O
has O
learned O
to O
deal O
with O
her O
dissatisfaction O
, O
her O
fears O
and O
worries O
. O

When O
the O
27 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
today O
has O
conflicts O
with O
her O
husband O
, O
the O
two O
talk O
about O
it O
. O

For O
example O
, O
in O
marriage O
counseling O
, O
to O
which O
you O
go O
regularly O
. O

From O
the O
illness O
of O
" O
crab O
addiction O
" O
Andrea B-PER
is O
not O
yet O
healed O
. O
" O

Whoever O
is O
addicted O
once O
will O
always O
stay O
somehow O
, O
” O
she O
says O
. O

And O
so O
she O
plans O
every O
day O
exactly O
what O
she O
is O
going O
to O
eat O
. O

If O
she O
does O
not O
comply O
, O
she O
gets O
angry O
. O

Regularly O
dealing O
with O
food O
will O
also O
remain O
a O
dream O
for O
them O
. O

The O
Doc- O

Stefan B-PER
Müller I-PER
- O
Doohm O
Interdisciplinarity O
from O
below O
Against O
the O
Loss O
of O
Utopia O
in O
Sociology O

An O
incitement O
to O
unrest O
in O
the O
Ivory O
Tower O

Sociology O
is O
not O
without O
reason O
suspicious O
of O
high O
robbery O
. O

For O
it O
claims O
nothing O
less O
as O
its O
specific O
object O
area O
than O
the O
whole O
of O
society O
. O

What O
a O
wonder O
that O
the O
society O
so O
targeted O
reacted O
suspiciously O
to O
the O
acquisition O
by O
sociology O
. O

Until O
the O
time O
of O
Adenauer O
, O
the O
lady O
society O
, O
which O
had O
grown O
to O
public O
reputation O
, O
felt O
most O
embarrassingly O
touched O
by O
the O
approaches O
of O
the O
becoming O
duller O
sociology O
. O

It O
was O
only O
in O
the O
turbulent O
political O
periods O
of O
the O
late O
1960s O
that O
she O
gave O
in O
to O
her O
stormy O
urges O
. O

The O
society B-ORG
of I-ORG
sociology I-ORG
fell O
into O
its O
arms O
. O

This O
yes O
- O
word O
has O
led O
to O
a O
covenant O
for O
life O
, O
but O
it O
has O
become O
anything O
but O
a O
burning O
love O
relationship O
. O

Meanwhile O
, O
the O
enthusiasm O
has O
been O
driven O
by O
the O
expectations O
of O
this O
young O
social O
science O
at O
the O
height O
of O
its O
academic O
expansion O
. O

The O
conviction O
that O
was O
associated O
with O
that O
demanding O
goal O
of O
knowledge O
was O
to O
formulate O
a O
theory O
of O
the O
whole O
of O
society O
that O
should O
be O
both O
critical O
and O
practically O
changing O
. O

Are O
we O
therefore O
at O
the O
end O
of O
a O
process O
in O
which O
the O
utopian O
energies O
, O
invested O
in O
the O
enormous O
undertaking O
of O
an O
enlightenmental O
and O
critical O
revolution O
of O
all O
outdated O
working O
and O
living O
relationships O
, O
have O
completely O
emerged O
? O

Asked O
otherwise O
: O

How O
can O
the O
attractiveness O
of O
sociology O
as O
a O
force O
of O
change O
of O
reality O
be O
recovered O
, O
which O
it O
reduced O
to O
normal O
science O
in O
the O
course O
of O
its O
“ O
maturation O
process O
” O
? O

There O
are O
three O
main O
reasons O
for O
the O
loss O
of O
utopia O
in O
sociology O
. O

On O
the O
one O
hand O
, O
it O
is O
the O
utopia O
itself O
that O
has O
become O
modest O
out O
of O
the O
historically O
until O
recently O
intrusive O
experience O
of O
the O
failure O
of O
the O
great O
visionary O
promises O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
the O
reality O
of O
the O
utopian O
challenge O
, O
which O
has O
become O
more O
and O
more O
concrete O
, O
has O
been O
posed O
by O
the O
simple O
cunning O
of O
realising O
utopian O
ideals O
. O

At O
the O
same O
time O
, O
the O
historical O
situation O
has O
taken O
on O
a O
gravity O
that O
permits O
any O
project O
of O
longing O
for O
something O
entirely O
different O
in O
the O
forthcoming O
morning O
to O
be O
merely O
an O
apocalypse O
. O

The O
wishes O
of O
the O
origin O
of O
modernity O
have O
been O
transformed O
in O
the O
critical O
tradition O
of O
the O
social O
doctrine O
into O
a O
concrete O
utopia O
of O
the O
real O
course O
of O
history O
of O
progressive O
bourgeois O
emancipation O
. O

The O
stage O
goes O
from O
the O
fictional O
future O
paintings O
of O
a O
Morus B-PER
, O
Campanella B-PER
, O
and O
Bacon B-PER
to O
the O
technical O
and O
early O
socialist O
utopism O
of O
Owen B-PER
, O
Saint B-PER
- I-PER
Simon I-PER
, O
Fourier B-PER
, O
and O
Proudhon B-PER
. O

Against O
these O
utopian O
socialists O
, O
Marx B-PER
polemized O
with O
all O
its O
sharpness O
, O
accusing O
them O
of O
being O
merely O
dreamers O
. O

He O
himself O
, O
like O
so O
many O
things O
, O
puts O
the O
utopia O
from O
head O
to O
foot O
and O
comes O
to O
the O
point O
materialistically O
: O

In O
communism O
, O
utopia O
and O
reality O
fuse O
as O
the O
society O
of O
free O
producers O
, O
as O
material O
abundance O
, O
and O
as O
transparent O
social O
relationships O
for O
all O
members O
of O
society O
. O

However O
, O
this O
concretization O
of O
Utopia O
has O
by O
no O
means O
led O
to O
the O
promised O
paradise O
. O

For O
, O
as O
we O
read O
in O
Horkheimer B-LOC
’s I-LOC
diary O
note O
from O
the O
1950s O
, O
the O
sky O
to O
which O
one O
can O
point O
the O
way O
is O
none O
. O

and O
more O
: O

Productive O
forces O
emerged O
as O
destructive O
forces O
, O
class O
consciousness O
became O
a O
fossil O
by O
the O
individualization O
of O
living O
conditions O
, O
and O
revolutions O
did O
not O
prove O
to O
be O
the O
locomotive O
of O
world O
history O
. O

Rather O
, O
in O
the O
words O
of O
Walter B-PER
Benjamin I-PER
, O
they O
are O
the O
grip O
of O
the O
human O
race O
travelling O
in O
this O
train O
after O
the O
emergency O
brake O
. O

The O
shock O
of O
those O
" O
normal O
disasters O
" O
, O
such O
as O
the O
reactor O
accidents O
that O
threaten O
the O
survival O
of O
the O
species O
, O
has O
ripped O
the O
social O
science O
out O
of O
the O
dorm O
of O
progressive O
belief O
. O

This O
awakening O
finds O
its O
present O
expression O
in O
the O
abbreviated O
concept O
of O
the O
“ O
risk O
society O
” O
, O
whose O
secret O
message O
of O
salvation O
is O
to O
make O
the O
course O
of O
the O
world O
still O
controllable O
according O
to O
an O
enlightened O
enlightenment O
of O
itself O
. O

This O
hope O
of O
Ulrich B-PER
Beck I-PER
’s O
“ O
reflective O
modernization O
” O
is O
by O
no O
means O
new O
. O

In O
order O
to O
avoid O
the O
predictable O
catastrophe O
, O
already O
leading O
sociologists O
of O
the O
Weimar B-MISC
era I-MISC
, O
such O
as O
Max B-PER
Weber I-PER
and O
Karl B-PER
Mannheim I-PER
, O
argued O
that O
the O
real O
is O
to O
approach O
the O
concrete O
utopian O
. O

And O
in O
fact O
: O

The O
rule O
of O
law O
, O
democratic O
self O
- O
determination O
and O
material O
welfare O
are O
nothing O
more O
than O
a O
disenchanted O
form O
of O
realization O
of O
that O
utopia O
that O
has O
long O
since O
been O
taken O
from O
heaven O
to O
earth O
: O

Everyone O
produces O
according O
to O
his O
abilities O
, O
each O
consumes O
according O
to O
his O
needs O
. O

This O
secularized O
ideal O
of O
the O
right O
of O
all O
to O
everything O
, O
however O
, O
is O
now O
seen O
as O
utopianly O
outdated O
by O
the O
ecologically O
- O
inspired O
“ O
utopia O
of O
zero O
option O
” O
, O
more O
specifically O
: O

A O
kind O
of O
general O
prohibition O
is O
imposed O
on O
the O
border O
. O

This O
formula O
, O
used O
by O
the O
social O
scientist O
Claus B-PER
Offe I-PER
, O
provides O
the O
entry O
into O
the O
exit O
of O
such O
almost O
objective O
processes O
as O
automation O
, O
agricultural O
chemization O
, O
wiring O
, O
etc O
. O

To O
make O
it O
tasty O
, O
however O
, O
is O
not O
much O
more O
than O
a O
residual O
hope O
of O
escaping O
the O
unstoppable O
catastrophe O
resulting O
from O
a O
generalization O
of O
the O
principle O
of O
“ O
free O
movement O
for O
free O
citizens O
” O
by O
halting O
and O
stalling O
. O

Is O
this O
utopia O
of O
voluntary O
ascension O
not O
at O
risk O
of O
succumbing O
to O
the O
ban O
of O
the O
omnipotence O
of O
the O
present O
? O

As O
the O
critical O
force O
of O
utopian O
thought O
is O
slowed O
down O
in O
the O
science O
of O
enlightenment O
, O
in O
social O
self O
- O
thematization O
the O
dimension O
of O
historical O
significance O
is O
diminished O
in O
the O
horizon O
of O
historical O
objective O
perspectives O
. O

This O
vacuum O
is O
not O
only O
a O
feedstock O
for O
ideologies O
such O
as O
those O
of O
posthistory O
, O
but O
this O
utopia O
also O
promotes O
fixation O
on O
substitute O
programs O
such O
as O
fundamentalism O
, O
regionalism O
, O
and O
feminism O
. O

It O
lacks O
the O
memory O
of O
what O
is O
undisturbed O
in O
utopian O
thinking O
, O
it O
gives O
up O
that O
utopian O
after O
- O
thinking O
that O
hits O
the O
spark O
that O
can O
ignite O
the O
light O
that O
accompanies O
the O
idea O
of O
a O
better O
society O
. O

Confronted O
with O
the O
risks O
of O
a O
risky O
society O
, O
a O
disciplinary O
organized O
scientific O
activity O
is O
objectively O
overloaded O
. O

For O
the O
increasing O
potential O
for O
destruction O
in O
nature O
and O
society O
created O
by O
the O
individual O
sciences O
themselves O
has O
its O
reason O
not O
least O
also O
in O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
subjects O
merely O
engage O
in O
umbilical O
observation O
, O
while O
remaining O
in O
their O
ivory O
towers O
. O

In O
this O
imperative O
multidisciplinary O
cooperation O
of O
the O
natural O
, O
human O
and O
social O
sciences O
, O
science O
raises O
a O
special O
responsibility O
from O
society O
because O
of O
its O
objective O
relationship O
to O
the O
totality O
of O
the O
social O
. O

First O
of O
all O
, O
sociology O
has O
the O
self O
- O
critical O
task O
of O
turning O
away O
from O
its O
own O
home O
and O
acting O
contagious O
by O
this O
example O
. O

Just O
like O
a O
“ O
house O
of O
open O
doors O
” O
with O
inner O
pluralism O
, O
it O
enables O
a O
process O
of O
combining O
various O
methods O
and O
theories O
. O

The O
cognitive O
identity O
of O
sociology O
is O
by O
no O
means O
jeopardized O
by O
this O
openness O
, O
as O
the O
subject O
has O
stabilized O
itself O
organizational O
and O
its O
academic O
reputation O
seems O
to O
be O
secured O
. O

Its O
status O
as O
a O
science O
of O
interpretation O
requires O
the O
practice O
of O
extreme O
tolerance O
toward O
competing O
paradigms O
, O
different O
methodological O
approaches O
, O
and O
the O
divergence O
in O
interpretation O
of O
social O
circumstances O
. O

Because O
social O
analysis O
can O
not O
operate O
with O
an O
objective O
claim O
to O
knowledge O
. O

Rather O
, O
social O
theory O
convinces O
by O
reasoning O
, O
that O
is O
, O
by O
empirical O
triviality O
and O
interpretative O
plausibility O
. O

For O
this O
reason O
, O
the O
future O
of O
sociology O
lies O
in O
establishing O
a O
unity O
of O
originally O
diverging O
traditions O
: O

The O
method O
of O
experiential O
knowledge O
, O
on O
the O
one O
hand O
, O
and O
the O
hermeneutics O
of O
the O
humanities O
, O
on O
the O
other O
. O

This O
principle O
of O
tolerance O
in O
one O
’s O
own O
home O
also O
implies O
a O
direct O
connection O
to O
the O
houses O
of O
the O
same O
street O
, O
that O
is O
, O
the O
strict O
cooperation O
of O
sociology O
with O
other O
social O
sciences O
, O
if O
it O
does O
not O
want O
to O
reveal O
its O
great O
goal O
of O
cognition O
, O
which O
, O
according O
to O
Horkheimer O
, O
consists O
in O
formulating O
a O
theory O
of O
the O
historical O
course O
of O
the O
era O
. O

This O
gigantic O
research O
program O
is O
only O
feasible O
if O
sociology O
advances O
into O
a O
medium O
of O
communication O
between O
the O
subjects O
of O
history O
, O
economics O
, O
anthropology O
, O
ethnology O
and O
psychology O
, O
etc O
. O
, O
which O
jointly O
engage O
in O
a O
philosophical O
fundamental O
reflection O
, O
are O
ready O
for O
a O
continuous O
exchange O
of O
individual O
scientific O
advances O
and O
systematically O
link O
the O
empirical O
research O
efforts O
with O
theory O
formation O
. O

This O
orientation O
of O
social O
sciences O
towards O
a O
historically O
and O
empirically O
meaningful O
theory O
of O
social O
sciences O
to O
be O
developed O
through O
research O
cooperation O
is O
only O
a O
first O
step O
. O

A O
second O
must O
follow O
. O

For O
in O
the O
social O
sciences O
, O
which O
are O
increasingly O
specialized O
, O
the O
subject O
of O
their O
research O
efforts O
is O
not O
only O
crumbling O
between O
the O
fingers O
, O
but O
the O
meaning O
of O
their O
teaching O
and O
research O
is O
limited O
to O
the O
craftsmanship O
of O
the O
shooter O
, O
who O
remains O
with O
his O
leaves O
, O
even O
if O
the O
water O
stands O
to O
his O
throat O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
the O
future O
perspective O
of O
the O
humanities O
and O
social O
sciences O
lies O
in O
the O
emerging O
coalition O
of O
humanities O
. O

According O
to O
American B-MISC
historian O
Robert B-PER
Darnton I-PER
, O
a O
new O
subject O
configuration O
, O
which O
consequently O
involves O
a O
dissolution O
of O
traditional O
faculties O
and O
disciplines O
, O
leads O
to O
an O
innovation O
boost O
: O

The O
one O
- O
dimensionality O
of O
cause O
and O
event O
research O
is O
overcome O
in O
favor O
of O
a O
reality O
- O
scientific O
understanding O
of O
the O
symbolic O
cultural O
system O
as O
the O
common O
reference O
point O
of O
humanities O
. O

Let O
us O
put O
together O
: O

First O
, O
sociology O
must O
not O
only O
recognize O
itself O
as O
an O
empirical O
, O
comprehensive O
and O
critical O
social O
science O
, O
but O
also O
productively O
use O
its O
character O
as O
a O
multi O
- O
paradigm O
science O
. O

Second O
, O
the O
project O
of O
a O
restructured O
social O
theory O
requires O
interdisciplinary O
cooperation O
among O
the O
various O
social O
sciences O
subjects O
. O

Finally O
, O
thirdly O
, O
the O
science O
of O
society O
, O
by O
its O
perspective O
on O
the O
whole O
of O
the O
human O
life O
context O
, O
is O
best O
suited O
to O
assert O
a O
general O
interest O
of O
mankind O
in O
the O
dangerous O
drive O
of O
the O
magical O
learners O
of O
the O
technical O
- O
scientific O
civilization O
, O
the O
independent O
individual O
sciences O
with O
their O
particularist O
rationalities O
. O

The O
current O
task O
of O
sociology O
is O
to O
bring O
the O
sciences O
whose O
differentiation O
is O
irreversible O
to O
the O
common O
denominator O
of O
a O
multidisciplinary O
discourse O
, O
which O
seeks O
to O
solve O
a O
question O
binding O
on O
all O
: O

How O
to O
prevent O
the O
disaster O
. O

The O
elaboration O
of O
this O
existential O
question O
does O
not O
succeed O
as O
a O
genius O
of O
a O
researcher O
or O
a O
subject O
, O
but O
is O
conceivable O
only O
as O
a O
joint O
work O
of O
all O
sciences O
. O

Thus O
, O
the O
science O
of O
enlightenment O
is O
quite O
the O
protagonist O
of O
a O
utopian O
program O
: O

Overcoming O
disciplinary O
boundaries O
. O

The O
indifferent O
side O
- O
by O
- O
side O
of O
university O
sciences O
is O
scientifically O
irresponsible O
and O
as O
outdated O
as O
the O
idea O
of O
unified O
science O
in O
the O
face O
of O
world O
hazards O
and O
their O
complex O
interdependence O
. O

The O
melody O
" O
If O
everyone O
does O
his O
thing O
, O
the O
whole O
thing O
will O
already O
succeed O
" O
is O
an O
extremely O
dangerous O
slumber O
song O
. O

From O
the O
sleep O
of O
reason O
a O
" O
interdisciplinarity O
from O
below O
" O
is O
awakened O
, O
which O
Jürgen B-PER
Mittelstraß I-PER
describes O
as O
cross O
- O
thinking O
, O
as O
questions O
that O
no O
one O
has O
asked O
yet O
, O
as O
learning O
what O
his O
own O
discipline O
does O
not O
yet O
know O
. O

The O
Doc- O

" O
Often O
a O
Dominant O
Mother O
" O
FR B-MISC
Talk I-MISC
with O
Psychotherapist O
Arthur B-PER
Cooper I-PER

The B-LOC
climate I-LOC
crisis I-LOC
. O

For O
therapists O
, O
eating O
disorders O
are O
often O
still O
a O
mystery O
. O

Their O
patients O
have O
a O
dependence O
that O
is O
purely O
psychological O
. O

A O
cure O
method O
that O
would O
rule O
out O
a O
relapse O
does O
not O
exist O
. O

It O
is O
so O
frightening O
that O
more O
and O
more O
people O
, O
especially O
women O
, O
suffer O
from O
bulimia O
, O
malnutrition O
or O
cravings O
. O

FR B-MISC
employee I-MISC
Daniela B-PER
Saur I-PER
spoke O
with O
psychotherapist O
Arthur B-PER
Cooper I-PER
about O
the O
diseases O
. O

He O
considers O
the O
topic O
of O
eating O
disorders O
to O
be O
one O
of O
the O
“ O
most O
exciting O
” O
in O
psychotherapy O
. O

from B-ORG
: O

Mr. O
Cooper B-PER
, O
you O
have O
said O
that O
you O
like O
working O
with O
people O
who O
have O
a O
disturbed O
eating O
behavior O
. O

Why O
is O
? O

and O
Cooper B-PER
: O

The O
rise O
in O
addiction O
diseases O
, O
especially O
those O
of O
bulimia O
, O
malnutrition O
and O
cravings O
, O
reflect O
our O
broken O
society O
. O

It O
shows O
that O
we O
are O
no O
longer O
able O
to O
take O
it O
in O
healthy O
measure O
. O

The O
Doc- O

Where O
to O
find O
unhelpful O
help O

Many O
people O
feel O
alone O
with O
their O
suffering O
. O

But O
it O
does O
not O
have O
to O
be O
so O
. O

There O
are O
also O
weather B-LOC
and O
surrounding O
areas O
: O

by O
Niddatal B-LOC
: O

Self O
- O
help O
group O
to O
cope O
with O
eating O
disorders O
, O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
from O
8 O
p.m. O
in O
the O
premises O
of O
the O
office O
activities O
in O
Kaichen B-LOC
. O

and O
Nidda B-LOC
: O

Self O
- O
help O
group O
of O
the O
Women O
’s O
Emergency O
Call O
in O
Borsdorf B-LOC
, O
meeting O
every O
Friday O
from O
7:30 O
p.m. O
in O
the O
Weiherstraße B-LOC
12 O
( O
Tel O
. O

0 O
60 O
43 O
/ O
44 O
71 O
) O
. O

by O
Karben B-LOC
: O

Conversational O
group O
for O
addicts O
, O
meetings O
every O
Thursday O
from O
17:00 O
to O
19:00 O
and O
from O
20:00 O
to O
22:00 O
in O
the O
Catholic O
community O
center O
of O
St. B-LOC
Bonifatius I-LOC
. O

The O
Doc- O

Social O
market O
economy O

In O
the O
face O
of O
ever O
- O
increasing O
debt O
mountains O
, O
Chancellor O
Kohl B-PER
appeals O
to O
a O
public O
who O
still O
remembers O
that O
after O
the O
reunification O
, O
no O
one O
will O
be O
worse O
than O
before O
. O

The O
motto O
is O
“ O
Keep O
Measure O
! O
” O

Ludwig B-PER
Erhard I-PER
had O
already O
issued O
decades O
earlier O
, O
which O
was O
then O
not O
least O
a O
seriously O
perceived O
economic O
downturn O
in O
the O
so O
far O
prosperous O
economy O
that O
cost O
him O
the O
chancellor O
’s O
office O
. O

The O
foundations O
of O
Erhard B-PER
’s I-PER
“ O
Social B-MISC
Market I-MISC
Economy I-MISC
” O
had O
, O
along O
with O
other O
economists O
of O
the O
“ O
Freiburger B-ORG
Schule I-ORG
” O
, O
mainly O
worked O
out O
by O
Walter B-PER
Eucken I-PER
. O

The O
new O
regulatory O
model O
was O
developed O
mainly O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
analyses O
of O
the O
" O
central O
administration O
economy O
" O
. O

Eucken B-PER
’s I-PER
research O
shows O
that O
plan O
and O
market O
economies O
are O
complex O
systems O
, O
whose O
different O
mechanisms O
of O
functioning O
can O
not O
be O
arbitrarily O
exchanged O
with O
one O
another O
. O

A O
proof O
of O
this O
is O
not O
only O
the O
failure O
of O
all O
previous O
attempts O
of O
a O
“ O
Third O
Way O
” O
, O
but O
also O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
transformation O
of O
the O
DDR B-MISC
economy I-MISC
. O

Thus O
, O
the O
private O
“ O
black O
markets O
” O
also O
existing O
in O
planned O
economies O
complement O
the O
central O
allocation O
system O
of O
planned O
bureaucracies O
. O

Under O
the O
conditions O
of O
free O
exchange O
relations O
, O
however O
, O
they O
are O
superfluous O
, O
but O
, O
as O
they O
arise O
from O
a O
particular O
special O
situation O
, O
they O
can O
not O
be O
transferred O
unbrokenly O
into O
“ O
normal O
” O
markets O
. O

The O
same O
applies O
to O
the O
exchange O
of O
goods O
with O
other O
state O
- O
commercial O
countries O
. O

As O
soon O
as O
free O
movement O
of O
goods O
becomes O
possible O
, O
those O
of O
a O
" O
rational O
choice O
" O
shall O
take O
the O
place O
of O
the O
previously O
prescribed O
trade O
relations O
. O

The O
establishment O
of O
the O
order O
model O
of O
the O
" O
Freiburger B-ORG
Schule I-ORG
" O
is O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
clearly O
dependent O
on O
a O
social O
" O
natural O
state O
" O
in O
Eucken B-PER
's I-PER
principles O
. O

The O
demand O
alone O
of O
the O
necessary O
dissolution O
of O
power O
groups O
is O
practically O
impossible O
in O
today O
’s O
Federal O
Republic B-LOC
; O
at O
least O
as O
long O
as O
it O
is O
rightly O
assumed O
that O
the O
accusation O
of O
“ O
group O
anarchy O
” O
is O
first O
directed O
at O
workers O
and O
trade O
unions O
. O

In O
many O
cases O
, O
they O
still O
have O
to O
struggle O
with O
income O
adjustments O
due O
to O
increased O
costs O
, O
although O
the O
share O
of O
wage O
costs O
in O
value O
- O
added O
production O
is O
now O
on O
average O
only O
20 O
% O
. O

However O
: O

The O
complexity O
of O
modern O
societies O
does O
not O
seem O
to O
override O
the O
order O
model O
of O
the O
“ O
social O
market O
economy O
” O
. O

Its O
purpose O
was O
precisely O
to O
reduce O
complexity O
by O
setting O
frameworks O
for O
private O
self O
- O
control O
– O
other O
models O
we O
do O
n’t O
have O
. O

The O
Doc- O

In O
reality O
, O
Empress O
Agnes B-PER
wore O
the O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
Jewelry I-MISC
" O
The O
long O
- O
standing O
mystery O
about O
the O
jewels O
of O
a O
Salier O
Empress O
now O
solved O
/ O
A O
dramatic O
finding O
in O
the O
Mainz B-MISC
Jewish B-MISC
Ghetto I-MISC

Few O
archaeological O
finds O
from O
the O
Middle O
Ages O
have O
gained O
such O
popularity O
as O
an O
eagle O
- O
powder B-MISC
fibel I-MISC
from O
a O
treasure O
of O
25 O
golden O
jewelry O
that O
was O
found O
in O
1880 O
by O
chance O
during O
drainage O
work O
from O
the O
cellar O
of O
a O
burnt O
house O
in O
the O
former O
" O
Judgasse B-LOC
" O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
and O
can O
now O
be O
shown O
in O
museum O
vitrines O
only O
after O
adventurous O
bypasses O
. O

It O
is O
still O
considered O
to O
be O
the O
largest O
and O
most O
important O
discovery O
of O
its O
kind O
. O

In O
addition O
to O
four O
half O
- O
moon O
ear O
rings O
, O
nine O
finger O
rings O
, O
a O
chest O
bandage O
( O
Loros O
) O
and O
a O
jewel O
collar O
( O
Maniacion O
) O
- O
both O
replicas O
of O
Byzantine B-MISC
Emperor O
insignia O
- O
especially O
among O
the O
eight O
buckle O
, O
kegel O
, O
and O
disc O
fibres O
was O
noticed O
an O
exceptionally O
precious O
with O
an O
eagle O
- O
powder B-MISC
motif I-MISC
, O
as O
she O
could O
have O
probably O
only O
adorned O
an O
Empress O
. O

To O
this O
view O
came O
the O
historian O
Otto B-PER
von I-PER
Falke I-PER
in O
1913 O
in O
his O
book O
with O
the O
first O
publication O
of O
the O
Jewelry O
Stock O
. O

He O
attributed O
them O
to O
Empress O
Gisela B-PER
, O
wife O
of O
Konrad B-PER
II I-PER
, O
German B-MISC
king O
( O
1024 O
- O
1039 O
) O
and O
emperor O
( O
from O
1027 O
) O
of O
the O
Salier O
family O
. O

Under O
the O
name O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
- I-MISC
Fibel I-MISC
" O
she O
has O
become O
known O
and O
famous O
. O

This O
dating O
was O
lively O
discussed O
at O
the O
time O
, O
but O
never O
disproved O
, O
until O
the O
senior O
conservator O
at O
the O
Roman O
- O
German B-LOC
Central I-LOC
Museum I-LOC
in O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
Dr. O
Mechthild B-PER
Schulze I-PER
- O
Dörrlamm O
, O
inspired O
by O
the O
years O
of O
preparations O
for O
the O
Salier O
Exhibition O
in O
Speyer B-LOC
, O
now O
introduces O
a O
younger O
emperor O
as O
the O
owner O
of O
this O
special O
jewelry O
: O

Agnes B-PER
of I-PER
Poitou I-PER
, O
1043 O
married O
to O
Emperor O
Henry B-PER
III I-PER
in O
Ingelheim B-LOC
and O
crowned O
Empress O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
the O
" O
secret O
capital O
of O
the O
empire O
" O
. O

The O
now O
- O
researched O
affiliation O
of O
the O
jewelry O
is O
based O
on O
new O
, O
well O
- O
dated O
archaeological O
finds O
and O
comparative O
studies O
with O
Byzantine B-MISC
and O
Fatimidic B-MISC
jewelry O
and O
decorative O
elements O
of O
the O
time O
in O
question O
, O
as O
she O
carries O
out O
Mechthild B-PER
Schulze I-PER
- O
Dörrlamm O
in O
her O
book O
" O
The O
Mainz B-MISC
treasure O
of O
Empress O
Agnes B-PER
from O
the O
mid-11th O
century O
- O
New O
investigations O
on O
the O
so O
- O
called O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
jewelry I-MISC
" O
" O
( O
Jan B-ORG
- I-ORG
Thorbecke I-ORG
- O
Verlag O
, O
Sigmaringen B-MISC
1991 O
) O
. O

The O
round O
, O
gold O
- O
mealed O
eagle O
Pfauen B-MISC
- I-MISC
Fibel I-MISC
is O
the O
only O
piece O
that O
could O
already O
be O
purchased O
in O
1880 O
shortly O
after O
the O
discovery O
of O
the O
jewelry O
from O
the O
Mainz B-MISC
Antiquity B-LOC
Museum I-LOC
and O
has O
since O
been O
preserved O
there O
. O

Today O
, O
after O
many O
turbulent O
years O
, O
all O
the O
other O
jewelry O
pieces O
are O
in O
the O
Kunstgewerbemuseum B-LOC
Berlin I-LOC
. O

In O
1880 O
, O
the O
construction O
workers O
had O
first O
hidden O
their O
find O
, O
then O
divided O
the O
jewelry O
among O
themselves O
and O
sold O
it O
in O
pieces O
. O

In O
the O
following O
decades O
, O
the O
jewelry O
appeared O
in O
the O
most O
diverse O
places O
and O
with O
the O
most O
diverse O
owners O
. O

Some O
parts O
were O
also O
considered O
completely O
lost O
in O
the O
meantime O
, O
while O
others O
were O
severely O
damaged O
in O
World O
War B-MISC
II I-MISC
. O

The O
eagle O
- O
powder B-MISC
fibel I-MISC
is O
the O
prototype O
of O
a O
fibel B-MISC
form I-MISC
, O
of O
which O
so O
far O
only O
three O
specimens O
are O
known O
, O
which O
, O
as O
by O
the O
senior O
conservative O
, O
besides O
, O
all O
originate O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
. O

A O
common O
characteristic O
of O
these O
three O
disc O
fibres O
is O
that O
the O
eagle O
is O
depicted O
with O
a O
parrot O
crown O
of O
spread O
wings O
. O

This O
mixture O
of O
eagle O
and O
peacock O
has O
a O
profoundly O
Christian O
meaning O
: O

The O
eagle O
symbolizes O
the O
resurrection O
and O
ascension O
of O
Christ B-PER
, O
the O
pavon O
the O
eternal O
life O
. O

That O
this O
crowned O
bird O
was O
regarded O
at O
the O
same O
time O
as O
an O
imperial O
sign O
and O
became O
the O
precursor O
of O
the O
Staubish O
Reichsadler B-MISC
, O
is O
also O
an O
indication O
of O
the O
time O
classification O
. O

His O
body O
shape O
in O
front O
view O
, O
only O
the O
head O
in O
profile O
, O
apparently O
dates O
back O
to O
Islamic O
art O
in O
the O
10th O
century O
. O

Stylistically O
, O
the O
most O
beautiful O
and O
" O
quality O
- O
filled O
" O
of O
the O
three O
eagle O
fibrils O
has O
new O
dimensions O
. O

Instead O
of O
the O
formerly O
largely O
framed O
small O
center O
, O
the O
dominant O
large O
motif O
is O
surrounded O
by O
a O
now O
narrow O
edge O
. O

Another O
clue O
to O
dating O
these O
breakthrough O
- O
worked O
email O
fibers O
to O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
11th O
century O
are O
small O
flower O
stems O
of O
gold O
wire O
at O
the O
roundings O
and O
pearl O
wire O
lines O
at O
the O
ends O
of O
the O
pavement O
wheel O
. O

Where O
and O
from O
whom O
the O
precious O
jewelry O
was O
made O
can O
only O
be O
guessed O
. O

Part O
of O
this O
suggests O
Byzantine B-MISC
or O
Italian B-MISC
goldsmiths O
who O
may O
have O
migrated O
to O
or O
have O
been O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
for O
a O
long O
time O
at O
that O
time O
. O

Because O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
in O
the O
high O
Middle O
Ages O
called O
the O
" O
Diadem B-MISC
of I-MISC
the O
Empire O
" O
, O
was O
in O
the O
Salier B-MISC
era I-MISC
the O
city O
with O
the O
most O
royal O
stays O
and O
possessed O
jewelry O
workshops O
of O
supra O
- O
regional O
importance O
, O
whose O
traces O
can O
still O
be O
demonstrated O
today O
on O
the O
old O
Rhine O
coast O
by O
lead O
waste O
, O
raw O
casts O
and O
semi O
- O
fabricates O
. O

Since O
the O
overwhelming O
majority O
of O
the O
jewelry O
comes O
from O
the O
mid O
- O
third O
of O
the O
11th O
century O
, O
it O
is O
most O
likely O
to O
be O
attributed O
to O
Agnes B-PER
of I-PER
Poitou I-PER
, O
Mechthild B-PER
Schulze I-PER
- O
Dörlamm O
believes O
, O
especially O
since O
underneath O
it O
is O
a O
golden O
finger O
ring O
with O
the O
image O
of O
her O
husband O
, O
Emperor O
Heinrich B-PER
III I-PER
. O

With O
the O
gift O
certificates O
issued O
immediately O
after O
the O
wedding O
on O
extensive O
lands O
and O
possessions O
, O
Henry B-PER
III I-PER
made O
her O
one O
of O
the O
richest O
- O
equipped O
queens O
in O
the O
history O
of O
the O
medieval O
empire O
; O
whether O
as O
an O
expression O
of O
his O
affection O
or O
foreseeable O
independent O
care O
for O
a O
" O
foreign O
" O
ruler O
, O
is O
not O
handed O
over O
. O

It O
is O
unlikely O
that O
this O
wealthy O
Empress O
would O
later O
have O
pledged O
all O
her O
jewelry O
by O
her O
own O
hand O
to O
a O
Jewish O
merchant O
. O

It O
would O
be O
conceivable O
that O
Agnes B-PER
, O
as O
a O
throne O
regent O
in O
1066 O
, O
on O
the O
occasion O
of O
the O
wedding O
of O
her O
barely O
16 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
son O
and O
successor O
to O
the O
throne O
, O
Henry B-PER
IV I-PER
, O
with O
Bertha B-PER
of I-PER
Turin I-PER
, O
almost O
a O
year O
younger O
, O
officially O
gave O
the O
jewelry O
to O
her O
daughter O
- O
in O
- O
law O
. O

Bertha B-PER
almost O
belonged O
to O
the O
family O
, O
since O
she O
had O
already O
renounced O
the O
throne O
as O
a O
young O
girl O
and O
retired O
to O
an O
Italian B-MISC
monastery O
, O
where O
she O
no O
longer O
needed O
the O
representative O
jewelry O
. O

When O
Empress O
Bertha B-PER
now O
died O
in O
1087 O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
at O
a O
time O
when O
Henry B-PER
IV I-PER
equipped O
his O
third O
Roman O
campaign O
and O
had O
to O
struggle O
again O
with O
financial O
difficulties O
due O
to O
his O
numerous O
wars O
, O
it O
could O
have O
been O
possible O
that O
under O
these O
circumstances O
he O
had O
pledged O
the O
jewelry O
of O
his O
deceased O
wife O
to O
a O
reliable O
, O
wealthy O
Jew O
. O

However O
, O
when O
Heinrich B-PER
returned O
to O
Mainz B-LOC
ten O
years O
later O
, O
there O
was O
no O
trace O
of O
the O
jewelry O
. O

For O
a O
year O
earlier O
, O
almost O
all O
the O
inhabitants O
of O
the O
Jewish B-LOC
Quarter I-LOC
had O
been O
killed O
by O
a O
pogrom O
of O
the O
Crusaders O
, O
including O
- O
as O
is O
traditionally O
believed O
- O
the O
chief O
of O
the O
synagogue O
, O
who O
two O
days O
after O
his O
forced B-LOC
baptism I-LOC
set O
fire O
to O
the O
synagogue O
and O
house O
and O
burned O
himself O
in O
it O
with O
his O
whole O
family O
. O

Ancient O
traces O
of O
fire O
are O
said O
to O
have O
been O
recognizable O
at O
the O
surprising O
discovery O
of O
the O
jewelry O
800 O
years O
later O
. O

Even O
if O
the O
history O
of O
this O
gold O
jewelry O
leaves O
some O
questions O
open O
, O
the O
individual O
pieces O
possess O
a O
special O
cultural O
- O
historical O
value O
and O
, O
within O
the O
framework O
of O
the O
newly O
acquired O
knowledge O
, O
convey O
a O
vivid O
picture O
of O
medieval O
splendor O
at O
the O
imperial O
court O
- O
but O
above O
all O
of O
a O
Salic O
Empress O
who O
has O
now O
really O
carried O
the O
famous O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
- I-MISC
Fibel I-MISC
" O
: O

Agnes B-PER
of I-PER
Poitou I-PER
. O

The O
Doc- O

Doctors O

The O
Emergency O
Service O
: O

DRK B-LOC
- I-LOC
Haus I-LOC
, O
Flachstraße B-LOC
1 O
, O
Tel O
. O

46 O
10 O
10 O
; O
fixed O
notary O
hours O
: O

11 O
to O
13 O
and O
15 O
to O
20 O
hours O
. O

The O
Doc- O

Pharmacy O

S O
is O
: O

Pharmacy B-LOC
at I-LOC
the O
Market O
, O
Marketstr B-LOC
. O
12 O
, O
Tel O
. O

by O
30 O
65 O
09 O
. O

Kohlheck B-LOC
Pharmacy I-LOC
, O
Eulenstr B-LOC
. O
5 O
, O
Tel O
. O

by O
46 O
65 O
15 O
. O

Merian B-LOC
Pharmacy I-LOC
, O
Kaiser O
- O
Friedrich B-LOC
Ring I-LOC
30 O
, O
Tel O
. O

by O
30 O
64 O
91 O
. O

and O
so O
. O
: O

Elephant B-LOC
Pharmacy I-LOC
, O
Kirchgasse B-LOC
18 O
, O
Tel O
. O

by O
30 O
33 O
48 O
. O

Paracelsus B-LOC
Pharmacy I-LOC
, O
Schultheßstr B-LOC
. O
32 O
a O
, O
Bierstadt B-LOC
, O
Tel O
. O

by O
50 O
27 O
25 O
. O

Pharmacy B-LOC
, O
Brunhildenstr B-LOC
. O
25 O
, O
Tel O
. O

76 O
to O
15 O
92 O
. O

eye O
doctors O

J. B-PER
Litsch I-PER
, O
Mainzer B-LOC
Str I-LOC
. O
36 O
, O
Wiesbaden B-LOC
, O
Tel O
. O

06 O
11 O
/ O
30 O
34 O
45 O
( O
practice O
) O
or O
06 O
11 O
/ O
80 O
99 O
11 O
( O
apartment O
) O
. O

The O
Doc- O

A O
new O
prize O
for O
women O
's O
political O
engagement O
City O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
grants O
" O
Tony B-MISC
- I-MISC
Sender I-MISC
" O
- O
award O
for O
the O
first O
time O
in O
autumn O
1992 O
/ O
Local O
reference O
is O
in O
demand O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
A. I-LOC
M. I-LOC
As O
the O
first O
German B-MISC
city O
in O
Frankfurt B-LOC
am I-LOC
Main I-LOC
, O
a O
prize O
was O
awarded O
for O
women O
’s O
political O
engagement O
or O
work O
in O
women O
’s O
research O
with O
local O
relevance O
. O

With O
the O
newly O
created O
Tony B-MISC
Sender I-MISC
Award I-MISC
, O
the O
City O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
aims O
to O
distinguish O
outstanding O
innovative O
achievements O
in O
the O
field O
of O
employment O
and O
works O
that O
deal O
with O
cultural O
or O
social O
issues O
. O

Priced O
are O
Frankfurt B-MISC
women I-MISC
, O
women O
’s O
projects O
of O
this O
city O
or O
women O
dedicated O
to O
a O
Frankfurt B-MISC
theme O
. O

The O
Tony B-MISC
Sender I-MISC
Prize I-MISC
is O
endowed O
with O
20,000 O
Mark O
and O
will O
be O
awarded O
for O
the O
first O
time O
on O
November O
27 O
, O
1992 O
, O
after O
a O
two O
- O
year O
period O
. O

The O
Women O
’s O
Referendum O
also O
wants O
to O
draw O
attention O
with O
the O
Tony O
- O
Sender B-MISC
Prize I-MISC
to O
the O
fact O
that O
more O
than O
40 O
years O
after O
the O
entry O
into O
force O
of O
the O
Constitution O
of O
the O
Federal O
Republic B-LOC
, O
Article O
3(2 O
) O
– O
“ O
Men O
and O
women O
are O
equal O
” O
– O
is O
still O
being O
violated O
. O

Women O
continue O
to O
suffer O
disadvantages O
in O
many O
areas O
of O
daily O
life O
. O

Who O
was O
the O
woman O
whose O
name O
will O
make O
the O
prize O
known O
again O
beyond O
the O
borders O
of O
the O
city O
? O

Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
was O
born O
in O
1888 O
in O
the O
present O
- O
day O
Wiesbaden B-MISC
district O
of O
Biebrich B-LOC
as O
a O
daughter O
of O
well O
- O
off O
parents O
. O

According O
to O
the O
end O
of O
the O
century O
and O
her O
social O
class O
, O
she O
had O
a O
life O
as O
a O
guardian O
daughter O
and O
an O
instruction O
in O
the O
" O
Salon O
Sciences O
" O
to O
take O
her O
intended O
place O
in O
civil O
society O
as O
a O
wife O
and O
mother O
. O

But O
already O
at O
the O
Higher O
School O
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
became O
aware O
that O
she O
did O
not O
want O
to O
be O
confined O
to O
" O
children O
, O
kitchen O
, O
church O
" O
. O

The O
struggle O
for O
more O
freedom O
should O
not O
stop O
throughout O
their O
lives O
. O

Instead O
of O
working O
on O
her O
taxes O
, O
she O
visited O
a O
commercial O
hospital O
and O
thus O
secured O
her O
independence O
as O
a O
commercial O
employee O
. O

Her O
political O
work O
began O
at O
the O
age O
of O
22 O
in O
Paris B-LOC
, O
where O
she O
worked O
as O
a O
correspondent O
of O
a O
German B-MISC
company O
during O
the O
day O
, O
and O
in O
the O
evening O
- O
in O
addition O
to O
studying O
socialist O
theorists O
- O
engaged O
in O
the O
French B-MISC
workers O
' O
movement O
and O
women O
's O
education O
work O
. O

Her O
stay O
in O
Paris B-LOC
, O
which O
promoted O
her O
emancipation O
, O
was O
closed O
by O
the O
outbreak O
of O
the O
First B-MISC
World I-MISC
War I-MISC
; O
she O
was O
dismissed O
as O
the O
Germans B-MISC
of O
the O
country O
. O

Returning O
to O
Frankfurt B-LOC
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
joined O
the O
Social O
Democratic O
War O
Opposition O
and O
became O
a O
fierce O
fighter O
for O
ending O
a O
war O
that O
served O
not O
the O
defense O
of O
the O
homeland O
, O
but O
the O
conquest O
of O
new O
markets O
and O
the O
oppression O
of O
previously O
free O
peoples O
. O

She O
was O
an O
opponent O
of O
the O
SPD B-MISC
's I-MISC
bourgeois I-MISC
peace I-MISC
policy I-MISC
, O
was O
expelled O
from O
the O
party O
and O
in O
1917 O
co O
- O
founder O
of O
the O
USPD B-ORG
. O

The O
Independent O
Social O
Democrat O
wrote O
Frankfurt B-MISC
City O
History O
during O
the O
November I-MISC
Revolution I-MISC
. O

She O
was O
the O
secretary O
- O
general O
of O
the O
Workers O
’ O
Council O
and O
– O
after O
the O
introduction O
of O
women O
’s O
voting O
rights O
in O
November O
1918 O
– O
a O
member O
of O
the O
Frankfurt B-MISC
City O
Ordinary O
Assembly O
. O

The O
young O
Weimar B-LOC
Republic I-LOC
did O
not O
find O
Tony B-PER
Senders I-PER
' O
unrestricted O
approval O
; O
it O
had O
hoped O
for O
more O
basic O
democracy O
from O
the O
revolution O
: O

the O
enforcement O
of O
council O
thought O
in O
politics O
, O
the O
economy O
and O
in O
the O
enterprises O
. O

As O
editor O
of O
the O
USPD B-MISC
daily I-MISC
newspaper I-MISC
" O
Volksrecht B-ORG
" O
and O
the O
German B-ORG
Metalworkers I-ORG
' O
Association O
's O
" O
Werfsräte O
- O
Magazin O
" O
, O
she O
criticized O
the O
political O
development O
; O
as O
a O
member O
of O
the O
German B-MISC
Reichstag B-ORG
and O
a O
party O
politician O
, O
she O
did O
her O
best O
to O
actively O
participate O
in O
shaping O
politics O
. O

Faced O
with O
the O
decision O
to O
either O
submit O
to O
Lenin B-PER
’s I-PER
dictates I-PER
and O
direct O
the O
USPD B-ORG
to O
Moscow O
or O
return O
to O
the O
ranks O
of O
social O
democracy O
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
once O
again O
chose O
freedom O
– O
this O
time O
to O
not O
let O
the O
party O
’s O
strategy O
be O
alienated O
. O

Not O
very O
easily O
, O
she O
decided O
to O
reunite O
with O
the O
SPD B-ORG
, O
which O
she O
thought O
had O
arranged O
too O
much O
with O
the O
bourgeois O
republic O
. O

In O
Parliament O
, O
she O
emerged O
as O
a O
recognised O
specialist O
in O
economic O
and O
foreign O
policy O
matters O
; O
as O
a O
politician O
and O
editor O
- O
in O
- O
chief O
of O
the O
SPD B-MISC
magazine I-MISC
" O
Womenwelt B-ORG
" O
she O
advocated O
the O
equal O
participation O
of O
women O
in O
all O
areas O
of O
life O
. O

The O
Jewish O
, O
Social O
Democrat O
, O
and O
trade O
unionist O
was O
targeted O
by O
the O
National O
Socialists B-ORG
in O
the O
late O
1920s O
. O

An O
open O
threat O
of O
murder O
prompted O
her O
to O
flee O
to O
Belgium B-LOC
via O
Czechoslovakia I-LOC
immediately O
after O
the O
Reichstag O
elections O
on O
5 O
March O
1933 O
. O

In O
1935 O
, O
she O
did O
not O
return O
to O
the O
Flanders B-LOC
, O
settled O
in O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
and O
soon O
applied O
for O
U.S. B-MISC
citizenship I-MISC
. O

The O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
in O
the O
era O
of O
the O
social O
- O
reforming O
“ O
New B-MISC
Deal I-MISC
” O
seemed O
to O
offer O
it O
the O
greatest O
possible O
guarantee O
of O
a O
life O
in O
individual O
and O
political O
freedom O
and O
without O
coercion O
to O
social O
conventions O
. O

Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
reached O
a O
final O
professional O
peak O
as O
a O
representative O
of O
the O
U.S. B-MISC
and O
later O
of O
the O
International O
Trade O
Union O
at O
the O
Economic O
and O
Social O
Council O
of O
the O
United O
Nations B-ORG
. O

Her O
main O
work O
was O
in O
the O
Commission B-ORG
on I-ORG
the I-ORG
Status I-ORG
of I-ORG
Women I-ORG
and O
in O
the O
Commission O
on O
Human B-ORG
Rights I-ORG
. O

Its O
name O
is O
associated O
with O
the O
struggle O
against O
human O
enslavement O
through O
forced O
labour O
and O
against O
politically O
motivated O
deprivation O
of O
liberty O
. O

She O
tirelessly O
gathered O
evidence O
of O
human O
rights O
violations O
and O
unwaveringly O
prosecuted O
states O
that O
violated O
human O
rights O
and O
freedoms O
. O

Until O
her O
death O
in O
1964 O
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
firmly O
insisted O
that O
women O
and O
men O
can O
equal O
achievements O
if O
they O
only O
have O
equal O
opportunities O
and O
are O
not O
hindered O
by O
social O
norms O
or O
economic O
disadvantages O
. O

To O
remove O
class O
and O
gender O
barriers O
, O
to O
make O
them O
completely O
disappear O
, O
was O
their O
program O
. O

Achieving O
a O
life O
in O
free O
self O
- O
determination O
was O
their O
goal O
. O

The O
Doc- O

Medical O
assistance O
for O
homeless O
A O
ambulance O
treats O
the O
" O
berbers B-MISC
" O
who O
are O
often O
sent O
away O
in O
medical O
offices O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
A. I-LOC
M. I-LOC
" O
So O
, O
the O
feet O
stay O
in O
for O
20 O
minutes O
now O
. O
" O

With O
a O
friendly O
but O
certain O
tone O
, O
Klaus B-PER
Hetzel I-PER
, O
a O
nurse O
and O
hygiene O
specialist O
, O
gives O
his O
instructions O
. O

Josef B-PER
Schmidt I-PER
( O
Name O
of O
the O
Red O
. O

Changed O
) O
, O
homeless O
, O
obediently O
puts O
his O
wounded O
legs O
in O
the O
large O
plastic O
bush O
with O
a O
dunkellila O
liquid O
. O
” O

Open O
legs O
, O
” O
explains O
Klaus B-PER
Hetzel I-PER
, O
“ O
are O
the O
most O
common O
disease O
among O
homeless O
people O
. O
” O

Since O
May O
18 O
, O
the O
" O
Medical O
Ambulance O
for O
Homeless O
People O
" O
in O
Sachsenhausen B-LOC
has O
opened O
its O
doors O
. O

Within O
two O
weeks O
, O
there O
were O
21 O
patients O
with O
Hetzel B-PER
and O
his O
team O
. O

Almost O
all O
patients O
, O
the O
nurse O
says O
, O
complained O
of O
“ O
smoking O
legs O
” O
or O
“ O
belly O
ulcers O
. O
” O

It O
is O
treated O
with O
a O
disinfecting O
solution O
of O
potassium O
permanganate O
. O

Other O
doctors O
suggest O
other O
remedies O
, O
” O
Hetzel B-PER
reports O
. O

However O
, O
he O
can O
demonstrate O
and O
prove O
success O
with O
his O
method O
: O

All O
treatments O
documented O
by O
Hetzel B-PER
with O
photos O
or O
video O
. O

As O
the O
homeless O
could O
see O
on O
their O
own O
, O
on O
the O
one O
hand O
, O
what O
the O
regular O
application O
brings O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
even O
newcomers O
can O
be O
more O
easily O
convinced O
by O
the O
images O
of O
the O
meaning O
of O
the O
undertaking O
. O

Suspicion O
is O
the O
main O
reason O
why O
most O
homeless O
people O
do O
n’t O
undergo O
“ O
normal O
” O
medical O
treatment O
, O
Hetzel B-PER
explains O
. O

In O
no O
case O
will O
I O
go O
to O
such O
a O
place O
again O
, O
” O
Josef B-PER
Schmidt I-PER
asserts O
. O

He O
knows O
what O
he O
is O
talking O
about O
. O

With O
their O
mostly O
not O
exactly O
“ O
bourgeois O
” O
appearance O
, O
the O
“ O
Barbers B-MISC
” O
, O
as O
they O
call O
themselves O
, O
are O
not O
popular O
clients O
in O
medical O
offices O
. O

They O
are O
often O
sent O
out O
on O
exits O
. O

The O
problem O
, O
the O
under O
- O
support O
of O
the O
homeless O
in O
the O
medical O
field O
, O
has O
been O
recognized O
by O
Hetzel B-PER
at O
his O
other O
workplace O
, O
the O
homeless O
- O
eating O
issue O
in O
the O
Affentorhaus B-LOC
, O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

Together O
with O
his O
wife O
Dagmar B-PER
– O
she O
is O
a O
doctor O
and O
makes O
the O
diagnoses O
in O
the O
“ O
Medical O
Ambulance O
” O
– O
he O
offered O
a O
weekly O
hour O
of O
care O
there O
. O

This O
was O
not O
enough O
and O
, O
above O
all O
, O
the O
necessary O
facilities O
were O
lacking O
. O

They O
are O
in O
the O
new O
home O
: O

Three O
rooms O
, O
fully O
furnished O
and O
a O
bathroom O
equipped O
with O
everything O
it O
needs O
for O
body O
care O
. O

One O
of O
the O
rooms O
serves O
as O
a O
treatment O
room O
, O
another O
as O
an O
office O
( O
“ O
the O
whole O
paperwork O
is O
no O
longer O
at O
home O
” O
) O
, O
and O
finally O
there O
is O
a O
living O
room O
in O
the O
entrance O
area O
– O
the O
“ O
waiting O
room O
” O
with O
a O
coffee O
outlet O
and O
a O
communication O
center O
. O

The O
carrier O
of O
the O
Medical O
Ambulance O
is O
the O
Working B-ORG
Community I-ORG
for I-ORG
Evangelical I-ORG
Communication I-ORG
( O
AFEK B-ORG
) O
. O

Since O
1984 O
, O
it O
has O
been O
registered O
as O
a O
non O
- O
profit O
association O
and O
is O
fully O
funded O
by O
donations O
. O

His O
statutory O
goal O
of O
caring O
for O
marginalized O
groups O
, O
he O
wants O
to O
cope O
with O
by O
giving O
" O
help O
to O
self O
- O
help O
" O
. O

This O
can O
be O
seen O
in O
the O
Medical O
Ambulance O
project O
. O

Without O
the O
dedicated O
packing O
of O
former O
homeless O
people O
, O
the O
rooms O
would O
hardly O
have O
been O
renovated O
so O
quickly O
and O
cheaply O
. O
” O

It O
was O
a O
completely O
down O
- O
down O
pub O
. O
” O

All O
the O
work O
, O
even O
the O
walls O
and O
tiles O
, O
had O
been O
done O
by O
the O
helpers O
. O
” O

If O
they O
have O
a O
goal O
in O
mind O
, O
then O
they O
become O
aware O
of O
their O
social O
co O
- O
responsibility O
, O
” O
explained O
Hetzel B-PER
, O
who O
describes O
himself O
as O
a O
“ O
decisive O
Christian B-MISC
, O
” O
using O
the O
former O
homeless O
. O

His O
Credo O
is O
therefore O
an O
ancient O
Indian B-MISC
prayer I-MISC
that O
hangs O
as O
a O
poster O
opposite O
his O
office O
chair O
: O

“ O
Great O
Spirit O
, O
keep O
me O
from O
judging O
a O
man O
before O
I O
have O
walked O
half O
a O
moon O
in O
his O
Mokassins O
. O
” O

Since O
the O
AFEK B-ORG
is O
fully O
engaged O
in O
donations O
, O
especially O
financial O
assistance O
is O
always O
welcome O
. O

Klaus B-PER
Hetzel I-PER
provides O
information O
by O
telephone O
62 O
35 O
59 O
from O
Monday O
to O
Thursday O
between O
9 O
a.m. O
and O
17 O
a.m. O
and O
Friday O
between O
9 O
a.m. O
and O
13 O
a.m. O

The O
Doc- O

Ludwig B-LOC
's I-LOC
Linde I-LOC
and O
a O
Lovely O
Maid O

by O
Auerbach B-LOC
. O

With O
the O
often O
quoted O
and O
much O
- O
songed O
" O
Tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
it O
is O
like O
with O
the O
repeatedly O
mentioned O
" O
Siegfriedquelle B-LOC
" O
, O
where O
the O
fabulous O
recke O
died O
: O

No O
one O
can O
tell O
and O
prove O
exactly O
where O
both O
natural O
monuments O
can O
be O
found O
. O

Therefore O
, O
it O
is O
not O
surprising O
that O
these O
are O
present O
multiple O
times O
. O

Thus O
, O
there O
is O
the O
said O
tree O
in O
Momart B-LOC
, O
Kimbach B-LOC
, O
Airlenbach B-LOC
, O
Olfen B-LOC
and O
also O
near O
the O
Fürstenlager B-LOC
near O
Auerbach B-LOC
( O
Kreis O
Bergstraße B-LOC
) O
. O

Per O
the O
latter O
place O
may O
be O
considered O
the O
" O
real O
" O
because O
there O
in O
1778 O
a O
linde O
was O
planted O
and O
" O
Tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
was O
baptized O
. O

The O
Prince B-LOC
's I-LOC
Camp I-LOC
, O
former O
summer O
residence O
of O
the O
Hessic B-MISC
Landgraphs O
, O
with O
its O
friendly O
park O
filled O
with O
numerous O
exotic O
trees O
, O
also O
seems O
to O
be O
the O
right O
environment O
for O
the O
legendary O
Linde O
. O

Because O
closely O
connected O
with O
the O
" O
Tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
and O
the O
graceful O
Prince B-LOC
camp I-LOC
is O
a O
love O
romance O
in O
that O
park O
and O
forest O
scene O
. O

The O
opera O
singer O
, O
later O
intendant O
of O
Darmstädter B-MISC
Hoftheater O
and O
master O
of O
local O
storytelling O
, O
Ernst B-PER
Pasqué I-PER
, O
drew O
them O
literally O
. O

That O
the O
poet O
was O
able O
to O
explain O
this O
so O
easily O
: O

He O
lived O
for O
two O
decades O
( O
1871 O
- O
1892 O
) O
on O
the O
Bergstraße B-LOC
and O
learned O
through O
his O
good O
relations O
with O
Grand O
Duke O
Ludwig B-PER
IV I-PER
many O
things O
, O
which O
distinguishes O
the O
originality O
of O
his O
narrative O
" O
There B-MISC
stands I-MISC
a I-MISC
tree I-MISC
in I-MISC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
. O

At O
the O
" O
Platz B-LOC
Fürstenlager I-LOC
" O
landgrave O
Friedrich B-PER
miraculously O
met O
Karoline B-PER
Seitz I-PER
of O
Grasellenbach B-LOC
, O
a O
girl O
of O
simple O
origin O
, O
he O
married O
her O
and O
lived O
with O
her O
a O
happy O
marriage O
. O

Pasqué B-PER
portrayed O
Karoline B-PER
in O
his O
booklet O
as O
" O
a O
strikingly O
beautiful O
blood O
- O
young O
thing O
of O
about O
17 O
years O
old O
, O
a O
blonde O
whose O
fine O
naturally O
crooked O
blondes O
under O
the O
sammet O
cap O
were O
a O
little O
too O
curious O
and O
made O
wide O
on O
the O
white O
forehead O
. O
" O

At O
this O
coincidental O
meeting O
on O
the O
occasion O
of O
a O
county O
feast O
in O
the O
Prince B-LOC
's I-LOC
camp I-LOC
, O
Karoline B-PER
is O
said O
to O
have O
sung O
the O
old O
folk O
song O
" O
It B-MISC
stands I-MISC
a I-MISC
tree I-MISC
in I-MISC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
. O

In O
commemoration O
of O
the O
feast O
, O
" O
under O
all O
sorts O
of O
solemn O
ceremonies O
" O
a O
young O
linde O
was O
planted O
, O
" O
at O
a O
place O
of O
height O
, O
from O
where O
one O
had O
a O
magnificent O
view O
of O
the O
Schönberger B-MISC
Valley O
and O
the O
old O
picturesque O
castle O
of O
the O
Count O
of O
Erbach B-LOC
- I-LOC
Schönberg I-LOC
" O
. O

An O
eremite O
spoke O
" O
the O
blessing O
of O
the O
forest O
over O
the O
young O
linde O
, O
whom O
he O
- O
inspired O
by O
Karolin B-PER
's I-PER
singing O
- O
baptized O
" O
tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
. O

However O
, O
this O
tree O
no O
longer O
exists O
, O
a O
flash O
destroyed O
it O
. O

In O
his O
place O
, O
however O
, O
Count O
Ludwig B-PER
zu I-PER
Erbach I-PER
- O
Schönberg O
( O
1792 O
- O
1863 O
) O
planted O
a O
new O
linde O
, O
which O
since O
then O
bears O
the O
name O
" O
Ludwigslinde B-LOC
" O
, O
a O
tall O
tree O
of O
powerful O
shape O
and O
widely O
branched O
peak O
growth O
. O

From O
the O
bank O
under O
the O
Linde O
you O
can O
enjoy O
a O
magnificent O
view O
- O
through O
the O
valley O
to O
the O
mountains O
, O
to O
Starkenburg B-LOC
, O
to O
Knodenkopf B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
point O
of O
reference O
Krehberg B-LOC
, O
Märkerwald B-LOC
, O
Hemsberg B-LOC
, O
Vetzersberg B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
Rhineland B-LOC
level I-LOC
to O
the O
Pfälzerwald B-LOC
. O

Next O
to O
the O
Ludwigslinde B-LOC
is O
the O
Schönberger B-MISC
Herrenwingert B-LOC
. O

Previously O
it O
belonged O
to O
the O
Count O
of O
Erbach B-LOC
- I-LOC
Schönberg I-LOC
, O
today O
it O
is O
owned O
by O
the O
State B-ORG
Weingutes I-ORG
Bergstraße I-ORG
. O

There O
should O
be O
not O
a O
few O
people O
– O
mountaineers B-MISC
and O
strangers O
– O
who O
fell O
in O
love O
with O
this O
square O
at O
the O
Ludwigslinde B-LOC
and O
the O
Herrenwingert B-LOC
. O

Reinhard B-PER
Treber I-PER

The O
Doc- O

Epiphanias O
- O
Kantorin O
has O
been O
dedicated O
to O
classical O
and O
new O
music O
for O
14 O
years O
. O

and O
north B-LOC
. O

Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
has O
been O
office O
for O
14 O
years O
at O
the O
Evangelical O
Epiphanias B-ORG
community I-ORG
in O
the O
North B-LOC
End I-LOC
. O

It O
can O
all O
be O
built O
. O

Especially O
the O
last O
concert O
in O
April O
did O
it O
to O
her O
. O
” O

Then O
I O
realized O
what O
we O
now O
have O
for O
an O
excellent O
choir O
. O
” O

In O
the O
difficult O
romantic O
A O
- O
cappella O
sentences O
, O
the O
singers O
would O
have O
responded O
to O
the O
slightest O
instruction O
. O

And O
for O
her O
orchestra O
, O
she O
has O
only O
praise O
words O
. O

That O
such O
achievements O
do O
not O
fall O
from O
the O
sky O
, O
but O
can O
only O
be O
achieved O
through O
continuous O
, O
tough O
trial O
work O
, O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
mentions O
only O
on O
the O
margins O
. O

Twice O
a O
year O
– O
mostly O
on O
Easter O
and O
during O
Advent O
– O
choir O
and O
orchestra O
give O
their O
major O
concerts O
to O
the O
Epiphanias B-ORG
community I-ORG
. O

This O
year O
, O
the O
office O
had O
selected O
an O
interesting O
blend O
of O
romantic O
a O
- O
cappella O
singing O
, O
i.e. O
unaccompanied O
pieces O
for O
choir O
, O
and O
orchestral O
works O
of O
the O
20th O
century O
. O

For O
the O
Advent O
, O
a O
program O
with O
music O
by O
Johann B-PER
Sebastian I-PER
Bach I-PER
is O
planned O
. O

This O
concert O
costs O
a O
lot O
to O
the O
community O
. O

On O
the O
columns O
sticky O
posters O
, O
and O
on O
leaflets O
and O
in O
newspapers O
is O
vigorously O
advertised O
. O

The O
church O
on O
Holzhausenstraße B-LOC
is O
usually O
full O
. O

However O
, O
other O
, O
less O
expensive O
events B-MISC
are O
almost O
always O
well O
attended O
. O

So O
the O
Matinee O
met O
with O
organ O
and O
violin O
music O
at O
the O
end O
of O
March O
at O
an O
astonishing O
audience O
interest O
, O
although O
not O
such O
as O
Bach B-PER
, O
Mozart B-PER
or O
Mendelssohn B-PER
, O
but O
exclusively O
music O
of O
the O
20th O
century O
was O
on O
the O
program O
. O

We O
just O
have O
our O
regular O
audience O
in O
the O
meantime O
, O
” O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
does O
not O
look O
without O
pride O
at O
the O
rugged O
musical O
activity O
. O

The O
office O
has O
something O
without O
which O
the O
concert O
operations O
do O
not O
work O
: O

of O
relationships O
. O

In O
difficult O
choir O
and O
orchestral O
works O
, O
especially O
high O
- O
quality O
blasts O
are O
important O
. O

Every B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
has O
the O
best O
contacts O
. O

Most O
work O
in O
the O
Radio O
Symphony O
Orchestra O
and O
like O
to O
help O
out O
in O
the O
Epiphanias B-LOC
Church I-LOC
. O

Many O
people O
enjoy O
playing O
music O
with O
the O
choir O
so O
much O
that O
they O
like O
to O
perform O
as O
a O
soloist O
. O
” O

The O
fact O
that O
the O
orchestra O
has O
its O
own O
orchestra O
is O
unusual O
. O

At O
church O
concerts O
, O
otherwise O
, O
the O
musicians O
you O
need O
are O
usually O
bought O
together O
. O

Or O
engage O
an O
entire O
professional O
. O

That O
’s O
expensive O
and O
it O
’s O
not O
guaranteed O
a O
good O
concert O
. O
” O

The O
orchestra O
performs O
as O
well O
as O
the O
choir O
. O

The O
relationships O
are O
much O
closer O
, O
and O
the O
musicians O
are O
motivating O
each O
other O
at O
concerts O
. O
” O

That O
very O
heavy O
romantic O
pieces O
, O
such O
as O
the O
German B-MISC
Requiem O
of O
Brahms B-PER
, O
with O
the O
orchestra O
consisting O
mainly O
of O
laymen O
, O
can O
hardly O
be O
created O
, O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
likes O
to O
buy O
. O

To O
Johann B-PER
Sebastian I-PER
Bach I-PER
the O
office B-MISC
has O
a O
divided O
relationship O
, O
despite O
the O
concerts O
on O
20 O
September O
and O
6 O
December O
, O
at O
which O
mainly O
works O
of O
the O
Thomas B-MISC
Cantor I-MISC
are O
performed O
. O

What O
disturbs O
them O
is O
translation O
. O

Every O
second O
year O
cantates O
from O
the O
Christmas B-MISC
oratory I-MISC
. O

That O
would O
be O
every B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
too O
boring O
. O
” O

Many O
do O
n’t O
even O
know O
that O
not O
only O
Bach B-PER
composed O
good O
and O
interesting O
music O
. O
” O

Thus O
, O
during O
her O
14 O
years O
of O
work O
, O
she O
performed O
no O
work O
twice O
except O
Mozart B-PER
's I-PER
" O
Requiem B-MISC
" O
and O
Johannes O
Brahms O
' O
" O
Song B-MISC
of I-MISC
Fate I-MISC
" O
. O

I O
want O
to O
suggest O
to O
people O
at O
least O
how O
wide O
the O
range O
of O
different O
pieces O
is O
. O
” O

Also O
, O
for O
them O
, O
the O
music O
history O
does O
not O
end O
with O
Anton B-PER
Bruckner I-PER
. O

His O
interest O
in O
modern O
music O
is O
great O
. O

With O
the O
chorus O
, O
the O
office O
is O
difficult O
with O
it O
. O
" O

I O
do O
n’t O
want O
to O
make O
the O
singers O
new O
music O
fans O
. O

Everyone O
should O
be O
open O
to O
it O
. O
” O

As O
an O
organist O
, O
she O
devotes O
herself O
largely O
to O
modern O
music O
. O

Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
conducts O
a O
brilliantly O
trained O
, O
70 O
- O
member O
church O
choir O
and O
its O
own O
orchestra O
, O
has O
a O
free O
hand O
in O
their O
planning O
, O
and O
even O
her O
church O
musical O
staff O
is O
currently O
not O
causing O
her O
any O
concerns O
. O

Do O
you O
have O
any O
wishes O
? O
” O

A O
new O
, O
modern O
organ O
– O
that O
would O
be O
what O
you O
are O
missing O
for O
musical O
happiness O
. O

The O
relatively O
small O
instrument O
from O
the O
1950s O
has O
few O
registers O
and O
an O
outdated O
technique O
. O
” O

The O
new O
intonation O
two O
years O
ago O
has O
, O
after O
all O
, O
sounded O
a O
lot O
. O
” O

But O
she O
does O
not O
give O
herself O
any O
illusions O
. O

There O
is O
a O
lack O
of O
money O
for O
a O
new O
organ O
. O

Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
has O
built O
up O
a O
lot O
in O
the O
North B-LOC
End I-LOC
and O
therefore O
does O
not O
waste O
the O
thought O
of O
a O
career O
change O
. O
” O

In O
a O
new O
community O
, O
I O
would O
have O
to O
start O
from O
the O
bottom O
. O
” O

The O
Doc- O

Meeting O
+ O
Meeting O

Acordeon O
- O
Musikverein O
" O
Heiterkeit B-ORG
" O
Griesheim B-LOC

Classes O
are O
held O
every O
Thursday O
( O
from O
2 O
p.m. O
) O
at O
the O
Bürgerhaus O
Griesheim B-LOC
, O
Schwarzerlenweg B-LOC
57 O
( O
Clubroom O
3 O
) O
. O

And O
the O
orchestra O
of O
the O
association O
performs O
in O
the O
club O
room O
1 O
in O
Griesheim B-LOC
every O
Tuesday O
, O
from O
19 O
to O
20.30 O
. O

Working O
Group O
for O
Seniors B-ORG
: O

Members O
meet O
on O
the O
afternoon O
of O
the O
association O
every O
first O
Tuesday O
of O
the O
month O
( O
at O
15 O
pm O
) O
at O
the O
social B-LOC
station I-LOC
at O
the O
Rohmerplatz B-LOC
( O
Parterre O
) O
. O

Athletik O
- O
Sportverein O
1990 B-ORG
in I-ORG
Griesheim I-ORG

Sports O
sign O
preparation O
and O
weight O
loss O
after O
prior O
registration O
every O
Monday O
, O
Wednesday O
and O
Friday O
( O
from O
18:00 O
each O
) O
in O
the O
Griesheimer B-LOC
Sporthalle I-LOC
, O
Linkstraße B-LOC
86 O
- O
88 O

Contact O
to O
: O

by O
Klaus B-PER
Samer I-PER
( O
tel O
. O

37 O
19 O
74 O
) O
and O
Hugo B-PER
Zingel I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

38 O
and O
42 O
27 O
. O

Bockenheimer B-ORG
Men I-ORG
's O
Choir O
1837 O

The O
active O
members O
of O
the O
choir O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
in O
the O
church O
hall O
of O
the O
evangelical O
St. B-LOC
Jakobskirche I-LOC
, O
Grempstraße B-LOC
41 O
. O

Women O
and O
men O
interested O
in O
singing O
in O
the O
community O
can O
participate O
in O
this O
test O
without O
obligation O
. O

Information O
about O
all O
association O
activities O
is O
given O
by O
Chairman O
Wolfgang B-PER
Ochs I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

and O
76 O
67 O
43 O
) O
. O

Bockenheimer B-ORG
Zitherkranz I-ORG
in O
1886 O

The O
activists O
of O
the O
association O
try O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
from O
8 O
p.m. O
) O
at O
the O
" O
Bürgertreff B-LOC
Bockenheim I-LOC
" O
, O
Schwälmer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Interested O
participants O
will O
receive O
more O
information O
from O
Rudi B-PER
May I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

77 O
15 O
and O
43 O
) O
. O

The O
Sporting B-ORG
Club O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
: O

The O
members O
meet O
for O
the O
association O
evening O
every O
Thursday O
, O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
, O
at O
the O
hostel O
" O
Zur B-LOC
Krone I-LOC
" O
in O
Seckbach B-LOC
, O
Wilhelmshöher B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
165 O
. O

Guests O
interested O
in O
sports O
are O
welcome O
. O

The O
BUND O
- O
Ortsverband B-ORG
2/9 I-ORG
holds O
a O
meeting O
every O
third O
Wednesday O
of O
the O
month O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
at O
the O
Bürgertreff B-LOC
Bockenheim I-LOC
, O
Schwälmer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Chorgemeinschaft B-ORG
1857 I-ORG
in O
Griesheim O

The O
participants O
meet O
every O
Thursday O
( O
from O
19:45 O
to O
21:15 O
) O
at O
the O
Bürgerhaus B-LOC
Griesheim I-LOC
, O
Schwarzerlenweg B-LOC
57 O
( O
Clubroom O
2 O
) O
. O

Women O
and O
men O
are O
included O
in O
the O
choir O
. O

For O
more O
information O
see O
Horst B-PER
Seip I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

38 O
and O
20 O
97 O
. O

From O
Frankfurt B-ORG
: O

The O
members O
of O
the O
diving O
group O
meet O
every O
Thursday O
at O
7:30 O
p.m. O
in O
the O
Hallenbad B-LOC
Sachsenhausen I-LOC
, O
Textorstraße B-LOC
42 O
. O

Information O
about O
rescue O
training O
gives O
Willi B-PER
Vogt I-PER
Tel O
. O

by O
58 O
66 O
23 O
. O

Information O
can O
also O
be O
obtained O
every O
Wednesday O
from O
15:00 O
to O
20:00 O
at O
the O
DLRG B-MISC
office I-MISC
Tel O
. O

28 O
05 O
12 O
. O

FKV B-ORG
1911 I-ORG
and I-ORG
Maagard I-ORG

The O
Dancing O
Corps O
of O
the O
Frankfurt B-ORG
Carnival I-ORG
Vereins I-ORG
1911 I-ORG
trains O
every O
Wednesday O
from O
19 O
to O
20:30 O
( O
minigarde O
from O
18 O
to O
19 O
) O
at O
the O
Vereinsheim B-LOC
, O
Petterweilstraße B-LOC
69 O
in O
Bornheim B-LOC
( O
Bunker O
) O
. O

Girls O
who O
are O
interested O
in O
dancing O
in O
the O
community O
are O
included O
. O

Contact O
to O
: O

by O
Manuela B-PER
Koch I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

0 O
61 O
87 O
/ O
34 O
56 O
. O

Frankfurt B-ORG
Canoe I-ORG
Club I-ORG
in O
1913 O

The O
association O
invites O
to O
its O
meetings O
- O
every O
Thursday O
, O
from O
18:00 O
, O
in O
the O
" O
Friedel B-LOC
- I-LOC
Baureis I-LOC
- O
Haus O
" O
, O
the O
boat O
house O
on O
the O
Peace B-LOC
Bridge I-LOC
. O

Further O
information O
is O
provided O
by O
Press O
Writer O
Eckard B-PER
Dünnemann I-PER
at O
Tel O
. O

88 O
98 O
81 O
( O
from O
6 O
p.m. O

Frankfurter O
Karneval O
- O
Gesellschaft B-ORG
Red I-ORG
and I-ORG
White I-ORG

The O
association O
’s O
“ O
regiment O
supporters O
” O
train O
every O
Monday O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
at O
the O
“ O
Bürgertreff B-LOC
Bockenheim I-LOC
” O
in O
Schwälmer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Frankfurter B-ORG
Liedertafel I-ORG
of O
1827 O

For O
the O
choir O
trial O
, O
the O
activists O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
from O
19:45 O
to O
21:45 O
am O
) O
at O
the O
" O
Council B-LOC
Meeting I-LOC
Philanthropin I-LOC
" O
, O
Hebelstraße B-LOC
17 O
. O

In O
the O
choir O
are O
included O
women O
and O
men O
interested O
in O
singing O
in O
the O
community O
. O

Contact O
to O
: O

Chairman O
Hans B-PER
Riebartsch I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

and O
31 O
34 O
61 O
. O

The O
Frankfurter B-ORG
Musikverein I-ORG

For O
the O
orchestra O
trial O
, O
the O
players O
will O
meet O
on O
Thursday O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
in O
the O
Josefsklause B-LOC
in O
Bornheim B-LOC
, O
Berger B-LOC
Street I-LOC
133 O
. O

Director O
of O
the O
Blasorchester O
( O
Big O
Band O
Sound O
): O

by O
Norbert B-PER
Natho I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

46 O
12 O
85 O
; O
Director O
: O

by O
Hans O
- O
Joachim B-PER
Eberhardt I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

and O
42 O
65 O
02 O
. O

Frankfurt B-ORG
City I-ORG
Guard I-ORG
: O

For O
training O
, O
the O
members O
of O
the O
Rambas O
Ballet O
of O
the O
1st B-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
Damen I-ORG
- O
Fanfarenkorps O
and O
the O
Playmannszug O
meet O
every O
Wednesday O
at O
the O
" O
Haus B-LOC
Gallus I-LOC
" O
, O
Frankenallee B-LOC
111 O
. O

The O
FTG B-ORG
47 I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG

Judo O
for O
children O
is O
offered O
by O
the O
Frankfurt O
Gym O
and B-ORG
Sport I-ORG
Community I-ORG
1847 I-ORG
every O
Friday O
( O
children O
from O
six O
to O
ten O
years O
old O
) O
, O
and O
every O
Monday O
( O
children O
and O
adolescents O
from O
ten O
years O
old O
) O
, O
each O
from O
16:00 O
to O
18:00 O
, O
at O
the O
FTG B-LOC
Sports I-LOC
Centre I-LOC
in O
Bockenheim B-LOC
on O
Marburger B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Contact O
the O
FTG B-MISC
office I-MISC
tel O
. O

by O
77 O
49 O
29 O
. O

Former B-ORG
Professional I-ORG
Firefighters I-ORG
: O

The O
membership O
meeting O
is O
held O
every O
first O
Tuesday O
of O
the O
month O
at O
the O
restaurant O
Zur B-LOC
Stalburg I-LOC
( O
Nordend B-LOC
) O
, O
Glauburgstraße B-LOC
80 O
. O

The O
Frankfurt B-ORG
Kneippverein I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
offers O
every O
Monday O
( O
16:00 O
) O
and O
Thursday O
( O
18:00 O
) O
yoga O
exercises O
, O
as O
well O
as O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
10:00 O
) O
light O
gymnastics O
for O
ladies O
and O
gentlemen O
( O
16:00 O
gymnastics O
for O
ladies O
and O
gentlemen O
) O
in O
the O
district B-LOC
pool I-LOC
South I-LOC
, O
Textorstraße B-LOC
42 O
. O

Further O
information O
on O
the O
offers O
of O
the O
Kneippverein O
can O
be O
found O
at O
Hannelore B-PER
Kehlmann I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

39 O
and O
17 O
78 O
. O

The O
athletics O
department O
of O
the O
gymnastics B-ORG
and I-ORG
sports I-ORG
district I-ORG
98 I-ORG
Nordwest I-ORG
is O
looking O
for O
children O
( O
from O
ten O
years O
old O
) O
. O

Exercise O
hours O
are O
held O
on O
Mondays O
, O
Wednesdays O
and O
Fridays O
from O
17.30 O
to O
19.30 O
on O
the O
sporting O
field O
of O
Ernst B-ORG
- I-ORG
Reuter I-ORG
- O
Schule O
I. O
Interested O
people O
can O
contact O
coach O
Helmut B-PER
Terstegen I-PER
during O
the O
training O
hours O
. O

The O
department O
offers O
students O
a O
talent O
promotion O
in O
the O
staff O
jump O
. O

Information O
about O
Karl B-PER
Terstegen I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

57 O
to O
74 O
. O

Choreographer B-ORG
of I-ORG
Praunheim I-ORG
: O

The O
active O
members O
of O
the O
choir O
meet O
every O
Monday O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
at O
Christ B-LOC
- I-LOC
König I-LOC
, O
Damaschkeanger B-LOC
158 O
. O

Young O
men O
interested O
in O
singing O
in O
the O
community O
can O
find O
out O
about O
the O
male O
choir O
at O
Wilfried B-PER
Roth I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

57 O
42 O
71 O
) O
. O

Choreographer B-ORG
of I-ORG
Praunheim I-ORG
: O

The O
women O
of O
the O
association O
meet O
for O
a O
cozy O
gathering O
each O
first O
Monday O
of O
the O
month O
, O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
, O
in O
the O
congregation O
house O
of O
ChristKönig B-LOC
, O
Damaskkeanger B-LOC
158 O
. O

The O
post O
- O
sports B-ORG
club I-ORG
Blau I-ORG
- O
Gelb O
Frankfurt O

The O
association O
invites O
you O
to O
the O
" O
Ginnheimer B-MISC
Lauftreff I-MISC
" O
every O
Tuesday O
at O
18.30 O
. O

The O
starting O
point O
is O
the O
parking O
lot O
of O
the O
club O
at O
the O
Poststadion B-LOC
( O
Am B-LOC
Ginnheimer I-LOC
Wäldchen I-LOC
) O
. O

Cycling B-ORG
community I-ORG
1890 I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG

On O
the O
evening O
of O
the O
association O
, O
members O
and O
cycling O
enthusiasts O
meet O
every O
Friday O
( O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
) O
at O
the O
" O
Haus B-LOC
Ronneburg I-LOC
" O
in O
Preungesheim B-LOC
in O
Gelnhäuser B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
2 O
. O

The O
Rödelheimer B-ORG
Nine I-ORG
: O

The O
choir O
tries O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
20:30 O
) O
at O
the O
Rödelheimer B-LOC
Vereinsringheim I-LOC
in O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

The O
Frankfurt B-ORG
Sports I-ORG
Club I-ORG
: O

The O
association O
is O
looking O
for O
dance O
enthusiastic O
pedestrians O
who O
can O
find O
joy O
and O
fun O
dancing O
with O
rollis O
. O

Tests O
are O
conducted O
every O
Thursday O
( O
from O
20 O
to O
22 O
o’clock O
) O
at O
the O
BG B-LOC
Accident I-LOC
Clinic I-LOC
, O
Friedberger B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
. O

Contact O
to O
: O

Horst B-PER
Lozar I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

76 O
and O
37 O
) O
. O

Singing B-ORG
choir I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
locomotives O
1919 O
Frankfurt O

For O
their O
choir O
trial O
, O
the O
activists O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
at O
17:30 O
in O
the O
railway B-LOC
operating I-LOC
cantine I-LOC
, O
Camberger B-LOC
Street I-LOC
17 O
. O

The O
Freischütz B-ORG
Rödelheim I-ORG
: O

The O
active O
members O
of O
the O
association O
train O
every O
Sunday O
( O
from O
10 O
to O
12.30 O
pm O
) O
and O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
from O
19.30 O
to O
22.00 O
pm O
) O
at O
the O
stands O
at O
the O
Vereinsringheim O
in O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

Athletic B-ORG
Club I-ORG
Anker I-ORG
Hausen I-ORG

The O
members O
and O
friends O
of O
the O
association O
meet O
for O
a O
cozy O
gathering O
each O
Tuesday O
, O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
, O
at O
the O
club O
home O
of O
sports O
fishermen O
on O
Hausener B-LOC
Weg I-LOC
. O

Sport B-ORG
and I-ORG
Fun I-ORG
Club I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG

The O
club O
is O
still O
looking O
for O
players O
for O
a O
mixed O
volleyball O
group O
. O

Training O
is O
held O
every O
Thursday O
( O
from O
18:00 O
to O
20:00 O
) O
at O
the O
Anne B-LOC
- I-LOC
Frank I-LOC
- O
School O
, O
Fritz B-LOC
- I-LOC
Tarnow I-LOC
- O
Straße O
29 O
. O

Further O
information O
on O
tel O
. O

0 O
61 O
07 O
/ O
6 O
12 O
69 O
. O

The O
town B-ORG
of I-ORG
Rome I-ORG
: O

At O
the O
end O
of O
the O
school O
holidays O
, O
the O
club O
offers O
exercises O
in O
athletics O
and O
tournaments O
for O
boys O
and O
girls O
( O
6 O
to O
9 O
years O
old O
): O

Tuesday O
from O
15 O
to O
16:30 O
in O
the O
brothers O
- O
Scholl B-LOC
school I-LOC
I O
m O
Burgfeld B-LOC
7 O
. O

Further O
information O
is O
provided O
by O
Constanze B-PER
Spitz I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

and O
58 O
86 O
32 O
) O
. O

Tournament B-ORG
and I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
98 I-ORG
Northwest I-ORG

Classes O
in O
spinal O
gymnastics O
in O
the O
gym O
, O
White B-LOC
Church I-LOC
Way I-LOC
12 O
, O
Thursday O
( O
16 O
and O
17 O
hours O
) O
, O
Saturday O
( O
9:30 O
, O
10:30 O
and O
11:30 O
) O
and O
Monday O
( O
9 O
hours O
) O
. O

The O
wishes O
: O

Headquarters O
on O
Tuesdays O
and O
Thursdays O
from O
17:00 O
to O
19:00 O
, O
Tel O
. O

by O
58 O
10 O
23 O
. O

Tournament B-ORG
and I-ORG
Sports I-ORG
Club I-ORG
1878 I-ORG
Ginnheim I-ORG

The O
mixed O
choir O
of O
the O
singing O
department O
of O
the O
association O
performs O
each O
Friday O
from O
20:00 O
to O
22:00 O
at O
Clubhaus B-LOC
Ginnheim I-LOC
, O
Am O
Mühlgarten B-LOC
2 O
( O
Little O
Saal O
) O
. O

Tournament B-ORG
and I-ORG
Sports I-ORG
Club I-ORG
1860 I-ORG
Housen I-ORG

The O
association O
offers O
" O
Swimming O
for O
everyone O
" O
on O
Fridays O
( O
20 O
to O
22 O
pm O
) O
in O
the O
swimming O
hall O
of O
the O
Liebigschule B-ORG
in O
Westhausen B-LOC
( O
Kollwitzstraße B-LOC
) O
. O

Further O
information O
can O
be O
found O
at O
Rudi B-PER
Litzinger I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

76 O
to O
35 O
50 O
. O

Association B-ORG
for I-ORG
Briefmarkenkunde I-ORG
Rödelheim I-ORG

The O
members O
of O
the O
association O
meet O
for O
the O
association O
and O
lecture O
evening O
every O
second O
and O
fourth O
Thursday O
of O
the O
month O
from O
7:30 O
p.m. O
at O
Rödelheimer B-LOC
Vereinsringheim I-LOC
, O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

The O
Water B-ORG
Sports I-ORG
Club I-ORG
: O

The O
association O
offers O
swimming O
lessons O
for O
beginners O
and O
advanced O
students O
every O
Thursday O
( O
18 O
- O
21 O
) O
at O
Berthold B-LOC
- I-LOC
Otto I-LOC
- O
Schule O
, O
Piefernstraße B-LOC
18a O
( O
Griesheim B-LOC
) O
. O

Further O
information O
on O
the O
offers O
of O
the O
association O
is O
given O
by O
Günter B-PER
Gronemann I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

It O
is O
39 O
57 O
49 O
. O

Vespa B-ORG
Club I-ORG
" O
Scooterlads O
" O
from O
1985 O

The O
riders O
will O
meet O
each O
Wednesday O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
at O
the O
Ergo B-LOC
Bibamus I-LOC
on O
Eschersheimer B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
401 O
. O

Further O
information O
about O
the O
Vespa O
Club O
is O
provided O
by O
Wolfgang B-PER
Frey I-PER
at O
Tel O
. O

and O
51 O
10 O
91 O
. O

People O
’s O
Choir B-ORG
“ I-ORG
Frohsinn I-ORG
” I-ORG
Rödelheim I-ORG

For O
the O
choir O
trial O
, O
the O
activists O
meet O
every O
Wednesday O
at O
7:30 O
p.m. O
at O
Rödelheimer B-LOC
Vereinsringheim I-LOC
, O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

The O
Doc- O

From O
business O
life O
: O

Restaurant O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
Idylle O
under O
the O
Kastanie O

and B-LOC
overrad I-LOC
. O

It O
is O
written O
in O
1708 O
. O

It O
will O
take O
a O
year O
for O
Böttger B-PER
to O
invent O
the O
porcelain O
. O

It O
is O
the O
age O
of O
reason O
, O
of O
enlightenment O
. O

In O
the O
small O
village O
of O
Oberrad B-LOC
, O
wealthy O
Frankfurter B-MISC
families O
buy O
a O
land O
to O
experience O
" O
alda O
those O
senses O
- O
and O
pleasant O
pleasure O
" O
that O
they O
were O
looking O
for O
in O
the O
city O
in O
vain O
. O

On O
this O
site O
is O
created O
an O
excursion O
venue O
, O
the O
hostel O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
. O

284 O
years O
later O
, O
hospitality O
is O
still O
one O
of O
the O
popular O
destinations O
of O
the O
Ebbeleifans B-MISC
. O

For O
there O
the O
guest O
can O
chat O
, O
drink O
and O
eat O
delicious O
meals O
from O
11 O
a.m. O
to O
23 O
a.m. O
under O
the O
huge O
castany O
, O
protected O
by O
the O
wine O
growing O
on O
the O
bridge O
fence O
: O

From O
" O
Lyon B-MISC
's I-MISC
Twin O
Cut O
" O
and O
Bavarian B-MISC
strawberries O
soup O
through O
the O
salad O
soup O
" O
Slanke O
Linie O
" O
to O
the O
grilled O
pork O
and O
traditional O
" O
Green O
Sauce O
" O
. O

The O
real O
" O
Aalen B-MISC
Oberräder I-MISC
" O
had O
always O
had O
their O
regular O
table O
in O
the O
hostel O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
. O

The O
Ebbelwei B-MISC
itself O
was O
climbed O
, O
as O
evidenced O
today O
by O
an O
apparatus O
in O
the O
idyllic O
backyard O
along O
with O
a O
voluminous O
wine O
barrel O
. O

Not O
much O
has O
changed O
in O
visibility O
either O
. O

Although O
the O
venue O
is O
located O
directly O
on O
the O
busy O
Offenbacher B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
, O
you O
can O
hardly O
notice O
the O
noise O
in O
the O
garden O
. O

The O
village O
character O
, O
which O
retained O
the O
" O
mouthful O
pleasure O
" O
. O

Everyday O
in O
the O
historic O
guesthouse O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
, O
where O
on O
the O
first O
floor O
sometimes O
the O
male O
singing O
club O
tastes O
. O

Just O
a O
small O
tip O
for O
wheat O
beer O
drinkers O
: O

Those O
who O
order O
the O
last O
round O
at O
twenty O
before O
eleven O
will O
still O
be O
timely O
complimented O
by O
eleven O
. O

There O
is O
a O
police O
hour O
. O

and O
then O
: O

It O
is O
recommended O
as O
a O
sleeper O
drunk O
then O
the O
good O
, O
old O
Ebbelwei B-MISC
. O

The O
hostel O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
is O
located O
on O
Offenbacher B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
289 O
and O
is O
open O
daily O
from O
11 O
am O
to O
24 O
pm O
. O

It O
is O
best O
to O
get O
there O
by O
tram O
( O
line O
15 O
and O
16 O
, O
stop O
Bleiweißstraße B-LOC
) O
. O

The O
Doc- O

Free O
Assistance O
for O
Family O
Problems O

Northwest B-LOC
of I-LOC
Frankfurt I-LOC
. O

The O
educational O
counseling O
agency O
offers O
advice O
. O

Open O
is O
the O
access O
point O
for O
children O
, O
adolescents O
and O
adults O
. O

Whether O
problems O
with O
general O
life O
issues O
, O
troubles O
in O
marriage O
, O
developmental O
or O
educational O
problems O
, O
advice O
and O
assistance O
are O
offered O
in O
Ernst O
- O
Kahn B-LOC
Street I-LOC
49a O
. O

The O
consultation O
is O
free O
, O
regardless O
of O
confession O
and O
confidential O
. O

In O
urgent O
cases O
, O
short O
- O
term O
appointments O
- O
even O
in O
the O
evening O
- O
are O
granted O
. O

Notification O
of O
: O

Monday O
to O
Thursday O
from O
8 O
a.m. O
to O
17 O
p.m. O
; O
Friday O
between O
12 O
a.m. O
and O
17 O
p.m. O
by O
phone O
57 O
40 O
91 O
. O

The O
Doc- O

Plans O
of O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
for O
the O
time O
being O
failed O
football O
association O
: O

Fusion O
with O
post B-ORG
sports I-ORG
club I-ORG
" O
Blue O
- O
Yellow O
" O
is O
not O
permitted O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
A. I-LOC
M. I-LOC
The O
planned O
game O
community O
of O
the O
Hessian B-MISC
national O
football O
league O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
with O
the O
post B-ORG
sports I-ORG
club I-ORG
( O
PSV O
) O
blue O
- O
yellow O
, O
which O
has O
been O
reduced O
to O
Circuit O
B O
, O
will O
now O
not O
be O
achieved O
. O

The O
reserve O
team O
of O
the O
national O
league O
should O
look O
together O
with O
the O
post B-MISC
sportsmen I-MISC
. O

However O
, O
the O
Football O
Committee O
of O
the O
Hessische B-ORG
Fußballverband I-ORG
( O
HFV B-ORG
) O
decided O
at O
its O
recent O
meeting O
: O

A O
merger O
of O
reserve O
troops O
and O
first O
crew O
can O
not O
be O
agreed O
according O
to O
the O
statute O
. O

At O
first O
, O
the O
plans O
of O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
to O
interfere O
with O
the O
PSV B-ORG
have O
also O
failed O
. O

The O
city O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
refused O
to O
pay O
the O
costs O
of O
68,000 O
marks O
. O

They O
are O
afraid O
to O
create O
a O
precedent O
. O

The O
background O
: O

As O
long O
as O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
can O
not O
register O
two O
complete O
youth O
teams O
for O
the O
game O
operation O
, O
the O
first O
team O
may O
not O
play O
in O
the O
national O
league O
. O

In O
the O
youth O
area O
, O
however O
, O
the O
play O
community O
with O
the O
blue B-ORG
- I-ORG
yellow I-ORG
will O
be O
established O
soon O
, O
according O
to O
the O
participants O
. O

Then O
the O
A O
, O
B O
and O
C O
youth O
teams O
could O
train O
together O
at O
the O
post B-LOC
sports I-LOC
facility I-LOC
on O
the O
edge O
of O
the O
former O
garden B-LOC
showground I-LOC
. O

Both O
clubs O
would O
have O
preferred O
to O
see O
it O
, O
if O
even O
with O
the O
seniors O
a O
collaboration O
of O
the O
clubs O
would O
be O
possible O
. O

The O
PSV B-ORG
had O
hoped O
for O
sports O
incentives O
and O
a O
financial O
compensation O
; O
after O
all O
, O
the O
maintenance O
of O
the O
terrain O
costs O
more O
than O
300,000 O
mark O
annually O
. O

FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
, O
on O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
floated O
before O
a O
sporting O
field O
appropriate O
to O
its O
status O
: O

After O
the O
Eintracht B-ORG
, O
the O
FSV B-ORG
and O
the O
Red B-ORG
- I-ORG
Whites I-ORG
, O
he O
is O
the O
fourth O
strongest O
football O
team O
in O
Frankfurt B-MISC
. O

The O
contract O
negotiated O
between O
PSV B-ORG
and O
Italy B-ORG
provided O
for O
rent O
payments O
of O
68 O
000 O
marks O
. O

The O
attractive O
plant O
with O
two O
lawns O
seemed O
to O
have O
significant O
advantages O
to O
the O
Italians B-MISC
, O
compared O
to O
their O
current O
" O
home O
" O
at O
the O
SG B-ORG
Westend I-ORG
. O

There O
they O
have O
to O
pay O
10,000 O
mark O
per O
year O
for O
using O
the O
dressing O
rooms O
. O

Haken O
in O
the O
West B-LOC
: O

At O
the O
SG B-ORG
, O
according O
to O
Stefan B-PER
Lottermann I-PER
, O
player O
coach O
at O
Italia B-ORG
and O
one O
of O
the O
negotiators O
, O
only O
seniors O
are O
allowed O
on O
the O
field O
. O

Insiders O
suspect O
that O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
is O
trying O
to O
provide O
the O
necessary O
support O
in O
youth O
work O
by O
cooperating O
with O
Blue B-ORG
- I-ORG
Yellow I-ORG
. O

Lotterman B-PER
rejected O
this O
. O

The O
city O
has O
criticized O
the O
club O
’s O
actions O
. O

Sports O
designer O
Sylvia B-PER
Schenk I-PER
complains O
that O
the O
contract O
was O
concluded O
without O
consultation O
with O
the O
municipality O
, O
but O
was O
at O
their O
expense O
. O

Regardless O
of O
the O
tense O
budgetary O
situation O
, O
a O
“ O
principal O
question O
” O
must O
be O
decided O
here O
: O

Where O
is O
the O
upper O
limit O
for O
promoting O
associations O
without O
their O
own O
territory O
? O

For O
Harald B-PER
Lochmann I-PER
, O
head O
of O
the O
sports O
and O
bathing O
office O
, O
the O
case O
is O
a O
“ O
precedent O
” O
. O

His O
Fear O
of O
: O

Once O
the O
city O
has O
given O
in O
to O
the O
requirement O
, O
within O
a O
short O
period O
of O
time O
" O
ten O
to O
20 O
clubs O
" O
report O
similar O
claims O
. O

This O
is O
financially O
unacceptable O
. O

Lottermann B-PER
can O
not O
agree O
with O
such O
considerations O
: O

“ O
What O
kind O
of O
club O
does O
Lochmann B-PER
mean O
? O
” O

The O
constellation O
is O
unique O
. O

Never O
before O
has O
a O
club O
rented O
into O
a O
club O
with O
its O
own O
land O
. O

The O
city O
’s O
offer O
to O
shoot O
up O
to O
18,000 O
mark O
, O
the O
coach O
describes O
as O
a O
“ O
laughing O
number O
” O
. O

In O
doing O
so O
, O
he O
points O
out O
the O
“ O
integrative O
work O
” O
that O
“ O
Italia B-ORG
” O
does O
and O
reminds O
of O
the O
sums O
that O
would O
be O
spent O
elsewhere O
for O
the O
promotion O
of O
sport O
. O

Should O
the O
35,000 O
mark O
raised O
by O
the O
FC B-ORG
not O
be O
realized O
, O
" O
I O
promise O
the O
responsible O
people O
a O
hot O
dance O
, O
" O
Lottermann B-PER
threatens O
. O

The O
Doc- O

Opening O
hours O
of O
the O
Hanauer B-MISC
Museen O

Museum B-LOC
Großauheim I-LOC
, O
Pfortenwingert B-LOC
4 O
, O
phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
55 O
16 O
and O
29 O
55 O
10 O
, O
open O
Thursday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
am O
to O
12 O
am O
and O
from O
14am O
to O
17am O
. O

Hessische B-LOC
Puppenmuseum I-LOC
, O
Parkpromenade B-LOC
4 O
, O
Hanau B-LOC
- I-LOC
Wilhelmsbad I-LOC
, O
Phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
8 O
62 O
12 O
, O
open O
Tuesday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
am O
to O
12 O
am O
and O
from O
14am O
to O
17am O
; O
Entry O
: O

Adults O
1.50 O
mark O
, O
children O
0.50 O
mark O
, O
students O
, O
students O
and O
disabled O
one O
mark O
. O

Deutsches B-LOC
Goldschmiedehaus I-LOC
, O
Altstädter B-LOC
Markt I-LOC
6 O
, O
phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
54 O
30 O
, O
open O
Tuesday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
to O
12 O
am O
and O
14 O
to O
17 O
pm O
. O

Museum B-LOC
Castle I-LOC
Philippsruhe I-LOC
, O
Philippsruher B-LOC
Avenue I-LOC
45 O
, O
phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
55 O
16 O
and O
29 O
55 O
10 O
, O
open O
Tuesday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
11 O
to O
18 O
a.m. O
continuously O
. O

Museum B-LOC
Schloß I-LOC
Steinheim I-LOC
, O
phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
55 O
16 O
and O
29 O
55 O
10 O
, O
open O
Thursday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
am O
to O
12 O
am O
and O
from O
14am O
to O
17am O
. O

The O
Doc- O

Currently O
no O
" O
guarantee O
card O
" O
for O
a O
healthy O
baby O
for O
early O
detection O
of O
hereditary O
damage O
/ O
blood O
test O
yet O
too O
inaccurate O

In O
the O
course O
of O
pregnancy O
prevention O
examinations O
, O
more O
and O
more O
expectant O
mothers O
use O
the O
opportunity O
with O
a O
blood O
test O
, O
the O
so O
- O
called O
triple O
diagnosis O
, O
to O
detect O
possible O
inherited O
damage O
to O
the O
unborn O
child O
early O
in O
order O
to O
have O
an O
abortion O
of O
pregnancy O
, O
if O
necessary O
. O

The O
test O
is O
not O
yet O
included O
in O
the O
catalogue O
of O
standard B-MISC
tests I-MISC
for O
pregnant O
women O
; O
it O
should O
not O
become O
a O
routine O
measure O
at O
the O
moment O
. O

This O
recommendation O
was O
given O
by O
an O
advisory O
panel O
of O
the O
“ O
Foundation O
for O
the O
Disabled O
Child O
” O
these O
days O
following O
a O
conference O
in O
Berlin B-LOC
. O

Renowned O
gynecologists O
, O
obstetricians O
, O
human O
geneticists O
, O
and O
laboratory O
diagnostics O
had O
participated O
in O
it O
and O
adopted O
a O
number O
of O
further O
demands O
. O

As O
the O
conference O
leader O
, O
Professor O
Joachim B-PER
Wolfram I-PER
Dudenhausen I-PER
of O
the O
Rudolf B-ORG
Virchow I-ORG
Clinic I-ORG
of O
the O
Free B-ORG
University I-ORG
of O
Berlin O
, O
explained O
, O
the O
in O
principle O
harmless O
, O
but O
costly O
test O
, O
when O
it O
provides O
clues O
for O
genetic O
damage O
such O
as O
neural O
tube O
defects O
or O
for O
trisomies O
( O
such O
as O
the O
earlier O
Mongolism B-MISC
called O
Down B-MISC
syndrome I-MISC
) O
, O
leads O
to O
further O
complicated O
and O
not O
entirely O
harmless O
examinations O
for O
the O
woman O
and O
the O
unborn O
, O
the O
so O
- O
called O
amniocentesis O
. O

Many O
of O
these O
procedures O
are O
unnecessary O
and O
should O
be O
avoided O
by O
pregnant O
women O
. O

Just O
as O
triple O
diagnostics O
is O
handled O
today O
, O
it O
too O
often O
provides O
clues O
to O
a O
genetic O
risk O
that O
can O
not O
be O
confirmed O
with O
amniocentesis O
. O

According O
to O
Professor O
Dudenhausen B-PER
, O
these O
deficiencies O
have O
less O
to O
do O
with O
the O
difficulties O
of O
laboratory O
determinations O
that O
biochemically O
measure O
three O
child O
substances O
in O
the O
mother O
’s O
blood O
( O
alpha O
- O
fetoprotein O
, O
chorionic O
gonadotropins O
, O
and O
estriol O
) O
. O

Rather O
, O
the O
validity O
of O
the O
test O
is O
affected O
mainly O
by O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
exact O
age O
of O
the O
unborn O
child O
is O
often O
not O
determined O
before O
the O
blood O
collection O
and O
the O
blood O
values O
then O
, O
when O
the O
child O
is O
older O
than O
suspected O
, O
predict O
a O
non O
- O
existent O
risk O
. O

Experts O
therefore O
require O
that O
the O
test O
be O
carried O
out O
only O
when O
the O
age O
of O
the O
fetus O
is O
determined O
simultaneously O
by O
ultrasound O
. O
