-DOCSTART- O

Event O
and O
narrative O
or O
: O

Difficulties O
in O
understanding O
Albrecht B-PER
Lehmann I-PER
lets O
refugees O
and O
displaced O
persons O
speak O
in O
West B-LOC
Germany I-LOC
, O
1945 O
- O
1990 O

Discussions O
on O
asylum O
seekers O
, O
resettlement O
and O
immigration O
issues O
have O
dominated O
politics O
and O
the O
media O
in O
Germany B-LOC
in O
recent O
months O
. O

It O
is O
therefore O
not O
difficult O
at O
the O
moment O
to O
attract O
attention O
with O
the O
publication O
of O
a O
book O
on O
refugees O
and O
displaced O
persons O
in O
West B-LOC
Germany I-LOC
from O
1945 O
to O
1990 O
. O

And O
indeed O
, O
there O
are O
hardly O
any O
serious O
scientific O
discussions O
that O
have O
taken O
up O
this O
issue O
so O
far O
. O

However O
, O
it O
is O
questionable O
whether O
such O
a O
topicality O
must O
necessarily O
lead O
to O
a O
doubtless O
forthcoming O
debate O
to O
deprive O
its O
core O
in O
favour O
of O
blurring O
the O
difference O
between O
past O
and O
present O
problem O
constellations O
. O

Albrecht B-PER
Lehmann I-PER
, O
in O
his O
book B-MISC
I I-MISC
m O
Freußer O
unintentionally O
at O
home O
, O
tries O
to O
adopt O
a O
neutral O
perspective O
, O
free O
of O
blame O
and O
innocency O
, O
against O
a O
policy O
and O
its O
consequences O
, O
which O
led O
to O
twelve O
million O
people O
fleeing O
or O
displaced O
from O
East O
Germany O
and O
the O
German O
settlement O
areas O
in O
Eastern O
Europe O
at O
the O
end O
of O
the O
Second B-MISC
World I-MISC
War I-MISC
. O

In O
what O
way O
the O
" O
refugees O
" O
- O
as O
it O
was O
called O
immediately O
after O
the O
war O
with O
a O
pejorative O
bytaste O
- O
or O
" O
displaced O
" O
- O
so O
the O
common O
name O
since O
c. O

1948 O
- O
found O
in O
their O
new O
circumstances O
and O
how O
these O
experiences O
have O
traded O
over O
the O
next O
decades O
in O
the O
different O
generations O
to O
today O
, O
Lehmann B-PER
demonstrates O
by O
means O
of O
a O
series O
of O
narratives O
, O
personal O
records O
, O
diaries O
and O
documents O
of O
the O
displaced O
press O
. O

Today O
, O
a O
picture O
is O
promoted O
, O
which O
is O
not O
surprising O
, O
but O
in O
its O
compilation O
convincingly O
allows O
readers O
to O
carry O
out O
a O
specific O
kind O
of O
foreignness O
experience O
. O

The O
respective O
experiences O
and O
their O
coping O
are O
presented O
very O
differently O
. O

However O
, O
certain O
topics O
appear O
again O
and O
again O
: O

Thus O
, O
the O
rape O
of O
German B-MISC
women O
by O
members O
of O
the O
Red B-ORG
Army I-ORG
not O
only O
led O
to O
irreparable O
mental O
disorders O
among O
women O
themselves O
, O
but O
also O
to O
complicated O
marriage O
relationships O
that O
dominated O
the O
lives O
of O
whole O
families O
often O
for O
years O
after O
these O
events O
. O

The O
uprooting O
from O
the O
old O
homeland O
produced O
in O
quite O
a O
few O
cases O
forms O
of O
social O
over O
- O
adjustment O
, O
which O
caused O
difficulties O
with O
the O
old O
- O
established O
population O
, O
especially O
in O
narrow O
village O
communities O
. O

A O
" O
sentimental O
perseverance O
" O
on O
old O
traditions O
and O
customs O
expressed O
how O
incapable O
the O
displaced O
were O
to O
forget O
the O
old O

In O
all O
narratives O
it O
is O
obvious O
that O
the O
pursuit O
of O
social O
harmony O
has O
been O
a O
guiding O
factor O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

The O
creation O
of O
a O
new O
sense O
of O
community O
should O
compensate O
for O
the O
loss O
experienced O
in O
most O
cases O
as O
a O
cruel O

In O
addition O
to O
showing O
such O
typical O
difficulties O
, O
a O
strength O
of O
the O
book O
is O
to O
highlight O
the O
differences O
in O
the O
experiences O
of O
different O
generations O
. O

Thus O
it O
is O
plausible O
that O
the O
generation O
that O
grew O
up O
in O
the O
sixties O
and O
seventies O
wanted O
little O
to O
do O
with O
the O
past O
of O
their O
parents O
who O
had O
been O
expelled O
. O

A O
consciousness O
about O
the O
" O
lost O
home O
" O
existed O
; O
however O
, O
it O
was O
no O
longer O
sentimentally O
occupied O
. O

This O
changed O
only O
in O
the O
1980s O
, O
when O
in O
Germany B-LOC
a O
renaissance O
of O
the O
concept O
of O
homeland O
allowed O
a O
stronger O
reference O
to O
the O
former O
German B-MISC
settlement O
areas O
again O
. O

Lehmann B-PER
is O
not O
tired O
in O
the O
description O
and O
reproduction O
of O
the O
stories O
of O
displaced O
persons O
, O
repeatedly O
pointing O
out O
that O
, O
despite O
long O
- O
tamed O
prejudices O
, O
they O
do O
not O
attach O
any O
revanchism O
. O

One O
may O
believe O
the O
author O
, O
who O
understands O
his O
book O
as O
a O
contribution O
to O
the O
understanding O
of O
different O
nations O
, O
when O
he O
calls O
in O
this O
sense O
to O
understand O
the O
old O
homeland O
only O
as O
a O
" O
home O
in O
the O
head O
" O
. O

However O
, O
despite O
this O
certainly O
laudable O
attitude O
and O
programmatics O
, O
the O
many O
reports O
and O
narratives O
leave O
a O
pale O
aftertaste O
, O
which O
is O
mainly O
due O
to O
the O
methodology O
of O
German B-MISC
ethnology O
. O

History O
, O
as O
it O
is O
written O
in O
this O
book O
, O
is O
primarily O
reproduced O
from O
the O
perspective O
of O
those O
involved O
in O
it O
. O

The O
one O
story O
decays O
into O
many O
narratives O
, O
which O
in O
turn O
can O
be O
classified O
scientifically O
according O
to O
different O
genres O
. O

So O
success O
stories O
, O
swans O
and O
trump O
stories O
are O
typical O
forms O
of O
narrating O
a O
particular O
group O
, O
which O
today O
still O
want O
to O
forget O
their O
initial O
difficulties O
in O
the O
new O
home O
. O

A O
ousting O
form O
of O
narration O
, O
on O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
is O
to O
be O
found O
among O
women O
who O
have O
become O
victims O
of O
rape O
. O

However O
, O
this O
scientifically O
derived O
classification O
of O
narrative O
types O
remains O
only O
external O
. O

The O
narratives O
themselves O
are O
central O
in O
the O
form O
of O
presentation O
available O
here O
; O
a O
reflection O
on O
them O
and O
thus O
a O
possibility O
of O
evaluation O
and O
classification O
remains O

This O
, O
however O
, O
makes O
it O
all O
too O
easy O
for O
compassionate O
understanding O
or O
sympathetic O
identification O
with O
those O
affected O
to O
forget O
those O
constellations O
of O
history O
, O
in O
the O
context O
of O
which O
the O
unquestionably O
cruel O
individual O
events O
should O
necessarily O
be O
presented O
. O

For O
example O
, O
it O
seems O
quite O
irritating O
when O
the O
" O
double O
luck O
" O
of O
Anton B-PER
K. I-PER
from O
Transylvania B-LOC
is O
reported O
, O
who O
as O
a O
people B-MISC
German I-MISC
was O
not O
allowed O
to O
join O
the O
Wehrmacht B-ORG
, O
but O
had O
to O
become O
the O
Waffen B-ORG
- I-ORG
SS I-ORG
; O
which O
could O
thus O
save O
itself O
over O
the O
war O
years O
and O
at O
the O
same O
time O
was O
spared O
from O
the O
prisoner O
of O
war O
. O

To O
imagine O
the O
happiness O
of O
an O
Anton B-PER
K. I-PER
is O
one O
side O
. O

The O
other O
must O
be O
to O
place O
the O
individual O
fates O
in O
the O
history O
of O
the O
Second B-MISC
World I-MISC
War I-MISC
and O
the O
years O
thereafter O
in O
such O
a O
way O
that O
an O
objective O
perspective O
can O
be O
taken O

It O
is O
a O
mistake O
to O
assume O
that O
the O
mere O
reproduction O
of O
authentic O
reports O
must O
necessarily O
lead O
to O
an O
appropriate O
view O
of O
history O
. O

Rather O
, O
it O
risks O
looking O
at O
history O
, O
which O
stylizes O
all O
those O
involved O
to O
their O
victims O
. O

There O
is O
no O
doubt O
that O
it O
is O
necessary O
to O
also O
deal O
with O
the O
victims O
of O
history O
who O
were O
on O
the O
perpetrator O
's O
side O
. O

However O
, O
it O
should O
be O
avoided O
in O
doing O
so O
, O
to O
promote O
a O
relativisation O
of O
history O
, O
which O
seeks O
to O
blur O
all O
differences O
in O
favour O
of O
an O
" O
understood O
understanding O
" O
. O

In O
this O
context O
it O
is O
not O
enough O
to O
spend O
programmatic O
slogans O
on O
" O
Reconciliation O
of O
all O
cultures O
" O
. O

This O
leads O
to O
other O
fundamental O
misunderstandings O
that O
contribute O
to O
the O
blurring O
of O
crucial O
differences O
. O

In O
Lehmann B-PER
's O
case O
, O
this O
blurry O
is O
most O
evident O
where O
he O
advocates O
a O
" O
post O
- O
national O
Europe B-LOC
" O
and O
declares O
this O
to O
be O
a O
perspective O
that O
should O
emerge O
from O
a O
non O
- O
revanchist O
resettlement O
perspective O
, O
so O
that O
the O
German B-MISC
solution O
to O
the O
resettlement O
problem O
becomes O
a O
model O
for O
those O
questions O
and O
problems O
arising O
as O
a O
result O
of O
the O
immigration O
movements O
: O

" O
The O
theme O
of O
this O
book O
remains O
current O
: O

The O
question O
of O
how O
individuals O
and O
families O
with O
their O
children O
and O
grandchildren O
find O
a O
new O
home O
in O
our O
country O
, O
in O
which O
images O
of O
memory O
they O
carry O
and O
trade O
the O
old O
home O
and O
the O
culture O
of O
the O
region O
of O
origin O
, O
in O
which O
way O
they O
maintain O
contact O
with O
the O
first O
home O
. O
" O

In O
the O
equation O
of O
the O
problems O
of O
resettlement O
and O
asylum O
seekers O
as O
well O
as O
their O
respective O
experiences O
of O
foreignness O
, O
the O
fundamental O
difference O
between O
these O
groups O
is O
swept O
under O
the O
table O
. O

A O
post O
- O
national O
Europe B-LOC
consists O
in O
the O
cohabitation O
of O
a O
wide O
variety O
of O
ethnic O
groups O
, O
which O
it O
has O
forcibly O
or O
deliberately O
led O
to O
Germany B-LOC
or O
other O
European B-LOC
countries O
. O

However O
, O
these O
groups O
' O
experiences O
of O
alienity O
are O
likely O
to O
be O
fundamentally O
different O
from O
those O
of O
the O
resettlements O
of O
the O
forties O
or O
those O
of O
their O
children O
decades O

The O
latter O
have O
been O
proven O
to O
have O
identified O
with O
Germany B-LOC
despite O
the O
losses O
of O
the O
" O
old O
homeland O
in O
the O
East O
" O
, O
have O
built O
up O
a O
national O
consciousness O
due O
to O
their O
ethnicity O
. O

Such O
identification O
is O
neither O
possible O
nor O
desirable O
for O
immigrants O
. O

While O
the O
idea O
of O
a O
homogeneous O
nation O
state O
was O
decisive O
for O
the O
resettlement O
, O
it O
is O
today O
the O
idea O
of O
a O
heterogeneous O
nation O
state O
for O
asylum O
seekers O
and O
immigrants O
. O

A O
focus O
on O
subjective O
sensitivities O
, O
as O
set O
out O
in O
this O
volume O
, O
should O
not O
lead O
to O
neglecting O
fundamental O
, O
objective O
differences O
. O

This O
does O
not O
serve O
a O
scientific O
context O
, O
nor O
does O
it O
help O
the O
author O
's O
desire O
to O
" O
build O
" O
a O
Europe B-LOC
in O
which O
the O
differences O
have O
been O
overcome O
without O
denying O
them O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

OFF O
ARE O
IT O
the O
small O
problems O
on O
the O
doorstep O
, O
which O
cause O
the O
Frankfurt B-MISC
citizens O
great O
trouble O
. O

The O
reader O
's O
phone O
in O
the O
district B-LOC
of I-LOC
Rundschau I-LOC
has O
been O
able O
to O
repeatedly O
help O
to O
find O
ways O
out O
of O
the O
scrubbing O
of O
the O
authorities O
' O
errands O
and O
to O
find O
solutions O
to O
some O
problems O
. O

Although O
the O
rapid O
success O
of O
everyday O
adversities O
does O
not O
always O
occur O
( O
persistent O
permanent O
falcon O
parkers O
can O
be O
impressed O
by O
neither O
parking O
tickets O
nor O
newspaper O
articles O
) O
, O
the O
direct O
wire O
in O
the O
editorial O
office O
repeatedly O
contributes O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
a O
donkey O
bridge O
can O
be O
spanned O
over O
some O
seemingly O
insurmountable O
trenches O
. O

The O
reader O
's O
telephone O
of O
the O
district O
- O
round O
show O
( O
phone O
number O
21 O
99 O
- O
3 O
60 O
) O
is O

every O
Thursday O
from O
2 O
pm O
to O
5 O
pm O
, O
Friday O
from O
10 O
am O
to O
1 O
pm O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

When O
the O
scale O
was O
112 O
kilos O
, O
Andrea B-PER
, O
27 O
years O
old O
: O

Greedy O
after O
Pregnancy O

She O
's O
always O
been O
overweight O
. O

The O
man O
she O
's O
been O
married O
to O
for O
ten O
years O
never O
made O
a O
difference O
. O

The O
marriage O
seemed O
happy O
, O
Andrea B-PER
was O
satisfied O
. O

When O
she O
was O
24 O
years O
pregnant O
for O
the O
second O
time O
, O
she O
was O
happy O
. O

She O
always O
wanted O
to O
have O
many O
children O
. O

But O
, O
after O
the O
birth O
of O
Miriam B-PER
, O
she O
felt O
overloaded O
. O

Andrea B-PER
started O
to O
eat O
more O
and O
more O
. O

It O
was O
no O
longer O
the O
healthy O
appetite O
that O
drew O
them O
to O
the O
fridge O
: O

She O
suddenly O
stuffed O
a O
great O
deal O
of O
food O
into O
her O

And O
at O
some O
point O
the O
scale O
indicates O
112 O
kilos O
. O

Andrea B-PER
had O
become O
addicted O
, O
addicted O
to O
the O
feeling O
of O

Hunger O
was O
foreign O
to O
her O
, O
her O
whole O
body O
was O
suddenly O
foreign O
to O
her O
. O

That O
she O
was O
sick O
, O
she O
did O
not O
know O
at O
that O
time O
. O

Only O
one O
day O
when O
she O
read O
a O
diet O
book O
, O
she O
noticed O
it O
. O

An O
eating O
woman O
was O
described O
- O
and O
in O
this O
story O
Andrea B-PER
recognized O
herself O
. O

At O
that O
moment O
she O
was O
aware O
that O
she O
had O
to O
do O
something O
about O
her O
suffering O
. O

Andrea B-PER
took O
the O
initiative O
and O
registered O
in O
a O
clinic O
for O
addicts O
in O
the O
Allgäu B-LOC
. O

A O
few O
weeks O
later O
, O
she O
left O
her O
husband O
and O
children O
for O
three O
months O
of O
therapy O
. O

The O
relatives O
accused O
her O
of O
being O
a O
raven O
's O
mother O
. O

For O
Andrea B-PER
, O
however O
, O
it O
was O
clear O
: O

" O
I O
can O
only O
be O
a O
good O
mother O
if O
I O
am O
well O
myself O
. O
" O

When O
Andrea B-PER
introduced O
herself O
to O
the O
group O
on O
the O
first O
day O
, O
she O
said O
: O

" O
My O
name O
is O
Andrea B-PER
, O
eat O
too O
much O
, O
but O
have O
no O
other O
problems O
. O
" O

Everyone O
laughed O
, O
and O
soon O
she O
knew O
why O
. O
" O

I O
had O
suppressed O
my O
problems O
until O
therapy O
. O
" O

It O
turned O
out O
that O
Andrea B-PER
was O
not O
so O
satisfied O
with O
her O
life O
as O
a O
young O
mother O
and O
wife O
. O

Today O
she O
admits O
: O

" O
I O
still O
feel O
like O
I O
missed O
something O
in O
my O
youth O
. O
" O

Through O
therapy O
, O
however O
, O
she O
has O
learned O
to O
deal O
with O
her O
dissatisfaction O
, O
her O
fears O
and O
worries O
. O

When O
the O
27 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
has O
conflicts O
with O
her O
husband O
today O
, O
the O
two O
talk O
about O
it O
. O

For O
example O
, O
in O
marriage O
counseling O
, O
to O
which O
they O
regularly O
go O
. O

Andrea B-PER
has O
not O
yet O
been O
healed O
of O
the O
disease O
" O
elation O
" O
. O
" O

Who O
is O
once O
addicted O
, O
it O
will O
somehow O
always O
remain O
" O
, O
she O
says O
. O

And O
so O
she O
plans O
every O
day O
exactly O
what O
she O
will O
eat O
. O

If O
she O
does O
n't O
keep O
it O
, O
she O
gets O
angry O
. O

Normal O
to O
deal O
with O
the O
food O
, O
will O
also O
remain O
a O
dream O
for O
them O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Stefan B-PER
Müller I-PER
- O
Doohm O
Interdisciplinarity O
from O
below O
Against O
the O
loss O
of O
utopia O
in O
sociology O
: O

A O
Incitement O
to O
Discord O
in O
the O
Ivory O
Tower O

Sociology O
is O
not O
without O
reason O
the O
suspicion O
of O
high O
stacking O
. O

For O
it O
claims O
nothing O
less O
than O
its O
specific O
subject O
- O
matter O
than O
the O
whole O
of O
society O
. O

What O
is O
surprising O
is O
that O
the O
society O
so O
targeted O
reacted O
suspiciously O
to O
the O
acquisition O
by O
sociology O
. O

Until O
the O
Adenauer O
period O
, O
the O
lady O
society O
sought O
to O
be O
public O
felt O
most O
embarrassed O
by O
the O
approaches O
of O
the O
dreary O
sociology O
. O

It O
was O
only O
in O
the O
turbulent O
political O
times O
of O
the O
late O
sixties O
that O
she O
gave O
in O
to O
her O
stormy O

The O
Society B-ORG
of I-ORG
Sociology I-ORG
fell O
blushingly O
into O
the O
arms O
. O

This O
yes O
word O
has O
led O
to O
a O
covenant O
for O
life O
, O
but O
it O
has O
become O
anything O
but O
a O
fervent O
love O
relationship O
. O

In O
the O
meantime O
, O
the O
enthusiasm O
behind O
the O
expectations O
of O
this O
young O
social O
science O
was O
at O
the O
height O
of O
its O
academic O
expansion O
. O

The O
conviction O
, O
which O
was O
combined O
with O
that O
demanding O
objective O
of O
knowledge O
, O
diminished O
to O
formulate O
a O
theory O
of O
the O
whole O
society O
, O
which O
should O
at O
the O
same O
time O
be O
critical O
and O
practically O
changing O
. O

Are O
we O
therefore O
at O
the O
end O
of O
a O
process O
in O
which O
the O
utopian O
energies O
, O
which O
were O
invested O
in O
the O
enormous O
enterprise O
of O
a O
revolution O
of O
all O
outdated O
working O
and O
living O
conditions O
to O
be O
brought O
about O
by O
enlightenment O
and O
criticism O
, O

In O
other O
words O
: O

How O
can O
the O
attractiveness O
of O
sociology O
be O
regained O
as O
a O
reality O
- O
changing O
force O
which O
it O
lost O
in O
the O
course O
of O
its O
" O
maturation O
process O
" O
to O
normal O
science O
? O

There O
are O
three O
main O
reasons O
for O
the O
loss O
of O
utopia O
in O
sociology O
. O

On O
the O
one O
hand O
, O
it O
is O
the O
utopia O
itself O
, O
which O
has O
become O
modest O
from O
the O
historical O
experiences O
of O
the O
failure O
of O
the O
great O
visionary O
promises O
, O
which O
have O
emerged O
from O
the O
historical O
upsurge O
of O
recent O
times O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
the O
reality O
of O
the O
increasingly O
concrete O
utopian O
challenge O
has O
arisen O
through O
the O
simple O
cunning O
of O
the O
realization O
of O
utopian O
ideals O
. O

At O
the O
same O
time O
, O
the O
historical O
situation O
has O
assumed O
a O
gravity O
that O
allows O
any O
longing O
projection O
of O
a O
completely O
different O
in O
the O
morning O
only O
as O
an O
apocalypse O
. O

In O
the O
critical O
tradition O
of O
social O
theory O
, O
the O
ideals O
at O
the O
origin O
of O
modernity O
were O
transformed O
into O
the O
concrete O
utopia O
of O
the O
real O
history O
of O
progressive O
bourgeois O
emancipation O
. O

The O
ladder O
goes O
from O
the O
fictitious O
future O
paintings O
of O
a O
Morus B-PER
, O
Campanella B-PER
and O
Bacon B-PER
to O
the O
technical O
and O
early O
socialist O
utopianism O
of O
an O
Owen B-PER
, O
Saint B-PER
- I-PER
Simon I-PER
, O
Fourier B-PER
and O
Proudhon B-PER
. O

Against O
these O
utopian O
socialists O
Marx B-PER
polemized O
with O
all O
the O
sharpness O
that O
accused O
them O
of O
being O
mere O
dreamers O
. O

He O
himself O
puts O
like O
so O
much O
, O
so O
also O
the O
utopia O
from O
the O
head O
on O
the O
feet O
and O
comes O
materialistic O
to O
the O
point O
: O

In O
communism O
, O
utopia O
and O
reality O
merge O
as O
the O
society O
of O
free O
producers O
, O
as O
material O
abundance O
and O
as O
transparent O
social O
relations O
for O
all O
members O
of O
society O
. O

However O
, O
this O
concretization O
of O
utopia O
has O
not O
led O
anyone O
to O
Paradise O
, O
which O
was O
promised O
. O

For O
, O
as O
we O
read O
in O
Horkheimer B-LOC
's I-LOC
daily O
book O
note O
from O
the O
fifties O
, O
the O
sky O
to O
which O
one O
can O
point O
the O
way O
is O
no O
one O
. O

More O
: O

The O
productive O
forces O
turned O
out O
to O
be O
destructive O
forces O
, O
class O
consciousness O
became O
a O
fossil O
through O
the O
individualization O
of O
life O
situations O
, O
and O
revolutions O
did O
not O
prove O
to O
be O
a O
locomotive O
of O
world O
history O
. O

Rather O
, O
according O
to O
Walter B-PER
Benjamin I-PER
, O
they O
are O
the O
grip O
of O
the O
human O
race O
traveling O
on O
this O
train O
after O
the O
emergency O
brake O
. O

The O
shock O
of O
those O
" O
normal O
disasters O
" O
, O
such O
as O
reactor O
accidents O
, O
which O
endanger O
the O
survival O
of O
the O
genus O
, O
has O
torn O
social O
science O
from O
the O
twilight O
sleep O
of O
the O
progressive O
faith O
. O

This O
awakening O
finds O
its O
current O
expression O
in O
the O
circulating O
concept O
of O
the O
" O
risk O
society O
" O
, O
whose O
secret O
message O
of O
salvation O
consists O
in O
making O
the O
world O
's O
course O
still O
manageable O
according O
to O
an O
enlightened O
information O
about O
itself O
. O

This O
hope O
for O
" O
reflexive O
modernization O
" O
by O
Ulrich B-PER
Beck I-PER
is O
by O
no O
means O
new O
. O

In O
order O
to O
avoid O
the O
foreseeable O
catastrophe O
, O
already O
leading O
sociologists O
of O
the O
Weimar B-MISC
era I-MISC
such O
as O
Max B-PER
Weber I-PER
and O
Karl B-PER
Mannheim I-PER
argued O
that O
the O
real O
approach O
to O
the O
concrete O
Utopian O
is O
. O

And O
in O
fact O

Rule O
of O
law O
, O
democratic O
self O
- O
determination O
and O
material O
welfare O
are O
nothing O
more O
than O
an O
unenchanted O
form O
of O
the O
realization O
of O
the O
utopia O
that O
has O
long O
been O
brought O
to O
earth O
from O
heaven O
: O

Everyone O
produces O
according O
to O
their O
abilities O
, O
everyone O
consumes O
according O
to O
their O
needs O
. O

This O
secularized O
ideal O
of O
the O
right O
of O
all O
to O
everything O
, O
however O
, O
is O
currently O
overtaken O
by O
the O
ecologically O
- O
inspired O
" O
zero O
option O
" O
utopian O
, O
more O
precisely O

by O
a O
kind O
of O
general O
overtaking O
ban O
placed O
in O

This O
formula O
, O
with O
which O
the O
social O
scientist O
Claus B-PER
Offe I-PER
entered O
the O
phase O
- O
out O
from O
such O
almost O
objective O
processes O
as O
automotiveization O
, O
agricultural O
chemistry O
, O
cabling O
etc O
. O

To O
make O
it O
tasty O
, O
however O
, O
is O
not O
much O
more O
than O
a O
residual O
hope O
to O
escape O
the O
unstoppable O
disaster O
as O
a O
result O
of O
a O
generalisation O
of O
the O
principle O
" O
free O
movement O
for O
free O
citizens O
" O
by O
pause O
and O
standstill O
. O

Is O
this O
utopia O
not O
a O
threat O
to O
the O
banishment O
of O
the O
omnipotence O
of O
the O
present O
? O

As O
the O
critical O
force O
of O
utopian O
thought O
fades O
in O
Enlightenment O
Science O
, O
the O
dimension O
of O
historical O
meaning O
formation O
in O
the O
horizon O
of O
historical O
target O
perspectives O
disappears O
in O
social O
self O
- O
thematization O
. O

This O
vacuum O
is O
not O
only O
a O
breeding O
ground O
for O
ideologies O
such O
as O
that O
of O
posthistoire O
, O
but O
this O
utopianism O
also O
promotes O
the O
fixation O
of O
replacement O
programs O
such O
as O
fundamentalism O
, O
regionalism O
and O
feminism O
. O

It O
lacks O
the O
memory O
of O
what O
is O
unrequited O
in O
utopian O
thinking O
, O
it O
is O
dispensed O
with O
that O
utopian O
forward O
thinking O
that O
strikes O
the O
spark O
that O
can O
ignite O
the O
light O
with O
which O
the O
idea O
of O
a O
better O
society O
goes O
along O
. O

A O
disciplinaryly O
organised O
science O
business O
is O
objectively O
overburdened O
against O
the O
risks O
of O
the O
risk O
society O
. O

For O
the O
growing O
destructive O
potentials O
in O
nature O
and O
society O
generated O
by O
the O
individual O
sciences O
themselves O
have O
their O
reason O
, O
not O
least O
because O
the O
subjects O
only O
operate O
navel O
shows O
and O
remain O
in O
their O
ivory O
towers O
. O

In O
this O
imperative O
multidisciplinary O
cooperation O
of O
the O
natural O
, O
humanities O
and O
social O
sciences O
, O
the O
science O
grows O
a O
special O
responsibility O
from O
society O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
its O
object O
relation O
to O
the O
totality O
of O
the O
social O
. O

First O
of O
all O
, O
sociology O
has O
the O
self O
- O
critical O
task O
of O
returning O
to O
its O
own O
home O
and O
acting O
contagious O
by O
this O
exemplary O
nature O
. O

Only O
as O
a O
" O
house O
of O
open O
doors O
" O
with O
internal O
plurality O
enables O
a O
process O
of O
combining O
diverse O
methods O
and O
theories O
. O

The O
cognitive O
identity O
of O
sociology O
is O
by O
no O
means O
endangered O
by O
this O
openness O
, O
since O
the O
subject O
has O
stabilised O
itself O
organizationally O
and O
seems O
to O
secure O
its O
academic O
reputation O
. O

Their O
status O
of O
interpretational O
science O
requires O
the O
practice O
of O
extreme O
tolerance O
to O
the O
competing O
paradigms O
, O
different O
methodological O
approaches O
and O
the O
divergent O
interpretation O
of O
social O
issues O
. O

Because O
social O
analyses O
can O
not O
operate O
with O
an O
objectiveistic O
claim O
to O
knowledge O
. O

Rather O
, O
social O
theory O
convinces O
through O
the O
formation O
of O
arguments O
, O
i.e. O
through O
empirical O
prudence O
and O
interpretative O
plausibility O
. O

For O
this O
reason O
, O
the O
future O
of O
sociology O
lies O
in O
the O
creation O
of O
a O
unity O
of O
traditions O
that O
originally O
diverge O
: O

the O
experiential O
method O
of O
cognition O
on O
the O
one O
hand O
and O
the O
hermeneutics O
of O
the O
humanities O
on O
the O

This O
principle O
of O
tolerance O
in O
one O
's O
own O
house O
also O
implies O
a O
direct O
connection O
to O
the O
houses O
of O
the O
same O
street O
, O
i.e. O
the O
strict O
cooperation O
of O
sociology O
with O
other O
social O
sciences O
, O
if O
it O
does O
not O
want O
to O
reveal O
its O
great O
objective O
of O
knowledge O
, O
which O
according O
to O
Horkheimer O
consists O
in O
formulating O
a O
theory O
of O
the O
historical O
course O
of O
the O
epoch O
. O

This O
gigantic O
research O
program O
can O
only O
be O
realized O
if O
sociology O
becomes O
the O
vehicle O
of O
communication O
between O
the O
subjects O
of O
history O
, O
economics O
, O
anthropology O
, O
ethnology O
and O
psychology O
, O
among O
others O
, O
which O
are O
jointly O
engaged O
in O
a O
philosophical O
fundamental O
reflection O
, O
are O
ready O
for O
a O
continuous O
exchange O
of O
individual O
scientific O
knowledge O
progress O
and O
systematically O
link O
the O
empirical O
research O
efforts O
with O
the O
formation O
of O
theory O
. O

This O
orientation O
of O
the O
social O
sciences O
towards O
a O
historical O
and O
empirically O
substantial O
theory O
of O
the O
social O
one O
to O
be O
developed O
through O
research O
cooperation O
is O
only O
a O
first O
step O
. O

A O
second O
one O
must O
follow O

For O
the O
increasingly O
specialized O
social O
sciences O
rinsing O
the O
object O
of O
their O
research O
efforts O
not O
only O
between O
the O
fingers O
, O
but O
the O
meaning O
of O
their O
teaching O
and O
research O
is O
limited O
to O
the O
work O
of O
the O
shoemaker O
who O
remains O
with O
his O
groin O
, O
the O
water O
may O
also O
stand O
to O
his O
neck O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
the O
future O
perspective O
of O
the O
humanities O
and O
social O
sciences O
lies O
in O
the O
emerging O
coalition O
of O
human O
sciences O
. O

According O
to O
the O
American B-MISC
historian O
Robert B-PER
Darnton I-PER
, O
a O
new O
configuration O
of O
subjects O
, O
which O
consequently O
involves O
the O
dissolution O
of O
traditional O
faculties O
and O
departments O
, O
leads O
to O
a O
boost O
of O
innovation O
: O

The O
one O
- O
dimensionality O
of O
cause O
and O
event O
research O
is O
overcome O
in O
favour O
of O
a O
reality O
- O
scientific O
understanding O
of O
the O
symbolic O
cultural O
system O
as O
the O
common O
point O
of O
reference O
of O
the O
human O
sciences O

Let O
's O
sum O
up O
: O

sociology O
must O
first O
recognise O
the O
status O
of O
an O
empirical O
, O
understanding O
and O
critical O
social O
science O
not O
only O
for O
itself O
, O
but O
also O
productively O
exploit O
its O
character O
as O
a O
multi O
- O
paradigm O
science O
. O

Secondly O
, O
the O
project O
requires O
a O
restructured O
social O
theory O
of O
interdisciplinary O
cooperation O
among O
the O
various O
subjects O
of O
social O
science O
. O

Finally O
, O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
its O
perspective O
on O
the O
whole O
of O
the O
human O
life O
context O
, O
science O
from O
society O
is O
best O
suited O
to O
bring O
to O
the O
fore O
an O
overall O
interest O
of O
humanity O
in O
the O
dangerous O
activity O
of O
the O
cultivating O
sorcerers O
of O
technical O
- O
scientific O
civilization O
, O
the O
independent O
individual O
sciences O
with O
their O
particularistic O
rationalities O
. O

The O
present O
task O
of O
sociology O
is O
to O
bring O
, O
through O
its O
interpretive O
translation O
and O
mediation O
services O
, O
the O
sciences O
, O
whose O
differentiation O
is O
irreversible O
, O
to O
the O
common O
denominator O
of O
a O
multidisciplinary O
discourse O
, O
which O
seeks O
to O
solve O
a O
binding O
question O
: O

how O
to O
prevent O
the O
disaster O
. O

The O
treatment O
of O
this O
existential O
question O
certainly O
does O
not O
succeed O
as O
a O
stroke O
of O
genius O
by O
a O
researcher O
or O
a O
specialist O
, O
but O
is O
only O
conceivable O
as O
a O
joint O
work O
of O
all O
sciences O
. O

From O
this O
point O
of O
view O
, O
the O
Enlightenment O
Science O
is O
the O
protagonist O
of O
a O
utopian O
program O
: O

that O
of O
overcoming O
disciplinary O
boundaries O
. O

The O
indifferent O
juxtaposition O
of O
university O
sciences O
is O
scientifically O
irresponsible O
and O
just O
as O
outdated O
as O
the O
idea O
of O
unity O
in O
view O
of O
the O
world O
dangers O
and O
their O
complex O
interdependencies O
. O

The O
melody O
" O
If O
everyone O
does O
his O
own O
, O
the O
whole O
will O
succeed O
" O
is O
an O
extremely O
dangerous O
slumber O
song O
. O

From O
the O
sleep O
of O
reason O
awakens O
an O
" O
interdisciplinarity O
from O
below O
" O
, O
which O
Jürgen B-PER
Mittelstrass I-PER
describes O
as O
transverse O
thinking O
, O
as O
questions O
where O
no O
one O
has O
asked O
yet O
, O
as O
learning O
what O
one O
's O
own O
discipline O
does O
not O
yet O
know O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

" O
Often O
a O
dominant O
mother O
" O
FR B-MISC
conversation I-MISC
with O
the O
psychotherapist O
Arthur B-PER
Cooper I-PER

COMPETITION B-LOC
. O

For O
therapists O
, O
eating O
disorders O
are O
often O
still O
a O
mystery O
. O

Your O
patients O
have O
an O
addiction O
that O
is O
purely O
psychological O
. O

A O
healing O
method O
that O
would O
exclude O
a O
relapse O
, O
there O
is O
no O
. O

There O
it O
is O
all O
the O
more O
frightening O
that O
more O
and O
more O
people O
, O
especially O
women O
, O
suffer O
from O
bulimia O
, O
anorexia O
or O
ferocity O
. O

FR B-MISC
employee I-MISC
Daniela B-PER
Saur I-PER
spoke O
to O
the O
psychotherapist O
Arthur B-PER
Cooper I-PER
about O
the O
diseases O
. O

He O
considers O
the O
topic O
of O
eating O
disorders O
to O
be O
one O
of O
the O
" O
most O
exciting O
" O
in O
psychotherapy O
. O

FR B-ORG
: O

Mr O
Cooper B-PER
, O
you O
have O
said O
that O
you O
especially O
like O
to O
work O
with O
people O
who O
have O
a O
disturbed O
behavior O
to O
eat O
. O

Why O
? O

Cooper B-PER
: O

The O
increase O
of O
addiction O
diseases O
, O
especially O
those O
of O
bulimia O
, O
anorexia O
and O
ferocity O
, O
reflect O
our O
broken O
society O
. O

It O
shows O
that O
we O
are O
no O
longer O
able O
to O
take O
to O
a O
healthy O
level O

-DOCSTART- O

Where O
Helpless O
Can O
Find O

Many O
people O
who O
are O
eating O
feel O
alone O
with O
their O
suffering O
. O

But O
that O
does O
not O
have O
to O
be O
the O
case O
. O

Also O
in O
the O
Wetteraukreis B-LOC
and O
the O
surrounding O
area O
there O
are O
contact O
points O
: O

Niddatal B-LOC
: O

Self O
- O
help O
group O
to O
cope O
with O
eating O
disorders O
, O
meeting O
every O
Tuesday O
from O
8 O
pm O
in O
the O
rooms O
of O
the O
citizens O
active O
in O
Kaichen B-LOC
. O

Nidda B-LOC
: O

Self O
- O
help O
group O
of O
the O
women O
's O
emergency O
call O
in O
Borsdorf B-LOC
, O
meeting O
every O
Friday O
from O
7.30 O
p.m. O
in O
Weiherstrasse B-LOC
12 O
( O
Tel O
. O

0 O
60 O
43 O
/ O
44 O
71 O
) O
. O

Carbs B-LOC
: O

Discussion O
group O
for O
addicts O
, O
meeting O
every O
Thursday O
from O
5 O
pm O
to O
7 O
pm O
and O
from O
8 O
pm O
to O
10.30 O
pm O
in O
the O
Catholic O
community O
center O
St. B-LOC
Bonifatius I-LOC
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Social O
market O
economy O

In O
the O
face O
of O
increasingly O
high O
levels O
of O
debt O
, O
Federal O
Chancellor O
Kohl B-PER
enters O
into O
a O
public O
debate O
, O
which O
still O
remembers O
that O
, O
after O
unification O
, O
nobody O
will O
be O
worse O
off O
than O
before O
. O

The O
slogan O
" O
keep O
measure O
! O
" O

had O
already O
spent O
decades O
earlier O
on O
Ludwig B-PER
Erhard I-PER
, O
which O
then O
cost O
the O
chancellor O
's O
office O
, O
not O
least O
as O
a O
serious O
economic O
downturn O
in O
the O
economy O
that O
had O
flourished O
up O
to O
then O
. O

The O
foundations O
of O
Erhard B-PER
's I-PER
" O
Social B-MISC
Market I-MISC
Economy I-MISC
" O
had O
been O
developed O
among O
other O
economists O
of O
the O
" O
Freiburg B-ORG
School I-ORG
" O
mainly O
Walter B-PER
Eucken I-PER
. O

The O
new O
regulatory O
model O
was O
developed O
mainly O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
analyses O
of O
the O
" O
central O
administrative O
economy O
" O
. O

Eucken B-PER
's I-PER
study O
shows O
that O
planners O
and O
market O
economies O
are O
complex O
systems O
, O
the O
different O
functional O
mechanisms O
of O
which O
can O
not O
be O
exchanged O
freely O
. O

A O
proof O
of O
this O
is O
not O
only O
the O
failure O
of O
all O
previous O
attempts O
of O
a O
" O
Third O
Way O
" O
, O
but O
also O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
transformation O
of O
the O
GDR B-MISC
- I-MISC
Economy I-MISC
. O

Although O
the O
private O
" O
black O
markets O
" O
also O
existing O
in O
plan O
economies O
complement O
the O
central O
allocation O
system O
of O
the O
plan O
bureaucracies O

However O
, O
under O
the O
conditions O
of O
free O
exchange O
relationships O
, O
they O
are O
superfluous O
, O
but O
, O
since O
they O
originate O
from O
a O
particular O
situation O
, O
they O
can O
not O
be O
translated O
unbroken O
into O
" O
normal O
" O
markets O
. O

The O
same O
applies O
to O
the O
exchange O
of O
goods O
with O
other O
state O
- O
trading O
countries O
. O

As O
soon O
as O
free O
movement O
of O
goods O
is O
possible O
, O
such O
a O
" O
rational O
choice O
" O
replaces O
previously O
prescribed O
trade O
relations O
. O

The O
establishment O
of O
the O
model O
of O
order O
of O
the O
" O
Freiburger B-ORG
Schule I-ORG
" O
is O
, O
also O
that O
becomes O
clear O
in O
Eucken B-PER
's I-PER
principles O
, O
de O
facto O
dependent O
on O
a O
social O
" O
state O
of O
nature O
" O
. O

Even O
the O
demand O
for O
the O
necessary O
dissolution O
of O
power O
groups O
is O
practically O
impracticable O
in O
today O
's O
Federal O
Republic B-LOC
; O
at O
least O
as O
long O
as O
it O
is O
rightly O
assumed O
that O
the O
accusation O
of O
" O
group O
anarchy O
" O
is O
directed O
at O
workers O
and O
trade O
unions O
first O
. O

In O
fact O
, O
income O
adjustments O
to O
increased O
costs O
are O
often O
still O
needed O
, O
although O
the O
share O
of O
labour O
costs O
in O
value O
added O
is O
now O
only O
20 O
% O
on O
average O
. O

Nevertheless O
: O

It O
is O
not O
indifferent O
that O
the O
complexity O
of O
modern O
societies O
seems O
to O
overwhelm O
the O
regulatory O
model O
of O
the O
" O
social O
market O
economy O
" O
. O

Its O
purpose O
was O
precisely O
to O
reduce O
complexity O
by O
setting O
frameworks O
for O
private O
self O
- O
control O
- O
we O
do O
not O
have O
other O
models O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

In O
reality O
, O
Empress O
Agnes B-PER
wore O
the O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
jewelry I-MISC
" O
The O
long O
- O
lasting O
riddle O
about O
the O
jewels O
of O
a O
Salier O
emperor O
now O
solved O
/ O
A O
dramatic O
find O
in O
the O
Mainz B-MISC
Jewish B-MISC
ghetto I-MISC

Few O
archaeological O
finds O
from O
the O
Middle O
Ages O
have O
gained O
such O
a O
great O
popularity O
as O
an O
eagle O
- O
peacock B-MISC
fib I-MISC
from O
a O
treasure O
of O
25 O
gold O
jewels O
, O
which O
was O
accidentally O
found O
in O
1880 O
during O
sewer O
works O
from O
the O
cellar O
niche O
of O
a O
burnt O
- O
down O
house O
in O
the O
former O
" O
Judengasse B-LOC
" O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
and O
can O
only O
be O
shown O
after O
adventurous O
detours O
now O
in O
museum O
vitrines O
. O

It O
is O
still O
considered O
to O
be O
the O
largest O
and O
most O
important O
find O
of O
its O
kind O
. O

In O
addition O
to O
four O
crescent O
earrings O
, O
nine O
fingerrings O
, O
a O
chest O
( O
Loros O
) O
and O
a O
jewel O
collar O
( O
Maniakion O
) O
- O
both O
replicas O
of O
Byzantine B-MISC
emperor O
insignia O
- O
especially O
under O
eight O
humpbacks O
, O
cones O
and O
disks O
had O
noticed O
an O
exceptionally O
precious O
with O
an O
eagle O
- O
peacock B-MISC
motif I-MISC
, O
as O
she O
probably O
could O
have O
adorned O
only O
one O
empress O
. O

The O
historian O
Otto B-PER
von I-PER
Falke I-PER
came O
to O
this O
view O
in O
1913 O
in O
his O
book O
with O
the O
first O
publication O
of O
the O
collection O
of O
jewellery O
. O

He O
wrote O
them O
as O
a O
royal O
sign O
of O
Empress O
Gisela B-PER
, O
wife O
of O
Konrad B-PER
II I-PER
, O
German B-MISC
king O
( O
1024 O
- O
1039 O
) O
and O
emperor O
( O
from O
1027 O
) O
from O
the O
family O
of O
the O
Salians O
. O

Under O
the O
name O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
- I-MISC
Fibel I-MISC
" O
she O
has O
become O
known O
and O
famous O
. O

This O
dating O
was O
already O
lively O
discussed O
at O
that O
time O
, O
but O
never O
disproved O
, O
until O
the O
Upper O
Conservator O
at O
the O
Roman O
- O
Germanic B-LOC
Central I-LOC
Museum I-LOC
in O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
Dr. O
Mechthild B-PER
Schulze I-PER
- O
Dörrlamm O
, O
stimulated O
by O
the O
years O
of O
preparations O
for O
the O
SalierExhibition O
in O
Speyer B-LOC
now O
introduces O
a O
generation O
younger O
empress O
as O
owner O
of O
this O
special O
jewelry O
: O

Agnes B-PER
of I-PER
Poitou I-PER
, O
married O
in O
1043 O
to O
Emperor O
Henry B-PER
III I-PER
in O
Ingelheim B-LOC
and O
crowned O
Empress O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
the O
" O
secret O
capital O
of O
the O
empire O
" O
. O

The O
now O
researched O
affiliation O
of O
the O
jewellery O
is O
based O
on O
new O
, O
easily O
datable O
archaeological O
finds O
and O
comparative O
studies O
with O
Byzantine B-MISC
and O
Fatimid B-MISC
jewels O
and O
ornaments O
of O
the O
time O
in O
question O
, O
as O
she O
performs O
Mechthild B-PER
Schulze I-PER
- O
Dörrlamm O
in O
her O
book O
" O
The O
Mainz B-MISC
Treasure O
of O
the O
Empress O
Agnes B-PER
from O
the O
middle O
11th O
century O
- O
New O
Investigations O
on O
the O
so O
- O
called O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
Jewelry I-MISC
" O
" O
( O
Jan B-ORG
- I-ORG
Thorbecke I-ORG
- O
Verlag O
, O
Sigmaringen B-MISC
1991 O
) O
. O

The O
round O
, O
gold O
enamelled O
eagle B-MISC
peacock I-MISC
fib I-MISC
is O
the O
only O
piece O
that O
could O
be O
purchased O
shortly O
after O
the O
discovery O
of O
the O
jewellery O
from O
the O
Mainz B-MISC
Antiquity B-LOC
Museum I-LOC
in O
1880 O
and O
has O
since O
been O
kept O
there O
. O

All O
other O
jewels O
are O
now O
after O
many O
turbulent O
years O
in O
the O
Kunstgewerbemuseum B-LOC
Berlin I-LOC
. O

The O
construction O
workers O
had O
first O
concealed O
their O
find O
in O
1880 O
, O
then O
divided O
the O
jewelry O
among O
themselves O
and O
sold O
piece O
by O
piece O
. O

In O
the O
next O
decades O
the O
jewels O
appeared O
in O
various O
places O
and O
among O
the O
most O
diverse O
owners O
. O

Some O
parts O
were O
also O
considered O
completely O
lost O
in O
the O
meantime O
, O
other O
parts O
were O
severely O
damaged O
during O
World O
War B-MISC
II I-MISC
. O

The O
eagle B-MISC
- I-MISC
peacock I-MISC
- O
fibel O
is O
the O
prototype O
of O
a O
fibelform B-MISC
, O
of O
which O
so O
far O
only O
three O
specimens O
are O
known O
, O
which O
, O
as O
reported O
by O
the O
upper O
conservator O
, O
also O
all O
come O
from O
Mainz B-LOC
. O

The O
common O
characteristic O
of O
these O
three O
disc O
fibulas O
is O
that O
the O
eagle O
is O
depicted O
with O
a O
peacock O
crown O
made O
of O
expanded O
wings O
. O

This O
mixture O
of O
eagle O
and O
peacock O
is O
based O
on O
a O
profoundly O
Christian O
meaning O
: O

The O
eagle O
symbolizes O
resurrection O
and O
ascension O
of O
Christ B-PER
, O
the O
peacock O
eternal O
life O
. O

That O
this O
crowned O
bird O
was O
at O
the O
same O
time O
regarded O
as O
an O
imperial O
sign O
of O
sovereignty O
and O
forerunner O
of O
the O
Staufian O
imperial B-MISC
eagle I-MISC
is O
also O
a O
reference O
to O
the O
temporal O
classification O
. O

Its O
body O
shape O
in O
frontal O
view O
, O
only O
the O
head O
in O
profile O
, O
obviously O
dates O
back O
to O
Islamic O
art O
in O
the O
10th O
century O
. O

Stylistically O
, O
the O
most O
beautiful O
and O
" O
most O
quality O
" O
of O
the O
three O
eagle O
fibulas O
has O
novel O
dimensions O
. O

Instead O
of O
the O
formerly O
broad O
- O
edge O
framed O
small O
center O
, O
here O
the O
dominant O
large O
motif O
is O
surrounded O
by O
a O
now O
narrow O
edge O
. O

Another O
indication O
for O
the O
dating O
of O
this O
broken O
enamel O
fibula O
into O
the O
middle O
11th O
century O
are O
small O
flower O
stems O
made O
of O
gold O
wire O
at O
the O
roundings O
and O
pearl O
wire O
lines O
at O
the O
ends O
of O
the O
peacock O
wheel O
. O

Where O
and O
by O
whom O
the O
precious O
jewelry O
was O
made O
, O
can O
only O
be O
guessed O
. O

Some O
of O
them O
indicate O
Byzantine B-MISC
or O
Italian B-MISC
goldsmiths O
who O
were O
perhaps O
immigrating O
at O
that O
time O
or O
who O
had O
been O
living O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
for O
some O
time O
. O

Because O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
in O
the O
high O
Middle O
Ages O
called O
" O
diadem B-MISC
of I-MISC
the O
empire O
" O
, O
was O
in O
the O
Salierzeit B-MISC
the O
city O
with O
most O
royal O
stays O
and O
owned O
jewelry O
workshops O
of O
supraregional O
importance O
, O
whose O
traces O
can O
still O
be O
detected O
today O
on O
the O
old O
Rhine O
bank O
by O
lead O
waste O
, O
raw O
casts O
and O
semi O
- O
manufactures O
. O

Since O
the O
overwhelming O
number O
of O
jewels O
originates O
from O
the O
middle O
third O
of O
the O
11th O
century O
, O
it O
will O
be O
most O
likely O
to O
be O
attributed O
to O
Agnes B-PER
of I-PER
Poitou I-PER
, O
Mechthild B-PER
Schulze I-PER
- O
Dörlamm O
believes O
, O
especially O
since O
a O
golden O
finger O
ring O
with O
the O
image O
of O
her O
husband O
, O
the O
Emperor O
Henry B-PER
III I-PER
, O
is O
preserved O
. O

With O
the O
gift O
certificates O
issued O
immediately O
after O
the O
wedding O
on O
extended O
lands O
and O
possessions O
, O
Henry B-PER
III I-PER
made O
them O
one O
of O
the O
most O
equipped O
queens O
in O
the O
history O
of O
the O
medieval O
empire O
; O
whether O
as O
an O
expression O
of O
his O
affection O
or O
foreseeing O
independent O
provision O
for O
a O
" O
foreign O
" O
ruler O
, O
is O
not O
handed O
down O
. O

That O
this O
wealthy O
Empress O
could O
have O
pledged O
her O
entire O
jewelry O
to O
a O
Jewish O
merchant O
by O
herself O
is O
unlikely O
. O

It O
would O
be O
conceivable O
that O
Agnes B-PER
, O
as O
Regent O
of O
the O
throne O
in O
1066 O
- O
on O
the O
occasion O
of O
the O
wedding O
of O
her O
barely O
16 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
son O
and O
heir O
to O
the O
throne O
, O
Henry B-PER
IV I-PER
, O
with O
whom O
almost O
a O
year O
younger O
Bertha B-PER
of I-PER
Turin I-PER
- O
officially O
handed O
over O
the O
jewellery O
to O
her O
daughter O
- O
in O
- O
law O
for O
a O
gift O
. O

Bertha B-PER
almost O
belonged O
to O
the O
family O
, O
since O
she O
had O
already O
renounced O
the O
throne O
as O
a O
young O
girl O
and O
had O
withdrawn O
to O
an O
Italian B-MISC
monastery O
, O
where O
she O
no O
longer O
needed O
the O
representative O
jewelry O
. O

When O
Empress O
Bertha B-PER
now O
died O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
in O
1087 O
, O
at O
a O
time O
when O
Henry B-PER
IV I-PER
equipped O
his O
third O
Rome O
campaign O
and O
had O
to O
fight O
again O
with O
money O
difficulties O
because O
of O
his O
numerous O
campaigns O
, O
it O
could O
have O
been O
possible O
that O
under O
these O
circumstances O
he O
has O
pledged O
the O
jewelry O
of O
his O
deceased O
wife O
to O
a O
reliable O
, O
rich O
Jew O
. O

But O
when O
Heinrich B-PER
returned O
to O
Mainz B-LOC
ten O
years O
later O
, O
there O
was O
no O
trace O
of O
the O
jewelry O
. O

For O
a O
year O
earlier O
almost O
all O
the O
inhabitants O
of O
the O
Jewish B-LOC
quarter I-LOC
were O
killed O
by O
a O
pogrom O
of O
the O
crusaders O
, O
among O
them O
also O
- O
as O
it O
is O
handed O
down O
- O
the O
synagogue O
chief O
, O
who O
lit O
synagogue O
and O
house O
two O
days O
after O
his O
forced B-LOC
baptism I-LOC
and O
burned O
himself O
in O
it O
with O
his O
whole O
family O
. O

Old O
traces O
of O
fire O
are O
said O
to O
have O
been O
recognizable O
in O
the O
surprising O
discovery O
of O
jewellery O
after O
800 O
years O
. O

Although O
the O
history O
of O
this O
gold O
jewellery O
may O
leave O
some O
questions O
unanswered O
, O
the O
individual O
pieces O
possess O
a O
special O
cultural O
historical O
value O
and O
convey O
a O
vivid O
picture O
of O
medieval O
splendour O
at O
the O
imperial O
court O
as O
part O
of O
the O
newly O
acquired O
findings O
- O
but O
above O
all O
by O
a O
Salian O
empress O
who O
has O
now O
really O
worn O
the O
famous O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
- I-MISC
Fibel I-MISC
" O
: O

Agnes B-PER
of I-PER
Poitou I-PER
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Doctors O

Emergency O
Service O
: O

DRK B-LOC
House I-LOC
, O
Flachstraße B-LOC
1 O
, O
Tel O
. O

46 O
10 O
10 O
; O
fixed O
emergency O
medical O
hours O
: O

11 O
to O
13 O
and O
15 O
to O
20 O
o'clock O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Pharmacies O

See O
: O

Pharmacy B-LOC
on I-LOC
the O
market O
, O
Marktstr B-LOC
. O
12 O
, O
Tel O
. O

30 O
65 O
09 O
. O

Kohlheck B-LOC
pharmacy I-LOC
, O
Eulenstr B-LOC
. O
5 O
, O
Tel O
. O

46 O
65 O
15 O
. O

Merian B-LOC
pharmacy I-LOC
, O
Kaiser B-LOC
- I-LOC
Friedrich I-LOC
- O
Ring O
30 O
, O
Tel O
. O

30 O
64 O
91 O
. O

So O
. O
: O

Elephant B-LOC
pharmacy I-LOC
, O
Kirchgasse B-LOC
18 O
, O

30 O
33 O
48 O
. O

Paracelsus B-LOC
pharmacy I-LOC
, O
Schultheissstr B-LOC
. O
32 O
a O
, O
Bierstadt B-LOC
, O
Tel O
. O

50 O
27 O
25 O
. O

Sonnen B-LOC
- I-LOC
Apotheke I-LOC
, O
Brunhildenstr B-LOC
. O
25 O
, O
Tel O
. O

76 O
15 O
92 O
. O

Ophthalmologists O

J. B-PER
Litsch I-PER
, O
Mainzer B-LOC
Str I-LOC
. O
36 O
, O
Wiesbaden B-LOC
, O
Tel O
. O

06 O
11 O
/ O
30 O
34 O
45 O
( O
practice O
) O
or O
06 O
11 O
/ O
80 O
99 O
11 O
( O
apartment O
) O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

A O
new O
prize O
for O
women O
's O
political O
engagement O
City O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
awards O
" O
Tony B-MISC
- I-MISC
Sender I-MISC
" O
- O
Award O
first O
in O
autumn O
1992 O
/ O
Local O
reference O
is O
in O
demand O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
A. I-LOC
M. I-LOC
As O
the O
first O
German B-MISC
city O
Frankfurt B-LOC
am I-LOC
Main I-LOC
a O
prize O
for O
women O
's O
political O
engagement O
or O
works O
of O
women O
's O
research O
with O
local O
reference O
. O

With O
the O
newly O
created O
Tony B-MISC
Sender I-MISC
Prize I-MISC
, O
the O
City O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
wants O
to O
award O
outstanding O
innovative O
achievements O
in O
the O
field O
of O
work O
and O
work O
dealing O
with O
cultural O
or O
social O
issues O
. O

Frankfurt B-MISC
women I-MISC
, O
women O
's O
projects O
of O
this O
city O
or O
women O
, O
which O
are O
dedicated O
to O
a O
Frankfurt B-MISC
theme O
are O
worthy O
of O

The O
Tony B-MISC
Sender I-MISC
Prize I-MISC
is O
endowed O
with O
20 O
000 O
marks O
and O
is O
awarded O
for O
the O
first O
time O
on O
27 O
November O
1992 O
, O
then O
in O
the O
two O
- O
year O

The O
Women O
's O
Unit O
would O
also O
like O
to O
draw O
attention O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
more O
than O
40 O
years O
after O
the O
entry O
into O
force O
of O
the O
Constitution O
of O
the O
Federal O
Republic O
of O
Germany B-LOC
, O
the O
Basic O
Law O
Article O
3 O
. O
2 O
- O
" O
men O
and O
women O
are O
equal O
" O
- O
is O
still O
being O
violated O
. O

Women O
must O
continue O
to O
accept O
disadvantages O
in O
many O
areas O
of O
daily O
life O
. O

Who O
was O
the O
woman O
whose O
name O
will O
make O
the O
prize O
known O
again O
beyond O
the O
borders O
of O
the O
city O
? O

Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
was O
born O
in O
1888 O
in O
the O
present O
- O
day O
Wiesbaden B-MISC
district O
of O
Biebrich B-LOC
as O
the O
daughter O
of O
well O
- O
situated O
parents O
. O

According O
to O
the O
Fin O
de O
siècle O
and O
her O
social O
class O
, O
she O
had O
a O
life O
before O
her O
as O
a O
protected O
daughter O
and O
an O
instruction O
in O
the O
" O
salonology O
" O
in O
order O
to O
take O
her O
intended O
place O
in O
civil O
society O
as O
a O
wife O
and O
mother O
. O

But O
already O
at O
the O
Higher O
Daughter O
School O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
became O
aware O
that O
she O
did O
not O
want O
to O
be O
restricted O
to O
" O
children O
, O
kitchen O
, O
church O
" O
. O

The O
struggle O
for O
more O
freedom O
should O
not O
stop O
her O
life O
. O

Instead O
of O
working O
on O
her O
tax O
return O
, O
she O
went O
through O
the O
visit O
of O
a O
commercial O
school O
and O
after O
that O
secured O
her O
independence O
as O
a O
commercial O
employee O
. O

The O
22 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
began O
her O
political O
work O
in O
Paris B-LOC
, O
where O
she O
worked O
as O
a O
correspondent O
for O
a O
German B-MISC
company O
during O
the O
day O
and O
engaged O
in O
the O
French B-MISC
workers O
' O
movement O
and O
women O
's O
education O
work O
in O
the O
evenings O
, O
alongside O
the O
study O
of O
socialist O
theoreticians O
. O

The O
outbreak O
of O
the O
First B-MISC
World I-MISC
War I-MISC
brought O
an O
abrupt O
end O
to O
the O
emancipation O
- O
promoting O
stay O
in O
Paris O
; O
it O
was O
expelled O
as O
the O
German B-MISC
of O
the O
country O
. O

Returning O
to O
Frankfurt B-LOC
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
joined O
the O
Social O
Democratic O
war O
opposition O
and O
became O
a O
vehement O
contender O
for O
the O
end O
of O
a O
war O
that O
did O
not O
serve O
the O
defence O
of O
the O
fatherland O
but O
the O
conquest O
of O
new O
markets O
and O
the O
oppression O
of O
hitherto O
free O
peoples O
. O

She O
was O
an O
opponent O
of O
the O
SPD B-MISC
peace I-MISC
policy I-MISC
, O
was O
expelled O
from O
the O
party O
and O
co O
- O
founder O
of O
the O
USPD B-ORG
in O
1917 O
. O

The O
Independent O
Social O
- O
Democrat O
wrote O
during O
the O
November B-MISC
Revolution I-MISC
Frankfurter B-MISC
Stadtgeschichte O
. O

She O
was O
Secretary O
General O
of O
the O
Workers O
' O
Council O
and O
- O
after O
the O
introduction O
of O
the O
women O
's O
suffrage O
in O
November O
1918 O
- O
a O
member O
of O
the O
Frankfurt B-MISC
City O
Council O

The O
young O
Weimar B-LOC
Republic I-LOC
did O
not O
find O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
's I-PER
unqualified O
approval O
; O
she O
had O
hoped O
for O
more O
basic O
democracy O
from O
the O
revolution O
: O

the O
implementation O
of O
the O
idea O
of O
the O
Council O
in O
politics O
, O
the O
economy O
and O
in O
enterprises O
. O

As O
editor O
of O
the O
USPD B-MISC
- I-MISC
Tageszeitung I-MISC
" O
Volksrecht B-ORG
" O
and O
the O
" O
Betriebsraten O
- O
Zeitschrift O
" O
of O
the O
German B-ORG
Metalworkers I-ORG
Association I-ORG
she O
criticized O
the O
political O
development O
; O
as O
a O
member O
of O
the O
German B-MISC
Reichstag B-ORG
and O
party O
politician O
she O
did O
her O
best O
to O
actively O
shape O
politics O
. O

Faced O
with O
the O
decision O
either O
to O
submit O
to O
Lenin B-PER
's I-PER
dictates O
and O
to O
align O
the O
USPD B-ORG
with O
a O
moscow B-MISC
or O
to O
return O
to O
the O
ranks O
of O
the O
Social O
Democracy O
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
once O
again O
chose O
freedom O
- O
this O
time O
to O
not O
allow O
the O
strategy O
of O
the O
party O
to O
be O
determined O
by O
others O
. O

Not O
easily O
in O
her O
heart O
she O
decided O
to O
reunite O
with O
the O
SPD B-ORG
, O
which O
in O
her O
opinion O
had O
arranged O
too O
much O
with O
the O
bourgeois O
republic O
. O

In O
Parliament O
she O
was O
a O
recognised O
specialist O
on O
economic O
and O
foreign O
policy O
issues O
; O
she O
was O
a O
politician O
and O
editor O
- O
in O
- O
chief O
of O
the O
SPD B-MISC
magazine I-MISC
" O
Womenwelt B-ORG
" O
for O
the O
equal O
participation O
of O
women O
in O
all O
areas O
of O
life O
. O

The O
Jewish O
woman O
, O
social O
democrat O
and O
trade O
unionist O
was O
targeted O
by O
the O
Nazis B-ORG
at O
the O
end O
of O
the O
1920s O
. O

An O
open O
death O
threat O
caused O
them O
to O
flee O
to O
Belgium B-LOC
immediately O
after O
the O
Reichstag O
election O
on O
5 O
March O
1933 O
via O
Czechoslovakia I-LOC
. O

In O
1935 O
she O
returned O
from O
a O
U.S. B-MISC
stay I-MISC
no O
longer O
to O
the O
provincial O
narrow O
Flanders O
, O
settled O
in O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
and O
soon O
applied O
for O
U.S. B-MISC
citizenship I-MISC
. O

The O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
in O
the O
era O
of O
the O
social O
reformer O
" O
New B-MISC
Deal I-MISC
" O
seemed O
to O
offer O
it O
the O
greatest O
possible O
guarantee O
of O
life O
in O
individual O
and O
political O
freedom O
and O
without O
compulsion O
to O
social O
conventions O
. O

Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
achieved O
a O
final O
professional O
highlight O
as O
a O
representative O
of O
the O
US B-MISC
- I-MISC
American I-MISC
, O
later O
of O
the O
international O
trade O
union O
federation O
at O
the O
Economic O
and O
Social O
Council O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
. O

She O
did O
her O
main O
work O
in O
the O
Commission B-ORG
on I-ORG
the I-ORG
Status I-ORG
of I-ORG
Women I-ORG
and O
in O
the O
Commission O
on O
Human B-ORG
Rights I-ORG
. O

Her O
name O
is O
associated O
with O
the O
struggle O
against O
human O
enslavement O
through O
forced O
labour O
and O
politically O
motivated O
deprivation O
of O
liberty O
. O

Untiringly O
, O
she O
collected O
evidence O
of O
human O
rights O
violations O
and O
intrepidly O
accused O
the O
states O
that O
were O
violating O
human O
and O
freedom O
rights O
. O

Until O
her O
death O
in O
1964 O
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
firmly O
maintained O
that O
women O
and O
men O
can O
perform O
equal O
benefits O
if O
they O
have O
only O
equal O
opportunities O
and O
are O
not O
hampered O
by O
social O
norms O
or O
economic O
disadvantages O
. O

To O
break O
down O
class O
and O
gender O
barriers O
, O
to O
make O
them O
disappear O
completely O
, O
was O
their O
program O
. O

To O
achieve O
a O
life O
- O
style O
in O
free O
self O
- O
determination O
was O
their O
goal O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Medical O
assistance O
for O
the O
homeless O
An O
ambulance O
treats O
the O
" O
berbers B-MISC
" O
who O
are O
often O
sent O
away O
in O
doctor O
's O
offices O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
A. I-LOC
M. I-LOC
" O
So O
, O
the O
feet O
stay O
in O
for O
20 O
minutes O
now O
. O
" O

With O
friendly O
, O
but O
certain O
tone O
gives O
Klaus B-PER
Hetzel I-PER
, O
nurse O
and O
hygienie O
specialist O
, O
his O
instructions O
. O

= O
= O
References====External B-PER
links== O

changed O
) O
, O
homeless O
, O
obediently O
puts O
his O
sore O
legs O
in O
the O
large O
plastic O
bucket O
with O
a O
dark O
purple O
liquid O
. O
" O

Open O
legs O
, O
" O
explains O
Klaus B-PER
Hetzel I-PER
, O
" O
the O
most O
common O
disease O
among O
homeless O
people O
. O
" O

Since O
May O
18 O
, O
the O
" O
Medical O
Clinic O
for O
Residents O
" O
in O
Sachsenhausen B-LOC
has O
opened O
its O
doors O
. O

Within O
two O
weeks O
, O
21 O
patients O
were O
already O
with O
Hetzel B-PER
and O
his O
team O
. O

Almost O
all O
patients O
, O
says O
the O
nurse O
, O
complained O
about O
" O
smoker O
's O
legs O
" O
or O
" O
leg O
ulcers O
" O
. O

Treated O
with O
a O
potassium O
permanganate O
disinfection O
solution O
. O
" O

While O
other O
doctors O
suggest O
other O
means O
, O
" O
reports O
Hetzel B-PER
. O

But O
with O
his O
method O
he O
can O
show O
and O
prove O
successes O
: O

All O
treatments O
documented O
Hetzel B-PER
with O
photos O
or O
with O
video O
film O
. O

Here O
, O
the O
homeless O
could O
see O
for O
themselves O
what O
the O
regular O
application O
brings O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
new O
arrivals O
can O
be O
more O
easily O
convinced O
by O
the O
images O
of O
the O
meaning O
of O
the O
enterprise O
. O

Mistrust O
is O
the O
main O
reason O
why O
most O
of O
the O
homeless O
do O
not O
undergo O
" O
normal O
" O
medical O
therapy O
, O
explains O
Hetzel B-PER
. O
" O

No O
way O
do O
I O
go O
to O
one O
of O
these O
again O
, O
" O
Josef B-PER
Schmidt I-PER
agrees O
. O

He O
knows O
what O
he O
's O
talking O
about O
. O

With O
their O
usually O
not O
exactly O
" O
bourgeois O
" O
appearance O
are O
the O
" O
Berber B-MISC
" O
as O
they O
call O
themselves O
, O
no O
popular O
customers O
in O
doctor O
's O
practices O
. O

Often O
they O
are O
sent O
away O
under O
excuses O
. O

The O
problem O
, O
the O
undersupply O
of O
the O
homeless O
in O
the O
medical O
field O
, O
Hetzel B-PER
at O
his O
other O
job O
, O
the O
residenceless O
food O
issue O
in O
the O
Affentorhaus B-LOC
, O
has O
been O
recognized O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

Together O
with O
his O
wife O
Dagmar B-PER
- O
she O
is O
a O
doctor O
and O
makes O
the O
diagnoses O
in O
the O
" O
medical O
ambulance O
" O
- O
he O
offered O
there O
weekly O
an O
hour O
care O
. O

That O
was O
too O
little O
, O
and O
above O
all O
lacked O
the O
necessary O
facilities O
. O

These O
are O
available O
in O
the O
new O
domicile O
: O

Three O
rooms O
, O
fully O
furnished O
and O
a O
bathroom O
equipped O
with O
everything O
it O
needs O
for O
personal O
care O
. O

One O
of O
the O
rooms O
serves O
as O
a O
treatment O
room O
, O
another O
as O
an O
office O
( O
" O
finally O
the O
whole O
paperwork O
no O
longer O
at O
home O
" O
) O
, O
and O
finally O
there O
is O
in O
the O
entrance O
area O
a O
lounge O
- O
the O
" O
waiting O
room O
" O
with O
coffee O
bar O
and O
thought O
as O
a O
communication O
center O
. O

The O
Medical O
Clinic O
is O
run O
by O
the O
evangelistic B-ORG
Communication I-ORG
Association I-ORG
( O
AFEK B-ORG
) O
. O

Since O
1984 O
he O
has O
been O
registered O
as O
a O
non O
- O
profit O
association O
and O
is O
financed O
entirely O
by O
donations O
. O

His O
statutory O
goal O
of O
caring O
for O
marginal O
groups O
, O
he O
wants O
to O
cope O
by O
giving O
" O
help O
to O
self O
- O
help O
" O
. O

This O
can O
be O
seen O
in O
the O
medical O
ambulance O
project O
. O

Without O
the O
dedicated O
packing O
of O
former O
homeless O
people O
the O
rooms O
would O
have O
been O
renovated O
hardly O
so O
quickly O
and O
cost O
- O
effectively O
. O
" O

This O
was O
a O
completely O
run O
down O
pub O
. O
" O

All O
the O
work O
, O
even O
the O
walls O
and O
tiles O
, O
had O
been O
done O
by O
the O
helpers O
. O
" O

If O
they O
have O
a O
goal O
in O
mind O
, O
then O
they O
become O
aware O
of O
their O
social O
co O
- O
responsibility O
" O
, O
said O
Hetzel B-PER
, O
who O
calls O
himself O
a O
" O
decisive O
Christian B-MISC
" O
, O
the O
use O
of O
the O
formerly O
homeless O
. O

His O
credo O
is O
therefore O
an O
old O
Indian B-MISC
prayer I-MISC
that O
hangs O
as O
a O
poster O
opposite O
his O
office O
chair O
: O

" O
Great O
Spirit O
, O
keep O
me O
from O
judging O
a O
man O
until O
I O
have O
walked O
half O
a O
moon O
into O
his O
moccasins O
. O
" O

Since O
AFEK B-ORG
is O
fully O
engaged O
in O
donations O
, O
financial O
assistance O
is O
always O
welcome O
. O

For O
further O
information O
, O
please O
contact O
Klaus B-PER
Hetzel I-PER
on O
telephone O
62 O
35 O
59 O
from O
Monday O
to O
Thursday O
between O
9 O
a.m. O
and O
5 O
p.m. O
and O
Friday O
between O
9 O
a.m. O
and O
1 O
p.m. O

-DOCSTART- O

Ludwig B-LOC
's I-LOC
Linde I-LOC
and O
a O
lovely O
Maid O

AUERBACH B-LOC
. O

With O
the O
often O
quoted O
and O
many O
- O
sung O
" O
tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
it O
is O
as O
with O
the O
time O
and O
again O
called O
" O
Siegfriedquelle B-LOC
" O
where O
the O
fabulous O
rector O
died O
: O

no O
one O
is O
able O
to O
say O
and O
document O
exactly O
where O
both O
natural O
monuments O
are O
to O
be O
found O
. O

Therefore O
, O
it O
is O
not O
surprising O
that O
these O
are O
present O
several O
times O

So O
there O
is O
the O
said O
tree O
in O
Momart B-LOC
, O
Kimbach B-LOC
, O
Airlenbach B-LOC
, O
Olfen B-LOC
and O
also O
near O
the O
princely B-LOC
camp I-LOC
near O
Auerbach B-LOC
( O
district O
Bergstraße B-LOC
) O
. O

Perhaps O
the O
last O
place O
mentioned O
may O
be O
considered O
the O
" O
real O
" O
because O
there O
was O
planted O
in O
1778 O
a O
linden O
tree O
and O
" O
tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
was O
baptized O
. O

The O
Prince B-LOC
's I-LOC
Camp I-LOC
, O
former O
summer O
residence O
of O
the O
Hessian B-MISC
Landgraves O
, O
with O
its O
friendly O
park O
interspersed O
with O
numerous O
exotic O
trees O
, O
also O
seems O
to O
be O
the O
right O
environment O
for O
the O
legendary O
Linde O
. O

For O
closely O
connected O
with O
the O
" O
tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
and O
the O
graceful O
princely B-LOC
camp I-LOC
is O
a O
romance O
romance O
in O
that O
park O
and O
forest O
scenery O
. O

The O
opera O
singer O
, O
later O
director O
of O
the O
Darmstadt B-MISC
Court O
Theatre O
and O
master O
of O
native O
narrative O
art O
, O
Ernst B-PER
Pasqué I-PER
, O
drew O
them O
literaryly O
after O
. O

That O
the O
poet O
was O
able O
to O
do O
this O
so O
aptly O
, O
is O
easily O
explained O
: O

He O
lived O
two O
decades O
( O
from O
1871 O
to O
1892 O
) O
on O
the O
Bergstraße B-LOC
and O
learned O
by O
his O
good O
relations O
with O
Grand O
Duke O
Ludwig B-PER
IV I-PER
many O
different O
, O
what O
distinguishes O
the O
originality O
of O
his O
story O
" O
There B-MISC
stands I-MISC
a I-MISC
tree I-MISC
in I-MISC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
. O

At O
the O
" O
Fürstenlager B-LOC
" I-LOC
scene I-LOC
, O
Landgraf O
Friedrich B-PER
miraculously O
met O
Karoline B-PER
Seitz I-PER
from O
Grasellenbach B-LOC
, O
a O
girl O
of O
simple O
origin O
, O
who O
married O
her O
and O
led O
her O
a O
happy O
marriage O
. O

Pasqué B-PER
portrayed O
Karoline B-PER
in O
his O
booklet O
as O
" O
a O
strikingly O
beautiful O
blood O
- O
young O
thing O
of O
about O
17 O
years O
, O
a O
blonde O
whose O
fine O
naturally O
ruffled O
blond O
socks O
under O
the O
Sammetkäppchen O
looked O
out O
a O
little O
too O
curious O
and O
spread O
on O
the O
white O
forehead O
" O
. O

At O
this O
chance O
meeting O
on O
the O
occasion O
of O
a O
courtly O
festival O
in O
the O
princely B-LOC
camp I-LOC
Karoline B-PER
is O
said O
to O
have O
sung O
the O
old O
folk O
song O
" O
There B-MISC
stands I-MISC
a I-MISC
tree I-MISC
in I-MISC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
. O

In O
memory O
of O
the O
feast O
was O
planted O
" O
under O
all O
kinds O
of O
solemn O
ceremonies O
" O
a O
young O
lime O
tree O
, O
" O
at O
a O
place O
of O
height O
, O
from O
where O
one O
had O
a O
magnificent O
view O
of O
the O
Schönberg B-MISC
valley O
and O
the O
old O
picturesque O
castle O
of O
the O
Counts O
of O
Erbach B-LOC
- I-LOC
Schönberg I-LOC
" O

A O
hermit O
said O
" O
the O
forest O
blessing O
on O
the O
young O
Linde O
, O
which O
he O
christened O
- O
inspired O
by O
Karolin B-PER
's I-PER
singing O
- O
, O
tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
' O

However O
, O
this O
tree O
no O
longer O
exists O
, O
a O
lightning O
strike O
destroyed O
it O
. O

But O
in O
his O
place O
, O
Count O
Ludwig B-PER
of I-PER
Erbach I-PER
- O
Schönberg O
( O
1792 O
- O
1863 O
) O
planted O
a O
new O
linden O
tree O
, O
which O
has O
since O
been O
called O
" O
Ludwigslinde B-LOC
" O
, O
a O
tall O
tree O
of O
powerful O
shape O
and O
wide O
branched O
mop O
growth O
. O

From O
the O
bank O
under O
the O
Linde O
you O
can O
enjoy O
a O
magnificent O
view O
- O
over O
the O
valley O
to O
the O
mountains O
, O
to O
the O
Starkenburg B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
Knodenkopf B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
direction O
point O
Krehberg B-LOC
, O
Märkerwald B-LOC
, O
Hemsberg B-LOC
, O
Vetzersberg B-LOC
, O
in O
the O
Rhine B-LOC
plain I-LOC
to O
the O
Pfälzerwald B-LOC
. O

Right O
next O
to O
the O
" O
Ludwigslinde B-LOC
" O
lies O
the O
Schönberger B-MISC
" O
Herrenwingert B-LOC
" O
. O

Formerly O
it O
belonged O
to O
the O
Counts O
of O
Erbach B-LOC
- I-LOC
Schönberg I-LOC
, O
today O
it O
is O
owned O
by O
the O
state B-ORG
wine I-ORG
estate I-ORG
Bergstraße I-ORG
. O

There O
should O
be O
not O
a O
few O
people O
- O
mountain B-MISC
roads I-MISC
and O
strangers O
- O
who O
have O
fallen O
in O
love O
with O
this O
place O
at O
the O
" O
Ludwigslinde B-LOC
" O
and O
the O
" O
Herrenwingert B-LOC

REINHARD B-PER
TREBER I-PER

-DOCSTART- O

Contacts O
to O
high O
- O
profile O
wind O
instruments O
Epiphanias O
- O
Kantorin O
has O
been O
working O
for O
classical O
and O
new O
music O
for O
14 O
years O

NORDEREND B-LOC
. O

Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
has O
been O
a O
cantor O
at O
the O
Evangelical O
Epiphany B-ORG
in O
the O
Nordend B-LOC
for O
14 O
years O
. O

It O
is O
possible O
to O
build O
up O
a O
lot O

Especially O
the O
last O
concert O
in O
April O
did O
it O
to O
her O
. O
" O

Since O
I O
have O
noticed O
what O
we O
have O
now O
for O
an O
excellent O
choir O
. O
" O

In O
the O
difficult O
romantic O
a O
cappella O
sets O
, O
the O
singers O
would O
have O
reacted O
to O
the O
smallest O
instruction O
. O

And O
also O
for O
her O
orchestra O
she O
has O
only O
commending O
words O
. O

That O
such O
achievements O
do O
not O
fall O
from O
the O
sky O
, O
but O
can O
only O
be O
achieved O
by O
continuous O
, O
tough O
sample O
work O
, O
mentions O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
only O
on O
the O
edge O
. O

Twice O
a O
year O
- O
mostly O
around O
Easter O
and O
in O
the O
Advent O
period O
- O
choir O
and O
orchestra O
of O
the O
Epiphany B-ORG
community I-ORG
give O
their O
great O
concerts O
. O

This O
year O
the O
cantor O
had O
chosen O
an O
interesting O
mix O
of O
romantic O
a O
cappella O
singing O
, O
that O
is O
, O
unaccompanied O
pieces O
for O
choir O
, O
and O
orchestral O
works O
of O
the O
20th O
century O
. O

A O
program O
with O
Johann B-PER
Sebastian I-PER
Bach I-PER
's I-PER
music O
is O
planned O
for O
Advent O

These O
concerts O
can O
cost O
the O
community O
a O
lot O

Posters O
stick O
to O
the O
Litfaßsäulen O
, O
and O
on O
handbills O
and O
in O
newspapers O
is O
strongly O
advertised O
. O

The O
church O
on O
Holzhausenstraße B-LOC
is O
then O
mostly O
also O
full O
breaking O
. O

But O
other O
, O
less O
elaborately O
announced O
events B-MISC
are O
almost O
always O
well O
attended O
. O

Thus O
the O
matinee O
with O
organ O
and O
violin O
music O
met O
at O
the O
end O
of O
March O
an O
amazing O
public O
interest O
, O
although O
not O
Bach B-PER
, O
Mozart B-PER
or O
Mendelssohn B-PER
, O
but O
exclusively O
music O
of O
the O
20th O
century O
was O
on O
the O
program O
. O
" O

We O
just O
now O
have O
our O
regular O
audience O
" O
, O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
does O
not O
look O
without O
pride O
at O
the O
lively O
musical O
activity O
. O

The O
cantor O
has O
something O
, O
without O
which O
in O
concert O
operation O
nothing O
runs O
: O

Relations O
. O

In O
difficult O
choral O
and O
orchestral O
works O
, O
top O
- O
class O
wind O
players O
are O
especially O
important O
. O

And O
to O
them O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
has O
best O
contacts O
. O

Most O
of O
them O
work O
in O
the O
Radio O
Symphony O
Orchestra O
and O
are O
happy O
to O
help O
out O
in O
the O
Epiphany B-LOC
. O
" O

Many O
enjoy O
to O
play O
with O
the O
choir O
, O
that O
they O
also O
like O
to O
perform O
as O
a O
soloist O
once O
. O
" O

That O
the O
cantor O
has O
its O
own O
string O
orchestra O
is O
unusual O
. O

For O
church O
concerts O
usually O
the O
musicians O
are O
bought O
together O
, O
which O
you O
need O
right O
now O
. O

Or O
you O
hire O
an O
entire O
professional O
orchestra O
. O

That O
's O
expensive O
and O
does O
n't O
guarantee O
a O
good O
concert O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O
" O

The O
orchestra O
rehearses O
as O
often O
as O
the O
choir O
. O

The O
relationships O
are O
thus O
much O
closer O
, O
and O
the O
musicians O
motivate O
each O
other O
at O
concerts O
. O
" O

That O
very O
heavy O
romantic O
chunks O
, O
such O
as O
the O
German B-MISC
Requiem O
of O
Brahms B-PER
, O
are O
hard O
to O
create O
with O
the O
mainly O
lay O
orchestra O
, O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
likes O
to O
buy O
. O

To O
Johann B-PER
Sebastian I-PER
Bach I-PER
the O
cantor B-MISC
has O
a O
split O
relationship O
, O
despite O
the O
concerts O
on O
20 O
September O
and O
6 O
December O
, O
in O
which O
mainly O
works O
of O
the O
Thomas B-MISC
cantor I-MISC
are O

What O
disturbs O
them O
is O
the O
oversaturation O
. O

Every O
second O
year O
cantatas O
from O
the O
Christmas B-MISC
Oratorio I-MISC
? O

That O
would O
be O
too O
boring O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
. O
" O

Many O
do O
not O
know O
that O
not O
only O
Bach B-PER
has O
composed O
good O
and O
interesting O
music O
. O
" O

During O
her O
14 O
- O
year O
work O
she O
did O
not O
perform O
a O
work O
twice O
, O
except O
Mozart B-PER
's I-PER
" O
Requiem B-MISC
" O
and O
the O
" O
Fate B-MISC
Song I-MISC
" O
by O
Johannes B-PER
Brahms I-PER
. O
" O

I O
want O
to O
at O
least O
tell O
people O
how O
wide O
the O
range O
of O
different O
pieces O
is O
. O
" O

Also O
for O
her O
the O
music O
history O
does O
not O
end O
with O
Anton B-PER
Bruckner I-PER
. O

Your O
interest O
in O
modern O
music O
is O
great O
. O

At O
the O
choir O
, O
it O
's O
hard O
for O
the O
cantor O
. O
" O

I O
do O
n't O
want O
to O
make O
new O
music O
fans O
out O
of O
the O
singers O
. O

But O
everyone O
should O
be O
open O
to O
this O
. O
" O

As O
an O
organist O
, O
she O
devotes O
herself O
extensively O
to O
modern O
music O
. O

Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
conducts O
a O
brilliantly O
trained O
, O
70 O
- O
member O
church O
choir O
and O
his O
own O
orchestra O
, O
has O
a O
free O
hand O
in O
her O
planning O
, O
and O
also O
her O
church O
musical O
budget O
does O
not O
worry O
her O
at O
present O
. O

Is O
there O
any O
wish O
at O
all O
? O
" O

A O
new O
, O
modern O
organ O
" O
- O
that O
would O
be O
what O
you O
still O
lack O
for O
musical O
happiness O
. O

The O
relatively O
small O
instrument O
from O
the O
1950s O
has O
few O
registers O
and O
an O
outdated O
technique O
. O
" O

The O
new O
intonation O
two O
years O
ago O
has O
brought O
a O
lot O
of O
sound O
. O
" O

But O
she O
does O
n't O
give O
herself O
any O
illusions O
. O

For O
a O
new O
organ O
simply O
lacks O
the O
money O
. O

Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
has O
built O
up O
a O
lot O
in O
the O
Nordend B-LOC
and O
therefore O
does O
not O
waste O
any O
thought O
of O
a O
career O
change O
. O
" O

In O
a O
new O
congregation O
I O
would O
have O
to O
start O
at O
the O
bottom O
. O
" O

-DOCSTART- O

Samples O
+ O
meetings O

Accordion O
music O
club O
" O
Cheerfulness B-ORG
" O
Griesheim B-LOC
: O

Classes O
for O
accordion O
students O
are O
available O
every O
Thursday O
( O
from O
2 O
pm O
) O
, O
in O
the O
Bürgerhaus O
Griesheim B-LOC
, O
Schwarzerlenweg B-LOC
57 O
( O
Club O
Room O
3 O
) O
. O

And O
the O
club O
's O
orchestra O
rehearses O
every O
Tuesday O
, O
from O
19 O
to O
20.30 O
in O
the O
club O
room O
1 O
in O
Griesheim B-LOC
. O

Arbeitskreis O
Bockenheimer B-ORG
Senior I-ORG
Citizens I-ORG
: O

Meeting O
of O
members O
to O
the O
club O
afternoon O
every O
first O
Tuesday O
of O
the O
month O
( O
3 O
p.m. O
) O
in O
the O
social B-LOC
station I-LOC
at O
Rohmerplatz B-LOC
( O
Parterre O
) O
. O

Athletics O
sports O
club O
1990 B-ORG
Griesheim I-ORG
: O

Sports O
badge O
preparation O
and O
- O
acceptance O
in O
weight O
lifting O
after O
prior O
registration O
every O
Monday O
, O
Wednesday O
and O
Friday O
( O
from O
18 O
o'clock O
each O
) O
in O
the O
Griesheimer B-LOC
Sporthalle I-LOC
, O
Linkstraße B-LOC
86 O
- O
88 O
. O

Contact O
: O

Klaus B-PER
Samer I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

37 O
19 O
74 O
) O
and O
Hugo B-PER
Zingel I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

38 O
42 O
27 O
) O
. O

Bockenheimer B-ORG
Men I-ORG
's O
Choir O
1837 O
: O

To O
the O
choir O
rehearsal O
the O
active O
members O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
, O
8 O
pm O
, O
in O
the O
community O
hall O
of O
the O
Protestant O
St. B-LOC
Jakobskirche I-LOC
, O
Grempstraße B-LOC
41 O
. O

Women O
and O
men O
interested O
in O
singing O
in O
the O
community O
can O
participate O
in O
this O
rehearsal O
without O
obligation O
. O

Information O
about O
all O
club O
activities O
is O
provided O
by O
Chairman O
Wolfgang B-PER
Ochs I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

76 O
67 O
43 O
) O
. O

Bockenheimer B-ORG
Zitherkranz I-ORG
1886 I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
's O
activists O
rehearse O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
from O
8 O
pm O
) O
at O
" O
Bürgertreff B-LOC
Bockenheim I-LOC
" O
, O
Schwälmer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

At O
the O
Zitherspiel O
interested O
parties O
receive O
more O
information O
from O
Rudi B-PER
May I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

77 O
15 O
43 O
) O
. O

Letter O
pigeon O
club O
" O
Sport B-ORG
" O
Frankfurt B-LOC
: O

The O
members O
meet O
for O
the O
club O
evening O
every O
Thursday O
, O
8 O
pm O
, O
in O
the O
restaurant O
" O
Zur B-LOC
Krone I-LOC
" O
in O
Seckbach B-LOC
, O
Wilhelmshöher B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
165 O
. O

Guests O
interested O
in O
pigeon O
sport O
are O
welcome O
. O

The O
BUND O
- O
Ortsverband B-ORG
2/9 I-ORG
has O
every O
third O
Wednesday O
of O
the O
month O
at O
8 O
pm O
Association O
meeting O
at O
the O
Bürgertreff B-LOC
Bockenheim I-LOC
, O
Schwälmer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Chorgemeinschaft B-ORG
1857 I-ORG
Griesheim I-ORG
: O

To O
the O
choir O
rehearsal O
the O
active O
people O
meet O
every O
Thursday O
( O
19.45 O
to O
21.15 O
clock O
) O
in O
the O
Bürgerhaus B-LOC
Griesheim I-LOC
, O
Schwarzerlenweg B-LOC
57 O
( O
club O
room O
2 O
) O
. O

Women O
and O
men O
are O
still O
included O
in O
the O
choir O
. O

For O
further O
information O
, O
please O
contact O
Horst B-PER
Seip I-PER
( O
tel O
. O

38 O
20 O
97 O
) O
. O

DLRG B-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

The O
members O
of O
the O
diving O
group O
meet O
every O
Thursday O
, O
7.30 O
pm O
, O
to O
Taining O
in O
the O
indoor B-LOC
swimming I-LOC
pool I-LOC
Sachsenhausen I-LOC
, O
Textorstraße B-LOC
42 O
. O

Information O
on O
rescue O
diving O
training O
is O
provided O
by O
Willi B-PER
Vogt I-PER
Tel O
. O

58 O
66 O
23 O
........................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................... O

Information O
can O
also O
be O
obtained O
from O
the O
DLRG B-MISC
office I-MISC
every O
Wednesday O
from O
3 O
p.m. O
to O
8 O
p.m. O
Tel O
. O

28 O
05 O
12 O
. O

FKV B-ORG
1911 I-ORG
and I-ORG
Maagard I-ORG
: O

The O
dance O
corps O
of O
the O
Frankfurt B-ORG
Carnival I-ORG
Club I-ORG
1911 I-ORG
trains O
every O
Wednesday O
, O
19 O
to O
20.30 O
clock O
( O
mini O
guard O
from O
18 O
to O
19 O
clock O
) O
, O
in O
the O
club B-LOC
home I-LOC
, O
Petterweilstraße B-LOC
69 O
in O
Bornheim B-LOC
( O
Bunker O
) O
. O

There O
are O
still O
girls O
interested O
in O
dancing O
in O
the O
community O
. O

Contact O
: O

Manuela B-PER
Koch I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

0 O
61 O
87 O
/ O
34 O
56 O
. O

Frankfurter B-ORG
Kanoe I-ORG
- O
Verein O
1913 O
: O

The O
association O
invites O
to O
its O
meetings O
- O
every O
Thursday O
, O
from O
6 O
pm O
, O
in O
the O
" O
Friedel B-LOC
- I-LOC
Baureis I-LOC
- O
Haus O
" O
, O
the O
boat O
house O
at O
the O
peace B-LOC
bridge I-LOC
. O

For O
more O
information O
, O
please O
contact O
Pressewart O
Eckard B-PER
Thinemann I-PER
at O
tel O
. O

88 O
98 O
81 O
( O
from O
6 O
p.m. O
) O
. O

Frankfurt B-ORG
Carnival I-ORG
- O
Gesellschaft O
Rot O
- O
Weiß O
: O

The O
" O
regiment O
daughters O
" O
of O
the O
association O
train O
every O
Monday O
, O
8 O
pm O
, O
in O
the O
" O
Citizenstreff B-LOC
Bockenheim I-LOC
" O
in O
the O
Schwälmer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Frankfurter B-ORG
Liedertafel I-ORG
1827 I-ORG
: O

To O
the O
choir O
rehearsal O
the O
active O
people O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
19.45 O
to O
21.45 O
clock O
) O
in O
the O
" O
Bürgertreff B-LOC
Philanthropin I-LOC
" O
, O
Hebelstraße B-LOC
17 O
. O

Women O
and O
men O
interested O
in O
singing O
in O
the O
community O
are O
still O
included O
in O
the O
choir O
. O

Contact O
: O

Chairman O
Hans B-PER
Riebartsch I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

31 O
34 O
61 O
) O
. O

Frankfurter B-ORG
Musikverein I-ORG
: O

To O
the O
orchestra O
rehearsal O
the O
musicians O
meet O
Thursdays O
, O
at O
8 O
pm O
in O
the O
" O
Josefsklause B-LOC
" O
in O
Bornheim B-LOC
, O
Berger B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
133 O
. O

Head O
of O
the O
brass O
orchestra O
( O
Big O
Band O
- O
Sound O
) O
: O

Norbert B-PER
Natho I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

46 O
12 O
85 O
; O
conductor O
: O

Hans O
- O
Joachim B-PER
Eberhardt I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

42 O
65 O
02 O
. O

Frankfurt B-ORG
City I-ORG
Guard I-ORG
: O

For O
the O
training O
, O
the O
members O
of O
the O
Rambasballett O
of O
the O
1st B-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
Women I-ORG
's I-ORG
Fanfare I-ORG
Corps I-ORG
and O
the O
Spielmannszug O
meet O
every O
Wednesday O
( O
8 O
pm O
) O
at O
the O
" O
Haus B-LOC
Gallus I-LOC
" O
, O
Frankenallee B-LOC
111 O
. O

FTG B-ORG
47 I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

Judo O
for O
children O
offers O
the O
Frankfurter B-ORG
Turn- I-ORG
und I-ORG
Sportgemeinschaft I-ORG
1847 I-ORG
every O
Friday O
( O
children O
from O
six O
to O
ten O
years O
) O
, O
and O
every O
Monday O
( O
children O
and O
teenagers O
from O
ten O
years O
old O
) O
, O
each O
from O
16 O
to O
18 O
o'clock O
, O
at O
the O
FTG B-LOC
sports I-LOC
center I-LOC
in O
Bockenheim B-LOC
in O
Marburger B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Contact O
via O
the O
FTG B-MISC
office I-MISC
Tel O
. O

77 O
49 O
29 O
. O

Comradeship O
of O
former B-ORG
professional I-ORG
firefighters I-ORG
: O

The O
member O
meeting O
for O
a O
pleasant O
gathering O
is O
every O
first O
Tuesday O
of O
the O
month O
( O
3 O
pm O
) O
in O
the O
restaurant O
" O
Zur B-LOC
Stalburg I-LOC
" O
( O
Nordend B-LOC
) O
, O
Glauburgstraße B-LOC
80 O
. O

Kneippverein B-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
offers O
yoga O
lessons O
every O
Monday O
( O
4 O
pm O
) O
and O
Thursday O
( O
6 O
pm O
) O
, O
also O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
10 O
am O
) O
light O
gymnastics O
for O
ladies O
and O
gentlemen O
( O
4 O
pm O
gymnastics O
for O
ladies O
and O
gentlemen O
) O
in O
the O
South B-LOC
District I-LOC
Bath I-LOC
, O
Textorstraße B-LOC
42 O
. O

Further O
information O
on O
the O
offers O
of O
the O
Kneippverein O
gives O
Hannelore B-PER
Kehlmann I-PER
, O
Tel O

39 O
17 O
78 O
. O

The O
athletics O
department O
of O
the O
gymnastics B-ORG
and I-ORG
sports I-ORG
community I-ORG
98 I-ORG
North I-ORG
West I-ORG
is O
looking O
for O
offspring O
( O
from O
ten O
years O

Exercise O
hours O
on O
Mondays O
, O
Wednesdays O
and O
Fridays O
from O
17.30 O
to O
19.30 O
on O
the O
sports O
field O
of O
the O
Ernst B-ORG
- I-ORG
Reuter I-ORG
- O
Schule O
I. O
Interested O
persons O
can O
contact O
coach O
Helmut B-PER
Terstegen I-PER
during O
the O
exercise O
hours O
. O

The O
department O
offers O
students O
a O
talent O
promotion O
in O
the O
pole O
vault O
. O

Information O
about O
Karl B-PER
Terstegen I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

57 O
19 O
74 O
. O

Men O
's O
choir B-ORG
Liederkranz I-ORG
Praunheim I-ORG
: O

To O
the O
choir O
rehearsal O
the O
active O
members O
meet O
every O
Monday O
, O
8 O
pm O
, O
in O
the O
parish O
house O
Christ B-LOC
- I-LOC
König I-LOC
, O
Damashkeanger B-LOC
158 O
. O

Young O
men O
interested O
in O
singing O
in O
the O
community O
can O
find O
out O
about O
the O
male O
choir O
at O
Wilfried B-PER
Roth I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

57 O
42 O
71 O
) O
. O

Men O
's O
choir B-ORG
Liederkranz I-ORG
Praunheim I-ORG
: O

The O
women O
of O
the O
association O
meet O
for O
a O
pleasant O
gathering O
every O
first O
Monday O
of O
the O
month O
, O
8 O
pm O
, O
in O
the O
parish O
house O
of O
ChristKönig B-LOC
, O
Damashkeanger B-LOC
158 O
. O

Post O
- O
Sportsverein B-ORG
Blau I-ORG
- O
Gelb O
Frankfurt O
: O

The O
club O
invites O
you O
to O
the O
" O
Ginnheimer B-MISC
Lauftreff I-MISC
" O
every O
Tuesday O
at O
6.30 O
p.m. O

The O
starting O
point O
is O
the O
car O
park O
of O
the O
club O
at O
the O
Poststadion B-LOC
( O
Am B-LOC
Ginnheimer I-LOC
Wäldchen I-LOC
) O

Cycling B-ORG
Community I-ORG
1890 I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

For O
the O
club O
evening O
members O
and O
cycling O
friends O
meet O
every O
Friday O
( O
8 O
pm O
) O
at O
the O
" O
Haus B-LOC
Ronneburg I-LOC
" O
in O
Preungesheim B-LOC
in O
the O
Gelnhäuser B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
2 O

Rödelheimer B-ORG
Neuner I-ORG
: O

The O
choir O
rehearses O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
8.30 O
pm O
) O
at O
the O
Rödelheimer B-LOC
Vereinsringheim I-LOC
in O
the O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

Wheelchair B-ORG
sports I-ORG
club I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
is O
looking O
for O
dance O
- O
loving O
pedestrians O
who O
can O
find O
pleasure O
and O
fun O
dancing O
with O
Rollis O
. O

It O
is O
rehearsed O
every O
Thursday O
( O
20 O
to O
22 O
o'clock O
) O
in O
the O
BG B-LOC
Accident I-LOC
Clinic I-LOC
, O
Friedberger B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
. O

Contact O
: O

Horst B-PER
Lozar I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

76 O
13 O
37 O
) O
. O

Sängerchor B-ORG
der I-ORG
Lokbedienstten I-ORG
1919 I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

For O
their O
choir O
rehearsal O
, O
the O
active O
people O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
, O
5.30 O
p.m. B-PER
, O
in O
the O
railway B-LOC
operation I-LOC
canteen I-LOC
, O
Camberger B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
17 O
. O

Schützenverein B-ORG
Freischütz I-ORG
Rödelheim I-ORG
: O

The O
active O
members O
of O
the O
association O
train O
every O
Sunday O
( O
from O
10 O
a.m. O
to O
12.30 O
p.m. O
) O
and O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
from O
7.30 O
p.m. O
to O
10 O
p.m. O
) O
, O
on O
the O
stands O
in O
the O
club O
ring O
home O
in O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

Sports B-ORG
Fishing I-ORG
Club I-ORG
Anchor I-ORG
Houses I-ORG
: O

The O
members O
and O
friends O
of O
the O
association O
meet O
for O
a O
pleasant O
gathering O
every O
Tuesday O
, O
8 O
pm O
, O
in O
the O
club O
home O
of O
the O
sports O
anglers O
on O
the O
Hausener B-LOC
Weg I-LOC
. O

Sports B-ORG
and I-ORG
fun I-ORG
club I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
is O
still O
looking O
for O
fellow O
players O
for O
a O
mixed O
volleyball O
group O
. O

Training O
is O
held O
every O
Thursday O
( O
from O
6 O
pm O
to O
8 O
pm O
) O
at O
the O
Anne B-LOC
Frank I-LOC
School I-LOC
, O
Fritz B-LOC
- I-LOC
Tarnow I-LOC
- O
Straße O
29 O

0 O
61 O
07 O
/ O
6 O
12 O
69 O
. O

Gymnasium B-ORG
Römerstadt I-ORG
: O

After O
the O
end O
of O
the O
school O
holidays O
, O
the O
association O
offers O
lessons O
in O
athletics O
and O
gymnastics O
for O
boys O
and O
girls O
( O
six O
to O
nine O
years O
) O
: O

Tuesdays O
from O
15 O
to O
16.30 O
, O
in O
the O
Siblings B-LOC
Scholl I-LOC
School I-LOC
I O
m O
Burgfeld B-LOC
7 O
. O

For O
further O
information O
, O
please O
contact O
Constanze B-PER
Spitz I-PER
( O
tel O

58 O
86 O
32 O
) O
. O

Gymnastics B-ORG
and I-ORG
sports I-ORG
community I-ORG
98 I-ORG
Northwest I-ORG
: O

Courses O
in O
vertebral O
gymnastics O
in O
the O
gym O
, O
Weißkirchener B-LOC
Weg I-LOC
12 O
, O
Thursdays O
( O
16 O
and O
17 O
o'clock O
) O
, O
Saturdays O
( O
9.30 O
, O
10.30 O
and O
11.30 O
o'clock O
) O
and O
Mondays O
( O
9 O
o'clock O
) O
. O

Requests O
for O
supporting O
documents O
: O

Office O
to O
meet O
Tuesdays O
and O
Thursdays O
from O
5 O
to O
7 O
p.m. O
, O
Tel O

58 O
10 O
23 O
. O

Gym B-ORG
and I-ORG
sports I-ORG
club I-ORG
1878 I-ORG
Ginnheim I-ORG
: O

The O
mixed O
choir O
of O
the O
singing O
department O
of O
the O
association O
rehearses O
on O
Fridays O
from O
8 O
p.m. O
to O
10 O
p.m. O
at O
the O
Clubhaus B-LOC
Ginnheim I-LOC
, O
Am O
Mühlgarten B-LOC
2 O
( O
small O
hall O
) O
. O

Gym B-ORG
and I-ORG
sports I-ORG
club I-ORG
1860 I-ORG
houses I-ORG
: O

The O
association O
offers O
" O
swimming O
for O
everyone O
" O
on O
Fridays O
( O
20 O
to O
22 O
o'clock O
) O
in O
the O
swimming O
hall O
of O
the O
Liebigschule B-ORG
in O
Westhausen B-LOC
( O
Kollwitzstraße B-LOC
) O

For O
more O
information O
, O
please O
contact O
Rudi B-PER
Litzinger I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

76 O
35 O
50 O
. O

Association B-ORG
for I-ORG
Postage I-ORG
Stamps I-ORG
Rödelheim I-ORG
: O

The O
members O
of O
the O
association O
meet O
every O
second O
and O
fourth O
Thursday O
in O
the O
month O
from O
7.30 O
p.m. O
at O
the O
Rödelheimer B-LOC
Vereinsringheim I-LOC
, O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

Association B-ORG
Water I-ORG
Sports I-ORG
Westend I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
offers O
swimming O
lessons O
for O
beginners O
and O
advanced O
every O
Thursday O
( O
from O
6 O
pm O
to O
9 O
pm O
) O
at O
Berthold B-LOC
- I-LOC
Otto I-LOC
- O
Schule O
, O
Kiefernstraße B-LOC
18 O
a O
( O
Griesheim B-LOC
) O
. O

For O
more O
information O
about O
the O
offers O
of O
the O
association O
, O
please O
contact O
Günter B-PER
Gronemann I-PER
( O
tel O
. O

39 O
57 O
49 O
) O
. O

Vespa B-ORG
- I-ORG
Clup I-ORG
" O
Scooterlads O
" O
1985 O
: O

The O
scooter O
drivers O
meet O
on O
Wednesdays O
at O
8 O
pm O
at O
" O
Ergo B-LOC
Bibamus I-LOC
" O
at O
Eschersheimer B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
401 O
. O

For O
more O
information O
about O
the O
Vespa O
Club O
, O
please O
contact O
Wolfgang B-PER
Frey I-PER
at O
tel O
. O

51 O
10 O
91 O
. O

Folk O
choir O
" O
Frohsinn B-ORG
" I-ORG
Rödelheim I-ORG
: O

Every O
Wednesday O
, O
7.30 O
p.m. O
, O
in O
the O
Rödelheimer B-LOC
Vereinsringheim I-LOC
, O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
meet O
to O
the O
choir O
rehearsal O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

From O
business O
life O

Restaurant O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
Idyll O
under O
the O
chestnut O

OBERRAD B-LOC
. O

The O
year O
1708 O
is O
written O
. O

A O
year O
it O
will O
still O
take O
until O
Böttger B-PER
invents O
the O
porcelain O
. O

It O
is O
the O
age O
of O
reason O
, O
of O
enlightenment O
. O

In O
the O
small O
village O
of O
Oberrad B-LOC
, O
wealthy O
Frankfurt B-MISC
families O
buy O
an O
area O
to O
experience O
" O
alda O
those O
senses O
- O
and O
joyful O
pleasures O
" O
that O
they O
sought O
in O
vain O
in O
the O
city O
. O

On O
this O
site O
is O
created O
a O
excursion O
restaurant O
, O
the O
inn O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
. O

284 O
years O
later O
, O
the O
restaurant O
industry O
is O
still O
one O
of O
the O
popular O
destinations O
of O
the O
Ebbelweifans B-MISC
. O

Because O
there O
the O
guest O
can O
drink O
from O
11 O
to O
23 O
o'clock O
under O
the O
huge O
chestnut O
, O
protected O
by O
wine O
proliferating O
at O
the O
board O
fence O
, O
chat O
, O
and O
eat O
hearty O
meals O
: O

From O
the O
" O
Lyoner B-MISC
Zweibelschnitzel O
" O
and O
Bavarian B-MISC
Leberknödelsuppe O
over O
the O
salad O
bowl O
" O
Schlanke O
Linie O
" O
to O
the O
grilled O
pork O
shax O
and O
traditional O
" O
Green O
sauce O
" O
. O

The O
real O
" O
aalen B-MISC
Oberräder I-MISC
" O
had O
always O
had O
their O
regular O
table O
in O
the O
inn O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
. O

The O
Ebbelwei B-MISC
itself O
was O
pressed O
, O
this O
is O
still O
evidenced O
by O
an O
apparatus O
in O
the O
idyllic O
backyard O
and O
voluminous O
wine O
barrel O
. O

Even O
in O
contemplativeness O
has O
not O
changed O
much O
. O

Although O
the O
restaurant O
is O
located O
directly O
on O
the O
busy O
Offenbacher B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
, O
you O
hardly O
notice O
the O
sounds O
in O
the O
garden O
. O

The O
village O
character O
, O
the O
" O
pleasure O
delight O
" O
remained O
. O

Everyday O
life O
in O
the O
historic O
inn O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
, O
where O
on O
the O
first O
floor O
sometimes O
the O
men O
's O
singing O
club O
rehearses O
. O

Just O
a O
little O
tip O
for O
wheat O
beer O
drinkers O
: O

Whoever O
ordered O
the O
last O
round O
by O
twenty O
to O
eleven O
, O
will O
nevertheless O
be O
completed O
on O
time O
by O
eleven O
. O

After O
all O
, O
there O
is O
a O
police O
hour O
. O

So O
: O

It O
is O
recommended O
as O
a O
slumber O
drink O
then O
nevertheless O
the O
good O
, O
old O
Ebbelwei B-MISC
. O

The O
inn O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
is O
located O
in O
Offenbacher B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
289 O
and O
is O
open O
daily O
from O
11 O
to O
24 O
o'clock O
. O

The O
best O
way O
to O
get O
there O
is O
by O
tram O
( O
lines O
15 O
and O
16 O
, O
stop O
Bleiweißstraße B-LOC
) O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Education O
Advice O
Centre O
Free O
assistance O
for O
family O
problems O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
- I-LOC
NORTHWEST I-LOC
. O

The O
educational O
advisory O
service O
is O
based O
on O
its O
advisory O
services O
. O

Open O
is O
the O
point O
of O
contact O
for O
children O
, O
adolescents O
and O
adults O
. O

Whether O
problems O
with O
general O
life O
issues O
, O
anger O
in O
marriage O
, O
development O
or O
education O
problems O
, O
in O
the O
Ernst B-LOC
- I-LOC
Kahn I-LOC
- O
Straße O
49 O
a O
is O
offered O
advice O
and O
help O
. O

The O
advice O
is O
free O
of O
charge O
, O
regardless O
of O
the O
denomination O
and O
confidential O
. O

In O
urgent O
cases O
short O
- O
term O
dates O
- O
even O
in O
the O
evening O
- O
are O
awarded O
. O

Registration O
: O

Mondays O
to O
Thursdays O
from O
8 O
a.m. O
to O
5 O
p.m. O
; O
Fridays O
between O
12 O
a.m. O
and O
5 O
p.m. O
on O
telephone O
57 O
40 O
91 O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Plans O
of O
the O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
failed O
for O
the O
time O
being O
football O
association O
: O

The O
merger O
with O
Postsportverein B-ORG
" I-ORG
Blau I-ORG
- O
Yellow O
" O
is O
not O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
A. I-LOC
M. I-LOC
The O
team O
planned O
for O
months O
by O
the O
Hessian B-MISC
football O
league O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
with O
the O
Postsportverein B-ORG
( I-ORG
PSV I-ORG
) O
Blue O
- O
Yellow O
slipped O
into O
the O
district O
class O
B O
will O
not O
come O
about O
after O
all O
. O

The O
reserve O
team O
of O
the O
national O
league O
should O
kikken O
together O
with O
the O
post B-MISC
athletes I-MISC
. O

But O
the O
match O
committee O
of O
the O
Hessian B-ORG
Football I-ORG
Association I-ORG
( O
HFV B-ORG
) O
decided O
at O
its O
most O
recent O
meeting O
: O

A O
merger O
of O
reserve O
force O
and O
first O
team O
could O
not O
be O
agreed O
according O
to O
the O
statutes O
. O

As O
a O
result O
, O
the O
plans O
of O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
to O
rent O
themselves O
on O
the O
grounds O
of O
the O
PSV B-ORG
have O
failed O
. O

The O
City O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
refused O
to O
cover O
costs O
of O
68,000 O
marks O
. O

She O
is O
afraid O
of O
creating O
a O
precedent O
. O

The O
background O
: O

As O
long O
as O
the O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
can O
not O
register O
two O
complete O
youth O
teams O
for O
the O
game O
operation O
, O
also O
the O
first O
team O
may O
not O
play O
in O
the O
Landesliga O
. O

In O
the O
youth O
field O
, O
however O
, O
the O
play O
community O
with O
the O
blue B-ORG
- I-ORG
yellows I-ORG
is O
to O
come O
about O
shortly O
, O
according O
to O
the O
participants O
. O

Then O
the O
A- O
, O
B- O
and O
C O
- O
youth O
teams O
could O
train O
together O
on O
the O
post B-LOC
sports I-LOC
complex I-LOC
on O
the O
edge O
of O
the O
former O
garden B-LOC
show I-LOC
grounds I-LOC
. O

Both O
clubs O
would O
have O
preferred O
to O
see O
it O
, O
if O
even O
with O
the O
seniors O
a O
cooperation O
of O
the O
clubs O
would O
be O
possible O
. O

The O
PSV B-ORG
had O
hoped O
for O
sports O
incentives O
and O
a O
financial O
compensation O
; O
after O
all O
, O
the O
maintenance O
of O
the O
site O
costs O
more O
than O
300 O
000 O
marks O
per O
year O
. O

FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
, O
on O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
had O
a O
sports O
field O
appropriate O
to O
its O
status O
: O

Because O
he O
is O
after O
the O
Eintracht B-ORG
, O
the O
FSV B-ORG
and O
the O
Red B-ORG
- I-ORG
White I-ORG
the O
fourth O
strongest O
Frankfurt B-MISC
football O
team O
. O

The O
contract O
negotiated O
between O
PSV B-ORG
and O
Italia B-ORG
provided O
for O
rental O
payments O
of O
68 O
000 O
marks O
. O

The O
attractive O
plant O
with O
two O
lawns O
seemed O
to O
the O
Italians B-MISC
, O
compared O
to O
their O
present O
" O
home O
" O
at O
the O
SG B-ORG
Westend I-ORG
, O
to O
have O
substantial O
advantages O
. O

There O
they O
have O
to O
pay O
almost O
10 O
000 O
marks O
per O
year O
for O
the O
use O
of O
changing O
rooms O
. O

The O
hook O
in O
the O
Westend B-LOC
: O

At O
the O
SG B-ORG
, O
according O
to O
Stefan B-PER
Lottermann I-PER
, O
player O
coach O
at O
Italia B-ORG
and O
one O
of O
the O
negotiators O
, O
only O
the O
seniors O
are O
allowed O
on O
the O
field O
. O

Insider O
suspect O
, O
the O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
tries O
to O
get O
itself O
" O
cheap O
" O
through O
the O
cooperation O
with O
blue B-ORG
- I-ORG
yellow I-ORG
the O
necessary O
substructure O
in O
the O
youth O
work O
. O

Lottermann B-PER
rejected O
this O
. O

The O
city O
criticizes O
the O
action O
of O
the O
club O
. O

Sportdezernentin O
Sylvia B-PER
Schenk I-PER
reprimands O
that O
the O
contract O
had O
been O
created O
without O
agreement O
with O
the O
municipality O
, O
but O
would O
be O
at O
their O
expense O
. O

Irrespective O
of O
the O
tense O
budgetary O
situation O
, O
a O
fundamental O
question O
must O
be O
decided O
here O
: O

Where O
is O
the O
upper O
limit O
for O
the O
promotion O
of O
clubs O
without O
their O
own O
grounds O
? O

For O
Harald B-PER
Lochmann I-PER
, O
head O
of O
the O
sports O
and O
bathing O
office O
, O
the O
matter O
is O
a O
" O
precise O
case O

His O
fear O
: O

Once O
the O
city O
has O
yielded O
to O
the O
demand O
, O
report O
within O
a O
short O
time O
" O
ten O
to O
20 O
clubs O
" O
similar O
claims O
to O
. O

This O
was O
financially O
but O
not O
acceptable O
. O

Lottermann B-PER
can O
not O
agree O
to O
such O
considerations O
: O

" O
Which O
clubs O
does O
Lochmann B-PER
mean O
? O
" O

The O
constellation O
is O
unique O
. O

Never O
had O
a O
club O
rented O
at O
a O
club O
with O
its O
own O
grounds O
. O

The O
offer O
of O
the O
city O
to O
shoot O
up O
to O
18 O
000 O
marks O
, O
the O
coach O
describes O
as O
" O
laughter O
number O
" O
. O

He O
points O
out O
the O
" O
integrative O
work O
" O
that O
" O
Italia B-ORG
" O
does O
and O
recalls O
the O
sums O
spent O
on O
sports O
promotion O
in O
other O
places O
. O

Should O
the O
35,000 O
mark O
targeted O
by O
the O
FC B-ORG
not O
be O
realized O
, O
" O
I O
promise O
the O
responsible O
still O
a O
hot O
dance O
" O
, O
threatens O
Lottermann B-PER
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Opening O
hours O
of O
the O
Hanau B-MISC
museums O

Museum B-LOC
Grossauheim I-LOC
, O
Gatewingert B-LOC
4 O
, O
phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
55 O
16 O
and O
29 O
55 O
10 O
, O
open O
Thursday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
a.m. O
to O
12 O
p.m. O
and O
from O
2 O
p.m. O
to O
5 O
p.m. O

Hessisches B-LOC
Puppenmuseum I-LOC
, O
Parkpromenade B-LOC
4 O
, O
Hanau B-LOC
- I-LOC
Wilhelmsbad I-LOC
, O
telephone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
8 O
62 O
12 O
, O
open O
Tuesday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
am O
to O
12 O
pm O
and O
from O
2 O
pm O
to O
5 O
pm O
; O
entrance O
: O

Adults O
1,50 O
marks O
, O
children O
0,50 O
marks O
, O
pupils O
, O
students O
and O
disabled O
a O
mark O
. O

Deutsches B-LOC
Goldschmiedehaus I-LOC
, O
Altstädter B-LOC
Markt I-LOC
6 O
, O
telephone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
54 O
30 O
, O
open O
Tuesday O
to O
Sunday O
10 O
a.m. O
to O
12 O
p.m. O
and O
2 O
p.m. O
to O
5 O
p.m. O

Museum B-LOC
Castle I-LOC
Philippsruhe I-LOC
, O
Philippsruher B-LOC
Avenue I-LOC
45 O
, O
telephone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
55 O
16 O
and O
29 O
55 O
10 O
, O
open O
Tuesday O
to O
Sunday O
11 O
to O
18 O
hrs O
throughout O
. O

Museum B-LOC
Schloss I-LOC
Steinheim I-LOC
, O
telephone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
55 O
16 O
and O
29 O
55 O
10 O
, O
open O
Thursday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
am O
to O
12 O
pm O
and O
from O
2 O
pm O
to O
5 O
pm O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

For O
the O
time O
being O
no O
" O
guarantee O
" O
for O
a O
healthy O
baby O
For O
early O
detection O
of O
genetic O
damage O
/ O
blood O
test O
still O
too O
inaccurate O

More O
and O
more O
expectant O
mothers O
are O
taking O
advantage O
of O
the O
opportunity O
to O
detect O
possible O
genetic O
damage O
to O
the O
unborn O
prematurely O
with O
a O
test O
of O
their O
blood O
, O
the O
so O
- O
called O
triple O
diagnosis O
, O
in O
order O
to O
have O
the O
pregnancy O
stopped O
if O
necessary O
. O

The O
test O
is O
not O
yet O
part O
of O
the O
catalogue O
of O
standard B-MISC
examinations I-MISC
for O
pregnant O
women O
; O
it O
should O
not O
become O
a O
routine O
measure O
for O
the O
time O
being O
. O

This O
recommendation O
was O
given O
by O
an O
advisory O
body O
of O
the O
" O
Foundation O
for O
the O
Disabled O
Child O
" O
these O
days O
after O
a O
conference O
in O
Berlin B-LOC
. O

Renowned O
gynaecologists O
, O
obstetricians O
, O
human O
geneticists O
and O
laboratory O
diagnostics O
had O
participated O
and O
passed O
a O
number O
of O
further O
demands O
. O

As O
the O
conference O
leader O
, O
Professor O
Joachim B-PER
Wolfram I-PER
Dudenhausen I-PER
of O
the O
Rudolf B-ORG
Virchow I-ORG
Clinic I-ORG
of O
the O
Free B-ORG
University I-ORG
of O
Berlin O
, O
explained O
, O
the O
basically O
harmless O
, O
but O
costly O
test O
, O
when O
it O
provides O
evidence O
of O
genetic O
damage O
such O
as O
neural O
tube O
defects O
or O
for O
trisomies O
( O
as O
the O
formerly O
called O
down B-MISC
syndrome I-MISC
) O
, O
draws O
further O
elaborate O
and O
for O
the O
woman O
and O
the O
unborn O
not O
quite O
harmless O
investigations O
after O
itself O
, O
the O
so O
- O
called O
amniocentesis O
. O

A O
great O
many O
of O
these O
interventions O
are O
, O
according O
to O
the O
consultants O
, O
unnecessary O
and O
should O
be O
spared O
to O
pregnant O
women O
. O
