-DOCSTART- O

Event O
and O
narrative O
or O
: O

Difficulties O
in O
comprehension O
Albrecht B-PER
Lehmann I-PER
lets O
refugees O
and O
displaced O
persons O
in O
West B-LOC
Germany I-LOC
speak O
, O
1945 O
- O
1990 O

Discussions O
on O
asylum O
- O
seekers O
, O
immigrants O
and O
immigration O
issues O
have O
dominated O
politics O
and O
the O
media O
in O
Germany B-LOC
in O
recent O
months O
. O

It O
is O
therefore O
not O
difficult O
at O
the O
moment O
, O
with O
the O
publication O
of O
a O
book O
about O
refugees O
and O
displaced O
persons O
in O
West B-LOC
Germany I-LOC
from O
1945 O
to O
1990 O
, O
to O
attract O
attention O
. O

And O
indeed O
there O
are O
hardly O
any O
serious O
scientific O
discussions O
that O
have O
taken O
up O
this O
subject O
so O
far O
. O

Nevertheless O
, O
it O
is O
questionable O
whether O
such O
a O
topicality O
must O
necessarily O
lead O
to O
an O
undoubtedly O
imminent O
debate O
to O
deprive O
it O
of O
its O
true O
essence O
in O
favour O
of O
obscuring O
the O
difference O
between O
past O
and O
present O
constellations O
of O
problems O
. O

In O
his O
book B-MISC
I I-MISC
m O
Fremden O
unwillingly O
zuhaus O
, O
Albrecht O
Lehmann O
tries O
to O
adopt O
a O
neutral O
, O
free O
perspective O
from O
guilt O
assignments O
and O
innocence O
confessions O
towards O
a O
policy O
and O
its O
consequences O
, O
which O
led O
to O
the O
end O
of O
the O
Second B-MISC
World I-MISC
War I-MISC
, O
when O
twelve O
million O
people O
from O
East B-LOC
Germany I-LOC
and O
German B-MISC
settlements O
in O
Eastern B-LOC
Europe I-LOC
fled O
or O
were O
expelled O
. O

In O
what O
way O
the O
" O
refugees O
" O
- O
as O
it O
was O
called O
immediately O
after O
the O
war O
still O
with O
a O
pejorative O
side O
effect O
- O
or O
" O
displaced O
" O
- O
so O
the O
common O
name O
since O
ca O
. O

1948 O
- O
found O
in O
their O
new O
circumstances O
and O
how O
these O
experiences O
have O
been O
traditional O
over O
the O
next O
decades O
in O
the O
different O
generations O
until O
today O
, O
Lehmann B-PER
demonstrates O
by O
means O
of O
a O
series O
of O
stories O
, O
personal O
records O
, O
diary O
and O
documents O
of O
the O
distributed O
press O
. O

Today O
promoted O
is O
an O
image O
, O
which O
, O
although O
little O
surprising O
, O
but O
in O
its O
composition O
convincing O
readers O
and O
readers O
allows O
the O
refinement O
of O
a O
specific O
kind O
of O
foreign O
experience O
. O

The O
respective O
experiences O
and O
their O
coping O
are O
presented O
quite O
differently O
. O

Certain O
topics O
, O
however O
, O
appear O
again O
and O
again O
: O

Thus O
, O
the O
rape O
of O
German B-MISC
women O
by O
members O
of O
the O
Red B-ORG
Army I-ORG
led O
not O
only O
to O
irreparable O
mental O
disorders O
among O
the O
women O
themselves O
, O
but O
also O
to O
complicated O
marriage O
relationships O
, O
which O
often O
dominated O
the O
life O
of O
entire O
families O
for O
years O
after O
these O
events O
. O

The O
design O
from O
the O
old O
home O
produced O
in O
not O
few O
cases O
forms O
of O
social O
overload O
, O
which O
especially O
in O
close O
village O
communities O
caused O
difficulties O
with O
the O
old O
indigenous O
population O
. O

A O
" O
sentimental O
restraint O
" O
on O
old O
traditions O
and O
customs O
expressed O
how O
incapable O
the O
displaced O
were O
to O
forget O
the O
old O
homeland O
. O

In O
all O
the O
narratives O
it O
is O
clear O
that O
the O
pursuit O
of O
social O
harmony O
has O
been O
guiding O
for O
action O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

The O
creation O
of O
a O
new O
sense O
of O
community O
should O
compensate O
for O
the O
loss O
most O
often O
experienced O
as O
cruel O
. O

In O
addition O
to O
the O
presence O
of O
such O
typical O
difficulties O
, O
a O
strength O
of O
the O
book O
is O
to O
highlight O
the O
differences O
in O
the O
experiences O
of O
the O
different O
generations O
. O

Thus O
, O
it O
is O
plausible O
that O
the O
generation O
that O
grew O
up O
in O
the O
sixties O
and O
seventies O
wanted O
to O
have O
little O
to O
do O
with O
the O
past O
of O
their O
parents O
who O
had O
been O
expelled O
. O

A O
consciousness O
of O
the O
" O
lost O
homeland O
" O
existed O
; O
however O
, O
it O
was O
no O
longer O
sentimentally O
occupied O
. O

This O
changed O
only O
again O
in O
the O
eighties O
, O
when O
in O
Germany B-LOC
a O
renaissance O
of O
the O
concept O
of O
home O
allowed O
a O
stronger O
reference O
to O
the O
former O
German B-MISC
settlements O
again O
. O

Lehmann B-PER
will O
not O
be O
tired O
in O
describing O
and O
reproducing O
the O
stories O
of O
displaced O
persons O
, O
repeatedly O
pointing O
out O
that O
, O
despite O
radical O
prejudices O
, O
they O
do O
not O
relate O
to O
revanchism O
. O

One O
may O
believe O
the O
author O
, O
who O
understands O
his O
book O
as O
a O
contribution O
to O
the O
understanding O
of O
different O
nations O
, O
when O
he O
calls O
in O
this O
sense O
to O
understand O
the O
old O
homeland O
only O
as O
a O
" O
homeland O
in O
the O
head O
" O
. O

But O
despite O
this O
certainly O
lazy O
attitude O
and O
programming O
, O
the O
many O
reports O
and O
narratives O
leave O
a O
false O
aftertaste O
, O
which O
is O
primarily O
due O
to O
the O
methodology O
of O
German B-MISC
folklore O
. O

History O
, O
as O
written O
in O
this O
book O
, O
is O
reproduced O
primarily O
from O
the O
perspective O
of O
those O
involved O
in O
it O
. O

The O
one O
story O
breaks O
down O
into O
many O
stories O
, O
which O
in O
turn O
can O
be O
scientifically O
classified O
exactly O
according O
to O
different O
genres O
. O

For O
example O
, O
success O
stories O
, O
weaknesses O
and O
overwhelming O
stories O
are O
typical O
forms O
of O
telling O
a O
particular O
group O
who O
still O
want O
to O
forget O
their O
initial O
difficulties O
in O
the O
new O
homeland O
. O

An O
overwhelming O
form O
of O
storytelling O
is O
to O
be O
found O
, O
in O
contrast O
, O
among O
women O
who O
have O
become O
victims O
of O
rape O
. O

However O
, O
this O
scientifically O
derived O
classification O
of O
narrative O
types O
remains O
only O
external O
. O

The O
narratives O
themselves O
are O
central O
in O
the O
present O
form O
of O
presentation O
; O
a O
reflection O
on O
them O
and O
thus O
a O
possibility O
of O
evaluation O
and O
arrangement O
remains O
out O
. O

This O
circumstance O
, O
however O
, O
leads O
all O
too O
easily O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
compassionate O
comprehension O
or O
sympathetic O
identification O
with O
the O
affected O
people O
forget O
those O
constellations O
of O
history O
, O
within O
the O
framework O
of O
which O
the O
fraglos O
cruel O
individual O
events O
should O
, O
however O
, O
necessarily O
be O
presented O
. O

Thus O
it O
seems O
quite O
irritating O
, O
for O
example O
, O
when O
it O
is O
reported O
about O
the O
" O
double O
luck O
" O
of O
Anton B-PER
K. I-PER
from O
Siebenbürgen B-LOC
, O
who O
as O
a O
People B-MISC
's I-MISC
German I-MISC
was O
not O
allowed O
to O
join O
the O
Wehrmacht B-ORG
, O
but O
had O
to O
join O
the O
Waffen B-ORG
- I-ORG
SS I-ORG
; O
who O
was O
thus O
able O
to O
save O
himself O
over O
the O
years O
of O
war O
and O
at O
the O
same O
time O
remained O
free O
from O
the O
prison O
of O
war O
. O

Leading O
the O
luck O
of O
an O
Anton B-PER
K. I-PER
in O
front O
of O
your O
eyes O
, O
is O
the O
one O
side O
. O

The O
other O
must O
be O
to O
arrange O
the O
individual O
episodes O
in O
the O
history O
of O
the O
Second B-MISC
World I-MISC
War I-MISC
and O
the O
years O
thereafter O
in O
such O
a O
way O
that O
an O
objective O
perspective O
can O
be O
taken O
. O

It O
is O
a O
mistake O
to O
assume O
that O
merely O
reproducing O
authentic O
reports O
necessarily O
leads O
to O
an O
appropriate O
view O
of O
history O
. O

Rather O
, O
it O
carries O
the O
danger O
of O
a O
look O
at O
history O
that O
styles O
all O
those O
involved O
to O
their O
victims O
. O

It O
is O
undoubtedly O
necessary O
to O
also O
deal O
with O
the O
victims O
of O
history O
who O
stood O
on O
the O
perpetrator O
's O
side O
. O

In O
doing O
so O
, O
however O
, O
it O
should O
be O
wisely O
avoided O
to O
suggest O
a O
relativeization O
of O
history O
, O
which O
seeks O
to O
confuse O
all O
differences O
in O
favour O
of O
a O
" O
comprehensible O
understanding O
. O
" O

In O
this O
context O
, O
it O
is O
also O
not O
enough O
to O
issue O
programmatic O
slogans O
for O
the O
" O
reconciliation O
of O
all O
cultures O
" O
. O

Rather O
, O
this O
leads O
to O
other O
fundamental O
misunderstandings O
that O
help O
to O
obscure O
crucial O
differences O
. O

This O
confusion O
is O
most O
evident O
at O
Lehmann B-PER
's O
place O
, O
where O
he O
advocates O
a O
" O
post O
- O
national O
Europe B-LOC
" O
and O
declares O
this O
as O
a O
perspective O
that O
should O
arise O
from O
a O
non O
- O
revanchistic O
immigrant O
perspective O
, O
so O
that O
the O
German B-MISC
solution O
of O
the O
immigrant O
problem O
becomes O
an O
example O
for O
those O
questions O
and O
problems O
that O
arise O
as O
a O
result O
of O
immigration O
movements O
: O

" O
The O
theme O
of O
this O
book O
remains O
current O
: O

The O
question O
, O
how O
individuals O
and O
families O
with O
their O
children O
and O
grandchildren O
in O
our O
country O
find O
a O
new O
home O
, O
in O
which O
memories O
they O
carry O
the O
old O
home O
and O
the O
culture O
of O
the O
region O
of O
origin O
and O
tradition O
, O
how O
they O
maintain O
contact O
with O
the O
first O
home O
. O
" O

In O
the O
equation O
here O
made O
of O
the O
problems O
of O
immigrants O
and O
asylum O
seekers O
as O
well O
as O
their O
respective O
experiences O
of O
foreignness O
, O
the O
fundamental O
difference O
between O
these O
groups O
is O
brought O
to O
the O
table O
. O

After O
all O
, O
a O
post O
- O
national O
Europe B-LOC
consists O
of O
the O
coexistence O
of O
the O
most O
diverse O
ethnic O
groups O
, O
who O
have O
forcibly O
or O
deliberately O
moved O
to O
Germany B-LOC
or O
other O
countries O
of O
Europe B-LOC
. O

The O
foreign O
experience O
of O
these O
groups O
, O
however O
, O
is O
likely O
to O
be O
fundamentally O
different O
from O
that O
of O
the O
settlers O
of O
the O
1940s O
or O
that O
of O
their O
children O
decades O
later O
. O

The O
latter O
have O
proven O
to O
identify O
with O
Germany B-LOC
despite O
the O
losses O
of O
the O
" O
old O
homeland O
in O
the O
east O
, O
" O
have O
built O
up O
a O
national O
consciousness O
due O
to O
their O
ethnic O
affiliation O
. O

Such O
identification O
is O
neither O
possible O
nor O
desirable O
for O
immigrants O
. O

While O
for O
immigrants O
the O
idea O
of O
a O
homogeneous O
nation O
state O
was O
decisive O
, O
for O
asylum O
seekers O
and O
immigrants O
today O
it O
is O
the O
idea O
of O
a O
heterogeneous O
nation O
state O
. O

A O
focus O
on O
subjective O
feelings O
, O
as O
is O
done O
in O
this O
volume O
, O
should O
not O
lead O
to O
neglecting O
fundamental O
, O
objective O
differences O
. O

This O
is O
neither O
scientifically O
relevant O
nor O
helps O
the O
author O
's O
desire O
to O
" O
build O
" O
a O
Europe B-LOC
in O
which O
the O
differences O
have O
been O
overcome O
, O
without O
denying O
them O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

OFT O
IS O
the O
small O
problems O
in O
front O
of O
the O
door O
that O
cause O
the O
citizens O
of O
Frankfurt B-MISC
great O
trouble O
. O

The O
reader O
phone O
of O
the O
district B-LOC
Rundschau I-LOC
has O
repeatedly O
been O
able O
to O
help O
to O
find O
ways O
out O
of O
the O
ruins O
of O
the O
authorities O
' O
errors O
and O
to O
find O
solutions O
to O
some O
problems O
. O

Even O
if O
in O
everyday O
contradictions O
the O
rapid O
success O
did O
not O
always O
settle O
( O
persistent O
long O
- O
term O
car O
parks O
can O
just O
not O
be O
impressed O
by O
punishment O
slips O
or O
newspaper O
articles O
) O
, O
the O
direct O
wire O
into O
the O
editorial O
office O
always O
contributes O
to O
that O
, O
that O
over O
some O
seemingly O
insurmountable O
trenches O
a O
rope O
bridge O
can O
be O
stretched O
. O

The O
reader O
phone O
of O
the O
district O
- O
Rundschau O
( O
phone O
number O
21 O
99 O
- O
3 O
60 O
) O
is O
occupied O
: O

every O
Thursday O
from O
14 O
to O
17 O
o'clock O
, O
on O
Fridays O
from O
10 O
to O
13 O
o'clock O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

When O
the O
scale O
showed O
112 O
kilos O
Andrea B-PER
, O
27 O
years O
old O
: O

Frustrated O
after O
pregnancy O

She O
had O
always O
been O
overweight O
. O

The O
man O
with O
whom O
she O
has O
been O
married O
for O
ten O
years O
, O
this O
never O
made O
any O
difference O
. O

The O
marriage O
seemed O
happy O
, O
Andrea B-PER
was O
satisfied O
. O

When O
she O
was O
24 O
years O
old O
for O
the O
second O
time O
pregnant O
, O
she O
was O
delighted O
. O

She O
always O
wanted O
to O
have O
many O
children O
. O

But O
, O
after O
the O
birth O
of O
Mirjam B-PER
, O
she O
felt O
overloaded O
. O

Andrea B-PER
started O
to O
eat O
more O
and O
more O
. O

It O
was O
no O
longer O
the O
healthy O
appetite O
that O
moved O
her O
to O
the O
refrigerator O
: O

Suddenly O
she O
put O
a O
lot O
of O
food O
in O
her O
mouth O
. O

And O
at O
some O
point O
the O
scale O
shows O
112 O
kilos O
. O

Andrea B-PER
had O
become O
addicted O
, O
addicted O
to O
the O
feeling O
of O
birds O
. O

Hunger O
was O
foreign O
to O
her O
, O
her O
whole O
body O
was O
foreign O
to O
her O
at O
once O
. O

That O
she O
was O
sick O
, O
she O
did O
n't O
know O
at O
the O
time O
. O

Only O
when O
she O
read O
a O
diet O
book O
one O
day O
, O
she O
noticed O
it O
. O

A O
devout O
woman O
was O
described O
- O
and O
in O
this O
story O
Andrea B-PER
recognized O
herself O
again O
. O

At O
that O
moment O
it O
was O
clear O
to O
her O
that O
she O
had O
to O
do O
something O
about O
her O
suffering O
. O

So O
Andrea B-PER
took O
the O
initiative O
and O
applied O
to O
a O
clinic O
for O
addicts O
in O
Allgäu B-LOC
. O

A O
few O
weeks O
later O
, O
she O
left O
her O
husband O
and O
children O
for O
three O
months O
of O
therapy O
. O

The O
relatives O
warned O
her O
to O
be O
a O
rhinoceros O
mother O
. O

For O
Andrea B-PER
, O
however O
, O
it O
was O
clear O
: O

" O
I O
can O
only O
be O
a O
good O
mother O
if O
I O
'm O
doing O
well O
for O
myself O
. O
" O

When O
Andrea B-PER
presented O
herself O
on O
the O
first O
day O
in O
the O
group O
, O
she O
said O
: O

" O
My O
name O
is O
Andrea B-PER
, O
eat O
too O
much O
, O
but O
otherwise O
have O
no O
problems O
. O
" O

Everyone O
laughed O
, O
and O
soon O
she O
also O
knew O
why O
. O
" O

I O
had O
suppressed O
my O
problems O
until O
the O
therapy O
. O
" O

It O
turned O
out O
that O
Andrea B-PER
was O
not O
so O
satisfied O
with O
her O
existence O
as O
a O
young O
mother O
and O
wife O
. O

Today O
it O
is O
available O
to O
: O

" O
I O
still O
feel O
like O
I O
missed O
something O
in O
my O
youth O
. O
" O

Through O
the O
therapy O
, O
however O
, O
she O
learned O
to O
deal O
with O
her O
dissatisfaction O
, O
her O
fears O
and O
worries O
. O

If O
today O
has O
27 O
years O
of O
conflicts O
with O
her O
husband O
, O
the O
two O
talk O
about O
it O
. O

For O
example O
, O
in O
the O
marriage O
counselling O
, O
to O
which O
they O
go O
regularly O
. O

Andrea B-PER
has O
not O
yet O
been O
cured O
of O
the O
disease O
" O
Fressucht O
" O
. O

Whoever O
is O
once O
addicted O
, O
it O
will O
somehow O
always O
remain O
, O
" O
she O
says O
. O

And O
so O
she O
plans O
every O
day O
exactly O
what O
she O
will O
eat O
. O

If O
she O
does O
n't O
keep O
it O
, O
she O
gets O
angry O
. O

Normally O
dealing O
with O
food O
, O
will O
also O
remain O
a O
dream O
for O
them O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Stefan B-PER
Müller I-PER
- O
Doohm O
interdisciplinarity O
from O
the O
bottom O
up O
Against O
the O
loss O
of O
utopia O
in O
sociology O
: O

An O
incitement O
to O
unrest O
in O
the O
Elven O
Tower O

The O
sociology O
does O
not O
without O
reason O
draw O
the O
suspicion O
of O
the O
high O
stakes O
on O
itself O
. O

Because O
it O
claims O
nothing O
less O
than O
the O
whole O
of O
society O
as O
its O
specific O
subject O
area O
. O

What O
a O
miracle O
that O
the O
society O
that O
was O
so O
targeted O
reacted O
with O
mistrust O
to O
the O
acquisition O
by O
sociology O
. O

Until O
the O
Adenauer O
period O
, O
the O
publicly O
respected O
lady O
society O
felt O
most O
embarrassed O
by O
the O
approach O
of O
the O
becoming O
third O
sociology O
. O

It O
was O
not O
until O
the O
turbulent O
political O
times O
of O
the O
late O
sixties O
that O
she O
succumbed O
to O
her O
stormy O
pressures O
. O

Encouragingly O
, O
the O
society B-ORG
of I-ORG
sociology I-ORG
fell O
into O
the O
arms O
. O

This O
yes O
- O
word O
has O
led O
to O
a O
covenant O
for O
life O
, O
but O
it O
has O
become O
nothing O
more O
than O
an O
incessant O
love O
relationship O
. O

Meanwhile O
, O
the O
enthusiasm O
of O
which O
the O
expectation O
of O
this O
young O
social O
science O
at O
the O
peak O
of O
its O
academic O
spread O
was O
sustained O
. O

The O
conviction O
that O
one O
associated O
with O
that O
sophisticated O
goal O
of O
knowledge O
was O
to O
formulate O
a O
theory O
of O
society O
as O
a O
whole O
that O
should O
be O
both O
critical O
and O
practically O
transformative O
. O

Are O
we O
, O
therefore O
, O
at O
the O
end O
of O
a O
process O
in O
which O
the O
utopian O
energies O
have O
completely O
revived O
, O
which O
had O
been O
invested O
in O
the O
massive O
undertaking O
of O
a O
revolution O
of O
all O
outdated O
working O
and O
living O
conditions O
to O
be O
effected O
by O
enlightenment O
and O
criticism O
? O

If O
asked O
differently O
: O

How O
can O
we O
regain O
the O
attraction O
of O
sociology O
as O
a O
changeling O
force O
in O
reality O
, O
which O
interrupted O
it O
in O
the O
course O
of O
its O
" O
maturation O
process O
" O
to O
normal O
science O
? O

For O
the O
utopian O
loss O
of O
sociology O
there O
are O
three O
main O
reasons O
. O

On O
the O
one O
hand O
, O
it O
is O
the O
utopia O
itself O
that O
has O
become O
modest O
from O
the O
experience O
of O
the O
failure O
of O
the O
great O
visionary O
promises O
pushed O
forward O
historically O
until O
recently O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
the O
reality O
of O
the O
increasingly O
concrete O
utopian O
challenge O
has O
arisen O
through O
the O
simple O
list O
of O
the O
realization O
of O
utopian O
ideals O
. O

At O
the O
same O
time O
, O
the O
historical O
situation O
has O
assumed O
a O
gravity O
that O
allows O
any O
longing O
projection O
of O
a O
completely O
different O
one O
in O
the O
forthcoming O
morning O
merely O
as O
an O
apocalypse O
. O

The O
desire O
images O
at O
the O
origin O
of O
modernity O
have O
been O
reshaped O
in O
the O
critical O
tradition O
of O
social O
teaching O
to O
the O
concrete O
utopia O
of O
the O
real O
history O
of O
progressive O
bourgeois O
emancipation O
. O

The O
stage O
leads O
from O
the O
fictional O
future O
paintings O
of O
a O
Morus B-PER
, O
Campanella B-PER
and O
Bacon B-PER
to O
the O
technical O
and O
early O
socialist O
utopianism O
of O
an O
Owen B-PER
, O
Saint B-PER
- I-PER
Simon I-PER
, O
Fourier B-PER
and O
Proudhon B-PER
. O

Marx B-PER
polemized O
against O
these O
utopian O
socialists O
with O
all O
sharpness O
, O
who O
warned O
them O
to O
be O
mere O
dreamers O
. O

He O
himself O
, O
like O
so O
many O
, O
puts O
the O
utopia O
from O
the O
head O
to O
the O
feet O
and O
comes O
to O
the O
matter O
materialistically O
: O

In O
Communism O
utopia O
and O
reality O
merge O
, O
namely O
as O
the O
society O
of O
free O
producers O
, O
as O
material O
abundance O
and O
as O
social O
relations O
transparent O
for O
all O
members O
of O
society O
. O

However O
, O
this O
concreteization O
of O
utopia O
has O
not O
led O
to O
the O
paradise O
promised O
. O

For O
, O
as O
we O
read O
in O
Horkheimer B-LOC
's I-LOC
diary O
note O
from O
the O
fifties O
, O
the O
sky O
to O
which O
one O
can O
point O
the O
way O
is O
none O
. O

More O
information O
: O

The O
productive O
forces O
disintegrated O
as O
destructive O
forces O
, O
class O
consciousness O
became O
fossilized O
by O
the O
individualization O
of O
life O
, O
and O
revolutions O
did O
not O
prove O
to O
be O
the O
locomotive O
of O
world O
history O
. O

Rather O
, O
they O
are O
, O
in O
the O
words O
of O
Walter B-PER
Benjamin I-PER
, O
the O
grip O
of O
the O
race O
travelling O
on O
this O
train O
after O
the O
emergency O
brake O
. O

The O
shock O
of O
those O
" O
normal O
catastrophes O
" O
, O
such O
as O
the O
reactor O
accidents O
that O
endanger O
the O
survival O
of O
the O
species O
, O
has O
brought O
sociology O
out O
of O
the O
sleep O
of O
dawn O
of O
progress O
. O

This O
awakening O
finds O
its O
current O
expression O
in O
the O
burning O
term O
of O
the O
" O
risk O
society O
" O
, O
whose O
secret O
message O
of O
salvation O
consists O
in O
making O
the O
world O
course O
still O
manageable O
according O
to O
a O
self O
- O
explained O
enlightenment O
. O

This O
hope O
of O
a O
" O
reflexive O
modernisation O
" O
by O
Ulrich B-PER
Beck I-PER
is O
by O
no O
means O
new O
. O

In O
order O
to O
avoid O
the O
foreseeable O
catastrophe O
, O
already O
leading O
sociologists O
of O
the O
Weimar B-MISC
era I-MISC
such O
as O
Max B-PER
Weber I-PER
and O
Karl B-PER
Mannheim I-PER
argued O
that O
the O
reality O
was O
closer O
to O
the O
concrete O
Utopian O
. O

And O
in O
fact O
: O

The O
rule O
of O
law O
, O
democratic O
self O
- O
determination O
and O
material O
welfare O
are O
nothing O
more O
than O
an O
enchanted O
form O
of O
the O
realization O
of O
that O
utopia O
that O
has O
long O
been O
brought O
from O
heaven O
to O
earth O
: O

Everyone O
produces O
according O
to O
his O
abilities O
, O
everyone O
consumes O
according O
to O
his O
needs O
. O

This O
secularized O
ideal O
of O
the O
right O
of O
all O
to O
everything O
, O
however O
, O
is O
currently O
being O
overlooked O
by O
the O
ecologically O
- O
inspired O
" O
utopia O
of O
the O
zero O
option O
" O
equally O
utopian O
, O
more O
precisely O
: O

by O
a O
kind O
of O
general O
prohibition O
of O
overtaking O
in O
the O
wardrobes O
. O

This O
formula O
, O
with O
which O
the O
social O
scientist O
Claus B-PER
Offe I-PER
entered O
the O
exit O
from O
such O
almost O
objective O
processes O
as O
automotive O
, O
agricultural O
chemistry O
, O
cabling O
etc O
. O

To O
make O
tasty O
, O
however O
, O
is O
not O
much O
more O
than O
a O
residual O
hope O
to O
avoid O
the O
continuing O
disaster O
resulting O
from O
a O
generalization O
of O
the O
principle O
of O
" O
free O
travel O
for O
free O
citizens O
" O
through O
inconvenience O
and O
stagnation O
. O

Does O
this O
utopia O
of O
voluntary O
on O
- O
the O
- O
ground O
walking O
not O
run O
the O
risk O
of O
succumbing O
to O
the O
temptation O
of O
the O
omnipotence O
of O
the O
contemporary O
? O

By O
relaxing O
the O
critical O
power O
of O
utopian O
thought O
in O
enlightenment O
science O
, O
the O
dimension O
of O
historical O
sense O
- O
making O
in O
the O
horizon O
of O
historical O
objective O
perspectives O
is O
diminished O
in O
the O
social O
self O
- O
thematization O
. O

This O
vacuum O
is O
not O
only O
a O
breeding O
ground O
for O
ideologies O
such O
as O
the O
posthistoric O
one O
, O
but O
this O
utopianism O
also O
promotes O
the O
fixation O
on O
alternative O
programs O
such O
as O
fundamentalism O
, O
regionalism O
, O
and O
feminism O
. O

There O
is O
a O
lack O
of O
memory O
of O
what O
is O
unspoken O
in O
utopian O
thinking O
, O
there O
is O
a O
lack O
of O
that O
utopian O
forward O
- O
thinking O
that O
strikes O
the O
spark O
that O
can O
light O
the O
light O
that O
accompanies O
the O
idea O
of O
a O
better O
society O
. O

Contrary O
to O
the O
risks O
of O
a O
risk O
society O
, O
a O
disciplined O
, O
organized O
scientific O
enterprise O
is O
objectively O
overwhelmed O
. O

For O
the O
growing O
destructive O
potentials O
in O
nature O
and O
society O
generated O
by O
the O
individual O
sciences O
themselves O
have O
their O
reason O
not O
least O
also O
in O
that O
the O
subjects O
are O
merely O
navel O
- O
gazing O
and O
at O
the O
same O
time O
remain O
in O
their O
ivory O
towers O
. O

In O
this O
compulsory O
multi O
- O
disciplinary O
cooperation O
between O
the O
natural O
sciences O
, O
the O
humanities O
and O
the O
social O
sciences O
, O
science O
assumes O
a O
special O
responsibility O
from O
society O
due O
to O
its O
object O
- O
relatedness O
to O
the O
totality O
of O
social O
science O
. O

First O
of O
all O
, O
sociology O
has O
the O
self O
- O
critical O
task O
of O
returning O
to O
its O
own O
home O
and O
acting O
contagious O
through O
this O
exemplaryness O
. O

Only O
as O
a O
" O
house O
of O
open O
doors O
" O
with O
internal O
plurality O
it O
allows O
a O
process O
of O
combining O
diverse O
methods O
and O
theories O
. O

The O
cognitive O
identity O
of O
sociology O
is O
not O
in O
any O
way O
jeopardized O
by O
this O
openness O
, O
as O
the O
discipline O
has O
stabilized O
organizationally O
and O
its O
academic O
reputation O
seems O
to O
be O
secured O
. O

Its O
status O
as O
a O
science O
of O
interpretation O
requires O
the O
practice O
of O
extreme O
tolerance O
towards O
competing O
paradigms O
, O
different O
methodical O
approaches O
and O
the O
divergent O
interpretation O
of O
social O
facts O
. O

Because O
social O
analyses O
can O
not O
operate O
with O
an O
objectiveistic O
claim O
to O
knowledge O
. O

Rather O
, O
societal O
theory O
is O
convinced O
by O
the O
formation O
of O
argumentation O
, O
that O
is O
, O
by O
empirical O
acuity O
and O
interpretative O
plausibility O
. O

For O
this O
reason O
, O
the O
future O
of O
sociology O
lies O
in O
establishing O
a O
unity O
of O
originally O
divergent O
traditions O
: O

the O
empirical O
method O
of O
knowledge O
on O
the O
one O
hand O
and O
the O
humanistic O
hermeneutics O
on O
the O
other O
. O

This O
principle O
of O
tolerance O
at O
home O
implies O
, O
moreover O
, O
a O
direct O
connection O
to O
the O
houses O
of O
the O
same O
street O
, O
that O
is O
, O
the O
strict O
cooperation O
of O
sociology O
with O
other O
social O
sciences O
, O
if O
it O
does O
not O
wish O
to O
give O
up O
its O
great O
aim O
of O
knowledge O
, O
which O
Horkheimer O
believes O
consists O
in O
formulating O
a O
theory O
of O
the O
historical O
course O
of O
the O
epoch O
. O

This O
gigantic O
research O
program O
is O
only O
feasible O
if O
sociology O
becomes O
the O
carrier O
of O
a O
communication O
between O
the O
fields O
of O
history O
, O
economics O
, O
anthropology O
, O
ethnology O
and O
psychology O
, O
among O
others O
, O
which O
jointly O
engage O
in O
a O
philosophical O
fundamental O
reflection O
, O
are O
ready O
for O
a O
continuous O
exchange O
of O
individual O
scientific O
advances O
and O
link O
the O
empirical O
research O
efforts O
systematically O
with O
theory O
formation O
. O

This O
orientation O
of O
the O
social O
sciences O
towards O
a O
historically O
and O
empirically O
sustained O
theory O
of O
social O
science O
to O
be O
developed O
through O
research O
cooperation O
is O
only O
a O
first O
step O
. O

A O
second O
must O
follow O
. O

For O
the O
increasingly O
specialized O
social O
sciences O
the O
subject O
of O
their O
research O
efforts O
breaks O
down O
not O
only O
between O
the O
fingers O
, O
but O
the O
meaning O
of O
their O
teaching O
and O
research O
is O
limited O
to O
the O
workload O
of O
the O
shoemaker O
, O
who O
stays O
at O
his O
leash O
, O
may O
the O
water O
even O
stand O
to O
his O
neck O
. O

In O
contrast O
, O
the O
future O
perspective O
of O
the O
humanities O
and O
social O
sciences O
lies O
in O
the O
emerging O
coalition O
of O
the O
humanities O
. O

According O
to O
the O
American B-MISC
historian O
Robert B-PER
Darnton I-PER
, O
a O
novel O
faculty O
configuration O
, O
which O
in O
consequence O
includes O
a O
dissolution O
of O
traditional O
faculties O
and O
departments O
, O
leads O
to O
an O
innovation O
spurt O
: O

The O
one O
- O
dimensionality O
of O
cause O
and O
event O
research O
is O
overcome O
in O
favour O
of O
a O
realistic O
understanding O
of O
the O
symbolic O
cultural O
system O
as O
the O
common O
reference O
point O
of O
the O
humanities O
. O

Let O
us O
take O
together O
: O

Sociology O
must O
firstly O
recognize O
the O
status O
of O
an O
empirical O
, O
comprehensible O
and O
critical O
social O
science O
, O
not O
only O
for O
itself O
, O
but O
also O
to O
exploit O
its O
character O
as O
a O
multi O
- O
paradigm O
science O
productively O
for O
itself O
. O

Secondly O
, O
the O
project O
requires O
a O
restructured O
societal O
theory O
of O
interdisciplinary O
cooperation O
among O
the O
various O
social O
sciences O
. O

Finally O
, O
thirdly O
, O
the O
science O
of O
society O
, O
due O
to O
its O
perspective O
on O
the O
whole O
of O
human O
life O
, O
is O
best O
suited O
to O
demonstrate O
a O
general O
interest O
of O
humanity O
in O
the O
dangerous O
work O
of O
the O
self O
- O
perpetuating O
sorcerer O
teachers O
of O
the O
technical O
- O
scientific O
civilization O
, O
the O
independent O
individual O
sciences O
with O
their O
particularistic O
rationalities O
. O

The O
present O
task O
of O
sociology O
is O
to O
bring O
the O
sciences O
, O
whose O
differentiation O
is O
irreversible O
, O
to O
the O
common O
denominator O
of O
a O
multi O
- O
disciplinary O
discourse O
, O
which O
seeks O
to O
solve O
a O
binding O
question O
for O
all O
: O

how O
to O
prevent O
the O
disaster O
. O

The O
processing O
of O
this O
existential O
question O
certainly O
does O
not O
succeed O
as O
the O
genius O
of O
a O
researcher O
or O
a O
discipline O
, O
but O
is O
only O
conceivable O
as O
a O
joint O
work O
of O
all O
sciences O
. O

In O
view O
of O
this O
, O
the O
science O
of O
enlightenment O
is O
quite O
the O
protagonist O
of O
a O
utopian O
program O
: O

the O
overcoming O
of O
discipline O
boundaries O
. O

The O
indifference O
of O
university O
sciences O
to O
each O
other O
is O
scientifically O
irresponsible O
in O
view O
of O
the O
world O
's O
dangers O
and O
their O
complex O
interdependencies O
and O
is O
as O
outdated O
as O
the O
idea O
of O
unity O
science O
. O

The O
melody O
" O
If O
everyone O
does O
his O
own O
, O
the O
whole O
thing O
will O
already O
succeed O
" O
is O
an O
extremely O
dangerous O
punchline O
. O

From O
the O
sleep O
of O
reason O
awakens O
an O
" O
interdisciplinarity O
from O
below O
" O
, O
which O
Jürgen B-PER
Mittelstraß I-PER
describes O
as O
cross O
- O
thinking O
, O
as O
questions O
where O
no O
one O
has O
asked O
yet O
, O
as O
learning O
what O
the O
own O
discipline O
does O
not O
yet O
know O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

" O
Often O
a O
dominant O
mother O
" O
FR B-MISC
- I-MISC
talk I-MISC
with O
the O
psychotherapist O
Arthur B-PER
Cooper I-PER

WETTERAUKREIS B-LOC
. O

For O
therapists O
eating O
disorders O
are O
often O
still O
a O
mystery O
. O

Your O
patients O
have O
a O
addiction O
that O
is O
solely O
mentally O
conditioned O
. O

A O
healing O
method O
that O
would O
exclude O
a O
relapse O
, O
there O
is O
no O
. O

There O
it O
is O
all O
the O
more O
terrifying O
that O
more O
and O
more O
people O
, O
especially O
women O
, O
suffer O
from O
bulimia O
, O
hunger O
or O
thirst O
. O

FR B-MISC
employee I-MISC
Daniela B-PER
Saur I-PER
spoke O
with O
the O
psychotherapist O
Arthur B-PER
Cooper I-PER
about O
the O
diseases O
. O

The O
topic O
of O
eating O
disorders O
he O
considers O
to O
be O
one O
of O
the O
" O
most O
exciting O
" O
in O
psychotherapy O
. O

FR B-ORG
: O

Mr O
Cooper B-PER
, O
you O
said O
that O
they O
particularly O
like O
working O
with O
people O
who O
have O
a O
disturbed O
behavior O
to O
eat O
. O

Why O
? O

Cooper B-PER
: O

The O
increase O
in O
addictions O
, O
especially O
those O
of O
bulimia O
, O
hunger O
and O
thirst O
, O
reflect O
our O
broken O
society O
. O

It O
shows O
that O
we O
are O
no O
longer O
able O
to O
take O
healthy O
measures O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Where O
to O
find O
help O
without O
advice O

Many O
distressed O
people O
feel O
alone O
with O
their O
suffering O
. O

But O
that O
does O
not O
have O
to O
be O
the O
case O
. O

Also O
in O
the O
weather B-LOC
circle I-LOC
and O
surroundings O
there O
are O
points O
of O
contact O
: O

Nida B-LOC
Valley I-LOC
: O

Self O
- O
help O
group O
to O
cope O
with O
eating O
disorders O
, O
meeting O
every O
Tuesday O
from O
20 O
o'clock O
in O
the O
rooms O
of O
the O
civic O
activity O
in O
Kaichen B-LOC
. O

Nida B-LOC
: O

Self O
- O
help O
group O
of O
the O
women O
's O
emergency O
call O
in O
Borsdorf B-LOC
, O
meeting O
every O
Friday O
from O
19:30 O
in O
Weiherstraße B-LOC
12 O
( O
Tel O
. O

0 O
60 O
43 O
/ O
44 O
71 O
) O
. O

Karben B-LOC
: O

Meetings O
every O
Thursday O
from O
17 O
to O
19 O
and O
from O
20 O
to O
22.30 O
in O
the O
Catholic O
Community O
Centre O
St. B-LOC
Bonifatius I-LOC
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Social O
market O
economy O

In O
the O
face O
of O
rising O
debts O
, O
Federal O
Chancellor O
Kohl B-PER
is O
appealing O
to O
a O
public O
that O
still O
remembers O
that O
after O
the O
unification O
no O
one O
will O
go O
any O
worse O
than O
before O
. O

The O
slogan O
" O
Keep O
the O
measure O
! O
" O

It O
was O
not O
until O
then O
that O
Ludwig B-PER
Erhard I-PER
, O
who O
had O
already O
spent O
decades O
before O
, O
spent O
the O
Chancellor O
's O
office O
on O
the O
economic O
downturn O
in O
the O
previously O
prosperous O
economy O
, O
not O
least O
because O
it O
was O
perceived O
to O
be O
a O
serious O
one O
. O

The O
foundations O
of O
Erhard B-PER
's I-PER
" O
Social B-MISC
Market I-MISC
Economy I-MISC
" O
had O
been O
developed O
by O
Walter B-PER
Eucken I-PER
in O
addition O
to O
other O
economists O
of O
the O
" O
Fryburg O
School O
" O
. O

The O
new O
model O
of O
order O
was O
developed O
mainly O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
analyses O
of O
the O
" O
central O
administrative O
economy O
" O
. O

Eucken B-PER
's I-PER
research O
illustrates O
that O
planning O
and O
market O
economy O
are O
each O
complex O
systems O
, O
whose O
different O
functional O
mechanisms O
can O
not O
be O
arbitrarily O
exchanged O
among O
themselves O
. O

One O
proof O
of O
this O
is O
not O
only O
the O
failure O
of O
all O
previous O
attempts O
of O
a O
" O
Third O
Way O
" O
, O
but O
also O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
transformation O
of O
the O
GDR B-MISC
economy I-MISC
. O

Thus O
, O
the O
private O
" O
black O
markets O
" O
that O
also O
exist O
in O
planning O
economies O
supplement O
the O
central O
allocation O
system O
of O
planning O
bureaucracies O
. O

Under O
the O
conditions O
of O
free O
exchange O
relations O
, O
however O
, O
they O
are O
superfluous O
, O
but O
can O
, O
since O
they O
originate O
from O
a O
particular O
special O
situation O
, O
not O
irrevocably O
transferred O
to O
" O
normal O
" O
markets O
. O

The O
same O
applies O
to O
the O
exchange O
of O
goods O
with O
other O
state O
trading O
countries O
. O

As O
soon O
as O
the O
free O
movement O
of O
goods O
is O
possible O
, O
such O
a O
" O
rational O
choice O
" O
replaces O
the O
previously O
prescribed O
trade O
relations O
. O

The O
establishment O
of O
the O
order O
model O
of O
the O
" O
Fryburg B-ORG
School I-ORG
" O
is O
, O
also O
this O
is O
clearly O
stated O
in O
Eucken B-PER
's I-PER
principles O
, O
in O
fact O
dependent O
on O
a O
social O
" O
natural O
state O
" O
. O

Even O
the O
demand O
for O
the O
necessary O
dissolution O
of O
power O
groups O
is O
practically O
impossible O
in O
today O
's O
Federal O
Republic B-LOC
; O
at O
least O
as O
long O
as O
, O
as O
is O
rightly O
assumed O
, O
the O
accusation O
of O
" O
group O
anarchy O
" O
is O
first O
directed O
at O
workers O
and O
trade O
unions O
. O

Indeed O
, O
income O
adjustments O
to O
rising O
costs O
often O
still O
have O
to O
be O
fought O
, O
even O
though O
the O
share O
of O
wage O
costs O
in O
value O
creation O
is O
now O
only O
20 O
% O
on O
average O
. O

Nevertheless O
: O

Nevertheless O
, O
it O
is O
not O
that O
the O
complexity O
of O
modern O
societies O
seems O
to O
overwhelm O
the O
order O
model O
of O
the O
" O
social O
market O
economy O
" O
. O

Its O
purpose O
was O
precisely O
to O
reduce O
complexity O
through O
framework O
rules O
for O
private O
self O
- O
control O
- O
other O
models O
we O
do O
not O
have O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

In O
reality O
, O
Empress O
Agnes B-PER
wore O
the O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
jewellery I-MISC
" O
The O
long O
- O
running O
puzzle O
about O
the O
jewels O
of O
a O
Salier O
emperor O
has O
now O
been O
solved O
/ O
A O
dramatic O
discovery O
in O
the O
Mainz B-MISC
Jewish B-MISC
Ghetto I-MISC

Few O
archaeological O
finds O
from O
the O
Middle O
Ages O
have O
gained O
such O
a O
popularity O
as O
an O
eagle O
- O
fowl B-MISC
fable I-MISC
from O
a O
treasure O
of O
25 O
golden O
jewels O
, O
which O
was O
accidentally O
found O
in O
1880 O
during O
sewerage O
work O
from O
the O
basement O
of O
a O
burned O
house O
in O
the O
former O
" O
Judengasse B-LOC
" O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
and O
only O
after O
adventurous O
walks O
can O
now O
be O
shown O
in O
museum O
windows O
. O

It O
is O
regarded O
to O
this O
day O
as O
the O
largest O
and O
most O
significant O
discovery O
of O
its O
kind O
. O

In O
addition O
to O
four O
half O
- O
moon O
rings O
, O
nine O
finger O
rings O
, O
a O
breastplate O
( O
loros O
) O
and O
a O
jeweled O
crown O
( O
maniakion O
) O
- O
both O
reproductions O
of O
Byzantine B-MISC
emperor O
insignia O
- O
was O
especially O
noticed O
under O
eight O
bubble O
, O
cone O
and O
disk O
fibulas O
an O
exceptionally O
precious O
with O
an O
eagle O
- O
fowl B-MISC
motif I-MISC
, O
as O
it O
could O
have O
decorated O
only O
a O
queen O
. O

To O
this O
view O
came O
the O
historian O
Otto B-PER
von I-PER
Falke I-PER
1913 O
in O
his O
book O
with O
the O
first O
publication O
of O
the O
jewelry O
stock O
. O

He O
wrote O
it O
as O
a O
symbol O
of O
the O
sovereignty O
of O
Empress O
Gisela B-PER
, O
wife O
of O
Konrad B-PER
II I-PER
, O
German B-MISC
king O
( O
1024 O
- O
1039 O
) O
and O
emperor O
( O
from O
1027 O
) O
of O
the O
Salier O
family O
. O

Under O
the O
name O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
- I-MISC
Fibel I-MISC
" O
she O
has O
become O
known O
and O
famous O
. O

This O
date O
has O
been O
actively O
discussed O
at O
the O
time O
, O
but O
never O
refuted O
, O
until O
the O
Oberkonservatorin O
at O
the O
Roman O
- O
German B-LOC
Central I-LOC
Museum I-LOC
in O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
Dr. O
Mechthild B-PER
Schulze I-PER
- O
Dörrlamm O
, O
encouraged O
by O
the O
years O
of O
preparations O
for O
the O
SalierAusstellung O
in O
Speyer B-LOC
now O
presents O
a O
generation O
younger O
Empress O
as O
the O
owner O
of O
this O
special O
jewellery O
: O

Agnes B-PER
of I-PER
Poitou I-PER
, O
1043 O
intermarried O
with O
Emperor O
Henry B-PER
III I-PER
in O
Ingelheim B-LOC
and O
crowned O
Empress O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
the O
" O
steadfast O
capital O
of O
the O
Reich O
" O
. O

The O
now O
investigated O
ancestry O
of O
the O
jewellery O
is O
based O
on O
new O
, O
well O
- O
dataable O
archaeological O
findings O
and O
comparative O
studies O
with O
Byzantine B-MISC
and O
Fatimid B-MISC
jewellery O
and O
ornamental O
elements O
of O
the O
time O
in O
question O
, O
as O
she O
conducts O
Mechthild B-PER
Schulze I-PER
- O
Dörrlamm O
in O
her O
book O
" O
The O
Mainz B-MISC
treasure O
of O
Empress O
Agnes B-PER
from O
the O
middle O
11th O
century O
- O
New O
investigations O
into O
the O
so O
- O
called O
, O
Gisela B-MISC
jewellery I-MISC
' O
" O
( O
Jan B-ORG
- I-ORG
Thorbecke I-ORG
- O
Verlag O
, O
Sigmaringen B-MISC
1991 O
) O
. O

The O
round O
, O
gold O
- O
plated O
AdlerPfauen B-MISC
- I-MISC
Fibel I-MISC
is O
the O
only O
piece O
that O
was O
acquired O
in O
1880 O
shortly O
after O
the O
discovery O
of O
the O
jewellery O
by O
the O
Mainz B-MISC
Museum B-LOC
of I-LOC
Antiquity I-LOC
and O
has O
been O
preserved O
there O
ever O
since O
. O

All O
other O
jewellery O
items O
are O
now O
in O
the O
Kunstgewerbemuseum B-LOC
Berlin I-LOC
after O
many O
turbulent O
years O
. O

The O
construction O
workers O
had O
in O
fact O
1880 O
their O
find O
first O
concealed O
, O
then O
the O
jewellery O
divided O
among O
themselves O
and O
sold O
piece O
by O
piece O
. O

Over O
the O
next O
few O
decades O
, O
the O
jewellery O
appeared O
in O
a O
variety O
of O
locations O
and O
in O
a O
variety O
of O
owners O
. O

Some O
parts O
were O
thought O
to O
have O
disappeared O
altogether O
in O
the O
meantime O
, O
while O
others O
were O
severely O
damaged O
in O
World O
War B-MISC
II I-MISC
. O

The O
Adler B-MISC
- I-MISC
Pfauen I-MISC
- O
Fibel O
is O
the O
prototype O
of O
a O
fictional O
form B-MISC
, O
of O
which O
so O
far O
only O
three O
specimens O
are O
known O
, O
which O
, O
as O
the O
Oberkonservatorin O
reports O
, O
in O
addition O
all O
come O
from O
Mainz B-LOC
. O

A O
common O
characteristic O
of O
these O
three O
disc O
beetles O
is O
that O
the O
eagle O
is O
depicted O
with O
a O
peacock O
crown O
made O
of O
extended O
wings O
. O

This O
mixture O
of O
eagle O
and O
peacock O
is O
based O
on O
a O
deeply O
Christian O
meaning O
: O

The O
eagle O
symbolizes O
the O
resurrection O
and O
ascension O
of O
Christ B-PER
, O
the O
dove O
eternal O
life O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
this O
crowned O
bird O
was O
also O
regarded O
as O
an O
imperial O
symbol O
of O
sovereignty O
and O
a O
predecessor O
of O
the O
Prussian O
Reichsadler B-MISC
is O
also O
an O
indication O
of O
the O
temporal O
arrangement O
. O

His O
body O
form O
in O
frontal O
view O
, O
only O
the O
head O
in O
profile O
, O
obviously O
goes O
back O
to O
Islamic O
art O
in O
the O
10th O
century O
. O

Stylistically O
considered O
, O
the O
most O
beautiful O
and O
" O
qualityful O
" O
of O
the O
three O
eagle O
bees O
has O
new O
dimensions O
. O

Instead O
of O
the O
former O
usually O
broad O
- O
straight O
framed O
small O
center O
, O
the O
dominant O
large O
motif O
is O
now O
surrounded O
by O
a O
narrow O
edge O
. O

Another O
clue O
to O
the O
dating O
of O
these O
broken O
- O
worked O
e O
- O
mail O
beads O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
11th O
century O
are O
small O
gold O
wire O
flower O
stalks O
at O
the O
roundings O
and O
pearl O
wire O
lines O
at O
the O
ends O
of O
the O
peacock O
's O
wheel O
. O

Where O
and O
by O
whom O
the O
precious O
jewellery O
was O
made O
, O
can O
only O
be O
presumed O
. O

Some O
of O
it O
refers O
to O
Byzantine B-MISC
or O
Italian B-MISC
goldsmiths O
, O
who O
may O
have O
migrated O
to O
Mainz B-LOC
at O
that O
time O
or O
were O
already O
in O
Mainz O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

Mainz B-LOC
, O
in O
the O
high O
Middle O
Ages O
called O
" O
Diadem B-MISC
of I-MISC
the O
Reich O
" O
, O
was O
in O
the O
Salier B-MISC
period I-MISC
the O
city O
with O
the O
most O
royal O
residences O
and O
owned O
jewellery O
workshops O
of O
supraregional O
significance O
, O
whose O
traces O
can O
still O
be O
traced O
today O
on O
the O
old O
Rhine O
shore O
by O
lead O
waste O
, O
raw O
cuts O
and O
semi O
- O
finished O
products O
. O

Since O
the O
majority O
of O
the O
jewellery O
comes O
from O
the O
middle O
third O
of O
the O
11th O
century O
, O
it O
will O
be O
best O
to O
attribute O
it O
to O
Agnes B-PER
of I-PER
Poitou I-PER
, O
Mechthild B-PER
Schulze I-PER
- O
Dörlamm O
says O
, O
especially O
among O
them O
a O
golden O
ring O
with O
the O
image O
of O
her O
husband O
, O
Emperor O
Heinrich B-PER
III I-PER
. O
, O
is O
preserved O
. O

With O
the O
gift O
certificates O
issued O
immediately O
after O
the O
wedding O
about O
extensive O
lands O
and O
possessions O
Heinrich B-PER
III I-PER
made O
her O
one O
of O
the O
richest O
equipped O
queens O
in O
the O
history O
of O
the O
medieval O
empire O
; O
whether O
as O
an O
expression O
of O
his O
affection O
or O
foreseeable O
independent O
provision O
for O
a O
" O
foreign O
" O
ruler O
, O
is O
not O
passed O
on O
. O

It O
is O
unlikely O
that O
the O
empress O
would O
later O
have O
handed O
over O
all O
her O
jewellery O
to O
a O
Jewish O
merchant O
. O

It O
would O
be O
conceivable O
that O
Agnes B-PER
as O
throne O
regent O
1066 O
- O
on O
the O
occasion O
of O
the O
wedding O
of O
her O
barely O
16 O
year O
old O
son O
and O
throne O
successor O
, O
Henry B-PER
IV I-PER
, O
with O
the O
barely O
a O
year O
younger O
Bertha B-PER
of I-PER
Turin I-PER
- O
her O
daughter O
- O
in O
- O
law O
officially O
handed O
over O
the O
jewellery O
as O
a O
gift O
. O

Bertha B-PER
was O
already O
almost O
part O
of O
the O
family O
, O
as O
she O
had O
previously O
renounced O
the O
throne O
as O
a O
young O
girl O
and O
had O
retired O
to O
an O
Italian B-MISC
monastery O
, O
where O
she O
no O
longer O
needed O
the O
representative O
jewellery O
. O

When O
Empress O
Bertha B-PER
now O
died O
in O
1087 O
in O
Mainz B-LOC
, O
at O
a O
time O
when O
Henry B-PER
IV I-PER
, O
equipped O
his O
third O
Rome O
campaign O
and O
had O
to O
fight O
again O
with O
financial O
difficulties O
because O
of O
his O
numerous O
campaigns O
, O
it O
might O
have O
been O
possible O
that O
under O
these O
circumstances O
he O
had O
offered O
the O
jewellery O
of O
his O
deceased O
wife O
to O
a O
reliable O
, O
wealthy O
Jew O
. O

But O
when O
Heinrich B-PER
returned O
to O
Mainz B-LOC
ten O
years O
later O
, O
there O
was O
no O
trace O
of O
the O
jewellery O
. O

For O
a O
year O
earlier O
in O
the O
Jewish B-LOC
quarter I-LOC
almost O
all O
the O
inhabitants O
had O
been O
killed O
by O
a O
pogrom O
of O
the O
Crusaders O
, O
including O
- O
as O
is O
surviving O
- O
the O
synagogue O
chief O
, O
who O
two O
days O
after O
his O
forced O
evacuation B-LOC
lit O
up O
synagogue O
and O
house O
and O
burned O
himself O
there O
with O
his O
whole O
family O
. O

Old O
fire O
traces O
are O
said O
to O
have O
been O
still O
visible O
in O
the O
surprising O
discovery O
of O
the O
jewellery O
after O
800 O
years O
. O

Although O
the O
history O
of O
this O
gold O
jewellery O
leaves O
some O
questions O
open O
, O
however O
, O
the O
individual O
pieces O
possess O
a O
special O
cultural O
historical O
value O
and O
convey O
within O
the O
framework O
of O
the O
newly O
acquired O
insights O
a O
vivid O
picture O
of O
medieval O
splendor O
development O
at O
the O
imperial O
court O
- O
but O
above O
all O
of O
a O
Salin O
emperor O
, O
who O
has O
now O
really O
carried O
the O
famous O
" O
Gisela B-MISC
- I-MISC
Fibel I-MISC
" O
: O

Agnes B-PER
of I-PER
Poitou I-PER
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Medical O
doctors O

Emergency O
services O
: O

DRK B-LOC
- I-LOC
Haus I-LOC
, O
Flat B-LOC
Road I-LOC
1 O
, O
Tel O
. O

46 O
10 O
10 O
; O
fixed O
emergency O
call O
hours O
: O

11 O
a.m. O
to O
1 O
p.m. O
and O
3 O
p.m. O
to O
6 O
p.m. O

-DOCSTART- O

Pharmacies O

Sa O
. O
: O

Pharmacy B-LOC
on I-LOC
the O
market O
, O
Marketstr B-LOC
. O
12 O
, O
Tel O
. O

30 O
65 O
09 O
. O

Kohlheck B-LOC
- I-LOC
Apotheke I-LOC
, O
Eulenstr B-LOC
. O
5 O
, O
Tel O
. O

46 O
65 O
15 O
. O

Merian B-LOC
- I-LOC
Apotheke I-LOC
, O
Kaiser B-LOC
- I-LOC
Friedrich I-LOC
- O
Ring O
30 O
, O
Tel O
. O

30 O
64 O
91 O
. O

So O
. O
: O

Elephant B-LOC
pharmacy I-LOC
, O
church B-LOC
street I-LOC
18 O
, O
Tel O
. O

30 O
33 O
48 O
. O

Paracelsus B-LOC
- I-LOC
Apotheke I-LOC
, O
Schultheißstr B-LOC
. O
32 O
a O
, O
Bierstadt B-LOC
, O
Tel O
. O

50 O
27 O
25 O
. O

Sun B-LOC
- I-LOC
Apotheke I-LOC
, O
Brunhildenstr B-LOC
. O
25 O
, O
Tel O
. O

76 O
15 O
92 O
. O

Ophthalmologists O

J. B-PER
Litsch I-PER
, O
Mainzer B-LOC
Str I-LOC
. O
36 O
, O
Wiesbaden B-LOC
, O
Tel O
. O

06 O
11 O
/ O
30 O
34 O
45 O
( O
Practice O
) O
or O
06 O
11 O
/ O
80 O
99 O
11 O
( O
Apartment O
) O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

A O
new O
prize O
for O
women O
's O
political O
commitment O
City O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
awards O
" O
Tony B-MISC
- I-MISC
Sender I-MISC
" O
- O
award O
for O
the O
first O
time O
in O
autumn O
1992 O
/ O
Local O
reference O
is O
in O
demand O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
A. I-LOC
M. I-LOC
As O
the O
first O
German B-MISC
city O
Frankfurt B-LOC
am I-LOC
Main I-LOC
a O
prize O
for O
women O
's O
political O
commitment O
or O
work O
of O
women O
's O
research O
with O
local O
relevance O
. O

With O
the O
newly O
created O
Tony B-MISC
- I-MISC
Sender I-MISC
- O
Preis O
, O
the O
City O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
wants O
to O
distinguish O
outstanding O
innovative O
achievements O
from O
the O
acquisition O
field O
and O
works O
that O
deal O
with O
cultural O
or O
social O
themes O
. O

Worthy O
of O
mention O
are O
Frankfurt B-MISC
women I-MISC
, O
women O
's O
projects O
of O
this O
city O
or O
women O
dedicated O
to O
a O
Frankfurt B-MISC
topic O
. O

The O
Tony O
- O
Sender B-MISC
Prize I-MISC
is O
awarded O
with O
20,000 O
marks O
and O
is O
first O
presented O
on O
November O
27 O
, O
1992 O
, O
followed O
by O
a O
two O
- O
year O
rhythm O
. O

With O
the O
Tony B-MISC
Sender I-MISC
Prize I-MISC
, O
the O
Women O
's O
Council O
would O
also O
like O
to O
draw O
attention O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
more O
than O
40 O
years O
after O
the O
entry O
into O
force O
of O
the O
Federal B-LOC
Constitution O
, O
Article O
3(2 O
) O
of O
the O
Basic O
Law O
- O
" O
Men O
and O
women O
are O
equally O
entitled O
" O
- O
is O
still O
being O
violated O
. O

Women O
continue O
to O
face O
inequalities O
in O
many O
areas O
of O
daily O
life O
. O

Who O
was O
the O
woman O
whose O
name O
the O
prize O
will O
again O
make O
known O
beyond O
the O
borders O
of O
the O
city O
? O

Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
was O
born O
in O
1888 O
in O
today O
's O
Wiesbaden B-MISC
district O
of O
Biebrich B-LOC
as O
the O
daughter O
of O
well O
- O
situated O
parents O
. O

According O
to O
the O
Fin O
de O
siècle O
and O
her O
social O
history O
, O
she O
had O
before O
her O
a O
life O
as O
a O
cared O
- O
for O
daughter O
and O
a O
teaching O
in O
the O
" O
Salon O
Sciences O
" O
in O
order O
to O
take O
her O
intended O
place O
in O
the O
bourgeois O
society O
as O
a O
wife O
and O
mother O
. O

But O
already O
at O
the O
Higher O
Daughter O
School O
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
became O
aware O
that O
she O
did O
not O
want O
to O
be O
limited O
to O
" O
children O
, O
kitchen O
, O
church O
" O
. O

The O
struggle O
for O
more O
freedom O
should O
not O
stop O
during O
her O
lifetime O
. O

Instead O
of O
working O
on O
her O
tax O
return O
, O
she O
went O
to O
a O
business O
school O
and O
secured O
her O
independence O
as O
a O
merchant O
employee O
. O

Her O
political O
work O
began O
at O
the O
age O
of O
22 O
in O
Paris B-LOC
, O
where O
she O
worked O
as O
a O
correspondent O
for O
a O
German B-MISC
company O
during O
the O
day O
and O
in O
the O
evenings O
- O
in O
addition O
to O
studying O
socialist O
theorists O
- O
engaged O
in O
the O
French B-MISC
workers O
' O
movement O
and O
women O
's O
education O
work O
. O

Their O
emigration O
to O
Paris B-LOC
ended O
abruptly O
with O
the O
outbreak O
of O
the O
First B-MISC
World I-MISC
War I-MISC
; O
she O
was O
transferred O
as O
a O
German B-MISC
of O
the O
country O
. O

Returning O
to O
Frankfurt B-LOC
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
joined O
the O
Social O
Democratic O
War O
Opposition O
and O
became O
a O
fierce O
advocate O
for O
an O
end O
to O
a O
war O
that O
served O
not O
the O
defence O
of O
the O
Fatherland O
, O
but O
the O
conquest O
of O
new O
markets O
and O
the O
suppression O
of O
previously O
free O
peoples O
. O

She O
was O
an O
opponent O
of O
the O
SPD O
- O
Burg B-MISC
peace I-MISC
policy I-MISC
, O
was O
excluded O
from O
the O
party O
and O
in O
1917 O
co O
- O
founder O
of O
the O
USPD B-ORG
. O

The O
Independent O
Social O
Democrat O
wrote O
during O
the O
November B-MISC
Revolution I-MISC
Frankfurt B-MISC
City O
History O
. O

She O
was O
Secretary O
- O
General O
of O
the O
Labour O
Council O
and O
- O
after O
the O
introduction O
of O
women O
's O
voting O
rights O
in O
November O
1918 O
- O
a O
member O
of O
the O
Frankfurt B-MISC
City O
Ordinary O
Assembly O
. O

The O
young O
Weimar B-LOC
Republic I-LOC
did O
not O
find O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
's I-PER
full O
approval O
; O
it O
had O
hoped O
for O
more O
basic O
democracy O
from O
the O
revolution O
: O

the O
implementation O
of O
advisory O
thought O
in O
politics O
, O
economy O
and O
in O
enterprises O
. O

As O
editor O
of O
the O
USPD B-MISC
daily I-MISC
newspaper I-MISC
" O
Volksrecht B-ORG
" O
and O
the O
" O
Betriebsräte O
- O
Zeitschrift O
" O
of O
the O
German B-ORG
Metallarbeiter I-ORG
- O
Verband O
she O
criticized O
the O
political O
development O
; O
as O
a O
member O
of O
the O
German B-MISC
Reichstag B-ORG
and O
party O
politician O
she O
did O
her O
best O
to O
actively O
participate O
in O
politics O
. O

Faced O
with O
the O
decision O
to O
either O
submit O
to O
Lenin B-PER
’s I-PER
dictatorship O
and O
align O
the O
USPD B-ORG
with B-MISC
Moscow O
or O
return O
to O
the O
ranks O
of O
social O
democracy O
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
once O
again O
chose O
freedom O
– O
this O
time O
the O
party O
’s O
strategy O
not O
to O
be O
left O
to O
foreigners O
. O

It O
was O
not O
very O
easy O
for O
her O
to O
decide O
to O
reunify O
with O
the O
SPD B-ORG
, O
which O
, O
in O
her O
opinion O
, O
had O
arranged O
too O
much O
with O
the O
bourgeois O
republic O
. O

In O
Parliament O
she O
emerged O
as O
a O
recognised O
specialist O
in O
economic O
and O
foreign O
policy O
issues O
; O
she O
stood O
up O
as O
a O
politician O
and O
editor O
- O
in O
- O
chief O
of O
the O
SPD B-MISC
magazine I-MISC
" O
Womenwelt B-ORG
" O
for O
the O
equal O
participation O
of O
women O
in O
all O
areas O
of O
life O
. O

The O
Jew O
, O
Social O
Democrat O
and O
trade O
unionist O
came O
into O
the O
eye O
of O
the O
Nazis B-ORG
at O
the O
end O
of O
the O
20th O
century O
. O

An O
open O
threat O
of O
murder O
prompted O
her O
to O
flee O
Czechoslovakia O
to O
Belgium O
immediately O
after O
the O
Reichstag B-MISC
election I-MISC
on O
March O
5 O
, O
1933 O
. O

In O
1935 O
she O
returned O
from O
a O
U.S. B-MISC
stay I-MISC
no O
longer O
to O
the O
nearby O
province O
of O
Flanders B-LOC
, O
settled O
in O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
and O
soon O
applied O
for O
U.S. B-MISC
citizenship I-MISC
. O

The O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
in O
the O
era O
of O
the O
social O
reformist O
" O
New B-MISC
Deal I-MISC
" O
seemed O
to O
offer O
it O
the O
greatest O
possible O
guarantee O
of O
a O
life O
in O
individual O
and O
political O
freedom O
and O
without O
compulsion O
to O
social O
conventions O
. O

Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
reached O
a O
final O
career O
high O
as O
a O
representative O
of O
the O
United B-MISC
States O
, O
later O
of O
the O
International O
Trade O
Union O
Confederation O
at O
the O
Economic O
and O
Social O
Council O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
. O

She O
served O
in O
the O
Commission B-ORG
on I-ORG
the I-ORG
Status I-ORG
of I-ORG
Women I-ORG
and O
the O
Commission O
on O
Human B-ORG
Rights I-ORG
. O

Its O
name O
is O
associated O
with O
the O
fight O
against O
human O
enslavement O
through O
forced O
labour O
and O
against O
politically O
motivated O
defamation O
of O
freedom O
. O

She O
tirelessly O
collected O
evidence O
of O
human O
rights O
violations O
and O
unhesitatingly O
accused O
states O
of O
violating O
human O
rights O
and O
freedoms O
. O

Until O
her O
death O
in O
1964 O
, O
Tony B-PER
Sender I-PER
firmly O
held O
that O
women O
and O
men O
can O
achieve O
the O
same O
benefits O
if O
they O
only O
have O
equal O
opportunities O
and O
are O
not O
hindered O
by O
social O
norms O
or O
economic O
disadvantages O
. O

Removing O
class O
and O
gender O
barriers O
, O
making O
them O
disappear O
completely O
, O
was O
her O
program O
. O

Achieving O
a O
life O
style O
in O
free O
self O
- O
determination O
was O
her O
goal O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Medical O
assistance O
for O
the O
homeless O
An O
ambulance O
treats O
the O
" O
berberbers B-MISC
" O
who O
are O
often O
sent O
away O
in O
medical O
practices O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
A. I-LOC
M. I-LOC
" O
So O
, O
the O
feet O
now O
stay O
inside O
for O
20 O
minutes O
. O
" O

With O
friendly O
, O
but O
specific O
tone O
, O
Klaus B-PER
Hetzel I-PER
, O
nurse O
and O
hygienist O
, O
gives O
his O
instructions O
. O

Josef B-PER
Schmidt I-PER
( O
name O
of O
the O
speech O
. O

changed O
) O
, O
homeless O
, O
obeying O
puts O
his O
whimsical O
legs O
in O
the O
large O
plastic O
container O
with O
a O
dark O
liquid O
. O
" O

Open O
legs O
, O
" O
explains O
Klaus B-PER
Hetzel I-PER
, O
" O
the O
most O
common O
disease O
among O
homeless O
people O
. O
" O

Since O
May O
18th O
, O
the O
" O
Medical O
Clinic O
for O
the O
homeless O
" O
in O
Sachsenhausen B-LOC
has O
opened O
its O
doors O
. O

Within O
two O
weeks O
, O
there O
were O
already O
21 O
patients O
with O
Hetzel B-PER
and O
his O
team O
. O

Almost O
all O
patients O
, O
says O
the O
caregiver O
, O
complained O
of O
" O
smoking O
legs O
" O
or O
" O
scrotums O
" O
. O

It O
is O
treated O
with O
a O
potassium O
permanganate O
disinfectant O
solution O
. O
" O

There O
are O
other O
doctors O
who O
suggest O
other O
methods O
, O
" O
reports O
Hetzel B-PER
. O

But O
he O
could O
show O
and O
prove O
successes O
with O
his O
method O
: O

All O
treatments O
documented O
Hetzel B-PER
with O
photos O
or O
video O
. O

Since O
the O
homeless O
could O
see O
for O
themselves O
on O
the O
one O
hand O
, O
what O
the O
regular O
application O
brings O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
newcomers O
can O
also O
be O
more O
easily O
convinced O
by O
the O
pictures O
of O
the O
meaning O
of O
the O
enterprise O
. O

Distrust O
is O
the O
main O
reason O
why O
most O
homeless O
people O
do O
not O
undergo O
" O
normal O
" O
medical O
therapy O
, O
Hetzel B-PER
explains O
. O

In O
no O
case O
will O
I O
go O
to O
such O
a O
again O
, O
" O
Joseph B-PER
Schmidt I-PER
agrees O
. O

He O
knows O
what O
he O
's O
talking O
about O
. O

With O
their O
mostly O
not O
exactly O
" O
bourgeois O
" O
appearance O
, O
the O
" O
Berbers B-MISC
" O
, O
as O
they O
call O
themselves O
, O
are O
not O
popular O
customers O
in O
medical O
practices O
. O

Often O
they O
are O
sent O
away O
as O
refugees O
. O

The O
problem O
, O
the O
under O
- O
supply O
of O
the O
homeless O
in O
the O
medical O
field O
, O
has O
Hetzel B-PER
recognized O
at O
his O
other O
workplace O
, O
the O
homeless O
dinner O
issue O
in O
the O
orphanage B-LOC
, O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

Together O
with O
his O
wife O
Dagmar B-PER
- O
she O
is O
a O
doctor O
and O
presents O
the O
diagnosis O
in O
the O
" O
Medical O
Clinic O
" O
- O
he O
offered O
there O
weekly O
one O
hour O
of O
care O
. O

That O
was O
too O
little O
, O
and O
above O
all O
the O
necessary O
facilities O
were O
lacking O
. O

These O
are O
available O
in O
the O
new O
domain O
: O

Three O
rooms O
, O
fully O
furnished O
and O
a O
bathroom O
equipped O
with O
everything O
it O
needs O
for O
body O
care O
. O

One O
of O
the O
rooms O
serves O
as O
a O
treatment O
room O
, O
another O
as O
an O
office O
( O
" O
finally O
all O
the O
paperwork O
no O
longer O
at O
home O
" O
) O
, O
and O
finally O
there O
is O
in O
the O
entrance O
area O
a O
lounge O
- O
the O
" O
waiting O
room O
" O
with O
coffee O
dispenser O
and O
as O
a O
communication O
center O
thought O
. O

The O
Medical O
Clinic O
is O
operated O
by O
the O
Evangelical B-ORG
Communication I-ORG
Working I-ORG
Group I-ORG
( O
AFEK B-ORG
) O
. O

Since O
1984 O
he O
has O
been O
registered O
as O
a O
non O
- O
profit O
organization O
and O
is O
fully O
funded O
by O
donations O
. O

His O
constitutional O
goal O
to O
care O
for O
marginalized O
groups O
, O
he O
wants O
to O
overcome O
by O
giving O
" O
help O
to O
self O
- O
help O
" O
. O

This O
can O
be O
seen O
in O
the O
medical O
ambulance O
project O
. O

Without O
the O
dedicated O
packing O
formerly O
homeless O
the O
rooms O
would O
hardly O
have O
been O
renovated O
so O
quickly O
and O
inexpensively O
. O
" O

That O
was O
a O
completely O
downed O
pub O
. O
" O

All O
the O
work O
, O
even O
the O
walls O
and O
tiles O
, O
had O
been O
done O
by O
the O
helpers O
. O
" O

If O
they O
have O
a O
goal O
in O
mind O
, O
then O
they O
will O
be O
aware O
of O
their O
social O
responsibility O
, O
" O
explained O
Hetzel B-PER
, O
who O
describes O
himself O
as O
a O
" O
determined O
Christian B-MISC
, O
" O
the O
use O
of O
formerly O
homeless O
people O
. O

His O
credo O
is O
therefore O
an O
ancient O
Indian B-MISC
prayer I-MISC
that O
hangs O
as O
a O
poster O
opposite O
his O
office O
chair O
: O

" O
Great O
Spirit O
, O
keep O
me O
from O
judging O
a O
man O
before O
I O
have O
gone O
half O
a O
moon O
in O
his O
mokassins O
. O
" O

Since O
AFEK B-ORG
is O
fully O
committed O
to O
donations O
, O
financial O
assistance O
is O
always O
welcome O
. O

Klaus B-PER
Hetzel I-PER
provides O
information O
by O
phone O
62 O
35 O
59 O
from O
Monday O
to O
Thursday O
between O
9 O
a.m. O
and O
5 O
p.m. O
and O
on O
Fridays O
between O
9 O
a.m. O
and O
1 O
p.m O
.. O

-DOCSTART- O

Ludwig B-LOC
's I-LOC
Linde I-LOC
and O
a O
Lovely O
Maid O

AUERBACH B-LOC
. O

With O
the O
often O
quoted O
and O
much O
praised O
" O
Tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
it O
is O
like O
with O
the O
repeatedly O
mentioned O
" O
Siegfriedquelle B-LOC
" O
where O
the O
legendary O
Recke O
died O
: O

No O
one O
can O
say O
exactly O
and O
prove O
where O
both O
natural O
monuments O
are O
to O
be O
found O
. O

Therefore O
, O
one O
does O
not O
need O
to O
wonder O
that O
these O
are O
present O
multiple O
times O
. O

So O
there O
is O
the O
mentioned O
tree O
in O
Momart B-LOC
, O
Kimbach B-LOC
, O
Airlenbach B-LOC
, O
Olfen B-LOC
and O
also O
near O
the O
Fürstenlager B-LOC
bei O
Auerbach B-LOC
( O
Kreis O
Bergstraße B-LOC
) O
. O

Perhaps O
the O
last O
mentioned O
place O
can O
be O
regarded O
as O
the O
" O
real O
" O
because O
there O
in O
1778 O
a O
pine O
tree O
was O
planted O
and O
" O
tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
was O
baptized O
. O

The O
Prince B-LOC
's I-LOC
Camp I-LOC
, O
former O
summer O
residence O
of O
the O
Hessian B-MISC
Landgraves O
, O
with O
its O
friendly O
park O
surrounded O
by O
numerous O
exotic O
trees O
, O
also O
seems O
to O
be O
the O
right O
environment O
for O
the O
legendary O
Linde O
. O

Because O
closely O
connected O
with O
the O
" O
tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
and O
the O
graceful O
prince B-LOC
camp I-LOC
is O
a O
love O
romance O
in O
that O
park O
and O
forest O
scenery O
. O

The O
opera O
singer O
, O
later O
Intendant O
of O
the O
Darmstädter B-MISC
Hoftheater O
and O
master O
of O
homeland O
narrative O
art O
, O
Ernst B-PER
Pasqué I-PER
, O
traced O
it O
literary O
. O

That O
the O
poet O
was O
able O
to O
do O
this O
so O
meticulously O
, O
is O
easily O
explained O
: O

He O
lived O
for O
two O
decades O
( O
1871 O
to O
1892 O
) O
on O
the O
mountain B-LOC
road I-LOC
and O
experienced O
through O
his O
good O
relations O
with O
Grand O
Duke O
Ludwig B-PER
IV I-PER
many O
things O
, O
which O
characterizes O
the O
originality O
of O
his O
story O
" O
There B-MISC
stands I-MISC
a I-MISC
tree I-MISC
in I-MISC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
. O

At O
the O
" O
Schauplatz B-LOC
Fürstenlager I-LOC
" O
Landgrave O
Friedrich B-PER
miraculously O
learned O
to O
know O
Karoline B-PER
Seitz I-PER
from O
Grasellenbach B-LOC
, O
a O
girl O
of O
simple O
origin O
, O
he O
married O
her O
and O
led O
a O
happy O
marriage O
with O
her O
. O

Pasqué B-PER
portrayed O
Karoline B-PER
in O
his O
booklet O
as O
" O
a O
strikingly O
beautiful O
bleeding O
thing O
of O
about O
17 O
years O
old O
, O
a O
blonde O
whose O
fine O
, O
naturally O
curved O
blonde O
spots O
under O
the O
collector O
's O
cups O
were O
a O
little O
too O
curious O
and O
made O
themselves O
wide O
on O
the O
white O
forehead O
" O
. O

At O
this O
coincidence O
on O
the O
occasion O
of O
a O
courteous O
feast O
in O
the O
prince B-LOC
's I-LOC
camp I-LOC
Karoline B-PER
is O
supposed O
to O
have O
sung O
the O
old O
folk O
song O
" O
There B-MISC
stands I-MISC
a I-MISC
tree I-MISC
in I-MISC
the O
Odenwald O
" O
. O

To O
commemorate O
the O
feast O
" O
under O
all O
kinds O
of O
solemn O
ceremonies O
" O
a O
young O
linden O
was O
planted O
, O
" O
at O
a O
place O
of O
height O
, O
from O
where O
one O
had O
a O
magnificent O
view O
of O
the O
Schönberger B-MISC
valley O
and O
the O
old O
picturesque O
castle O
of O
the O
Counts O
of O
Erbach B-LOC
- I-LOC
Schönberg I-LOC
" O
. O

An O
Eremit O
spoke O
" O
the O
forest O
blessing O
over O
the O
young O
forest O
tree O
, O
which O
he O
- O
inspired O
by O
Karolin B-PER
's I-PER
singing O
- O
baptized O
, O
tree B-LOC
in I-LOC
the O
Odenwald O
' O
. O

However O
, O
this O
tree O
no O
longer O
exists O
, O
a O
lightning O
strike O
destroyed O
it O
. O

But O
in O
his O
place O
Count O
Ludwig B-PER
to I-PER
Erbach I-PER
- O
Schönberg O
( O
1792 O
- O
1863 O
) O
planted O
a O
new O
leaf O
, O
which O
since O
then O
bears O
the O
name O
" O
Ludwigslinde B-LOC
" O
, O
a O
tall O
tree O
of O
powerful O
shape O
and O
widespread O
apple O
growth O
. O

From O
the O
bank O
under O
the O
Linde O
you O
can O
enjoy O
a O
wonderful O
view O
- O
over O
the O
valley O
to O
the O
mountains O
, O
to O
Starkenburg B-LOC
, O
to O
Knodenkopf B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
point O
of O
reference O
Krehberg B-LOC
, O
Märkerwald B-LOC
, O
Hemsberg B-LOC
, O
Vetzersberg B-LOC
, O
into O
the O
Rhine B-LOC
plain I-LOC
to O
the O
Pfälzerwald B-LOC
. O

Right O
next O
to O
the O
" O
Ludwigslinde B-LOC
" O
is O
the O
Schönberger B-MISC
" O
Herrenwingert B-LOC
" O
. O

Earlier O
he O
belonged O
to O
the O
Counts O
of O
Erbach B-LOC
- I-LOC
Schönberg I-LOC
, O
today O
he O
owns O
the O
state O
- O
owned B-ORG
Bergstraße I-ORG
. O

There O
should O
not O
be O
few O
people O
- O
mountaineers B-MISC
and O
strangers O
- O
who O
have O
fallen O
in O
love O
in O
this O
place O
at O
the O
" O
Ludwigslinde B-LOC
" O
and O
at O
the O
" O
Herrenwingert B-LOC
" O
. O

REINHARD B-PER
TREBER I-PER

-DOCSTART- O

Contacts O
to O
high O
- O
quality O
glasses O
Epiphanias O
- O
Kantorin O
has O
been O
committed O
to O
classical O
and O
new O
music O
for O
14 O
years O

NORDEND B-LOC
. O

Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
has O
been O
a O
cantor O
at O
the O
Evangelical O
Epiphanias B-ORG
Church I-ORG
in O
the O
North B-LOC
for O
14 O
years O
. O

That O
can O
be O
built O
all O
by O
all O
. O

Especially O
the O
last O
concert O
in O
April O
did O
it O
to O
her O
. O
" O

That O
's O
when O
I O
noticed O
what O
we O
mean O
by O
an O
excellent O
choir O
. O
" O

In O
the O
difficult O
romantic O
A O
- O
cappella O
sets O
, O
the O
singers O
had O
already O
reacted O
to O
the O
smallest O
instructions O
. O

And O
also O
for O
her O
orchestra O
she O
has O
only O
praise O
words O
. O

That O
such O
achievements O
are O
not O
falling O
from O
heaven O
, O
but O
can O
only O
be O
achieved O
through O
continuous O
, O
hard O
- O
working O
sampling O
, O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
only O
mentions O
on O
the O
edge O
. O

Two O
times O
a O
year O
- O
usually O
on O
Easter O
and O
in O
the O
Advent O
period O
- O
the O
Epiphanias B-ORG
congregation I-ORG
choir O
and O
orchestra O
give O
their O
great O
concerts O
. O

This O
year O
the O
Kantorin O
had O
selected O
an O
interesting O
mixture O
of O
romantic O
A O
- O
cappella O
singing O
, O
i.e. O
unseen O
pieces O
for O
choir O
, O
and O
orchestral O
works O
of O
the O
20th O
century O
. O

A O
program O
with O
music O
by O
Johann B-PER
Sebastian I-PER
Bach I-PER
is O
planned O
for O
the O
Advent O
. O

These O
concerts O
can O
cost O
the O
community O
a O
lot O
: O

Posters O
are O
glued O
to O
the O
Litfaßsäulen O
, O
and O
strongly O
proclaimed O
on O
billboards O
and O
in O
newspapers O
. O

The O
church O
on O
Holzhausenstraße B-LOC
is O
then O
mostly O
also O
breaking O
full O
. O

But O
also O
other O
, O
less O
expensively O
announced O
events B-MISC
are O
almost O
always O
well O
visited O
. O

Thus O
the O
Matinee O
with O
organ O
and O
violin O
music O
at O
the O
end O
of O
March O
on O
an O
amazing O
audience O
interest O
, O
although O
not O
about O
Bach B-PER
, O
Mozart B-PER
or O
Mendelssohn B-PER
, O
but O
exclusively O
music O
of O
the O
20th O
century O
stood O
on O
the O
program O
. O
" O

We O
have O
just O
now O
our O
regular O
audience O
" O
, O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
does O
not O
look O
without O
pride O
on O
the O
lively O
musical O
activity O
. O

The O
Kantorin O
has O
something O
, O
without O
which O
nothing O
works O
in O
concert O
operation O
: O

Relations O
. O

In O
difficult O
choral O
and O
orchestral O
works O
, O
especially O
high O
- O
quality O
beads O
are O
important O
. O

And O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
has O
the O
best O
contacts O
with O
them O
. O

Most O
of O
them O
work O
in O
the O
Radio O
Symphony O
Orchestra O
and O
like O
to O
help O
out O
in O
the O
Epiphanias B-LOC
Church I-LOC
. O
" O

Many O
have O
so O
much O
fun O
playing O
with O
the O
choir O
that O
they O
also O
like O
to O
perform O
as O
soloists O
once O
. O
" O

The O
fact O
that O
the O
Kantorin O
has O
her O
own O
string O
orchestra O
is O
unusual O
. O

To O
church O
concerts O
usually O
the O
musicians O
are O
bought O
together O
, O
which O
you O
just O
need O
. O

Or O
you O
can O
hire O
a O
whole O
professional O
orchestra O
at O
once O
. O

This O
is O
expensive O
and O
guarantees O
not O
a O
good O
concert O
for O
a O
long O
time O
yet O
. O
" O

The O
orchestra O
tastes O
just O
as O
well O
as O
the O
choir O
. O

The O
relationships O
are O
thus O
much O
closer O
, O
and O
the O
musicians O
motivate O
each O
other O
at O
concerts O
. O
" O

That O
very O
heavy O
romantic O
pieces O
, O
such O
as O
the O
German B-MISC
Requiem O
by O
Brahms B-PER
, O
with O
the O
mainly O
lay O
orchestra O
are O
hardly O
to O
create O
, O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
likes O
to O
buy O
in O
. O

To O
Johann B-PER
Sebastian I-PER
Bach I-PER
the O
Kantorin B-MISC
has O
a O
split O
relationship O
, O
despite O
the O
concerts O
on O
September O
20th O
and O
December O
6th O
, O
where O
mainly O
works O
of O
the O
Thomaskantor B-MISC
are O
played O
. O

What O
disturbs O
them O
is O
over O
- O
consumption O
. O

Every O
second O
year O
quotations O
from O
the O
Christmas B-MISC
oratory I-MISC
? O

That O
would O
be O
Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
too O
boring O
. O
” O

Many O
do O
not O
know O
that O
not O
only O
Bach B-PER
composed O
good O
and O
interesting O
music O
. O
" O

Thus O
during O
her O
14 O
years O
of O
work O
, O
apart O
from O
Mozart B-PER
's I-PER
" O
Requiem B-MISC
" O
and O
the O
" O
Death B-MISC
Song I-MISC
" O
by O
Johannes B-PER
Brahms I-PER
, O
she O
has O
not O
performed O
a O
work O
twice O
. O
" O

I O
want O
to O
at O
least O
tell O
people O
how O
wide O
the O
range O
of O
different O
pieces O
is O
. O
" O

Also O
for O
her O
the O
music O
history O
does O
not O
end O
with O
Anton B-PER
Bruckner I-PER
. O

Your O
interest O
in O
modern O
music O
is O
great O
. O

In O
the O
choir O
it O
is O
difficult O
for O
the O
cantor O
to O
do O
so O
. O
" O

I O
do O
n't O
want O
to O
make O
the O
singers O
into O
new O
music O
fans O
. O

But O
everyone O
should O
be O
open O
to O
it O
. O
" O

In O
this O
way O
, O
she O
devotes O
herself O
primarily O
as O
an O
organizer O
to O
modern O
music O
. O

Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
conducts O
a O
brilliantly O
trained O
, O
70 O
- O
strong O
church O
choir O
and O
her O
own O
orchestra O
, O
has O
free O
hand O
in O
her O
planning O
, O
and O
also O
her O
church O
musical O
budget O
does O
not O
currently O
worry O
her O
. O

Do O
you O
have O
any O
wishes O
? O
" O

A O
new O
, O
modern O
organ O
" O
- O
that O
would O
be O
what O
you O
still O
lack O
for O
musical O
happiness O
. O

The O
relatively O
small O
instrument O
from O
the O
1950s O
has O
only O
a O
few O
registers O
and O
an O
outdated O
technology O
. O
" O

The O
re O
- O
intonation O
two O
years O
ago O
has O
brought O
a O
lot O
of O
sound O
after O
all O
. O
” O

But O
she O
does O
n't O
give O
herself O
any O
illusions O
. O

For O
a O
new O
organ O
simply O
lacks O
the O
money O
. O

Elke B-PER
Mattmüller I-PER
has O
built O
a O
lot O
in O
the O
North B-LOC
and O
therefore O
does O
not O
waste O
any O
thought O
on O
a O
career O
change O
. O
" O

In O
a O
new O
congregation O
I O
would O
have O
to O
start O
all O
the O
way O
down O
again O
. O
" O

-DOCSTART- O

Samples O
+ O
Meetings O

Accordion O
Music O
Association O
" O
Heiterkeit B-ORG
" O
Griesheim B-LOC
: O

Classes O
for O
accordion O
pupils O
and O
- O
pupils O
is O
every O
Thursday O
( O
from O
14 O
o'clock O
) O
, O
in O
the O
Bürgerhaus O
Griesheim B-LOC
, O
Schwarzerlenweg B-LOC
57 O
( O
Clubroom O
3 O
) O
. O

And O
the O
club O
's O
orchestra O
samples O
in O
Clubroom O
1 O
in O
Griesheim B-LOC
every O
Tuesday O
, O
from O
19 O
to O
20.30 O
. O

Working O
Group O
of O
Bockenheim B-ORG
Seniors I-ORG
: O

Member O
meetings O
every O
first O
Tuesday O
of O
the O
month O
( O
15 O
o'clock O
) O
in O
the O
social B-LOC
station I-LOC
at O
Rohmerplatz B-LOC
( O
Partrre O
) O
. O

Athletics O
Association O
1990 B-ORG
Griesheim I-ORG
: O

Sports O
badge O
preparation O
and O
weight O
loss O
after O
prior O
registration O
every O
Monday O
, O
Wednesday O
and O
Friday O
( O
each O
from O
18 O
o'clock O
) O
in O
the O
Griesheimer B-LOC
Sporthalle I-LOC
, O
Linkstraße B-LOC
86 O
- O
88 O
. O

Contact O
: O

Klaus B-PER
Samer I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

37 O
19 O
74 O
) O
and O
Hugo B-PER
Zingel I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

38 O
42 O
27 O
) O
. O

Bockenheimer B-ORG
men I-ORG
's O
choir O
1837 O
: O

The O
active O
members O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
, O
20 O
o'clock O
, O
in O
the O
parish O
hall O
of O
the O
Evangelical O
St. B-LOC
James I-LOC
Church I-LOC
, O
Grempstraße B-LOC
41 O
. O

Women O
and O
men O
interested O
in O
singing O
in O
the O
community O
can O
participate O
in O
this O
sample O
without O
obligation O
. O

Information O
on O
all O
activities O
of O
the O
association O
is O
provided O
by O
the O
chairman O
Wolfgang B-PER
Ochs I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

76 O
67 O
43 O
) O
. O

Bockenheimer B-ORG
Zitherkranz I-ORG
1886 I-ORG
: O

The O
activities O
of O
the O
association O
are O
tested O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
from O
20 O
o'clock O
) O
in O
the O
" O
Bürgertreff B-LOC
Bockenheim I-LOC
" O
, O
Schwälmer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Interested O
in O
the O
Zitherspiel O
can O
obtain O
more O
information O
from O
Rudi B-PER
May I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

77 O
15 O
43 O
) O
. O

Letter O
Taubenverein O
" O
Sport B-ORG
" O
Frankfurt B-LOC
: O

The O
members O
meet O
for O
the O
club O
evening O
every O
Thursday O
, O
20 O
hrs O
, O
in O
the O
restaurant O
" O
Zur B-LOC
Krone I-LOC
" O
in O
Seckbach B-LOC
, O
Wilhelmshöher B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
165 O
. O

Guests O
interested O
in O
letter O
diving O
are O
welcome O
. O

The O
BUND O
- O
Ortsverband B-ORG
2/9 I-ORG
has O
a O
meeting O
every O
third O
Wednesday O
of O
the O
month O
at O
8:00 O
p.m. O
at O
the O
citizen B-LOC
meeting I-LOC
in O
Bockenheim O
, O
Schwälmer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Chorus B-ORG
Society I-ORG
1857 I-ORG
Griesheim I-ORG
: O

Every O
Thursday O
( O
19.45 O
to O
21.15 O
p.m. O
) O
the O
activists O
meet O
at O
the O
Griesheim B-LOC
Town I-LOC
Hall I-LOC
, O
Schwarzerlenweg B-LOC
57 O
( O
Clubraum O
2 O
) O
. O

Women O
and O
men O
are O
still O
included O
in O
the O
choir O
. O

More O
information O
is O
available O
from O
Horst B-PER
Seip I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

38 O
20 O
97 O
) O
. O

DLRG B-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

The O
members O
of O
the O
dive O
group O
meet O
every O
Thursday O
, O
19.30 O
o'clock O
, O
for O
Taining O
in O
the O
Hallenbad B-LOC
Sachsenhausen I-LOC
, O
Textorstraße B-LOC
42 O
. O

Information O
about O
rescue O
diving O
training O
is O
provided O
by O
Willi B-PER
Vogt I-PER
Tel O
. O

58 O
66 O
23 O
. O

Information O
can O
also O
be O
obtained O
every O
Wednesday O
from O
15:00 O
to O
20:00 O
at O
the O
DLRG B-MISC
office I-MISC
Tel O
. O

28 O
05 O
12 O
. O

FKV B-ORG
1911 I-ORG
and I-ORG
Maagard I-ORG
: O

The O
dance O
corps O
of O
the O
Frankfurt B-ORG
Carnival I-ORG
Club I-ORG
1911 I-ORG
trains O
every O
Wednesday O
, O
19 O
to O
20.30 O
( O
mini O
guard O
from O
18 O
to O
19 O
o'clock O
) O
, O
in O
the O
clubhouse B-LOC
, O
Petterweilstraße B-LOC
69 O
in O
Bornheim B-LOC
( O
bunker O
) O
. O

There O
are O
still O
girls O
interested O
in O
dancing O
in O
the O
community O
. O

Contact O
: O

Manuela B-PER
Koch I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

0 O
61 O
87 O
/ O
34 O
56 O
. O

Frankfurt B-ORG
Canoe I-ORG
Association I-ORG
1913 I-ORG
: O

The O
association O
invites O
to O
its O
meetings O
- O
every O
Thursday O
, O
from O
6 O
p.m. O
, O
in O
the O
" O
Friedel B-LOC
- I-LOC
Baureis I-LOC
- O
Haus O
" O
, O
the O
boathouse O
at O
the O
Peace B-LOC
Bridge I-LOC
. O

For O
more O
information O
, O
please O
contact O
press O
officer O
Eckard B-PER
Dünnemann I-PER
at O
Tel O
. O

88 O
98 O
81 O
( O
from O
18 O
o'clock O
) O
. O

Frankfurt B-ORG
Carnival I-ORG
Society I-ORG
Red I-ORG
- O
Weiß O
: O

The O
" O
regiment O
guards O
" O
of O
the O
association O
train O
every O
Monday O
, O
20 O
o'clock O
, O
in O
the O
" O
citizen B-LOC
meeting I-LOC
Bockenheim I-LOC
" O
in O
Schwälmer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Frankfurt B-ORG
Liedertafel I-ORG
1827 I-ORG
: O

To O
try O
the O
choir O
, O
the O
activists O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
19.45 O
to O
21.45 O
o'clock O
) O
at O
the O
" O
Citizen B-LOC
meeting I-LOC
Philanthropin I-LOC
" O
, O
Hebelstraße B-LOC
17 O
. O

Women O
and O
men O
interested O
in O
singing O
in O
the O
community O
are O
still O
included O
in O
the O
choir O
. O

Contact O
: O

President O
Hans B-PER
Riebartsch I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

31 O
34 O
61 O
) O
. O

Frankfurter B-ORG
Musikverein I-ORG
: O

To O
try O
the O
orchestra O
the O
players O
meet O
on O
Thursdays O
, O
at O
20 O
o'clock O
in O
the O
" O
Josefsklause B-LOC
" O
in O
Bornheim B-LOC
, O
Berger B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
133 O
. O

Head O
of O
the O
Blasorchester O
( O
Big O
Band O
Sound O
) O
: O

Norbert B-PER
Natho I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

46 O
12 O
85 O
; O
conductor O
: O

Hans O
- O
Joachim B-PER
Eberhardt I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

42 O
65 O
02 O
. O

Frankfurt B-ORG
City I-ORG
Guard I-ORG
: O

For O
training O
, O
the O
members O
of O
the O
Rambassball O
team O
of O
the O
1st B-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
Women I-ORG
's I-ORG
Fanfarencorps I-ORG
and O
the O
player O
's O
squad O
meet O
every O
Wednesday O
( O
20 O
o'clock O
) O
at O
" O
Haus B-LOC
Gallus I-LOC
" O
, O
Frankenallee B-LOC
111 O
. O

FTG B-ORG
47 I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

Judo O
for O
children O
offers O
the O
Frankfurt B-ORG
Turn- I-ORG
und I-ORG
Sportgemeinschaft I-ORG
1847 I-ORG
every O
Friday O
( O
children O
from O
six O
to O
ten O
years O
old O
) O
, O
and O
every O
Monday O
( O
children O
and O
young O
people O
from O
ten O
years O
old O
) O
, O
each O
from O
16 O
to O
18 O
hours O
, O
in O
the O
FTG B-LOC
Sportzentrum I-LOC
in O
Bockenheim B-LOC
in O
Marburger B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
28 O
. O

Contact O
the O
FTG B-MISC
office I-MISC
Tel O
. O

77 O
49 O
29 O
. O

Comradeship O
of O
former B-ORG
professional I-ORG
firefighters I-ORG
: O

The O
meeting O
of O
members O
for O
a O
cozy O
gathering O
is O
every O
first O
Tuesday O
of O
the O
month O
( O
15 O
o'clock O
) O
in O
the O
restaurant O
" O
Zur B-LOC
Stalburg I-LOC
" O
( O
Nordend B-LOC
) O
, O
Glauburgstraße B-LOC
80 O
. O

Club B-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
offers O
every O
Monday O
( O
16 O
o'clock O
) O
and O
Thursday O
( O
18 O
o'clock O
) O
yoga O
exercises O
, O
as O
well O
as O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
10 O
o'clock O
) O
light O
gymnastics O
for O
ladies O
and O
gentlemen O
( O
16 O
o'clock O
gymnastics O
for O
ladies O
and O
gentlemen O
) O
in O
the O
district B-LOC
bath I-LOC
South I-LOC
, O
Textorstraße B-LOC
42 O
. O

Further O
information O
on O
the O
offers O
of O
the O
kneippverein O
is O
given O
by O
Hannelore B-PER
Kehlmann I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

39 O
17 O
78 O
. O

The O
Athletics O
Department O
of O
the O
Turn- B-ORG
und I-ORG
Sportgemeinde I-ORG
98 I-ORG
Nordwest I-ORG
is O
looking O
for O
young O
people O
( O
from O
ten O
years O
old O
) O
. O

Exercise O
hours O
on O
Mondays O
, O
Wednesdays O
and O
Fridays O
from O
17.30 O
to O
19.30 O
on O
the O
sports O
ground O
of O
Ernst B-ORG
- I-ORG
Reuter I-ORG
- O
Schule O
I. O
Anyone O
interested O
can O
contact O
trainer O
Helmut B-PER
Terstegen I-PER
during O
the O
exercise O
hours O
. O

The O
department O
offers O
students O
a O
talent O
promotion O
in O
jumping O
. O

Information O
about O
Karl B-PER
Terstegen I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

57 O
19 O
74 O
. O

Men O
's O
Choir B-ORG
Songkranz I-ORG
Praunheim I-ORG
: O

The O
active O
members O
meet O
every O
Monday O
, O
20 O
o'clock O
, O
in O
the O
church O
of O
Christ B-LOC
King I-LOC
, O
Damaschkeanger B-LOC
158 O
. O

Young O
men O
interested O
in O
singing O
in O
the O
community O
can O
find O
out O
about O
the O
men O
's O
choir O
at O
Wilfried B-PER
Roth I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

57 O
42 O
71 O
) O
. O

Men O
's O
Choir B-ORG
Songkranz I-ORG
Praunheim I-ORG
: O

The O
women O
of O
the O
association O
meet O
for O
a O
cozy O
gathering O
every O
first O
Monday O
of O
the O
month O
, O
20 O
o'clock O
, O
in O
the O
parish O
house O
of O
Christ B-LOC
King I-LOC
, O
Damaschkeanger B-LOC
158 O
. O

Post O
- O
Sportverein B-ORG
Blau I-ORG
- O
Gelb O
Frankfurt O
: O

The O
club O
invites O
you O
to O
the O
" O
Ginnheimer B-MISC
Lauftreff I-MISC
" O
every O
Tuesday O
at O
18.30 O
. O

The O
starting O
point O
is O
the O
parking O
lot O
of O
the O
club O
at O
the O
Poststadion B-LOC
( O
Am B-LOC
Ginnheimer I-LOC
Wäldchen I-LOC
) O
. O

Cycling B-ORG
community I-ORG
1890 I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

For O
the O
club O
evening O
, O
members O
and O
cyclist O
friends O
meet O
every O
Friday O
( O
20 O
o'clock O
) O
in O
the O
" O
Haus B-LOC
Ronneburg I-LOC
" O
in O
Preungesheim B-LOC
in O
the O
Gelnhäuser B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
2 O
. O

Rödelheimer B-ORG
Neuner I-ORG
: O

The O
choir O
performs O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
20.30 O
hrs O
) O
at O
the O
Rödelheimer B-LOC
Vereinsringheim I-LOC
in O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

Wheelchair B-ORG
Sports I-ORG
Club I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
is O
looking O
for O
dancing O
enthusiastic O
pedestrians O
who O
can O
find O
joy O
and O
fun O
in O
dancing O
with O
Rollis O
. O

It O
is O
tested O
every O
Thursday O
( O
20 O
to O
22 O
hrs O
) O
in O
the O
BG B-LOC
- I-LOC
Unfallklinik I-LOC
, O
Friedberger B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
. O

Contact O
: O

Horst B-PER
Lozar I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

76 O
13 O
37 O
) O
. O

Singer O
choir O
of O
the O
locomotive B-ORG
servicemen I-ORG
1919 I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

For O
their O
choir O
test O
, O
the O
activists O
meet O
every O
Tuesday O
, O
5.30 O
p.m. B-PER
, O
in O
the O
railway B-LOC
cafeteria I-LOC
, O
Camberger B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
17 O
. O

Schützenverein B-ORG
Freischütz I-ORG
Rödelheim I-ORG
: O

Activists O
of O
the O
club O
train O
every O
Sunday O
( O
from O
10 O
to O
12.30 O
o'clock O
) O
and O
every O
Tuesday O
( O
from O
19.30 O
to O
22 O
o'clock O
) O
, O
at O
the O
stands O
in O
the O
Vereinsringheim O
in O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

Sportanglerclub B-ORG
Anker I-ORG
Hausen I-ORG
: O

The O
members O
and O
friends O
of O
the O
association O
meet O
for O
a O
cozy O
gathering O
every O
Tuesday O
, O
20 O
o'clock O
, O
in O
the O
club O
home O
of O
sports O
anglers O
on O
the O
Hausner B-LOC
Weg I-LOC
. O

Sport- B-ORG
und I-ORG
Spaßverein I-ORG
Frankfurt I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
is O
still O
looking O
for O
players O
for O
a O
mixed O
volleyball O
group O
. O

Training O
is O
every O
Thursday O
( O
18 O
to O
20 O
o'clock O
) O
at O
Anne B-LOC
- I-LOC
Frank I-LOC
- O
Schule O
, O
Fritz B-LOC
- I-LOC
Tarnow I-LOC
- O
Straße O
29 O
. O

For O
more O
information O
, O
please O
call O
Tel O
. O

0 O
61 O
07 O
/ O
6 O
12 O
69 O
. O

Turn B-ORG
municipality I-ORG
Römerstadt I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
offers O
after O
the O
school O
holidays O
exercises O
in O
athletics O
and O
gymnastics O
for O
boys O
and O
girls O
( O
six O
to O
nine O
years O
old O
) O
: O

Tuesdays O
from O
15 O
to O
16.30 O
, O
in O
the O
Sister B-LOC
School I-LOC
School I-LOC
I O
m O
Burgfeld B-LOC
7 O
. O

Further O
information O
is O
provided O
by O
Constanze B-PER
Spitz I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

58 O
86 O
32 O
) O
. O

Turn- B-ORG
und I-ORG
Sportgemeinde I-ORG
98 I-ORG
Northwest I-ORG
: O

Courses O
in O
spinal O
gymnastics O
in O
the O
gym O
, O
Weißkirchener B-LOC
Weg I-LOC
12 O
, O
Thursdays O
( O
16 O
and O
17 O
o'clock O
) O
, O
Saturday O
( O
9.30 O
, O
10.30 O
and O
11.30 O
o'clock O
) O
and O
Monday O
( O
9 O
o'clock O
) O
. O

Requests O
for O
documents O
: O

Office O
on O
Tuesdays O
and O
Thursdays O
from O
17 O
to O
19 O
o'clock O
, O
Tel O
. O

58 O
10 O
23 O
. O

Turn- B-ORG
und I-ORG
Sportverein I-ORG
1878 I-ORG
Ginnheim I-ORG
: O

The O
mixed O
choir O
of O
the O
singing O
department O
of O
the O
club O
tastes O
on O
Fridays O
from O
20 O
to O
22 O
o'clock O
in O
the O
Clubhaus B-LOC
Ginnheim I-LOC
, O
Am O
Mühlgarten B-LOC
2 O
( O
smaller O
hall O
) O
. O

Turn- B-ORG
und I-ORG
Sportverein I-ORG
1860 I-ORG
Hausen I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
offers O
" O
swimming O
for O
everyone O
" O
on O
Fridays O
( O
20 O
to O
22 O
o'clock O
) O
in O
the O
swimming O
hall O
of O
the O
Liebigschule B-ORG
in O
Westhausen B-LOC
( O
Kollwitzstraße B-LOC
) O
. O

For O
more O
information O
, O
please O
contact O
Rudi B-PER
Litzinger I-PER
, O
Tel O
. O

76 O
35 O
50 O
. O

Association B-ORG
for I-ORG
Stamp I-ORG
Studies I-ORG
Rödelheim I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
members O
meet O
for O
the O
club O
and O
lecture O
evening O
every O
second O
and O
fourth O
Thursday O
of O
the O
month O
from O
19:30 O
in O
Rödelheimer B-LOC
Vereinsringheim I-LOC
, O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

Water B-ORG
sports I-ORG
club I-ORG
Westend I-ORG
: O

The O
club O
offers O
swimming O
lessons O
for O
beginners O
and O
advanced O
every O
Thursday O
( O
18 O
to O
21 O
h O
) O
in O
the O
Berthold B-LOC
- I-LOC
Otto I-LOC
- O
Schule O
, O
Kiefernstraße B-LOC
18 O
a O
( O
Griesheim B-LOC
) O
. O

More O
information O
about O
the O
offers O
of O
the O
association O
is O
given O
by O
Günter B-PER
Gronemann I-PER
( O
Tel O
. O

39 O
57 O
49 O
) O
. O

Vespa O
Cup O
" O
Scooterlads B-ORG
" I-ORG
1985 I-ORG
: O

The O
roller O
skaters O
meet O
at O
the O
Ergo B-LOC
Bibamus I-LOC
on O
Eschersheimer B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
401 O
every O
Wednesday O
at O
8:00 O
p.m. O

For O
more O
information O
about O
the O
Vespa O
Club O
see O
Wolfgang B-PER
Frey I-PER
at O
Tel O
. O

51 O
10 O
91 O
. O

Volkschor B-ORG
" I-ORG
Frohsinn I-ORG
" O
Rödelheim O
: O

To O
try O
the O
choir O
, O
the O
activists O
meet O
every O
Wednesday O
, O
19.30 O
, O
in O
Rödelheimer B-LOC
Vereinsringheim I-LOC
, O
Assenheimer B-LOC
Straße I-LOC
24 O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

From O
business O
life O
: O

Gaststätte O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
Idylle O
under O
the O
chestnut O

OBERRAD B-LOC
. O

The O
year O
1708 O
is O
written O
. O

A O
year O
will O
still O
take O
until O
goddess B-PER
invents O
the O
porcelain O
. O

It O
is O
the O
age O
of O
reason O
, O
of O
enlightenment O
. O

In O
the O
small O
village O
Oberrad B-LOC
wealthy O
Frankfurt B-MISC
families O
buy O
a O
site O
to O
experience O
" O
alda O
those O
senses O
- O
and O
comforting O
bliss O
" O
that O
they O
sought O
in O
the O
city O
forgiven O
. O

On O
this O
site O
a O
excursion O
place O
is O
created O
, O
the O
inn O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
. O

284 O
years O
later O
, O
the O
catering O
industry O
is O
still O
one O
of O
the O
popular O
destinations O
of O
the O
Ebbelweifans B-MISC
. O

For O
there O
the O
guest O
can O
from O
11 O
to O
23 O
o'clock O
under O
the O
giant O
chestnut O
, O
protected O
by O
the O
brewery O
fence O
whispering O
wine O
, O
chat O
, O
drink O
and O
take O
delicious O
meals O
: O

From O
" O
Lyoner B-MISC
Zweibelschnitzel O
" O
and O
Bavarian B-MISC
liver O
noodle O
soup O
to O
the O
salad O
bowl O
" O
Schlanke O
Linie O
" O
to O
grilled O
pork O
shell O
and O
traditional O
" O
Green O
sauce O
" O
. O

The O
real O
" O
aalen B-MISC
Oberräder I-MISC
" O
always O
had O
their O
usual O
table O
in O
the O
inn O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
. O

The O
Ebbelwei B-MISC
was O
self O
- O
cured O
, O
which O
is O
still O
evidenced O
today O
by O
an O
apparatus O
in O
the O
idyllic O
backyard O
with O
a O
voluminous O
vineyard O
. O

Not O
much O
has O
changed O
in O
terms O
of O
visibility O
either O
. O

Although O
the O
restaurant O
is O
located O
directly O
on O
the O
busy O
Offenbacher B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
, O
you O
can O
hardly O
hear O
the O
noise O
in O
the O
garden O
anymore O
. O

The O
village O
character O
, O
the O
" O
peaceful O
joy O
" O
remained O
. O

Everyday O
in O
the O
historic O
inn O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
, O
where O
on O
the O
first O
floor O
sometimes O
the O
men O
's O
singing O
club O
tastes O
. O

Just O
a O
small O
tip O
for O
wheat O
beer O
drinkers O
: O

Who O
orders O
the O
last O
round O
twenty O
before O
eleven O
, O
is O
nevertheless O
supplemented O
on O
time O
by O
eleven O
. O

After O
all O
, O
there O
is O
a O
police O
hour O
. O

So O
: O

It O
is O
recommended O
as O
a O
silly O
drink O
then O
the O
good O
, O
old O
Ebbelwei B-MISC
. O

The O
inn O
" O
Zum B-LOC
Hirsch I-LOC
" O
is O
located O
in O
Offenbacher B-LOC
Landstraße I-LOC
289 O
and O
is O
open O
daily O
from O
11 O
to O
24 O
hours O
. O

The O
best O
way O
to O
get O
there O
is O
by O
tram O
( O
line O
15 O
and O
16 O
, O
stop O
Bleiweißstraße B-LOC
) O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Educational O
counselling O
centre O
Free O
help O
with O
family O
problems O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
- I-LOC
NORDWEST I-LOC
. O

The O
educational O
advisory O
office O
refers O
to O
its O
advisory O
offer O
. O

Open O
is O
the O
contact O
point O
for O
children O
, O
teenagers O
and O
adults O
. O

Whether O
problems O
with O
general O
life O
issues O
, O
anger O
in O
marriage O
, O
developmental O
or O
educational O
problems O
, O
in O
Ernst B-LOC
- I-LOC
Kahn I-LOC
- O
Straße O
49a O
advice O
and O
help O
is O
offered O
. O

The O
consultation O
is O
free O
of O
charge O
, O
independent O
of O
the O
conference O
and O
confidential O
. O

In O
urgent O
cases O
short O
- O
term O
appointments O
- O
even O
in O
the O
evening O
- O
are O
granted O
. O

Registration O
: O

Monday O
to O
Thursday O
from O
8 O
a.m. O
to O
5 O
p.m. O
; O
on O
Fridays O
from O
12 O
a.m. O
to O
5 O
p.m. O
by O
phone O
57 O
40 O
91 O
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Plans O
of O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
previously O
failed O
Football O
Association O
: O

The O
merger O
with O
Postsportverein B-ORG
" I-ORG
Blau I-ORG
- O
Gelb O
" O
is O
not O
allowed O

FRANKFURT B-LOC
A. I-LOC
M. I-LOC
The O
game O
community O
planned O
for O
months O
by O
the O
Hessian B-MISC
football O
country O
league O
club O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
with O
the O
postsport O
club O
( O
PSV B-ORG
) I-ORG
Blau I-ORG
- O
Gelb O
dropped O
into O
the O
district O
class O
B O
will O
not O
happen O
now O
, O
however O
. O

The O
reserve O
team O
of O
the O
national O
league O
should O
kick O
together O
with O
the O
post B-MISC
athletes I-MISC
. O

But O
the O
Hessian B-ORG
Football I-ORG
Association I-ORG
( O
HFV B-ORG
) O
play O
committee O
decided O
at O
its O
most O
recent O
meeting O
: O

A O
merger O
of O
reserve O
troops O
and O
first O
team O
could O
not O
be O
approved O
according O
to O
the O
statute O
. O

This O
initially O
also O
failed O
the O
plans O
of O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
to O
rent O
on O
the O
site O
of O
the O
PSV B-ORG
. O

The O
city O
of O
Frankfurt B-LOC
refused O
to O
accept O
costs O
amounting O
to O
68 O
000 O
marks O
. O

She O
fears O
creating O
a O
precedent O
case O
. O

The O
background O
: O

As O
long O
as O
the O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
can O
not O
register O
two O
complete O
youth O
teams O
for O
the O
game O
, O
the O
first O
team O
is O
not O
allowed O
to O
play O
in O
the O
national O
league O
. O

In O
the O
youth O
area O
, O
however O
, O
according O
to O
the O
participants O
, O
the O
play O
community O
with O
the O
blue B-ORG
- I-ORG
golds I-ORG
is O
to O
be O
established O
shortly O
. O

Then O
the O
A O
, O
B O
and O
C O
youth O
teams O
could O
train O
together O
on O
the O
post O
- O
sport B-LOC
facility I-LOC
on O
the O
edge O
of O
the O
former O
garden B-LOC
fountain I-LOC
. O

Both O
clubs O
would O
have O
preferred O
it O
if O
it O
were O
possible O
for O
the O
seniors O
to O
cooperate O
with O
the O
clubs O
. O

The O
PSV B-ORG
had O
hoped O
for O
sporting O
incentives O
and O
financial O
compensation O
; O
after O
all O
, O
the O
maintenance O
of O
the O
site O
costs O
more O
than O
300 O
000 O
marks O
a O
year O
. O

FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
, O
on O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
had O
an O
adequate O
sports O
field O
for O
its O
status O
: O

Because O
he O
is O
the O
fourth O
strongest O
Frankfurt O
football O
team O
after O
Eintracht B-ORG
, O
FSV B-ORG
and O
the O
Rot B-ORG
- I-ORG
Weißen I-ORG
. O

The O
contract O
negotiated O
between O
PSV B-ORG
and O
Italia B-ORG
provided O
for O
rent O
payments O
of O
68 O
000 O
marks O
. O

The O
attractive O
plant O
with O
two O
lawns O
seemed O
to O
the O
Italians B-MISC
, O
compared O
to O
their O
current O
" O
home O
" O
at O
the O
SG B-ORG
Westend I-ORG
, O
to O
have O
substantial O
advantages O
. O

There O
they O
have O
to O
pay O
almost O
10 O
000 O
marks O
annually O
for O
the O
use O
of O
the O
changing O
rooms O
. O

The O
hook O
in O
the O
west B-LOC
end I-LOC
: O

At O
the O
SG B-ORG
, O
according O
to O
Stefan B-PER
Lottermann I-PER
, O
player O
coach O
at O
Italia B-ORG
and O
one O
of O
the O
negotiators O
, O
only O
the O
seniors O
are O
allowed O
on O
the O
field O
. O

Insiders O
suspect O
that O
FC B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
is O
trying O
to O
" O
cheap O
" O
through O
the O
collaboration O
with O
Blau B-ORG
- I-ORG
Gelb I-ORG
to O
provide O
the O
necessary O
underpinnings O
in O
youth O
work O
. O

Lottermann B-PER
said O
this O
back O
. O

The O
city O
criticizes O
the O
club O
's O
conduct O
. O

Sports O
director O
Sylvia B-PER
Schenk I-PER
argues O
that O
the O
contract O
had O
arisen O
without O
agreement O
with O
the O
municipality O
, O
but O
went O
to O
their O
expense O
. O

Regardless O
of O
the O
tight O
budgetary O
situation O
, O
" O
a O
fundamental O
question O
must O
be O
decided O
here O
" O
: O

Where O
is O
the O
upper O
limit O
for O
the O
promotion O
of O
clubs O
without O
own O
premises O
? O

For O
Harald B-PER
Lochmann I-PER
, O
Head O
of O
the O
Sports O
and O
Bathing O
Authority O
, O
the O
matter O
is O
a O
" O
precedent O
case O
" O
. O

His O
fears O
: O

If O
the O
city O
has O
first O
submitted O
the O
claim O
, O
report O
within O
a O
short O
time O
" O
ten O
to O
20 O
associations O
" O
similar O
claims O
. O

This O
is O
not O
financially O
acceptable O
. O

Such O
considerations O
can O
not O
be O
joined O
by O
Lottermann B-PER
: O

" O
Which O
clubs O
does O
Lochmann B-PER
mean O
? O
" O

The O
constellation O
is O
unique O
. O

Never O
before O
has O
a O
club O
rented O
itself O
to O
a O
club O
with O
its O
own O
site O
. O

The O
offer O
of O
the O
city O
to O
shoot O
up O
to O
18 O
000 O
marks O
, O
the O
coach O
refers O
to O
as O
" O
Lach O
number O
" O
. O

In O
doing O
so O
, O
he O
points O
to O
the O
" O
integrative O
work O
" O
that O
" O
Italia B-ORG
" O
performs O
and O
recalls O
the O
sums O
that O
would O
be O
spent O
at O
other O
places O
for O
the O
promotion O
of O
sport O
. O

Should O
the O
35 O
000 O
marks O
promised O
by O
the O
FC B-ORG
not O
be O
realized O
, O
" O
I O
promise O
the O
responsible O
one O
more O
hot O
dance O
" O
, O
threatens O
Lottermann B-PER
. O

-DOCSTART- O

Opening O
hours O
of O
Hanau B-MISC
museums O

Museum B-LOC
Großauheim I-LOC
, O
Pfortenwingert B-LOC
4 O
, O
Phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
55 O
16 O
and O
29 O
55 O
10 O
, O
open O
Thursday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
a.m. O
to O
12 O
p.m. O
and O
from O
14 O
a.m. O
to O
5 O
p.m. O

Hessisches B-LOC
Puppenmuseum I-LOC
, O
Parkpromenade B-LOC
4 O
, O
Hanau B-LOC
- I-LOC
Wilhelmsbad I-LOC
, O
Phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
8 O
62 O
12 O
, O
open O
Tuesday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
a.m. O
to O
12 O
p.m. O
and O
from O
14 O
a.m. O
to O
17 O
p.m. O
; O
Admission O
: O

Adults O
1.50 O
mark O
, O
children O
0.50 O
mark O
, O
students O
, O
students O
and O
disabled O
one O
mark O
. O

Deutsches B-LOC
Goldschmiedehaus I-LOC
, O
Altstädter B-LOC
Markt I-LOC
6 O
, O
Phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
54 O
30 O
, O
open O
Tuesday O
to O
Sunday O
10 O
a.m. O
to O
12 O
p.m. O
and O
14 O
a.m. O
to O
5 O
p.m. O

Museum B-LOC
Castle I-LOC
Philippsruhe I-LOC
, O
Philippsruher B-LOC
Allee I-LOC
45 O
, O
Phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
55 O
16 O
and O
29 O
55 O
10 O
, O
open O
Tuesday O
to O
Sunday O
11 O
to O
18 O
o'clock O
continuously O
. O

Museum B-LOC
Castle I-LOC
Steinheim I-LOC
, O
Phone O
0 O
61 O
81 O
/ O
29 O
55 O
16 O
and O
29 O
55 O
10 O
, O
open O
Thursday O
to O
Sunday O
from O
10 O
a.m. O
to O
12 O
p.m. O
and O
from O
14 O
a.m. O
to O
5 O
p.m O
.. O

-DOCSTART- O

Not O
yet O
a O
" O
guarantee O
certificate O
" O
for O
a O
healthy O
baby O
For O
early O
detection O
of O
inheritance O
damage O
/ O
blood O
test O
too O
inaccurate O

More O
and O
more O
mothers O
, O
in O
the O
course O
of O
pregnancy O
screenings O
, O
use O
the O
possibility O
of O
detecting O
possible O
inheritance O
damage O
of O
the O
unborn O
prematurely O
with O
a O
blood O
test O
, O
the O
so O
- O
called O
triple O
diagnosis O
, O
in O
order O
to O
allow O
a O
termination O
of O
pregnancy O
if O
necessary O
. O

The O
test O
does O
not O
yet O
belong O
to O
the O
catalogue O
of O
standard B-MISC
tests I-MISC
for O
pregnant O
women O
; O
it O
should O
not O
be O
a O
routine O
measure O
for O
the O
time O
being O
. O

This O
recommendation O
was O
made O
by O
an O
advisory O
board O
of O
the O
" O
Foundation O
for O
the O
Disabled O
Child O
" O
these O
days O
after O
a O
conference O
in O
Berlin B-LOC
. O

Famous O
female O
doctors O
, O
birth O
attendants O
, O
human O
geneticists O
and O
laboratory O
diagnosticians O
had O
participated O
and O
adopted O
a O
number O
of O
further O
demands O
. O

As O
the O
head O
of O
the O
conference O
, O
Professor O
Joachim B-PER
Wolfram I-PER
Dudenhausen I-PER
from O
the O
Rudolf B-ORG
Virchow I-ORG
Clinic I-ORG
of O
the O
Freie B-ORG
Universität I-ORG
Berlin I-ORG
, O
explained O
, O
the O
in O
principle O
harmless O
, O
but O
costly O
test O
, O
if O
it O
provides O
clues O
to O
genetic O
damage O
such O
as O
neural O
tube O
defects O
or O
for O
trisomies O
( O
such O
as O
the O
former O
Mongolism B-MISC
called O
Down B-MISC
syndrome I-MISC
) O
, O
further O
extensive O
and O
for O
the O
woman O
and O
the O
unborn O
not O
entirely O
harmless O
examinations O
after O
themselves O
, O
the O
so O
- O
called O
amniocentesis O
. O
