Melbourne B-LOC
( O
Australia B-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Attorney B-PER
General I-PER
of I-PER
the O
State O
, O
Daryl B-PER
Williams I-PER
, O
today O
stressed O
the O
need O
to O
take O
steps O
to O
protect O
the O
Australian O
judicial O
system O
against O
an O
Internet O
page O
that O
makes O
it O
impossible O
to O
comply O
with O
the O
basic O
principles O
of O
law B-MISC
. O

The O
Attorney B-PER
General I-PER
's O
request O
comes O
after O
a O
judge O
of O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of O
the O
state O
of O
Victoria B-LOC
( O
Australia B-LOC
) O
was O
forced O
to O
dissolve O
a O
popular O
jury O
and O
suspend O
the O
process O
in O
the O
face O
of O
the O
defense O
's O
argument O
that O
the O
people O
who O
composed O
it O
could O
have O
obtained O
information O
about O
the O
accused O
through O
the O
CrimeNet B-MISC
website O
. O

This O
website O
has O
been O
in O
existence O
for O
a O
month O
, O
during O
which O
time O
it O
has O
been O
visited O
more O
than O
a O
million O
times O
, O
and O
provides O
information O
on O
thousands O
of O
crimes O
and O
criminals O
already O
prosecuted O
or O
still O
being O
prosecuted O
, O
data O
that O
come O
out O
of O
newspaper O
articles O
and O
court O
records O
. O

For O
his O
part O
, O
the O
Attorney B-PER
General I-PER
of O
Victoria B-LOC
, O
Rob B-PER
Hulls I-PER
, O
said O
there O
is O
no O
one O
to O
control O
that O
the O
information O
contained O
in O
CrimeNet B-MISC
are O
truthful O
. O

Hulls B-PER
pointed O
out O
that O
in O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORG
legal O
system O
, O
on O
which O
the O
Australian O
justice O
system O
is O
based O
, O
it O
is O
essential O
that O
the O
person O
is O
judged O
only O
on O
the O
evidence O
presented O
to O
the O
judge O
. O

The O
website O
is O
also O
considered O
the O
cause O
of O
the O
premature O
conclusion O
in O
a O
murder O
case O
recently O
tried O
in O
the O
city O
of O
Melbourne B-LOC
, O
capital O
of O
the O
state O
of O
Victoria B-LOC
. O

- O

Izquierda B-ORG
Unida I-ORG
de I-ORG
Santander I-ORG
today O
presented O
its O
new O
quarterly O
newsletter O
" O
City B-MISC
" O
, O
a O
publication O
of O
which O
10,000 O
copies O
will O
be O
distributed O
preferably O
in O
the O
neighborhoods O
of O
the O
municipality O
where O
the O
collation O
has O
greater O
citizen O
support O
. O

The O
spokesman O
for O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Political I-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
IU I-ORG
in O
Santander B-LOC
, O
Ernesto B-PER
Gomez I-PER
de I-PER
la I-PER
Hera I-PER
, O
explained O
today O
at O
a O
press O
conference O
that O
this O
newsletter O
aims O
, O
rather O
than O
inform O
, O
open O
spaces O
for O
debate O
and O
serve O
as O
" O
seed O
of O
political O
mobilization O
" O
in O
the O
city O
. O

Gomez B-PER
de I-PER
la I-PER
Hera I-PER
commented O
that O
the O
contents O
of O
the O
publication O
" O
City B-MISC
" O
respond O
to O
the O
program O
that O
he O
headed O
as O
a O
candidate O
in O
the O
municipal O
elections O
of O
1999 O
, O
in O
which O
IU B-ORG
lost O
its O
representation O
in O
the O
City B-ORG
Council O
, O
and O
hoped O
that O
its O
dissemination O
will O
be O
wider O
once O
the O
coalition O
resolves O
its O
economic O
crisis O
. O

For O
the O
moment O
, O
" O
City B-MISC
" O
will O
be O
distributed O
preferentially O
in O
the O
neighborhoods O
with O
more O
IU B-ORG
voters O
, O
among O
which O
the O
municipal O
spokesman O
for O
the O
coalition O
cited O
the O
northern O
slope O
of O
Alta B-LOC
Street I-LOC
, O
Cazoña B-LOC
and O
the O
area O
between O
the O
streets O
Castilla B-LOC
and O
Hermida B-LOC
. O

" O
City B-MISC
" O
, O
a O
bulletin O
composed O
of O
two O
sheets O
folded O
in O
half O
, O
takes O
to O
the O
streets O
in O
its O
first O
issue O
criticizing O
the O
construction O
works O
of O
subway O
parking O
lots O
, O
the O
inconvenience O
they O
are O
causing O
to O
neighbors O
and O
the O
way O
they O
will O
be O
exploited O
. O

Gomez B-PER
de I-PER
la I-PER
Hera I-PER
believes O
that O
" O
the O
PP B-ORG
policy O
of O
making O
money O
absolutely O
everything O
and O
that O
this O
money O
is O
distributed O
mainly O
for O
their O
friends O
" O
has O
turned O
Santander B-LOC
in O
" O
a O
trap O
full O
of O
holes O
, O
when O
all O
the O
cities O
of O
Western O
Europe B-LOC
are O
trying O
to O
make O
their O
urban O
centers O
more O
livable O
" O
. O

In O
his O
view O
, O
the O
reasons O
of O
the O
City B-ORG
Council O
to O
carry O
out O
these O
works O
are O
" O
crematísticas O
, O
mercenary O
, O
but O
have O
nothing O
to O
do O
with O
the O
future O
of O
Santander B-LOC
or O
with O
the O
welfare O
of O
the O
vast O
majority O
of O
its O
population O
" O
. O

EFE B-ORG
- O
Cantabria B-LOC
Frankfurt B-LOC
( O
FRG B-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFECOM B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
German O
telephone O
group O
Deutsche B-ORG
Telekom I-ORG
has O
acquired O
the O
remaining O
50 O
percent O
of O
the O
Swiss O
telecommunications O
operator O
Multilink B-ORG
, O
which O
until O
now O
owned O
by O
France B-ORG
Telecom I-ORG
, O
and O
has O
become O
its O
sole O
owner O
, O
reported O
today O
, O
Thursday O
, O
the O
German O
company O
. O

In O
return O
, O
Deutsche B-ORG
Telekom I-ORG
will O
sell O
its O
25 O
percent O
stake O
in O
the O
British O
joint O
venture O
MetroHoldings B-ORG
to O
the O
French O
consortium O
. O

Multilink B-ORG
was O
created O
in O
1998 O
and O
offers O
telephone O
and O
data O
transmission O
services O
in O
Switzerland B-LOC
and O
abroad O
, O
in O
addition O
to O
having O
its O
own O
urban O
fiber O
optic O
network O
. O

Deutsche B-ORG
Telekom I-ORG
described O
this O
purchase O
, O
the O
price O
of O
which O
it O
did O
not O
specify O
, O
as O
another O
step O
towards O
its O
internationalization O
through O
majority O
acquisitions O
aimed O
at O
gaining O
management O
control O
of O
these O
companies O
. O

= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O
= O

- O

Mérida B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
President O
of O
the O
Government O
of B-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
, O
Juan B-PER
Carlos I-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Ibarra I-PER
, O
will O
receive O
at O
the O
headquarters O
of O
the O
Presidency B-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Government O
of O
Extremadura O
, O
relatives O
of O
several O
of O
those O
convicted O
in O
the O
" O
Lasa B-MISC
- I-MISC
Zabala I-MISC
" O
trial O
, O
including O
Lourdes B-PER
Díez I-PER
Urraca I-PER
, O
wife O
of O
former O
civil O
governor O
of O
Guipúzcoa B-LOC
Julen B-PER
Elgorriaga I-PER
; O
and O
Antonio B-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Galindo I-PER
, O
brother O
of O
General O
Enrique B-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Galindo I-PER
. O

( O
with O
photograph O
) O
( O
PLENARY O
ASSEMBLY O
) O
. O

- O

Mérida B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
Plenary B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Assembly I-ORG
of I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
will O
debate O
, O
among O
others O
, O
a O
non O
- O
legislative O
proposal O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
- I-ORG
NI I-ORG
, O
PP B-ORG
and O
Mixed B-ORG
- I-ORG
Deputy I-ORG
groups O
of O
IU O
in O
which O
the O
central O
government B-ORG
is O
urged O
to O
enact O
a O
Ministerial B-MISC
Order I-MISC
that O
reflects O
the O
regionalization O
of O
the O
base O
area O
for O
the O
cultivation O
of O
corn O
. O

( O
ENTREPRENEURS O
) O
. O

- O

Mérida B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
Minister O
of O
Economy B-MISC
, I-MISC
Industry I-MISC
. O
Commerce O
, O
Manuel B-PER
Amigo I-PER
, O
and O
the O
presidents O
of O
Caja B-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
and O
Caja B-ORG
Badajoz I-ORG
, O
Jesús B-PER
Medina I-PER
and O
José B-PER
Manuel I-PER
Sánchez I-PER
Rojas I-PER
, O
respectively O
, O
will O
sign O
a O
collaboration O
agreement O
to O
finance O
business O
projects O
of O
young O
entrepreneurs O
. O

( O
CARLOS B-PER
V I-PER
- O
CONGRESS O
) O
. O

- O

Jaraíz O
de O
la O
Vera B-LOC
( O
Cáceres B-LOC
) O
. O

- O

The O
Historical B-ORG
Institute I-ORG
" O
Hoffmeyer O
" O
will O
host O
the O
inauguration O
and O
first O
session O
of O
the O
Congress B-MISC
of I-MISC
Modern I-MISC
History I-MISC
" O
Charles O
. O
and B-MISC
the I-MISC
end I-MISC
of I-MISC
an I-MISC
era I-MISC
. O
1500 O
- O
1558 O
" O
, O
which O
is O
part O
of O
the O
commemoration O
of O
the O
V B-MISC
Centenary I-MISC
of O
the O
birth O
of O
the O
emperor O
. O

Informative O
agenda O
: O
- O
10:00 O
h. O
- O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
President O
of O
the O
Regional O
Government O
of B-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
, O
Juan B-PER
Carlos I-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Ibarra I-PER
, O
will O
receive O
relatives O
of O
several O
of O
those O
convicted O
in O
the O
" O
Lasa B-MISC
- I-MISC
Zabala I-MISC
" O
trial O
at O
the O
headquarters O
of O
the O
Presidency O
of O
the O
Government O
of O
Extremadura O
. O

10:00 O
h. O
- O
Mérida B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
Minister O
of O
Economy B-MISC
, I-MISC
Industry I-MISC
. O
Commerce O
, O
Manuel B-PER
Amigo I-PER
, O
and O
the O
presidents O
of O
Caja B-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
and O
Caja B-ORG
Badajoz I-ORG
, O
Jesús B-ORG
Medina I-ORG
and O
José B-PER
Manuel I-PER
Sánchez I-PER
Rojas I-PER
, O
respectively O
, O
will O
sign O
a O
collaboration O
agreement O
. O

10:00 O
h. O
- O
Jaraíz B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Vera I-LOC
( O
Cáceres B-LOC
) O
. O

- O

The O
Congress O
" O
Charles O
. O
and B-MISC
the I-MISC
end I-MISC
of I-MISC
an I-MISC
era I-MISC
. O
1500 O
- O
1558 O
" O
. O

10:00 O
h. O
- O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
Minister O
of O
Housing O
, O
Urbanism B-MISC
. I-MISC
Transportes I-MISC
, O
Javier B-PER
Corominas I-PER
, O
will O
deliver O
94 O
special O
regime O
housing O
units O
built O
by O
the O
" O
Magenta B-ORG
" I-ORG
Group I-ORG
in O
" O
La B-LOC
Corchera I-LOC
" O
. O

10:30 O
h. O
- O
Plasencia B-LOC
( O
Cáceres B-LOC
) O
. O

- O

The O
Mayor O
, O
José B-PER
Luis I-PER
Díez I-PER
, O
will O
speak O
on O
various O
issues O
of O
municipal O
interest O
. O

11:00 O
h. O
- O
Mérida B-LOC
. O

- O

A O
session O
of O
the O
Plenary B-MISC
of I-MISC
the I-MISC
Assembly I-MISC
of I-MISC
Extremadura I-MISC
will O
be O
held O
. O

12:00 O
h. O
- O
Montijo B-LOC
( O
Badajoz B-LOC
) O
. O

- O

The O
Minister O
of O
Culture B-MISC
, O
Francisco B-PER
Muñoz I-PER
, O
will O
inaugurate O
the O
IV O
local O
Book B-MISC
Fair I-MISC
. O

12:00 O
h. O
- O
Azuaga B-LOC
( O
Badajoz B-LOC
) O
. O

- O

Inauguration O
of O
the O
XIX O
Trade O
Fair B-MISC
of I-MISC
the I-MISC
Southern I-MISC
Countryside I-MISC
of I-MISC
Extremadura I-MISC
( O
FECSUR B-MISC
) O
. O

12:30 O
h. O
- O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
Plenary B-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
City O
Council O
will O
discuss O
issues O
such O
as O
the O
requalification O
of O
land O
adjacent O
to O
the O
" O
Salesianos B-LOC
" I-LOC
School I-LOC
. O

20:30 O
h. O
- O
Cáceres B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
Minister O
of O
Culture B-MISC
, O
Francisco B-PER
Muñoz I-PER
, O
will O
attend O
the O
presentation O
of O
the O
book O
" O
Seres B-MISC
. I-MISC
Stars I-MISC
" O
, O
which O
analyzes O
the O
origins O
of O
the O
Universe B-MISC
, O
and O
data O
on O
the O
research O
project O
" O
The B-MISC
First I-MISC
Settlers I-MISC
of I-MISC
Extremadura I-MISC
" O
. O

- O

: O
- O
h. O
- O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
public O
television O
and O
the O
information O
society O
, O
the O
regional O
funding O
, O
the O
contents O
of O
the O
extracurricular O
day O
and O
the O
creation O
of O
an O
Advisory O
Council B-ORG
are O
the O
first O
issues O
to O
be O
negotiated O
from O
tomorrow O
the O
PP B-ORG
and O
the O
Junta B-ORG
de I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
to O
reach O
a O
regional O
pact O
on O
13 O
issues O
of O
interest O
. O

- O

: O
- O
h. O
- O
Cáceres B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
activities O
of O
" O
Agora O
. O
The B-MISC
peninsular I-MISC
debate I-MISC
" O
. O

By O
Caius B-PER
Apicius I-PER
Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

A O
vice O
that O
should O
never O
be O
incurred O
by O
anyone O
who O
considers O
himself O
a O
gourmet O
and O
aspires O
to O
be O
recognized O
as O
such O
is O
that O
of O
patriotism O
, O
understood O
as O
excessive O
and O
inappropriate O
display O
of O
patriotism O
: O
the O
gourmet O
is O
not O
stateless O
, O
but O
must O
flee O
like O
the O
plague O
of O
chauvinism O
. O

Years O
ago O
, O
in O
one O
of O
his O
travel O
books O
, O
the O
Nobel B-PER
Literature I-PER
Camilo I-PER
José I-PER
Cela I-PER
said O
that O
the O
patriot O
is O
the O
one O
who O
is O
proud O
of O
the O
place O
where O
he O
was O
born O
and O
defends O
it O
, O
an O
attitude O
in O
which O
he O
is O
right O
, O
while O
the O
patriotic O
- O
at O
that O
time O
, O
Cela B-PER
used O
the O
word O
' O
nationalist O
' O
- O
is O
the O
one O
who O
proclaims O
against O
all O
odds O
that O
his O
homeland O
is O
superior O
to O
all O
others O
, O
something O
in O
which O
- O
said O
Cela B-PER
- O
may O
well O
not O
be O
right O
. O

In O
this O
matter O
of O
food O
, O
patriotism O
abounds O
too O
much O
. O

One O
has O
no O
objection O
to O
accept O
that O
everyone O
defends O
the O
cuisine O
and O
products O
of O
their O
land O
... O
as O
long O
as O
this O
defense O
does O
not O
imply O
contempt O
for O
what O
is O
alien O
to O
the O
gastronomic O
customs O
of O
their O
homeland O
. O

In O
this O
case O
, O
it O
will O
be O
necessary O
to O
go O
from O
Cela B-PER
to O
Antonio B-PER
Machado I-PER
and O
remember O
that O
of O
" O
despise O
what O
ignores O
... O
" O
. O

" O
The O
problem O
of O
gastronomic O
patriotism O
- O
and O
, O
let O
us O
not O
deceive O
ourselves O
, O
of O
any O
other O
- O
is O
precisely O
that O
: O
ignorance O
. O

Of O
course O
, O
that O
same O
ignorance O
can O
make O
many O
fall O
into O
the O
opposite O
defect O
: O
the O
, O
let O
's O
say O
, O
papanatism O
that O
makes O
for O
these O
citizens O
everything O
foreign O
is O
better O
. O

Well O
... O
neither O
. O

A O
gastronome O
is O
something O
like O
a O
traveler O
, O
but O
a O
traveler O
, O
not O
a O
tourist O
; O
a O
traveler O
, O
let O
's O
say O
, O
in O
the O
style O
of O
the O
nineteenth O
century O
, O
a O
person O
full O
of O
curiosity O
and O
freed O
, O
as O
far O
as O
possible O
, O
of O
prejudices O
, O
willing O
to O
accept O
the O
good O
things O
of O
others O
without O
denying O
their O
own O
. O

But O
this O
universality O
of O
the O
gastronome O
- O
the O
first O
to O
universalize O
gastronomy O
were O
the O
Romans O
- O
does O
not O
imply O
the O
renunciation O
of O
one O
's O
own O
. O

Much O
less O
the O
absurd O
mixtures O
, O
that O
cuisine O
that O
today O
we O
call O
' O
fusion O
' O
, O
very O
defensible O
. O
when O
it O
does O
not O
derive O
, O
as O
in O
so O
many O
cases O
, O
in O
' O
confusion O
' O
cuisine O
. O

We O
will O
always O
insist O
that O
a O
cuisine O
, O
to O
be O
truly O
great O
, O
must O
be O
faithful O
to O
its O
land O
, O
and O
also O
to O
its O
time O
. O

But O
it O
must O
, O
of O
course O
, O
be O
open O
to O
foreign O
incorporations O
. O

What O
would O
European O
cuisine O
be O
without O
potatoes O
, O
for O
example O
, O
or O
Mediterranean O
cuisine O
without O
tomatoes O
, O
both O
products O
that O
arrived O
in O
the O
Old B-MISC
World I-MISC
less O
than O
five O
centuries O
ago O
? O

Imagine O
that O
among O
those O
Spaniards O
, O
who O
were O
the O
ones O
who O
brought O
those O
American O
gifts O
to O
Europe B-LOC
, O
gastronomic O
patriotism O
would O
have O
prevailed O
: O
potatoes O
and O
tomatoes O
would O
have O
remained O
botanical O
curiosities O
. O

There O
is O
not O
, O
there O
can O
not O
be O
, O
a O
universal O
cuisine O
; O
remember O
that O
horror O
known O
as O
' O
international O
cuisine O
' O
so O
frequent O
in O
hotel O
restaurants O
. O

But O
neither O
can O
there O
be O
a O
cuisine O
closed O
in O
on O
itself O
. O

It O
is O
not O
possible O
to O
ask O
oneself O
, O
when O
faced O
with O
a O
new O
food O
, O
a O
new O
spice O
, O
where O
does O
it O
come O
from O
? O
without O
first O
investigating O
what O
is O
really O
important O
: O
is O
it O
tasty O
? O

Well O
, O
if O
it O
tastes O
good O
... O
go O
ahead O
, O
wherever O
it O
comes O
from O
. O

Of O
course O
, O
it O
is O
necessary O
to O
study O
how O
we O
adapt O
this O
new O
product O
to O
our O
most O
deeply O
rooted O
culinary O
uses O
. O

Thus O
, O
our O
cuisine O
evolves O
, O
enriches O
itself O
. O

Otherwise O
, O
by O
closing O
in O
on O
itself O
, O
it O
ends O
up O
weakening O
and O
becoming O
extinct O
; O
inbreeding O
is O
not O
good O
for O
almost O
anything O
. O

So O
keep O
an O
open O
mind O
, O
and O
your O
senses O
even O
more O
so O
. O

That O
, O
to O
paraphrase O
Shakespeare B-PER
in O
' O
Hamlet B-MISC
' O
, O
there O
are O
richer O
things O
on O
earth B-MISC
than O
your O
wisdom O
, O
or O
your O
personal O
experience O
reaches O
. O

Do O
not O
become O
eunuchs O
of O
taste O
by O
mere O
jingoism O
: O
you O
will O
miss O
so O
many O
rich O
things O
... O

... O
- O
. O

- O

The O
Museum B-ORG
of I-ORG
Art I-ORG
Glass O
Alcorcon B-LOC
hosts O
from O
today O
until O
June O
28 O
an O
exhibition O
of O
glass O
sculptures O
by O
Romanian O
artist O
Edward B-PER
Leibovtiz I-PER
, O
consisting O
of O
35 O
pieces O
of O
different O
formats O
and O
whose O
size O
ranges O
between O
40 O
centimeters O
and O
2 O
meters O
of O
some O
of O
the O
figures O
. O

The O
pieces O
of O
this O
exhibition O
, O
organized O
by O
the O
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Culture I-ORG
, O
have O
a O
figurative O
character O
and O
they O
appreciate O
faces O
, O
bodies O
and O
various O
fantasies O
, O
even O
showing O
erotic O
aspects O
. O

Edward B-PER
Leibovitz I-PER
, O
who O
currently O
resides O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
has O
exhibited O
in O
his O
30 O
years O
of O
work O
as O
a O
contemporary O
glass O
sculptor O
in O
numerous O
European O
, O
American O
and O
Asian O
museums O
in O
countries O
such O
as O
Japan B-LOC
, O
Germany B-LOC
, O
France B-LOC
, O
Belgium B-LOC
and O
Israel B-LOC
. O

Those O
attending O
the O
exhibition O
, O
which O
will O
open O
this O
afternoon O
, O
will O
enjoy O
the O
various O
works O
of O
Leibovitz B-PER
, O
who O
points O
out O
that O
" O
I O
like O
to O
work O
the O
composition O
of O
the O
piece O
and O
try O
to O
convey O
the O
fantasy O
of O
life O
with O
an O
absurd O
aspect O
" O
. O

The O
inauguration O
, O
scheduled O
at O
20 O
hours O
, O
will O
be O
attended O
by O
the O
artist O
and O
the O
Councillor O
for O
Culture B-MISC
, O
Francisco B-PER
Torres I-PER
, O
from O
whose O
Department O
has O
extended O
an O
invitation O
to O
the O
ambassadors O
of O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
Israel B-LOC
and O
Romania B-LOC
, O
consulates O
that O
according O
to O
municipal O
sources O
have O
confirmed O
their O
presence O
through O
various O
representatives O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFECOM B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
maximum O
capital O
increase O
of O
Terra B-ORG
for O
the O
exchange O
of O
shares O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
including O
the O
stock O
options O
of O
the O
workers O
of O
the O
American O
company O
, O
will O
not O
exceed O
340,922,712 O
shares O
which O
, O
at O
yesterday O
's O
closing O
price O
on O
the O
stock O
exchange O
( O
50.9 O
pesetas O
per O
share O
) O
, O
would O
be O
2.887 O
billion O
pesetas O
. O

This O
is O
stated O
in O
an O
explanatory O
note O
from O
the O
Telefónica B-ORG
group O
to O
the O
National O
Securities O
Market B-ORG
Commission I-ORG
( O
CNMV O
) O
on O
the O
capital O
increases O
that O
will O
be O
submitted O
for O
approval O
at O
the O
General B-MISC
Shareholders I-MISC
' O
Meeting O
in O
June O
to O
carry O
out O
the O
operation O
of O
its O
subsidiary O
Terra B-ORG
Network I-ORG
on O
the O
purchase O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
a O
U.S. O
Internet B-MISC
portal O
. O

In O
that O
note O
of O
clarification O
, O
Telefónica B-ORG
indicates O
that O
these O
are O
maximum O
capital O
increases O
, O
to O
cover O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

The O
increase O
of O
340,922,712 O
shares O
for O
the O
exchange O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
has O
been O
made O
, O
it O
says O
, O
taking O
into O
account O
that O
the O
American O
company O
has O
112,192,815 O
shares O
, O
and O
options O
provided O
for O
the O
acquisition O
of O
assets O
in O
the O
amount O
of O
9.7 O
million O
titles O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
have O
stock O
option O
plans O
for O
23,640,000 O
securities O
, O
and O
at O
the O
closing O
of O
the O
transaction O
with O
Telefonica B-ORG
there O
may O
be O
another O
7,440,000 O
stock O
options O
. O

The O
note O
notes O
that O
the O
maximum O
number O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
shares O
that O
could O
be O
issued O
in O
total O
for O
exchange O
with O
Telefónica B-ORG
will O
not O
exceed O
158,568,703 O
shares O
, O
which O
would O
be O
exchanged O
for O
a O
maximum O
of O
2.15 O
shares O
of O
the O
Spanish O
company O
each O
. O

As O
for O
the O
issuance O
of O
38,346,984 O
shares O
of O
warrants O
( O
rights O
) O
for O
the O
purchase O
of O
stock O
options O
for O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
and O
which O
could O
involve O
a O
capital O
increase O
of O
82.45 O
million O
shares O
, O
the O
text O
clarifies O
that O
this O
is O
a O
maximum O
number O
that O
is O
already O
included O
in O
the O
increase O
of O
340,922,712 O
shares O
. O

The O
capital O
increase O
of O
35.48 O
million O
shares O
to O
be O
submitted O
for O
approval O
by O
the O
shareholders O
' O
meeting O
, O
which O
as O
of O
yesterday O
would O
mean O
300,514 O
million O
pesetas O
, O
and O
which O
will O
be O
carried O
out O
for O
a O
price O
of O
62 O
euros O
- O
higher O
than O
its O
quotation O
these O
days O
in O
the O
stock O
exchange O
- O
is O
the O
one O
agreed O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
since O
it O
is O
the O
quotation O
of O
the O
day O
of O
the O
signing O
of O
the O
agreement O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
Terra B-ORG
is O
currently O
trading O
below O
62 O
euros O
could O
cause O
the O
operator O
's O
shareholders O
not O
to O
participate O
in O
the O
capital O
increase O
, O
which O
would O
oblige O
Telefónica B-ORG
to O
also O
subscribe O
to O
this O
increase O
, O
as O
it O
is O
included O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

This O
increase O
, O
he O
explains O
, O
is O
the O
result O
of O
dividing O
the O
amount O
of O
the O
committed O
increase O
of O
2,200 O
million O
euros O
by O
the O
issue O
rate O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
maximum O
capital O
increase O
of O
Terra B-ORG
for O
the O
exchange O
of O
shares O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
including O
the O
stock O
options O
of O
the O
workers O
of O
the O
American O
company O
, O
will O
not O
exceed O
340,922,712 O
shares O
which O
, O
at O
yesterday O
's O
closing O
price O
on O
the O
stock O
exchange O
( O
50.9 O
pesetas O
per O
share O
) O
, O
would O
be O
2.887 O
billion O
pesetas O
. O

This O
is O
stated O
in O
an O
explanatory O
note O
from O
the O
Telefónica B-ORG
group O
to O
the O
National O
Securities O
Market B-ORG
Commission I-ORG
( O
CNMV O
) O
on O
the O
capital O
increases O
that O
will O
be O
submitted O
for O
approval O
at O
the O
General B-ORG
Shareholders I-ORG
' O
Meeting O
in O
June O
to O
carry O
out O
the O
operation O
of O
its O
subsidiary O
Terra B-ORG
Network I-ORG
on O
the O
purchase O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
a O
U.S. O
Internet B-MISC
portal O
. O

In O
that O
note O
of O
clarification O
, O
Telefónica B-ORG
indicates O
that O
these O
are O
maximum O
capital O
increases O
, O
to O
cover O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

The O
increase O
of O
340,922,712 O
shares O
for O
the O
exchange O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
has O
been O
made O
, O
it O
says O
, O
taking O
into O
account O
that O
the O
American O
company O
has O
112,192,815 O
shares O
, O
and O
options O
provided O
for O
the O
acquisition O
of O
assets O
in O
the O
amount O
of O
9.7 O
million O
titles O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
have O
stock O
option O
plans O
for O
23,640,000 O
securities O
, O
and O
at O
the O
closing O
of O
the O
transaction O
with O
Telefonica B-ORG
there O
may O
be O
another O
7,440,000 O
stock O
options O
. O

The O
note O
notes O
that O
the O
maximum O
number O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
shares O
that O
could O
be O
issued O
in O
total O
for O
exchange O
with O
Telefónica B-ORG
will O
not O
exceed O
158,568,703 O
shares O
, O
which O
would O
be O
exchanged O
for O
a O
maximum O
of O
2.15 O
shares O
of O
the O
Spanish O
company O
each O
. O

As O
for O
the O
issuance O
of O
38,346,984 O
shares O
of O
warrants O
( O
rights O
) O
for O
the O
purchase O
of O
stock O
options O
for O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
and O
which O
could O
involve O
a O
capital O
increase O
of O
82.45 O
million O
shares O
, O
the O
text O
clarifies O
that O
this O
is O
a O
maximum O
number O
that O
is O
already O
included O
in O
the O
increase O
of O
340,922,712 O
shares O
. O

The O
capital O
increase O
of O
35.48 O
million O
shares O
to O
be O
submitted O
for O
approval O
by O
the O
shareholders O
' O
meeting O
, O
which O
as O
of O
yesterday O
would O
mean O
300,514 O
million O
pesetas O
, O
and O
which O
will O
be O
carried O
out O
for O
a O
price O
of O
62 O
euros O
- O
higher O
than O
its O
quotation O
these O
days O
in O
the O
stock O
exchange O
- O
is O
the O
one O
agreed O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
since O
it O
is O
the O
quotation O
of O
the O
day O
of O
the O
signing O
of O
the O
agreement O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
Terra B-ORG
is O
currently O
trading O
below O
62 O
euros O
could O
cause O
the O
operator O
's O
shareholders O
not O
to O
participate O
in O
the O
capital O
increase O
, O
which O
would O
oblige O
Telefónica B-ORG
to O
also O
subscribe O
to O
this O
increase O
, O
as O
it O
is O
included O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

This O
increase O
, O
he O
explains O
, O
is O
the O
result O
of O
dividing O
the O
amount O
of O
the O
committed O
increase O
of O
2,200 O
million O
euros O
by O
the O
issue O
rate O
. O

( O
DUQUES B-PER
LUGO I-PER
) O
. O

- O

Padrón B-LOC
- O
Lugo B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
Infanta B-PER
Elena I-PER
and O
her O
husband O
Jaime B-PER
de I-PER
Marichalar I-PER
, O
dukes O
of O
Lugo B-LOC
, O
begin O
a O
two O
- O
day O
visit O
to O
Galicia B-LOC
, O
in O
which O
it O
is O
expected O
that O
, O
in O
addition O
to O
inaugurating O
a O
classroom O
of O
the O
Cela B-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
, O
participate O
in O
an O
act O
of O
declaration O
of O
support O
for O
the O
Roman O
wall O
lucense O
as O
a O
World B-MISC
Heritage O
Site O
. O

( O
CONSELLO O
XUNTA B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
president O
of O
the O
Xunta B-ORG
will O
report O
on O
the O
agreements O
taken O
in O
the O
council O
of O
the O
Galician O
Government B-ORG
. O

( O
BNG B-ORG
GROUP O
) O
. O

- O

Madrid B-LOC
. O

- O

The O
deputies O
of O
the O
BNG B-ORG
present O
in O
the O
Constitutional B-LOC
appeal O
for O
having O
been O
denied O
the O
obtaining O
of O
own O
group O
( O
PP B-ORG
CONGRESOS O
) O
. O

- O

Santiago B-LOC
/ O
A B-LOC
Coruña I-LOC
. O

- O

The O
secretary O
of O
the O
Galician O
PP B-ORG
, O
Jesus B-PER
Palmou I-PER
, O
offers O
a O
statement O
to O
EFE B-ORG
to O
explain O
the O
details O
of O
the O
provincial O
congresses O
this O
weekend O
in O
A B-LOC
Coruña I-LOC
and O
Pontevedra B-LOC
. O

. O

- O

A B-LOC
Coruña I-LOC
. O

- O

The O
Museum B-ORG
of I-ORG
Fine I-ORG
Arts I-ORG
of O
A B-LOC
Coruña I-LOC
inaugurates O
the O
photographic O
exhibition O
" O
Emmanuel B-MISC
Souguez I-MISC
. O
Photographs O
1928 O
- O
1958 O
" O
. O

. O

EFE B-ORG
GALICIA B-LOC
by O
Kathy B-PER
Seleme I-PER
Beirut B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
22 O
years O
of O
Israeli O
occupation O
of O
southern O
Lebanon O
ended O
in O
a O
few O
hours O
, O
but O
the O
underlying O
problems O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
persist O
, O
a O
country O
still O
hostage O
to O
its O
two O
powerful O
neighbors O
, O
Israel B-LOC
and O
Syria B-LOC
, O
which O
can O
use O
it O
at O
any O
time O
for O
their O
interests O
. O

The O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
south O
, O
although O
planned O
and O
announced O
, O
caught O
everyone O
off O
guard O
by O
its O
haste O
, O
six O
weeks O
earlier O
than O
announced O
by O
the O
Government B-ORG
of I-ORG
Israel I-ORG
, O
and O
by O
the O
chaotic O
manner O
in O
which O
it O
occurred O
. O

Israel B-LOC
withdrew O
in O
little O
more O
than O
48 O
hours O
from O
the O
south O
after O
the O
collapse O
of O
its O
allies O
in O
the O
South B-ORG
Lebanese I-ORG
Army I-ORG
( O
FSA B-ORG
) O
, O
which O
had O
helped O
it O
to O
maintain O
its O
occupation O
, O
and O
which O
it O
intended O
to O
leave O
in O
a O
" O
buffer O
zone O
" O
to O
protect O
its O
northern O
border O
, O
along O
with O
the O
United O
Nations B-ORG
Interim I-ORG
Force I-ORG
in I-ORG
Lebanon I-ORG
( O
UNIFIL B-ORG
) O
. O

Paradoxically O
, O
it O
had O
to O
cede O
ground O
to O
its O
main O
enemy O
, O
the O
Shiite O
group O
Hezbollah B-ORG
( O
Party B-ORG
of I-ORG
God I-ORG
) O
, O
which O
since O
the O
second O
Israeli O
invasion O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
in O
1982 O
, O
led O
the O
guerrilla O
organizations O
fighting O
the O
occupation O
. O

Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
supported O
by O
Beirut B-ORG
, O
Damascus O
and O
Tehran O
, O
took O
control O
of O
the O
liberated O
south O
in O
the O
absence O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
, O
which O
has O
not O
yet O
defined O
the O
mission O
it O
will O
entrust O
to O
its O
" O
blue O
helmets O
" O
, O
whose O
troops O
it O
wants O
to O
increase O
from O
4,500 O
to O
7,935 O
. O

Although O
Beirut B-ORG
considers O
that O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
is O
incomplete O
, O
because O
it O
did O
not O
include O
the O
controversial O
Chebaa B-LOC
farms O
, O
on O
the O
border O
with O
Syria B-LOC
, O
and O
the O
release O
of O
some O
20 O
Lebanese O
detained O
in O
Israel B-LOC
, O
assured O
that O
it O
will O
cooperate O
with O
the O
UN B-ORG
. O

Israel B-ORG
and O
the O
UN B-ORG
claim O
that O
these O
farms O
are O
Syrian O
, O
but O
Damascus O
and O
Beirut B-LOC
claim O
that O
they O
are O
Lebanese O
and O
, O
to O
that O
effect O
, O
the O
Government B-ORG
has O
sent O
several O
documents O
to O
the O
United B-ORG
Nations I-ORG
to O
attest O
to O
its O
sovereignty O
. O

The O
leader O
of O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
Sheikh O
Hasan B-PER
Nasrala I-PER
, O
for O
his O
part O
, O
announced O
that O
he O
will O
continue O
the O
fight O
until O
the O
liberation O
of O
that O
territory O
, O
located O
at O
the O
foot O
of O
Mount B-LOC
Hermon I-LOC
and O
rich O
in O
aquifers O
. O

In O
response O
to O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
Israel B-ORG
threatened O
with O
" O
painful O
responses O
" O
in O
case O
of O
continued O
attacks O
on O
its O
territory O
, O
referring O
to O
the O
" O
katiuska O
" O
rockets O
that O
this O
group O
launches O
sporadically O
against O
the O
Israeli O
north O
. O

Apparently O
, O
Syria B-ORG
, O
which O
exerts O
a O
preponderant O
influence O
in O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
where O
it O
has O
about O
35,000 O
soldiers O
stationed O
, O
gave O
for O
the O
moment O
carte O
blanche O
to O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
a O
pro O
- O
Iranian O
group O
in O
which O
Damascus O
also O
has O
a O
strong O
influence O
. O

Israel B-ORG
's O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
south O
was O
part O
of O
the O
strategy O
of O
Israeli O
Prime O
Minister O
, O
Ehud B-PER
Barak I-PER
, O
to O
force O
Syria B-ORG
in O
its O
negotiations O
on O
the O
Golan B-LOC
, O
occupied O
by O
Israel B-ORG
in O
1967 O
and O
annexed O
in O
1981 O
. O

In O
theory O
, O
Syria B-ORG
is O
harmed O
by O
the O
unilateral O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
southern O
Lebanon O
, O
as O
it O
deprives O
Damascus O
of O
a O
card O
that O
it O
used O
, O
through O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
to O
put O
pressure O
on O
Israel B-ORG
. O

However O
, O
in O
practice O
, O
Damascus B-ORG
, O
which O
is O
adamant O
on O
the O
issue O
of O
the O
return O
of O
the O
Golan B-LOC
to O
the O
pre O
- O
June O
1967 O
demarcation O
line O
, O
appears O
to O
have O
forced O
Israel B-ORG
to O
execute O
its O
threat O
and O
has O
been O
strengthened O
in O
its O
control O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
. O

If O
Israel B-ORG
occupied O
ten O
percent O
of O
Lebanese O
territory O
, O
Syrian O
troops O
are O
deployed O
in O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
country O
and O
it O
is O
not O
ruled O
out O
that O
they O
could O
be O
assigned O
a O
mission O
in O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
thus O
complicating O
their O
withdrawal O
, O
despite O
the O
desire O
of O
a O
majority O
of O
Lebanese O
. O

The O
major O
powers O
assigned O
to O
Syria B-ORG
the O
role O
of O
guardian O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
and O
know O
that O
if O
it O
does O
not O
reach O
an O
agreement O
with O
Israel B-ORG
, O
the O
Lebanese O
situation O
will O
remain O
insecure O
and O
unpredictable O
. O

The O
only O
hope O
for O
the O
Lebanese O
situation O
to O
stabilize O
is O
to O
achieve O
a O
comprehensive O
peace O
in O
the O
Middle B-LOC
East I-LOC
, O
so O
that O
this O
country O
, O
which O
has O
been O
the O
main O
victim O
, O
along O
with O
the O
Palestinians O
, O
the O
Arab O
- O
Israeli O
conflict O
, O
will O
not O
remain O
so O
in O
the O
future O
. O
by O
Orlando B-PER
Lizama I-PER
Washington B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
U.S. B-ORG
President O
, O
Bill B-PER
Clinton I-PER
, O
scored O
a O
major O
triumph O
in O
foreign O
policy O
with O
the O
approval O
in O
the O
House B-ORG
of I-ORG
Representatives I-ORG
of O
a O
trade O
agreement O
with O
China B-ORG
that O
will O
add O
to O
the O
economic O
success O
of O
his O
administration O
. O

Political O
analysts O
said O
today O
that O
the O
decision O
of O
the O
House B-ORG
, O
which O
has O
secured O
the O
approval O
of O
the O
Senate B-ORG
, O
will O
open O
a O
new O
chapter O
in O
relations O
between O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
and O
China B-ORG
and O
, O
above O
all O
, O
the O
world O
's O
largest O
market O
for O
American O
products O
. O

By O
approving O
the O
granting O
of O
permanent O
trade O
privileges O
to O
China B-ORG
by O
237 O
votes O
to O
197 O
against O
, O
the O
House B-ORG
on O
Wednesday O
ended O
the O
practice O
of O
discussing O
those O
privileges O
every O
year O
and O
ensured O
the O
application O
to O
Chinese O
products O
of O
the O
same O
tariffs O
that O
are O
charged O
on O
those O
of O
other O
countries O
. O

Also O
, O
after O
China B-ORG
got O
a O
similar O
agreement O
last O
week O
with O
the O
European B-ORG
Union I-ORG
, O
the O
Beijing B-LOC
authorities O
secured O
their O
country O
's O
entry O
into O
the O
World B-ORG
Trade I-ORG
Organization I-ORG
( O
WTO B-ORG
) O
. O

In O
exchange O
for O
that O
, O
once O
the O
Senate B-ORG
makes O
its O
approval O
official O
in O
June O
, O
China B-LOC
will O
open O
its O
market O
of O
1.3 O
billion O
consumers O
to O
a O
wide O
range O
of O
U.S. O
products O
, O
from O
agricultural O
to O
telecommunications O
to O
automobiles O
. O

With O
no O
foreign O
conflicts O
and O
a O
booming O
economy O
, O
Clinton B-PER
had O
made O
the O
approval O
the O
legislative O
priority O
of O
his O
administration O
that O
will O
end O
in O
January O
next O
year O
, O
and O
after O
the O
vote O
did O
not O
hide O
his O
happiness O
. O

" O
The O
House B-ORG
of I-ORG
Representatives I-ORG
has O
taken O
a O
historic O
step O
toward O
continued O
prosperity O
in O
America B-ORG
, O
reform O
in O
China B-ORG
and O
peace O
in O
the O
world O
, O
" O
noted O
Clinton B-PER
, O
who O
in O
1993 O
signed O
the O
Free B-MISC
Trade I-MISC
Agreement I-MISC
( O
NAFTA B-MISC
) O
with O
Mexico B-ORG
and O
Canada B-ORG
. O

" O
I O
have O
always O
been O
a O
believer O
that O
if O
we O
open O
markets O
abroad O
, O
we O
give O
way O
to O
more O
opportunities O
at O
home O
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O

And O
in O
reference O
to O
criticism O
about O
the O
lack O
of O
democracy O
and O
reported O
human O
rights O
violations O
in O
China B-LOC
, O
the O
president O
said O
the O
agreement O
will O
help O
improve O
the O
situation O
. O

" O
We O
will O
have O
a O
more O
positive O
influence O
with O
an O
outstretched O
hand O
than O
with O
a O
clenched O
fist O
, O
" O
he O
added O
. O

Clinton B-PER
and O
his O
advisers O
had O
previously O
said O
that O
rejecting O
the O
agreement O
would O
have O
meant O
pushing O
relations O
between O
the O
two O
countries O
into O
an O
abyss O
that O
would O
threaten O
stability O
in O
Asia B-LOC
and O
aggravate O
tensions O
between O
China B-ORG
and O
Taiwan B-ORG
. O

" O
The O
approval O
was O
a O
concrete O
result O
because O
it O
makes O
no O
sense O
to O
confront O
the O
most O
populous O
country O
in O
the O
world O
, O
" O
said O
Sidney B-PER
Weintraub I-PER
, O
of O
the O
Center B-ORG
for I-ORG
Strategic O
International O
Studies O
( O
CSIS B-ORG
) O
. O

" O
Opening O
up O
other O
markets O
is O
not O
a O
favor O
we O
do O
for O
other O
countries O
. O

It O
is O
an O
opportunity O
we O
create O
for O
ourselves O
, O
" O
noted O
Sherman B-PER
Katc I-PER
, O
a O
CSIS B-MISC
analyst O
. O

However O
, O
there O
was O
also O
criticism O
, O
especially O
from O
those O
who O
reject O
China B-ORG
's O
political O
ideology O
and O
human O
rights O
situation O
, O
globalization O
and O
from O
trade O
unions O
who O
fear O
that O
the O
agreement O
will O
lead O
to O
job O
losses O
in O
the O
country O
. O

The O
chairman O
of O
the O
influential O
Senate B-ORG
Foreign I-ORG
Relations I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
, O
Jesse B-PER
Helms I-PER
, O
vowed O
to O
fight O
to O
prevent O
that O
branch O
of O
Congress B-ORG
from O
approving O
the O
agreement O
. O

" O
I O
do O
n't O
want O
to O
spoil O
their O
party O
, O
but O
I O
feel O
compelled O
to O
make O
it O
clear O
that O
I O
do O
not O
intend O
for O
the O
Senate B-ORG
to O
bend O
to O
the O
plan O
to O
reward O
Chinese O
communists O
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O

The O
president O
of O
the O
conservation O
group O
Friends B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Earth I-ORG
, O
Brent B-PER
Blackwelder I-PER
, O
said O
the O
deal O
" O
shows O
that O
US B-ORG
foreign O
policy O
has O
been O
captured O
by O
corporate O
polluters O
and O
big O
campaign O
contributors O
" O
. O

To O
secure O
approval O
, O
House B-ORG
lawmakers O
added O
to O
the O
bill O
a O
proposal O
to O
create O
a O
human O
rights O
monitoring O
group O
. O

But O
, O
according O
to O
Friends B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Earth I-ORG
, O
the O
bill O
omitted O
references O
to O
environmental O
protection O
in O
China B-LOC
, O
" O
where O
two O
million O
people O
die O
each O
year O
due O
to O
water O
and O
air O
pollution O
" O
. O

" O
Where O
is O
the O
freedom O
of O
speech O
? O
Where O
is O
the O
freedom O
of O
worship O
? O
Where O
is O
the O
freedom O
of O
assembly O
? O

Not O
in O
China B-ORG
, O
" O
said O
Georgia B-LOC
Representative O
John B-PER
Lewis I-PER
in O
expressing O
his O
rejection O
of O
the O
agreement O
. O

" O
If O
we O
defend O
human O
and O
civil O
rights O
in O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
and O
elsewhere O
in O
the O
world O
, O
we O
should O
defend O
them O
in O
China B-LOC
, O
" O
he O
added O
. O

In O
a O
debate O
that O
was O
made O
more O
with O
economic O
than O
political O
interests O
in O
mind O
, O
the O
approval O
was O
applauded O
by O
Texas B-LOC
Governor O
George B-PER
W I-PER
. O
Bush O
, O
Republican O
presidential O
candidate O
facing O
Democrat O
and O
Vice O
President O
Al B-PER
Gore I-PER
in O
the O
November O
election O
. O

" O
It O
means O
a O
stronger O
economy O
for O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
, O
as O
well O
as O
more O
opportunities O
for O
freedom O
in O
China B-ORG
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O
by O
Claudia B-PER
Gutierrez I-PER
Beijing B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Chinese O
government B-ORG
today O
urged O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
to O
correct O
the O
" O
mistake O
" O
of O
having O
included O
the O
creation O
of O
a O
human O
rights O
commission O
in O
the O
resolution O
granting O
the O
United O
States O
permanent O
normal O
trade O
relationship O
( O
PNTR B-MISC
) O
status O
. O

According O
to O
Foreign B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
spokeswoman O
, O
Zhang B-PER
Qiyue I-PER
, O
Beijing B-ORG
has O
already O
lodged O
its O
complaint O
with O
the O
US O
executive O
on O
this O
matter O
, O
as O
it O
not O
only O
opposes O
the O
articles O
referring O
to O
such O
a O
commission O
but O
" O
will O
not O
accept O
them O
" O
. O

" O
We O
urge O
the O
US B-ORG
to O
correct O
its O
mistake O
, O
so O
as O
to O
ensure O
a O
healthy O
and O
smooth O
development O
of O
bilateral O
economic O
and O
trade O
cooperation O
" O
, O
warned O
both O
the O
Ministry B-ORG
of I-ORG
Foreign O
Affairs O
and O
the O
Ministry O
of O
Foreign B-ORG
Trade I-ORG
today O
. O
Economic O
Cooperation O
( O
Moftec B-ORG
) O
. O

The O
U.S. B-ORG
House I-ORG
of I-ORG
Representatives I-ORG
passed O
the O
resolution O
early O
last O
night O
( O
local O
time O
) O
, O
after O
more O
than O
seven O
hours O
of O
debate O
, O
by O
a O
vote O
of O
237 O
in O
favor O
and O
197 O
against O
. O

To O
ensure O
the O
victory O
of O
this O
historic O
measure O
, O
strongly O
defended O
before O
the O
Republicans O
by O
the O
U.S. O
President O
, O
Bill B-PER
Clinton I-PER
, O
during O
the O
last O
few O
months O
, O
congressional B-ORG
leaders O
agreed O
to O
create O
a O
commission O
of O
legislative O
and O
executive O
that O
will O
monitor O
annually O
the O
human O
rights O
policy O
in O
this O
country O
. O

Although O
Beijing B-LOC
today O
called O
the O
U.S. O
resolution O
a O
" O
wise O
move O
" O
, O
it O
also O
accused O
Washington B-ORG
of O
using O
human O
rights O
as O
an O
excuse O
to O
interfere O
in O
its O
internal O
affairs O
and O
harm O
its O
interests O
, O
" O
something O
unacceptable O
to O
the O
Chinese O
government B-ORG
" O
. O

The O
Moftec B-ORG
was O
quick O
to O
threaten O
retaliation O
if O
such O
a O
commission O
really O
gets O
underway O
to O
audit O
the O
human O
rights O
situation O
. O

" O
China B-ORG
wishes O
to O
express O
its O
deep O
dissatisfaction O
with O
this O
resolution O
and O
reserves O
the O
right O
to O
react O
in O
the O
future O
" O
on O
a O
matter O
that O
" O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
has O
a O
duty O
to O
resolve O
" O
, O
warned O
Hu B-PER
Chusheng I-PER
, O
Moftec B-ORG
spokesman O
. O

" O
Granting O
China B-ORG
PNTR B-MISC
is O
an O
obligation O
of O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
, O
following O
the O
rules O
of O
the O
World B-ORG
Trade I-ORG
Organization I-ORG
( O
WTO B-ORG
) O
, O
" O
said O
the O
representative O
of O
Foreign B-MISC
Affairs O
, O
" O
as O
the O
permanent O
status O
is O
the O
basis O
and O
a O
prerequisite O
" O
for O
the O
entry O
into O
force O
of O
the O
bilateral O
agreement O
on O
China B-ORG
's O
accession O
to O
the O
WTO B-ORG
signed O
last O
November O
15 O
in O
this O
capital O
. O

Zhang B-PER
said O
the O
congressional O
resolution O
, O
which O
must O
be O
ratified O
by O
the O
Senate B-ORG
in O
mid O
- O
June O
, O
not O
only O
helps O
China B-ORG
and O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
develop O
their O
economic O
and O
trade O
exchanges O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
equality O
and O
mutual O
benefit O
, O
but O
also O
helps O
create O
conditions O
for O
the O
healthy O
and O
stable O
development O
of O
bilateral O
relations O
. O

The O
spokeswoman O
urged O
the O
U.S. O
side O
to O
respect O
the O
three O
communiqués O
signed O
by O
the O
two O
countries O
, O
the O
basic O
rules O
governing O
international O
relations O
and O
the O
WTO B-ORG
rules O
. O

With O
the O
approval O
of O
the O
PNTR B-MISC
ends O
20 O
years O
of O
annual O
reviews O
of O
China B-LOC
's O
trade O
status O
by O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
and O
opens O
the O
door O
for O
this O
country O
to O
become O
before O
the O
end O
of O
the O
year O
the O
136th O
partner O
of O
the O
WTO B-ORG
, O
an O
opportunity O
that O
was O
more O
within O
reach O
after O
Beijing B-ORG
signed O
last O
Friday O
a O
similar O
agreement O
with O
the O
European B-ORG
Union I-ORG
( O
EU B-ORG
) O
in O
this O
capital O
. O

With O
the O
entry O
of O
China B-ORG
in O
the O
regulatory O
body O
of O
world O
trade O
, O
the O
tariffs O
that O
this O
country O
must O
pay O
to O
access O
the O
U.S. B-LOC
will O
be O
equated O
to O
those O
of O
virtually O
all O
other O
nations O
, O
while O
Beijing B-ORG
should O
open O
its O
markets O
to O
sectors O
such O
as O
agriculture O
, O
telecommunications O
or O
insurance O
of O
that O
country O
. O

While O
the O
detractors O
of O
the O
resolution O
believe O
that O
China B-ORG
's O
accession O
to O
the O
WTO B-ORG
will O
aggravate O
the O
already O
gigantic O
trade O
deficit O
that O
the O
US B-ORG
maintains O
with O
this O
country O
, O
$ O
68 O
billion O
last O
year O
, O
its O
supporters O
claim O
that O
not O
only O
will O
benefit O
the O
US O
economy O
, O
but O
also O
national O
security O
, O
as O
it O
will O
boost O
political O
and O
economic O
reforms O
in O
this O
Asian O
giant O
. O

Lisbon B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Portuguese O
press O
today O
highlights O
the O
eighth O
victory O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
in O
a O
historic O
final O
of O
the O
European B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
, O
which O
for O
the O
first O
time O
pitted O
two O
teams O
from O
the O
same O
country O
. O

They O
are O
unanimous O
judgments O
favorable O
to O
the O
game O
developed O
by O
the O
winning O
team O
, O
" O
simply O
unsurpassed O
" O
, O
" O
history O
won O
, O
the O
madridista O
religiously O
respected O
their O
past O
and O
built O
a O
cruel O
end O
to O
the O
beautiful O
adventure O
of O
Valencia B-ORG
" O
, O
comments O
" O
A B-ORG
Bola I-ORG
" O
in O
its O
first O
pages O
. O

" O
The O
myth O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
continues O
to O
grow O
" O
, O
" O
Raul O
: O
the B-MISC
eighth I-MISC
wonder I-MISC
" O
headlines O
" O
Record B-MISC
" O
, O
which O
reports O
that O
the O
sporting O
spectacle O
was O
" O
superb O
" O
for O
the O
quality O
of O
the O
game O
and O
a O
stadium O
divided O
between O
the O
two O
fans O
who O
passionately O
followed O
the O
incidents O
of O
the O
match O
. O

" O
The O
Valencian O
rice O
was O
a O
sweet O
merengue O
" O
according O
to O
the O
" O
Jornal B-MISC
de I-MISC
Noticias I-MISC
" O
, O
which O
highlights O
the O
superiority O
of O
the O
Madrid O
team O
against O
a O
Valencia B-ORG
that O
suffered O
from O
" O
lack O
of O
rhythm O
" O
and O
" O
lost O
almost O
all O
the O
inspiration O
of O
attack O
" O
. O

Freetown B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
murder O
in O
Sierra B-LOC
Leone I-LOC
of O
four O
soldiers O
of O
the O
pro O
- O
government O
forces O
and O
two O
journalists O
at O
the O
hands O
of O
the O
rebels O
of O
the O
United B-ORG
Revolutionary I-ORG
Forces I-ORG
( O
RUF B-ORG
) O
coincided O
with O
the O
resurgence O
of O
the O
wave O
of O
violence O
that O
for O
almost O
a O
month O
this O
African O
country O
has O
been O
experiencing O
. O

The O
Spanish O
journalist O
Miguel B-PER
Gil I-PER
Moreno I-PER
, O
who O
worked O
as O
a O
cameraman O
for O
the O
American O
agency O
Associated O
Press B-ORG
TV I-ORG
and O
his O
American O
colleague O
Kurt B-PER
Schork I-PER
, O
correspondent O
of O
the O
British O
news O
agency O
Reuters B-ORG
, O
were O
killed O
yesterday O
when O
the O
column O
of O
government O
troops O
with O
which O
they O
were O
traveling O
was O
assaulted O
by O
RUF B-ORG
rebels O
. O

In O
the O
event O
, O
which O
took O
place O
at O
the O
Rogberi B-LOC
crossroads O
, O
about O
80 O
kilometers O
northeast O
of O
Freetown B-LOC
, O
two O
other O
journalists O
were O
also O
slightly O
injured O
, O
the O
Greek O
Yannis B-PER
Behrakis I-PER
and O
South O
African O
Mark B-PER
Chisholm I-PER
, O
both O
Reuters B-ORG
correspondents O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
and O
as O
confirmed O
by O
UN B-ORG
sources O
in O
the O
Sierra B-LOC
Leonean I-LOC
capital O
, O
four O
Sierra O
Leonean O
soldiers O
were O
also O
killed O
in O
the O
ambush O
. O

The O
two O
wounded O
reporters O
were O
taken O
to O
a O
field O
hospital O
set O
up O
by O
UN B-ORG
forces O
without O
fear O
for O
their O
lives O
, O
while O
the O
body O
of O
the O
Spanish O
journalist O
, O
32 O
, O
was O
in O
Freetown B-LOC
yesterday O
awaiting O
repatriation O
, O
UN B-ORG
sources O
in O
the O
city O
told O
EFE I-ORG
. O

As O
soon O
as O
the O
incident O
became O
known O
, O
the O
UN B-PER
Secretary I-PER
, O
the O
Ghanaian O
Kofi B-PER
Annan I-PER
, O
expressed O
his O
sadness O
at O
the O
death O
of O
the O
two O
journalists O
, O
of O
whom O
he O
said O
" O
they O
were O
professionals O
who O
sought O
to O
report O
the O
bloody O
conflict O
that O
has O
already O
claimed O
too O
many O
lives O
" O
. O

" O
They O
were O
doing O
what O
every O
other O
journalist O
around O
the O
world O
does O
: O
taking O
risks O
so O
that O
we O
can O
be O
informed O
, O
" O
Annan B-PER
added O
in O
a O
statement O
. O

For O
his O
part O
, O
the O
president O
of O
Associated O
Press B-ORG
, O
Louis B-PER
D. I-PER
Boccardi I-PER
, O
said O
that O
" O
the O
loss O
of O
Miguel B-PER
leaves O
them O
with O
an O
indescribable O
sense O
of O
loss O
. O

Our O
grief O
is O
not O
relieved O
by O
the O
knowledge O
that O
he O
was O
doing O
the O
work O
he O
loved O
when O
tragedy O
struck O
. O

Gil B-PER
Moreno I-PER
, O
a O
native O
of O
Barcelona B-LOC
, O
in O
northeastern O
Spain B-LOC
, O
had O
covered O
among O
others O
the O
conflicts O
in O
Kosovo B-LOC
, O
Chechnya B-LOC
, O
Iraq B-LOC
and O
Congo B-LOC
, O
but O
as O
stated O
Nigel B-PER
Baker I-PER
, O
news O
director O
of O
the O
U.S. O
agency O
" O
never O
took O
a O
step O
without O
measuring O
the O
reasons O
for O
doing O
so O
and O
their O
options O
" O
. O

The O
Spanish O
reporter O
had O
received O
last O
month O
the O
award O
for O
cameraman O
of O
the O
year O
by O
the O
Royal B-ORG
Television I-ORG
Society I-ORG
. O

Kurt B-PER
Shork I-PER
, O
the O
other O
victim O
, O
aged O
53 O
, O
worked O
for O
Reuters B-ORG
agency O
for O
the O
last O
decade O
. O

" O
Kurt B-PER
was O
a O
brave O
reporter O
, O
a O
brave O
man O
, O
who O
perhaps O
better O
than O
other O
journalists O
knew O
how O
to O
reflect O
the O
plight O
of O
the O
Kurdish O
population O
during O
the O
Gulf B-MISC
War I-MISC
and O
the O
victims O
of O
the O
Balkan B-LOC
conflict O
afterwards O
" O
said O
the O
editor O
- O
in O
- O
chief O
of O
the O
British O
agency O
, O
Geert B-PER
Linnebank I-PER
. O

Also O
, O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
yesterday O
issued O
a O
statement O
strongly O
condemning O
the O
event O
. O

" O
We O
condemn O
this O
violent O
attack O
in O
the O
strongest O
possible O
terms O
, O
both O
the O
U.S. B-ORG
Embassy I-ORG
in O
Freetown B-LOC
and O
the O
State B-ORG
Department I-ORG
in O
Washington B-LOC
stand O
ready O
to O
assist O
the O
families O
at O
this O
difficult O
time O
, O
" O
said O
Philip B-PER
Reeker I-PER
, O
State B-ORG
Department I-ORG
spokesman O
. O

The O
journalists O
were O
assaulted O
by O
RUF B-ORG
rebels O
while O
traveling O
in O
two O
military O
trucks O
alongside O
a O
column O
of O
pro O
- O
government O
soldiers O
at O
the O
Rogberi B-LOC
road O
junction O
near O
the O
town O
of O
Masaka B-LOC
, O
about O
80 O
kilometers O
northeast O
of O
Freetown B-LOC
. O

In O
this O
area O
, O
of O
high O
strategic O
value O
, O
there O
had O
previously O
been O
other O
clashes O
between O
" O
blue O
helmets O
" O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
rebel O
groups O
. O

Last O
Monday O
, O
troops O
of O
the O
Sierra O
Leonean O
Army B-ORG
had O
taken O
the O
Rogberi B-LOC
crossing O
, O
where O
that O
same O
day O
several O
corpses O
were O
found O
, O
in O
advanced O
state O
of O
decomposition O
, O
dressed O
in O
uniforms O
of O
UN B-ORG
" O
blue O
helmets O
" O
and O
that O
could O
correspond O
to O
the O
members O
of O
this O
international O
organization O
kidnapped O
by O
the O
rebels O
three O
weeks O
ago O
. O

The O
RUF B-ORG
still O
holds O
290 O
blue O
helmets O
, O
and O
according O
to O
Liberian O
President O
Charles B-PER
Taylor I-PER
, O
who O
acts O
as O
a O
mediator O
between O
the O
United O
Nations B-ORG
and O
the O
Sierra O
Leonean O
rebels O
, O
the O
latter O
will O
not O
release O
more O
hostages O
until O
government O
forces O
stop O
their O
offensive O
against O
the O
RUF B-ORG
and O
halt O
their O
unstoppable O
advance O
towards O
the O
guerrilla O
fiefdoms O
in O
the O
interior O
of O
the O
country O
. O

Rome B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
- O
" O
Europe B-MISC
is I-MISC
again I-MISC
Real I-MISC
Madrid I-MISC
's O
" O
, O
is O
the O
headline O
with O
which O
the O
Italian O
press O
highlights O
the O
victory O
of O
the O
team O
from O
the O
capital O
of O
Spain B-LOC
in O
the O
final O
of O
the O
Champions O
League O
against O
the O
other O
Spanish O
club O
, O
Valencia B-ORG
, O
which O
the O
newspapers O
say O
did O
not O
show O
the O
brilliant O
game O
that O
did O
against O
Barcelona B-ORG
or O
Lazio B-ORG
. O

Although O
it O
appears O
in O
a O
box O
on O
the O
front O
pages O
, O
the O
final O
of O
the O
Champions O
Cup B-MISC
does O
not O
occupy O
the O
big O
headlines O
of O
the O
front O
pages O
of O
Italian O
sports O
newspapers O
, O
which O
in O
the O
case O
of O
" O
La B-ORG
Gazzetta I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
confines O
it O
to O
page O
15 O
and O
in O
the O
case O
of O
" O
Corriere B-ORG
dellos I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
to O
page O
17 O
. O

This O
is O
because O
no O
Italian O
club O
was O
among O
the O
finalists O
. O

" O
Real B-MISC
wins I-MISC
its I-MISC
eighth I-MISC
victory I-MISC
in I-MISC
the O
Champions O
Cup O
. O
Valencia O
defeated O
by O
3 O
- O
0 O
" O
, O
is O
the O
headline O
of O
" O
La B-ORG
Gazzetta I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
, O
which O
on O
the O
inside O
page O
adds O
: O
" O
Real B-ORG
's O
eighth O
wonder O
, O
Valencia B-ORG
wakes O
up O
from O
the O
dream O
" O
. O

According O
to O
the O
Milanese O
newspaper O
, O
the O
" O
most O
experienced O
" O
team O
, O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
, O
" O
who O
beat O
a O
Valencia B-ORG
team O
that O
stuttered O
" O
was O
the O
winner O
. O

It O
adds O
that O
the O
madridistas O
prevailed O
in O
the O
duels O
and O
that O
in O
the O
midfield O
dominated O
Redondo B-PER
and O
McManaman B-PER
. O

After O
highlighting O
Raul B-PER
's O
game O
, O
" O
La B-ORG
Gazzetta I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
states O
that O
the O
young O
madridista O
player O
" O
is O
one O
step O
away O
" O
from O
the O
Ballon B-MISC
d'Or I-MISC
and O
deserves O
to O
be O
in O
the O
gallery O
of O
Real B-MISC
Madrid I-MISC
Greats I-MISC
, O
between O
Di B-PER
Stefano I-PER
and O
Kopa B-PER
. O

" O
Real B-MISC
hurricane I-MISC
over I-MISC
Valencia I-MISC
" O
is O
the O
title O
of O
" O
Corriere B-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
, O
the O
Roman O
newspaper O
that O
affirms O
that O
the O
madridistas O
gave O
" O
a O
severe O
lesson O
to O
the O
team O
alienated O
by O
Cuper B-PER
" O
. O

The O
morning O
paper O
states O
that O
for O
Real B-ORG
the O
achievement O
of O
the O
cup O
means O
to O
make O
up O
for O
a O
bad O
season O
and O
that O
Valencia B-ORG
relied O
too O
much O
on O
their O
counterattacks O
, O
which O
did O
not O
stop O
Moriente B-PER
, O
McManaman B-PER
and O
Raul B-PER
to O
" O
sign O
" O
the O
eighth O
cup O
of O
champions O
. O

He O
highlights O
the O
young O
goalkeeper O
Iker B-PER
Casillas I-PER
( O
he O
calls O
him O
the O
baby O
- O
champion O
) O
and O
Helguera B-PER
and O
above O
all O
Raul B-PER
, O
whom O
he O
defines O
as O
a O
" O
total O
champion O
" O
who O
scores O
goals O
of O
all O
types O
and O
ways O
, O
" O
He O
has O
a O
strength O
and O
a O
crazy O
desire O
to O
win O
" O
. O

For O
" O
Corriere B-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
, O
the O
triumph O
of O
Madrid B-ORG
is O
the O
revenge O
of O
Del B-PER
Bosque I-PER
( O
the O
coach O
) O
, O
who O
lost O
as O
a O
player O
of O
Real B-ORG
in O
Paris B-LOC
in O
the O
1981 O
final O
against O
Liverpol B-ORG
, O
and O
the O
surrender O
of O
Cuper B-PER
. O

San B-LOC
Sebastian I-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
judge O
investigating O
the O
death O
of O
Mikel B-PER
Zabalza I-PER
in O
1985 O
has O
summoned O
to O
testify O
as O
defendants O
in O
this O
case O
the O
former O
civil O
guards O
Enrique B-PER
Dorado I-PER
and O
Felipe B-PER
Bayo I-PER
, O
recently O
convicted O
for O
the O
murders O
of O
Lasa B-PER
and O
Zabala B-PER
, O
legal O
sources O
confirmed O
today O
. O

In O
an O
order O
notified O
yesterday O
, O
the O
head O
of O
the O
Court B-ORG
of I-ORG
Instruction I-ORG
Number I-ORG
1 I-ORG
of O
San B-LOC
Sebastian I-LOC
, O
Augusto B-PER
Maeso I-PER
, O
who O
is O
currently O
in O
the O
First B-ORG
Section I-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Provincial I-ORG
Court I-ORG
on O
secondment O
, O
recalls O
that O
during O
the O
investigation O
of O
the O
summary O
the O
names O
of O
Dorado B-PER
and O
Bayo B-PER
, O
who O
have O
been O
called O
to O
testify O
on O
September O
19 O
, O
were O
cited O
by O
several O
witnesses O
and O
appeared O
in O
press O
reports O
. O

Maeso B-PER
considers O
that O
some O
of O
these O
testimonies O
" O
question O
" O
the O
veracity O
of O
the O
official O
version O
, O
which O
defends O
that O
Zabalza B-PER
died O
by O
drowning O
when O
he O
fell O
into O
the O
Bidasoa B-LOC
River I-LOC
when O
he O
tried O
to O
escape O
from O
the O
Guardia B-ORG
Civil I-ORG
agents O
he O
was O
guiding O
in O
the O
search O
for O
an O
ETA B-ORG
" O
hideout O
" O
. O

In O
the O
opinion O
of O
the O
judge O
, O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
young O
man O
was O
applied O
the O
anti O
- O
terrorist O
legislation O
after O
his O
arrest O
for O
his O
alleged O
relationship O
with O
ETA B-ORG
and O
that O
he O
had O
revealed O
the O
location O
of O
a O
" O
den O
" O
are O
data O
that O
" O
advise O
security O
measures O
to O
avoid O
escapes O
in O
the O
alleged O
place O
where O
" O
this O
hideout O
would O
be O
found O
, O
while O
Zabalza B-PER
was O
led O
by O
" O
only O
three O
members O
of O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Guard I-ORG
" O
. O

One O
of O
the O
testimonies O
on O
which O
the O
order O
is O
based O
is O
a O
statement O
by O
Dorado B-PER
himself O
, O
who O
admitted O
to O
two O
journalists O
from O
El B-ORG
Mundo I-ORG
that O
Zabalza B-PER
died O
in O
the O
barracks O
of O
Intxaurrondo B-LOC
when O
Bayo B-PER
practiced O
the O
torture O
known O
as O
" O
the O
bathtub O
" O
. O

Moscow B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

Russia B-LOC
's O
gold O
and O
foreign O
exchange O
reserves O
rose O
$ O
600 O
million O
and O
by O
May O
19 O
were O
equivalent O
to O
$ O
18.3 O
billion O
, O
said O
today O
a O
statement O
from O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
. O

According O
to O
the O
report O
, O
by O
May O
12 O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
's O
gold O
and O
foreign O
exchange O
reserves O
were O
$ O
17.7 O
billion O
. O

Foreign O
currency O
assets O
held O
by O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
and O
the O
Ministry B-ORG
of I-ORG
Finance I-ORG
are O
calculated O
in O
U.S. O
dollars O
and O
their O
value O
depends O
on O
the O
official O
ruble O
- O
dollar O
exchange O
rate O
set O
by O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
at O
the O
time O
of O
accounting O
. O

Gold O
reserves O
are O
valued O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
300 O
US O
dollars O
per O
troy O
ounce O
of O
gold O
. O

Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
( O
Badajoz B-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
socialist O
groups O
of O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
and O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
have O
agreed O
to O
create O
a O
joint O
political O
commission O
whose O
function O
will O
be O
to O
develop O
joint O
proposals O
to O
present O
them O
in O
their O
respective O
municipalities B-ORG
, O
the O
Junta B-ORG
de I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
and O
the O
central O
government B-ORG
. O

This O
has O
been O
announced O
by O
the O
general O
secretaries O
in O
the O
respective O
localities O
, O
Francisco B-PER
García I-PER
Ramos I-PER
, O
on O
behalf O
of O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
, O
and O
Juan B-PER
Manzano I-PER
, O
on O
behalf O
of O
Dombenitense O
, O
at O
a O
press O
conference O
which O
was O
also O
attended O
by O
the O
spokesman O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
in O
the O
City B-ORG
of I-ORG
Don I-ORG
Benito I-ORG
, O
Julio B-PER
Carmona I-PER
, O
and O
the O
number O
two O
of O
socialists O
villanovenses O
, O
Raul B-PER
Borrasca I-PER
. O

The O
aforementioned O
commission O
will O
consist O
of O
four O
representatives O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
of O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
and O
four O
others O
from O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
and O
will O
also O
be O
responsible O
for O
raising O
their O
proposals O
to O
the O
provincial O
, O
regional O
and O
even O
national O
bodies O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
itself O
. O

The O
combined O
strength O
of O
the O
Socialists O
in O
both O
municipalities O
is O
17 O
councilors O
, O
9 O
in O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
and O
8 O
in O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
. O

The O
number O
of O
members O
in O
both O
towns O
is O
over O
500 O
. O

The O
idea O
of O
creating O
this O
alliance O
arose O
approximately O
three O
weeks O
ago O
through O
a O
telephone O
call O
made O
by O
the O
socialist O
spokesman O
of O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
, O
Julio B-PER
Carmona I-PER
, O
to O
the O
socialist O
spokesman O
of O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
, O
Francisco B-PER
García I-PER
Ramos I-PER
, O
according O
to O
the O
latter O
leader O
. O

The O
subsequent O
step O
was O
the O
convening O
of O
both O
local O
executives O
, O
who O
have O
held O
several O
meetings O
before O
publicly O
disseminating O
the O
understanding O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Minister O
of O
Justice B-MISC
, O
Angel B-PER
Acebes I-PER
, O
today O
stressed O
that O
Judge O
Manuel B-PER
Garcia I-PER
Castellon I-PER
, O
who O
will O
be O
the O
Spanish O
liaison O
magistrate O
in O
France B-LOC
, O
will O
not O
exercise O
any O
kind O
of O
jurisdictional O
function O
but O
of O
cooperation O
and O
collaboration O
. O

In O
statements O
to O
Cadena B-ORG
Cope I-ORG
picked O
up O
by O
EFE B-ORG
, O
Acebes B-PER
explained O
that O
the O
work O
of O
the O
liaison O
magistrate O
is O
to O
exercise O
a O
number O
of O
functions O
of O
cooperation O
between O
States B-ORG
in O
a O
particular O
area O
, O
in O
this O
case O
with O
France B-ORG
in O
the O
fight O
against O
terrorism O
. O

The O
liaison O
magistrates O
try O
to O
promote O
, O
to O
speed O
up O
procedures O
, O
contacts O
between O
the O
competent O
services O
when O
delays O
occur O
and O
know O
the O
laws O
of O
both O
countries O
, O
said O
Acebes B-PER
, O
who O
said O
that O
they O
are O
" O
typical O
work O
of O
collaboration O
and O
cooperation O
" O
. O

He O
clarified O
that O
García B-PER
Castellón I-PER
will O
not O
exercise O
any O
kind O
of O
jurisdictional O
function O
and O
recalled O
that O
the O
system O
that O
regulates O
these O
liaison O
magistrates O
allows O
that O
he O
was O
not O
a O
judge O
, O
as O
he O
could O
have O
been O
appointed O
a O
prosecutor O
. O

Even O
, O
he O
added O
, O
in O
other O
countries O
it O
is O
not O
even O
necessary O
that O
this O
function O
is O
developed O
by O
a O
magistrate O
or O
a O
prosecutor O
, O
but O
it O
is O
sufficient O
that O
it O
is O
a O
specialist O
in O
law B-MISC
. O

" O
It O
does O
not O
resolve O
any O
matter O
or O
exercise O
other O
powers O
of O
judges O
of O
one O
country O
or O
another O
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O

This O
figure O
is O
regulated O
by O
a O
law O
that O
was O
passed O
in O
1998 O
and O
that O
establishes O
its O
legal O
regime O
and O
its O
system O
of O
election O
, O
said O
the O
Minister O
of O
Justice B-MISC
, O
adding O
that O
his O
appointment O
is O
a O
competence O
of O
the O
Government B-ORG
and O
that O
he O
spoke O
previously O
with O
the O
General B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Judiciary O
. O

London B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Iraqi O
President O
, O
Saddam B-MISC
Hussein I-MISC
, O
rebuilds O
its O
arsenals O
of O
mass O
destruction O
and O
is O
once O
again O
a O
threat O
to O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
world O
, O
said O
today O
, O
Thursday O
, O
the O
British O
Deputy O
Foreign B-ORG
Minister O
, O
Peter B-PER
Hain I-PER
. O

Speaking O
to O
the O
BBC B-ORG
, O
Hain B-PER
said O
that O
Hussein B-PER
must O
allow O
access O
to O
Iraqi O
territory O
of O
United B-ORG
Nations I-ORG
weapons O
inspectors O
to O
destroy O
chemical O
and O
biological O
weapons O
. O

Hain B-PER
's O
warnings O
came O
after O
former O
UN B-ORG
weapons O
inspector O
, O
Richard B-PER
Butler I-PER
, O
expressed O
concerns O
about O
the O
military O
capabilities O
of O
the O
Baghdad B-LOC
regime O
. O

" O
This O
is O
very O
worrying O
and O
that O
is O
why O
we O
have O
taken O
a O
very O
firm O
position O
in O
saying O
that O
UN B-ORG
weapons O
inspections O
should O
be O
allowed O
, O
" O
added O
the O
deputy O
minister O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Champions B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
ended O
with O
a O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
victory O
against O
Valencia B-ORG
by O
three O
goals O
to O
zero O
and O
the O
celebration O
of O
this O
triumph O
in O
Madrid B-LOC
and O
in O
the O
French O
city O
of O
Paris B-LOC
, O
focuses O
the O
attention O
of O
sports O
newspapers O
. O

" O
More B-MISC
cool I-MISC
than I-MISC
an I-MISC
eight I-MISC
" O
headlines O
the O
newspaper O
" O
Marca B-ORG
" O
to O
focus O
on O
the O
triumph O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
that O
gets O
the O
Eighth B-MISC
European I-MISC
Cup I-MISC
and O
becomes O
the O
team O
that O
has O
taken O
more O
triumphs O
in O
this O
competition O
. O

The O
final O
of O
the O
Copa B-MISC
del I-MISC
Rey I-MISC
between O
Espanyol B-ORG
and O
Atlético B-ORG
de I-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
the O
question O
of O
whether O
the O
new O
coach O
of O
Atlético B-ORG
de I-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
, O
Fernando B-PER
Zambrano I-PER
, O
will O
be O
able O
to O
count O
on O
the O
presence O
of O
Solari B-PER
or O
Kiko B-PER
, O
and O
the O
Russian O
tennis O
player O
Anna B-PER
Kournikova I-PER
who O
is O
preparing O
for O
the O
Roland B-MISC
Garros I-MISC
tournament O
in O
Mallorca B-LOC
, O
make O
up O
the O
bulk O
of O
the O
newspaper O
's O
news O
. O

Diario O
" O
As B-ORG
" O
focuses O
on O
the O
triumph O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
which O
wins O
the O
eighth O
European B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
after O
defeating O
Valencia B-ORG
by O
three O
goals O
to O
zero O
in O
the O
final O
held O
in O
Paris B-LOC
. O

The O
declarations O
of O
the O
president O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
, O
Lorenzo B-PER
Sanz I-PER
, O
and O
the O
coach O
of O
the O
team O
, O
Vicente B-PER
Del I-PER
Bosque I-PER
, O
after O
the O
match O
played O
in O
Paris B-LOC
, O
the O
ACB B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
between O
Real B-ORG
Madrid O
and O
Barcelona B-ORG
, O
the O
Italian O
club O
Juventus B-ORG
which O
" O
offers O
7,500 O
million O
for O
Anelka B-PER
" O
and O
the O
final O
match O
of O
the O
Copa B-MISC
del I-MISC
Rey I-MISC
between O
Atletico B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
Espanyol B-ORG
complete O
the O
sports O
news O
of O
the O
newspaper O
. O

Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
's O
victory O
over O
Valencia B-ORG
by O
three O
goals O
to O
zero O
in O
the O
Champions B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
played O
in O
Paris B-LOC
focuses O
the O
attention O
of O
the O
newspapers O
published O
in O
Barcelona B-LOC
. O

" O
The B-MISC
headline O
" O
Mundo B-ORG
Deportivo I-ORG
" O
focuses O
on O
the O
lack O
of O
resistance O
shown O
by O
Valencia B-ORG
in O
the O
European B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
final O
in O
Paris B-LOC
, O
which O
was O
won O
by O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
. O

The O
latest O
electoral O
news O
of O
the O
Barcelona O
club O
that O
focus O
on O
a O
" O
consensus O
for O
Guardiola B-PER
, O
Figo B-PER
and O
Rivaldo B-PER
to O
continue O
" O
, O
the O
coach O
of O
Celta B-ORG
, O
Victor B-PER
Fernandez I-PER
, O
who O
will O
renew O
for O
next O
season O
and O
the O
ACB B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
faces O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
Barca B-ORG
complete O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
sports O
news O
of O
the O
newspaper O
. O

The O
newspaper O
" O
Sport B-ORG
" O
focuses O
on O
the O
Champions B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
between O
Real B-ORG
Madrid O
and O
Valencia B-ORG
yesterday O
and O
the O
two O
teams O
' O
reactions O
: O
on O
the O
one O
hand O
, O
euphoria O
and O
tears O
for O
the O
losers O
on O
the O
other O
. O

The O
Copa B-MISC
del I-MISC
Rey I-MISC
final O
between O
Atletico B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
Espanyol B-ORG
, O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
's O
new O
signing O
Albert B-PER
Celades I-PER
, O
Barcelona B-ORG
fans O
asking O
for O
a O
better O
contract O
for O
player O
Luis B-PER
Figo I-PER
so O
that O
he O
does O
not O
leave O
, O
and O
the O
ACB B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
between O
Real B-ORG
Madrid O
and O
Barca B-ORG
are O
the O
focus O
of O
this O
newspaper O
's O
attention O
. O

Tokyo B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
EU O
euro O
fell O
today O
in O
Tokyo B-LOC
against O
the O
Japanese O
yen O
and O
mid O
- O
afternoon O
was O
quoted O
at O
97.22 O
yen O
, O
compared O
to O
96.25 O
at O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
day O
. O

With O
the O
U.S. O
dollar O
the O
euro O
remained O
at O
0.901 O
units O
, O
down O
from O
0.903 O
at O
the O
opening O
. O

Tokyo B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFECOM B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
EU O
euro O
fell O
today O
in O
Tokyo B-LOC
against O
the O
Japanese O
yen O
and O
mid O
- O
afternoon O
was O
quoted O
at O
97.22 O
yen O
, O
compared O
to O
96.25 O
at O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
day O
. O

With O
the O
U.S. O
dollar O
the O
euro O
remained O
at O
0.901 O
units O
, O
down O
from O
0.903 O
at O
the O
opening O
. O

Manila B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

A O
man O
armed O
with O
a O
grenade O
jumped O
today O
by O
parachute O
over O
a O
Manila B-LOC
neighborhood O
to O
escape O
from O
the O
plane O
he O
had O
tried O
to O
hijack O
the O
airline O
Philippine B-ORG
Airlines I-ORG
( O
PAL B-ORG
) O
, O
reported O
local O
broadcaster O
DZMM B-ORG
. O

The O
hijacker O
, O
according O
to O
that O
version O
, O
did O
not O
harm O
the O
crew O
of O
the O
aircraft O
and O
jumped O
over O
the O
capital O
's O
Antipolo B-LOC
district O
, O
and O
shortly O
after O
the O
plane O
landed O
safely O
at O
the O
same O
airport O
in O
Manila B-LOC
. O

The O
plane O
, O
an O
Airbus B-MISC
330 O
with O
280 O
passengers O
, O
took O
off O
from O
Davao B-LOC
airport O
, O
in O
Mindanao B-LOC
, O
at O
14.00 O
local O
time O
( O
06.00 O
GMT O
) O
and O
was O
scheduled O
to O
land O
in O
Manila B-LOC
hour O
. O
half O
hour O
later O
. O

The O
director O
of O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Aviation I-ORG
Bureau I-ORG
, O
Antonio B-PER
Gana I-PER
, O
said O
the O
hijacker O
asked O
the O
pilot O
to O
return O
to O
Davao B-LOC
, O
about O
1,000 O
kilometers O
south O
of O
Manila B-LOC
, O
but O
the O
lack O
of O
fuel O
forced O
to O
continue O
en O
route O
to O
Manila B-LOC
, O
where O
it O
is O
expected O
to O
arrive O
. O

In O
a O
statement O
to O
state O
broadcaster O
DZRB B-ORG
, O
Ricardo B-PER
Puno I-PER
, O
spokesman O
for O
Philippine O
President O
Joseph B-PER
Estrada I-PER
, O
said O
the O
hijacker O
was O
part O
of O
the O
passage O
and O
carried O
a O
hand O
grenade O
and O
a O
parachute O
. O

According O
to O
Puno B-PER
, O
the O
hijacker O
asked O
to O
be O
allowed O
to O
parachute O
from O
the O
plane O
, O
but O
due O
to O
the O
altitude O
of O
flight O
was O
not O
possible O
to O
open O
the O
doors O
of O
the O
aircraft O
, O
so O
the O
" O
Airbus B-MISC
" O
headed O
to O
Manila B-LOC
. O

However O
, O
after O
descending O
the O
plane O
to O
about O
1,800 O
meters O
, O
the O
skyjacker O
insisted O
on O
his O
purpose O
and O
managed O
to O
parachute O
. O

Jerusalem B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Israeli O
army B-ORG
has O
adapted O
its O
concept O
of O
security O
to O
the O
new O
reality O
created O
after O
the O
evacuation O
of O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
which O
is O
to O
defend O
its O
border O
within O
its O
own O
soil O
instead O
of O
fighting O
the O
fundamentalist O
group O
Hezbollah B-ORG
in O
Lebanese O
territory O
, O
explained O
today O
its O
commander O
. O

The O
commander O
- O
in O
- O
chief O
of O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
, O
General O
Shaul B-PER
Mofaz I-PER
, O
said O
that O
this O
includes O
the O
order O
to O
open O
fire O
, O
although O
he O
estimated O
that O
" O
soldiers O
have O
to O
be O
very O
careful O
not O
to O
make O
mistakes O
that O
lead O
to O
an O
escalation O
of O
violence O
" O
. O

This O
means O
that O
Israeli O
soldiers O
will O
not O
fire O
at O
the O
sight O
of O
Hezbollah B-ORG
fighters O
- O
as O
they O
have O
done O
so O
far O
in O
southern O
Lebanon O
- O
just O
as O
they O
will O
not O
interfere O
with O
Syrian O
troops O
, O
whose O
country O
de O
facto O
controls O
Lebanon B-LOC
. O

Mofaz B-PER
indicated O
that O
" O
we O
must O
be O
very O
vigilant O
" O
and O
added O
that O
in O
the O
coming O
days O
representatives O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
will O
examine O
the O
exact O
lines O
of O
the O
international O
border O
with O
Lebanon B-LOC
and O
, O
if O
necessary O
, O
their O
deployment O
will O
be O
adjusted O
. O

Meanwhile O
, O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
was O
still O
deployed O
today O
- O
the O
day O
after O
the O
withdrawal O
- O
in O
the O
north O
of O
his O
country O
, O
bordering O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
. O

According O
to O
Mofaz B-PER
, O
" O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
left O
Lebanon B-LOC
( O
in O
the O
early O
hours O
of O
yesterday O
morning O
Wednesday O
) O
properly O
and O
without O
casualties O
in O
their O
ranks O
, O
despite O
. O
it O
was O
a O
withdrawal O
under O
fire O
" O
from O
the O
Lebanese O
pro O
- O
Iranian O
group O
Hezbollah B-ORG
( O
Party B-ORG
of I-ORG
God I-ORG
) O
, O
which O
took O
control O
of O
the O
abandoned O
area O
in O
the O
south O
of O
the O
neighboring O
Arab O
country O
. O

The O
general O
said O
that O
in O
the O
fighting O
killed O
at O
least O
twelve O
guerrillas O
of O
the O
Shiite O
group O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
which O
also O
took O
weapons O
left O
on O
the O
ground O
by O
Israeli O
soldiers O
and O
militiamen O
of O
the O
Army B-ORG
of I-ORG
Southern I-ORG
Lebanon I-ORG
( O
ESL B-ORG
) O
, O
an O
ally O
of O
Israel B-ORG
. O

The O
commander O
- O
in O
- O
chief O
of O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
stressed O
that O
it O
was O
important O
that O
his O
troops O
went O
out O
in O
a O
quick O
operation O
, O
in O
the O
dark O
and O
before O
it O
cleared O
, O
and O
that O
it O
was O
not O
justified O
that O
the O
soldiers O
endangered O
their O
lives O
for O
weaponry O
left O
on O
the O
ground O
. O

Finally O
, O
Mofaz B-PER
warned O
that O
" O
I O
do O
not O
recommend O
anyone O
, O
including O
the O
Palestinians O
, O
to O
draw O
the O
wrong O
conclusions O
about O
the O
responsiveness O
of O
the O
Israeli O
army B-ORG
" O
. O

In O
this O
regard O
, O
the O
well O
- O
known O
Palestinian O
journalist O
Daud B-PER
Kutab I-PER
wonders O
, O
in O
a O
column O
published O
today O
in O
the O
Israeli O
daily O
" O
Jerusalem B-ORG
Post I-ORG
" O
: O
" O
How O
can O
we O
convince O
people O
that O
nonviolent O
resistance O
works O
, O
when O
we O
see O
that O
armed O
resistance O
( O
of O
Hezbollah B-ORG
) O
is O
working O
while O
negotiations O
fail O
? O

" O
. O

As O
for O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
Israel B-ORG
recognizes O
its O
sovereignty O
over O
the O
whole O
of O
its O
territory O
, O
but O
demands O
that O
Beirut B-ORG
guarantee O
a O
secure O
border O
and O
, O
if O
this O
is O
not O
achieved O
, O
the O
Israeli O
army B-ORG
is O
prepared O
for O
a O
series O
of O
responses O
and O
retaliation O
. O

This O
was O
warned O
in O
recent O
days O
the O
Israeli O
Prime O
Minister O
, O
Ehud B-PER
Barak I-PER
, O
and O
also O
Mofaz B-PER
himself O
, O
Foreign B-ORG
Minister O
David B-PER
Levy I-PER
, O
and O
other O
rulers O
, O
who O
held O
the O
Lebanese O
and O
Syrian O
governments B-ORG
responsible O
for O
maintaining O
calm O
on O
the O
border O
. O

That O
is O
, O
if O
fired O
from O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
against O
northern O
Israel B-LOC
, O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
will O
immediately O
launch O
a O
retaliation O
against O
Lebanese O
, O
Syrian O
and O
even O
Iranian O
interests O
throughout O
that O
neighboring O
Arab O
country O
. O

To O
defend O
the O
borders O
, O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
decided O
to O
install O
fortified O
positions O
in O
the O
very O
towns O
in O
the O
north O
of O
its O
territory O
, O
where O
its O
more O
than O
250,000 O
inhabitants O
have O
often O
been O
the O
target O
of O
attacks O
from O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
in O
particular O
" O
Katiusha B-MISC
" O
rockets O
fired O
by O
the O
Hezbollah B-ORG
. O

Military O
commentators O
today O
point O
out O
that O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
will O
have O
more O
troops O
to O
the O
south O
, O
ready O
to O
respond O
with O
new O
techniques O
, O
as O
well O
as O
with O
great O
speed O
and O
mobility O
, O
while O
maintaining O
a O
" O
low O
profile O
" O
on O
the O
border O
itself O
. O

Faced O
with O
this O
new O
situation O
, O
the O
military O
commentator O
of O
the O
prestigious O
Israeli O
newspaper O
" O
Haaretz B-ORG
" O
, O
Zeev B-PER
Schiff I-PER
, O
concludes O
that O
" O
the O
withdrawal O
from O
Lebanon B-LOC
does O
not O
mean O
the O
end O
of O
the O
conflict O
" O
. O

Ceuta B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

Two O
young O
men O
, O
both O
from O
Morocco B-LOC
, O
face O
a O
sentence O
of O
six O
years O
in O
prison O
on O
charges O
of O
having O
stuck O
a O
knife O
in O
the O
head O
of O
another O
young O
man O
, O
also O
Moroccan O
, O
who O
was O
robbed O
of O
1,500 O
pesetas O
when O
he O
was O
on O
a O
beach O
in O
Ceuta O
. O

According O
to O
judicial O
sources O
, O
the O
Criminal B-ORG
Court I-ORG
number I-ORG
2 I-ORG
of O
Ceuta B-LOC
has O
judged O
today O
to O
R. B-PER
E. I-PER
Ch I-PER
. O
and O
M. B-PER
M I-PER
. O
for O
which O
the O
prosecutor O
is O
asking O
for O
six O
years O
in O
prison O
, O
two O
for O
injuries O
and O
four O
for O
robbery O
. O

The O
facts O
judged O
occurred O
on O
January O
2 O
when O
allegedly O
both O
young O
men O
attacked O
a O
third O
in O
the O
vicinity O
of O
the O
beach B-LOC
of I-LOC
La I-LOC
Ribera I-LOC
, O
and O
robbed O
him O
of O
1,500 O
pesetas O
and O
two O
sleeping O
bags O
after O
assaulting O
him O
with O
a O
knife O
in O
the O
head O
that O
caused O
his O
hospitalization O
. O

The O
defense O
has O
requested O
the O
acquittal O
of O
the O
two O
young O
men O
to O
consider O
that O
there O
is O
insufficient O
evidence O
to O
determine O
the O
guilt O
of O
his O
defendants O
, O
which O
were O
recognized O
by O
the O
victim O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Malaga O
group O
Digital B-ORG
21 I-ORG
wants O
to O
show O
in O
his O
debut O
album O
that O
" O
digital O
and O
analog O
are O
not O
at O
odds O
" O
, O
as O
explained O
today O
to O
Efe B-ORG
its O
leader O
, O
singer O
, O
songwriter O
and O
guitarist O
, O
Miguel B-PER
Lopez I-PER
, O
who O
says O
his O
music O
" O
offers O
the O
contemporary O
of O
the O
machines O
and O
the O
strength O
of O
the O
guitar O
and O
drums O
" O
. O

Paco B-PER
( O
guitar O
) O
, O
Salva B-PER
( O
drums O
) O
and O
Alberto B-PER
( O
bass O
) O
form O
, O
along O
with O
Miguel B-PER
, O
Digital B-ORG
21 I-ORG
, O
a O
band O
that O
" O
at O
the O
gates O
of O
the O
XXI O
century O
" O
wants O
to O
demonstrate O
that O
" O
despite O
the O
importance O
that O
when O
composing O
have O
computers O
and O
loops O
, O
traditional O
instruments O
continue O
to O
maintain O
the O
freshness O
of O
the O
music O
, O
and O
although O
sometimes O
the O
voices O
are O
distorted O
, O
melodies O
and O
songs O
are O
the O
most O
important O
" O
. O

Groups O
like O
" O
Radiohead B-ORG
" O
, O
" O
Portishead B-ORG
" O
, O
" O
Smashing B-ORG
Punpkins I-ORG
" O
and O
" O
Chemikal B-ORG
Brothers I-ORG
" O
, O
and O
the O
musician O
Beck B-PER
, O
are O
some O
of O
the O
influences O
of O
this O
group O
from O
Malaga O
, O
which O
although O
it O
does O
not O
refuse O
to O
sing O
in O
Castilian O
, O
is O
one O
of O
those O
who O
record O
in O
English O
. O

" O
It O
's O
not O
for O
anything O
in O
particular O
, O
we O
have O
songs O
in O
Spanish O
, O
which O
we O
play O
live O
, O
but O
we O
thought O
that O
for O
the O
album O
was O
better O
to O
do O
everything O
in O
one O
language O
" O
. O

Tomorrow O
Friday O
the O
Caracol B-LOC
hall I-LOC
in O
Madrid O
has O
been O
chosen O
for O
the O
official O
presentation O
of O
the O
album O
" O
Digital B-MISC
21 I-MISC
" O
, O
later O
the O
malagueña O
formation O
will O
travel O
to O
Santiago B-LOC
de I-LOC
Compostela I-LOC
to O
participate O
on O
July O
13 O
in O
the O
Celtirock B-MISC
Festival I-MISC
and O
on O
August O
3 O
will O
be O
part O
of O
the O
poster O
of O
the O
" O
Benicassim B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
" O
. O

Digital B-ORG
21 I-ORG
was O
not O
born O
with O
the O
intention O
of O
becoming O
professional O
, O
but O
to O
put O
on O
the O
table O
and O
the O
stage O
their O
music O
, O
but O
after O
the O
success O
they O
have O
had O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
where O
they O
have O
just O
offered O
their O
second O
tour O
of O
four O
performances O
, O
they O
decided O
that O
why O
would O
not O
they O
devote O
themselves O
to O
this O
" O
. O

Seville B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
cell O
phone O
company O
Amena B-ORG
will O
continue O
its O
criminal O
action O
against O
the O
company O
Airtel B-ORG
for O
an O
alleged O
scam O
, O
which O
prompted O
the O
statement O
in O
a O
court O
in O
Seville B-LOC
, O
as O
accused O
, O
four O
Andalusian O
managers O
of O
Airtel B-ORG
, O
told O
Efe B-ORG
a O
spokesman O
for O
Amena B-ORG
. O

The O
alleged O
crimes O
, O
according O
to O
Amena B-ORG
's O
complaint O
to O
the O
Guardia B-ORG
Civil I-ORG
, O
took O
place O
late O
last O
year O
, O
when O
Airtel B-ORG
bought O
through O
intermediaries O
about O
60,000 O
cell O
phones O
that O
Amena B-ORG
had O
offered O
for O
sale O
at O
a O
price O
below O
market O
price O
to O
attract O
customers O
. O

The O
lines O
rented O
by O
Amena B-ORG
to O
Airtel B-ORG
in O
Andalusia B-LOC
were O
also O
manipulated O
in O
order O
to O
charge O
for O
a O
non O
- O
existent O
use O
, O
collapse O
them O
and O
cause O
the O
loss O
of O
users O
. O

According O
to O
the O
operator O
, O
his O
complaint O
was O
aimed O
at O
clarifying O
facts O
constituting O
a O
criminal O
conduct O
typified O
as O
a O
crime O
of O
fraud O
and O
damage O
. O

Airtel B-ORG
has O
compensated O
Amena B-ORG
, O
as O
reported O
by O
this O
second O
operator O
, O
for O
civil O
liability O
arising O
from O
the O
offenses O
allegedly O
committed O
. O

Therefore O
, O
Amena B-ORG
has O
waived O
the O
action O
of O
subsidiary O
civil O
liability O
that O
could O
arise O
from O
the O
criminal O
proceedings O
, O
although O
it O
is O
" O
fully O
confident O
" O
that O
the O
investigations O
being O
carried O
out O
by O
judges O
and O
criminal O
courts O
, O
which O
are O
currently O
under O
secret O
summary O
proceedings O
, O
clarify O
" O
completely O
" O
the O
alleged O
facts O
, O
said O
in O
a O
statement O
. O

Melbourne B-LOC
( O
Australia B-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Chiefs I-ORG
of O
Fiji B-LOC
today O
allowed O
some O
members O
of O
the O
attempted O
coup O
led O
by O
businessman O
George B-PER
Speight I-PER
to O
participate O
in O
the O
transitional O
government O
to O
be O
formed O
by O
the O
country O
's O
president O
, O
Kamisese B-PER
Mara I-PER
. O

This O
is O
one O
of O
several O
resolutions O
passed O
today O
by O
the O
Great B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Chiefs I-ORG
, O
in O
addition O
to O
requesting O
that O
the O
Constitution B-MISC
be O
amended O
, O
to O
end O
the O
democratically O
elected O
government O
in O
last O
year O
's O
elections O
and O
to O
recommend O
to O
the O
head O
of O
state B-ORG
to O
pardon O
all O
coup O
plotters O
. O

A O
delegation O
of O
the O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
went O
to O
Parliament B-ORG
after O
the O
meeting O
to O
communicate O
its O
decisions O
to O
Speight B-PER
and O
ask O
him O
to O
release O
all O
the O
hostages O
he O
has O
been O
holding O
since O
last O
Friday O
, O
including O
Prime O
Minister O
, O
Mahendra B-PER
Chaudhry I-PER
. O

The O
three O
days O
of O
deliberations O
of O
the O
Great B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Chiefs I-ORG
have O
concluded O
with O
an O
unexpected O
culprit O
, O
not O
the O
coup O
plotter O
Speight B-PER
, O
but O
Chaudhry B-PER
, O
who O
did O
not O
have O
" O
the O
humility O
and O
political O
courage O
to O
listen O
to O
the O
growing O
popular O
discontent O
" O
, O
according O
to O
the O
resolution O
of O
the O
42 O
heads O
of O
the O
various O
ethnic O
communities O
in O
the O
country O
. O

The O
decision O
to O
amend O
the O
current O
Constitution B-MISC
, O
adopted O
in O
1997 O
, O
has O
been O
due O
, O
according O
to O
the O
president O
of O
the O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
, O
Sitiveni B-PER
Rabuka I-PER
, O
because O
it O
has O
failed O
in O
its O
task O
. O

" O
We O
must O
change O
the O
document O
that O
has O
brought O
us O
to O
the O
current O
situation O
. O

I O
thought O
it O
was O
a O
very O
good O
Constitution B-MISC
and O
brought O
unity O
to O
all O
communities O
, O
but O
the O
parties O
have O
rejected O
it O
, O
" O
Rabuka B-PER
explained O
to O
the O
press O
in O
Suva B-LOC
. O

The O
1997 O
Magna B-MISC
Carta I-MISC
amended O
the O
1987 O
Constitution O
which O
prevented O
the O
Hindu O
community O
from O
holding O
political O
office O
, O
allowing O
Chaudhry B-PER
to O
become O
the O
first O
Hindu O
to O
become O
Prime O
Minister O
in O
Fiji B-LOC
's O
history O
in O
May O
last O
year O
. O

The O
decisions O
adopted O
by O
the O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Fiji I-ORG
disregard O
all O
the O
recommendations O
given O
by O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORG
, O
as O
well O
as O
other O
countries O
, O
in O
relation O
to O
respect O
the O
constitutionality O
and O
the O
government O
of O
Chaudhry B-PER
, O
which O
was O
democratically O
elected O
. O

The O
resolutions O
of O
the O
big O
chiefs O
were O
announced O
shortly O
after O
the O
president O
of O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORG
, O
the O
New O
Zealander O
Don B-PER
McKinnon I-PER
, O
left O
Suva B-LOC
with O
a O
warning O
to O
Fiji B-ORG
not O
to O
abandon O
the O
path O
of O
democracy O
. O

Damascus B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

Syria B-ORG
believes O
that O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
completed O
on O
Wednesday O
, O
" O
indicates O
that O
Israel B-ORG
was O
defeated O
politically O
and O
militarily O
" O
, O
reports O
today O
the O
official O
Syrian O
press O
. O

" O
The O
day O
of O
liberation O
will O
be O
unforgettable O
for O
the O
people O
and O
the O
resistance O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
as O
well O
as O
for O
all O
freedom O
fighters O
around O
the O
world O
" O
, O
says O
the O
daily O
" O
Al B-ORG
Zaura I-ORG
" O
, O
organ O
of O
the O
Syrian B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
of I-ORG
Defense I-ORG
. O

Israel B-ORG
yesterday O
completed O
its O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
strip O
of O
about O
1,000 O
square O
kilometers O
it O
had O
occupied O
in O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
since O
1978 O
. O

For O
the O
Syrian O
newspaper O
, O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
, O
which O
ends O
22 O
years O
of O
occupation O
, O
" O
not O
only O
meant O
a O
military O
defeat O
for O
Israel B-ORG
, O
but O
also O
political O
" O
. O

Another O
newspaper O
, O
" O
Tishrin B-ORG
" O
, O
organ O
of O
the O
Syrian O
Government B-ORG
, O
considers O
that O
" O
the O
policy O
of O
oppression O
and O
terrorism O
that O
the O
Israelis O
practiced O
in O
the O
south O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
did O
not O
guarantee O
security O
for O
them O
nor O
prevented O
the O
Lebanese O
from O
recovering O
their O
rights O
and O
liberating O
their O
land O
" O
. O

For O
its O
part O
, O
the O
daily O
" O
Baath B-ORG
" O
, O
which O
reflects O
the O
views O
of O
the O
ruling O
party O
of O
the O
same O
name O
, O
believes O
that O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
southern O
Lebanon O
" O
does O
not O
mean O
isolation O
for O
Syria B-ORG
" O
in O
peace O
negotiations O
with O
the O
Jewish O
state B-ORG
. O

Damascus B-ORG
, O
which O
maintains O
about O
35,000 O
troops O
in O
Lebanon B-LOC
since O
1976 O
, O
and O
is O
considered O
the O
main O
arbiter O
of O
politics O
in O
this O
country O
, O
insisted O
on O
negotiating O
, O
along O
with O
Beirut B-ORG
, O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
Lebanese O
south O
and O
the O
Syrian O
Golan B-LOC
plateau O
, O
occupied O
since O
1967 O
. O

" O
Syria B-ORG
still O
opens O
the O
door O
wide O
for O
the O
resumption O
of O
negotiations O
" O
with O
Israel B-ORG
, O
adds O
" O
Baath B-ORG
" O
. O

The O
Syrian O
- O
Israeli O
dialogue O
has O
been O
suspended O
since O
last O
January O
due O
to O
differences O
between O
the O
two O
sides O
over O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
Golan B-LOC
Heights I-LOC
. O

Damascus B-ORG
insists O
that O
Israel B-ORG
undertakes O
to O
leave O
the O
entire O
Golan B-LOC
before O
negotiating O
the O
establishment O
of O
relations O
between O
the O
two O
neighboring O
states B-ORG
, O
a O
condition O
rejected O
by O
the O
Israelis O
. O

Porzuna B-LOC
( O
Ciudad B-LOC
Real I-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
City O
Council O
of B-ORG
Porzuna I-ORG
( O
Ciudad B-LOC
Real I-LOC
) O
has O
organized O
a O
conference O
on O
education O
and O
family O
with O
the O
aim O
of O
addressing O
the O
progressive O
increase O
in O
school O
failure O
and O
school O
dropout O
. O

The O
day O
held O
yesterday O
was O
attended O
by O
parents O
and O
teachers O
of O
about O
a O
thousand O
students O
who O
are O
enrolled O
in O
the O
public O
school O
" O
Nuestra B-ORG
Señora I-ORG
del I-ORG
Rosario I-ORG
" O
and O
the O
Institute B-ORG
of I-ORG
Secondary I-ORG
Education I-ORG
" O
Ribera B-ORG
del I-ORG
Bullaque I-ORG
" O
, O
as O
reported O
today O
to O
EFE B-ORG
, O
the O
mayor O
of O
Porzuna B-LOC
, O
Bienvenida B-PER
Garcia I-PER
. O

The O
delegate O
of O
Education B-MISC
of I-MISC
the I-MISC
Junta I-MISC
de I-MISC
Comunidades I-MISC
, O
José B-PER
Fuentes I-PER
Pastrana I-PER
, O
was O
in O
charge O
of O
inaugurating O
the O
day O
during O
which O
presentations O
, O
round O
tables O
and O
debates O
were O
developed O
. O

Bienvenida B-PER
Garcia I-PER
explained O
that O
the O
main O
purpose O
that O
has O
pursued O
has O
been O
to O
analyze O
the O
progressive O
increase O
of O
school O
dropout O
that O
occurs O
in O
the O
Institute B-ORG
of I-ORG
Secondary I-ORG
Education O
, O
in O
order O
to O
seek O
solutions O
to O
minimize O
this O
situation O
. O

According O
to O
the O
mayor O
of O
Porzuna B-LOC
, O
both O
the O
family O
and O
the O
education O
system O
and O
institutions O
must O
play O
an O
important O
role O
in O
trying O
to O
" O
curb O
" O
school O
dropouts O
, O
so O
it O
is O
necessary O
greater O
involvement O
in O
their O
educational O
responsibility O
. O

The O
mayoress O
of O
Porzuna B-LOC
explained O
that O
72 O
percent O
of O
the O
current O
unemployed O
under O
25 O
years O
old O
dropped O
out O
of O
school O
at O
one O
time O
and O
added O
that O
to O
reduce O
this O
figure O
one O
of O
the O
priorities O
is O
to O
raise O
awareness O
in O
the O
family O
to O
try O
to O
keep O
young O
people O
linked O
to O
schools O
and O
be O
able O
to O
complete O
their O
training O
cycle O
. O

Bienvenida B-PER
García I-PER
pointed O
out O
that O
among O
the O
measures O
proposed O
in O
this O
conference O
to O
avoid O
school O
dropout O
is O
to O
diversify O
the O
offer O
of O
training O
modules O
. O

Finally O
, O
she O
commented O
on O
the O
intention O
of O
the O
City O
Council O
of B-ORG
Porzuna I-ORG
to O
work O
in O
this O
line O
of O
action O
and O
assured O
that O
" O
from O
the O
municipal O
institution O
we O
will O
make O
an O
effective O
and O
active O
effort O
in O
this O
matter O
" O
. O

Sabadell B-LOC
( O
Barcelona B-LOC
) O
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
Royal O
Philharmonic O
Orchestra B-ORG
of I-ORG
Galicia I-ORG
will O
offer O
tomorrow O
at O
the O
municipal O
theater O
La B-LOC
Farándula I-LOC
de I-LOC
Sabadell I-LOC
a O
concert O
with O
works O
by O
Mendelssohn B-PER
, O
Gaos B-PER
and O
Stravinsky B-PER
, O
according O
to O
municipal O
sources O
The O
concert O
will O
take O
place O
as O
part O
of O
the O
program O
of O
events O
" O
Galicia B-MISC
today I-MISC
, O
Galicia O
today O
" O
organized O
by O
the O
city O
council O
and O
the O
Centro B-ORG
Galego I-ORG
Nos I-ORG
. O

Conducted O
by O
Máximo B-PER
Zumalave I-PER
and O
with O
the O
presence O
of O
violinist O
Herwig B-PER
Zack I-PER
and O
pianist O
Bernd B-PER
Zack I-PER
, O
the O
orchestra O
will O
perform O
the O
concerto O
for O
violin O
and O
piano O
in O
D O
minor O
by O
F. B-PER
Mendelssohn I-PER
; O
Granada O
, O
un B-MISC
atardecer I-MISC
en I-MISC
la I-MISC
Alhambra I-MISC
by O
A. B-PER
Gaos I-PER
and O
The B-MISC
Firebird I-MISC
by O
Igor B-PER
Stravinsky I-PER
. O

The O
orchestra O
, O
which O
manages O
the O
Auditorio B-ORG
de I-ORG
Galicia I-ORG
, O
was O
publicly O
constituted O
in O
February O
1996 O
with O
a O
concert O
conducted O
by O
its O
leader O
, O
the O
German O
maestro O
Helmuth B-PER
Rilling I-PER
. O

During O
this O
period O
of O
time O
has O
performed O
in O
major O
classical O
music O
concerts O
that O
have O
been O
held O
in O
Spain B-LOC
and O
in O
different O
countries O
and O
has O
been O
the O
subject O
of O
multiple O
awards O
for O
its O
musical O
quality O
. O

- O

EFE B-ORG
. O

CSA O
/ O
SC O
/ O
fjn O
/ O
JF O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
26 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

The O
young O
people O
arrested O
last O
night O
for O
the O
disorders O
that O
occurred O
during O
the O
party O
held O
by O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
fans O
in O
the O
vicinity O
of O
the O
Plaza B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Cibeles I-LOC
amounted O
to O
nineteen O
, O
told O
EFE B-ORG
today O
sources O
of O
the O
Superior B-ORG
Police I-ORG
Headquarters I-ORG
. O

The O
detainees O
remain O
in O
police O
custody O
and O
is O
waiting O
for O
their O
lawyers O
to O
appear O
. O

Most O
of O
them O
are O
expected O
to O
be O
released O
with O
charges O
as O
they O
are O
accused O
of O
public O
disorder O
and O
damage O
. O

Only O
one O
of O
the O
detainees O
, O
said O
the O
same O
sources O
, O
is O
accused O
of O
injury O
to O
an O
officer O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

Francisco B-PER
Arias I-PER
Cardenas I-PER
, O
main O
opponent O
of O
President O
Hugo B-PER
Chavez I-PER
in O
the O
Venezuelan O
elections O
next O
Sunday O
, O
assures O
that O
he O
will O
cut O
the O
presidential O
mandate O
and O
will O
revise O
the O
Constitution B-MISC
if O
he O
wins O
in O
the O
elections O
. O

In O
an O
interview O
published O
today O
by O
the O
Madrid O
newspaper O
" O
El B-ORG
Pais I-ORG
" O
, O
the O
Christian O
Democrat O
politician O
rejects O
" O
the O
outdated O
leftism O
" O
of O
President O
Chávez B-PER
, O
of O
whom O
he O
was O
a O
barracks O
mate O
in O
1992 O
and O
now O
his O
main O
adversary O
. O

" O
The O
first O
thing O
I O
offer O
to O
Venezuelans O
is O
tranquility O
, O
less O
talk O
, O
changes O
in O
peace O
" O
, O
says O
Arias B-PER
. O
says O
Arias O
. O

The O
presidential O
candidate O
promises O
to O
thoroughly O
amend O
the O
Constitution B-MISC
adopted O
on O
December O
15 O
, O
cut O
the O
presidential O
term O
, O
open O
the O
economy O
, O
and O
limit O
the O
size O
of O
the O
state B-ORG
in O
the O
operation O
of O
the O
economy O
. O

" O
The O
State B-ORG
should O
not O
be O
an O
entrepreneur O
" O
. O

Arias B-PER
, O
to O
whom O
the O
polls O
show O
him O
as O
a O
loser O
in O
the O
elections O
, O
plays O
down O
these O
forecasts O
and O
warns O
that O
" O
there O
is O
a O
silent O
vote O
that O
is O
with O
us O
, O
and O
that O
will O
manifest O
itself O
on O
election O
day O
( O
... O
) O
We O
will O
be O
very O
attentive O
to O
the O
traps O
" O
. O

Arias B-PER
warns O
that O
the O
elections O
take O
place O
in O
circumstances O
where O
" O
all O
powers O
, O
including O
the O
electoral O
one O
, O
are O
in O
the O
hands O
of O
one O
candidate O
" O
, O
although O
he O
emphasizes O
that O
" O
we O
are O
putting O
the O
means O
to O
prevent O
any O
attempt O
by O
those O
who O
have O
prepared O
this O
whole O
process O
to O
circumvent O
the O
will O
of O
the O
people O
" O
. O

He O
blames O
the O
Chávez B-ORG
Government I-ORG
for O
not O
having O
taken O
decisions O
in O
economic O
matters O
" O
and O
those O
that O
are O
taken O
-he O
assures- O
are O
slow O
" O
. O

" O
There O
is O
a O
contradiction O
when O
the O
public O
sector O
is O
managed O
as O
a O
permanent O
confrontation O
, O
when O
investment O
is O
discouraged O
, O
when O
State B-ORG
resources O
for O
investments O
are O
withheld O
from O
opposition O
governors O
and O
mayors O
so O
that O
they O
may O
carry O
out O
works O
that O
may O
present O
results O
to O
the O
voters O
" O
, O
he O
affirms O
. O

As O
for O
his O
project O
to O
reform O
the O
new O
Constitution B-LOC
, O
he O
explains O
that O
he O
wants O
to O
reduce O
the O
presidential O
term O
, O
" O
which O
is O
excessive O
" O
, O
and O
modify O
, O
for O
example O
, O
" O
the O
power O
to O
undo O
Congress B-ORG
, O
decentralization O
, O
the O
management O
of O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
State I-ORG
, O
the O
transfer O
of O
resources O
. O

These O
are O
very O
serious O
matters O
. O

Barcelona B-LOC
, O
May O
23 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O

An O
alternating O
air O
mattress O
that O
allows O
adjusting O
the O
pressure O
to O
prevent O
injury O
to O
patients O
and O
a O
bathtub O
of O
" O
hydrosound O
" O
capable O
of O
making O
a O
perfect O
hygiene O
of O
a O
patient O
without O
rubbing O
are O
some O
of O
the O
innovations O
in O
the O
medical O
- O
health O
field O
are O
presented O
at O
the O
Medical B-MISC
Forum I-MISC
Expo I-MISC
in I-MISC
Barcelona I-MISC
. O

A O
total O
of O
132 O
specialized O
companies O
are O
participating O
in O
Barcelona B-LOC
in O
this O
great O
exhibition O
in O
which O
the O
latest O
technological O
advances O
in O
hospital O
and O
medical O
- O
surgical O
equipment O
are O
presented O
, O
an O
event O
that O
coincides O
with O
the O
celebration O
of O
a O
forum O
of O
sanitary O
debate O
on O
the O
harmonization O
of O
the O
sanitary O
rights O
of O
European O
citizens O
. O
