Melbourne B-LOC
( O
Australia B-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
Attorney B-PER
General I-PER
, O
Daryl B-PER
Williams I-PER
, O
stressed O
today O
the O
need O
to O
take O
steps O
to O
protect O
the O
Australian O
judicial O
system O
from O
a O
website O
that O
makes O
compliance O
with O
the O
basic O
principles O
of O
the O
Law B-MISC
impossible O
. O

The O
Attorney B-PER
General I-PER
’s O
request O
comes O
after O
a O
judge O
of O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of O
the O
state O
of O
Victoria B-LOC
( O
Australia B-LOC
) O
was O
forced O
to O
dissolve O
a O
popular O
jury O
and O
suspend O
the O
trial O
over O
the O
defense O
’s O
argument O
that O
the O
people O
who O
composed O
it O
could O
have O
obtained O
information O
about O
the O
accused O
through O
the O
CrimeNet B-MISC
page O
. O

It O
has O
been O
visited O
over O
a O
million O
times O
, O
and O
provides O
information O
about O
thousands O
of O
crimes O
and O
criminals O
already O
prosecuted O
or O
persecuted O
, O
data O
coming O
from O
newspaper O
articles O
and O
judicial O
archives O
. O

Victoria O
’s O
attorney B-PER
general I-PER
, O
Rob B-PER
Hulls I-PER
, O
said O
there O
is O
no O
one O
to O
control O
that O
the O
information O
contained O
on O
CrimeNet B-MISC
is O
truthful O
. O

Hulls B-PER
noted O
that O
in O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORG
legal O
system O
, O
on O
which O
Australian O
justice O
is O
based O
, O
it O
is O
fundamental O
that O
the O
person O
is O
judged O
only O
taking O
into O
account O
the O
evidence O
presented O
before O
the O
judge O
. O

The O
aforementioned O
internet O
page O
is O
also O
considered O
the O
cause O
of O
the O
premature O
conclusion O
in O
a O
murder O
case O
recently O
tried O
in O
the O
city O
of O
Melbourne B-LOC
, O
the O
capital O
of O
the O
state O
of O
Victoria B-LOC
. O

Santander B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

Izquierda B-ORG
Unida I-ORG
de I-ORG
Santander I-ORG
presented O
today O
its O
new O
quarterly O
bulletin O
" O
City B-MISC
" O
, O
a O
publication O
of O
which O
10,000 O
copies O
will O
be O
distributed O
preferably O
in O
the O
neighborhoods O
of O
the O
municipality O
where O
the O
collation O
has O
greater O
citizen O
support O
. O

The O
spokesman O
of O
the O
IU B-ORG
Municipal I-ORG
Political I-ORG
Council I-ORG
in O
Santander B-LOC
, O
Ernesto B-PER
Gómez I-PER
de I-PER
la I-PER
Hera I-PER
, O
explained O
today O
at O
a O
press O
conference O
that O
this O
newsletter O
seeks O
, O
rather O
than O
informing O
, O
to O
open O
spaces O
of O
debate O
and O
serve O
as O
" O
seed O
of O
political O
mobilization O
" O
in O
the O
city O
. O

Gómez B-PER
de I-PER
la I-PER
Hera I-PER
commented O
that O
the O
contents O
of O
the O
" O
City B-MISC
" O
publication O
respond O
to O
the O
program O
he O
headed O
as O
a O
candidate O
in O
the O
1999 O
municipal O
elections O
, O
in O
which O
IU B-ORG
lost O
its O
representation O
in O
the O
City B-ORG
Hall O
, O
and O
trusted O
that O
its O
dissemination O
would O
be O
wider O
once O
the O
coalition O
resolved O
its O
economic O
crisis O
. O

At O
the O
moment O
, O
" O
City B-MISC
" O
will O
be O
distributed O
preferentially O
in O
the O
neighborhoods O
with O
the O
most O
voters O
of O
IU B-ORG
, O
among O
which O
the O
coalition O
's O
municipal O
spokesman O
cited O
the O
northern O
slope O
of O
the O
street B-LOC
Alta I-LOC
, O
Cazoña B-LOC
and O
the O
area O
comprised O
between O
the O
streets O
Castilla B-LOC
and O
Hermida B-LOC
. O

" O
City B-MISC
" O
, O
a O
bulletin O
composed O
of O
two O
folios O
folded O
in O
half O
, O
goes O
out O
on O
the O
street O
in O
its O
first O
issue O
criticising O
the O
construction O
works O
of O
underground O
parking O
spaces O
, O
the O
discomfort O
they O
are O
causing O
neighbors O
and O
the O
way O
they O
will O
be O
exploited O
. O

Gómez B-PER
de I-PER
la I-PER
Hera I-PER
considers O
that O
" O
the O
PP B-ORG
's O
policy O
of O
making O
money O
absolutely O
of O
everything O
and O
that O
that O
money O
is O
distributed O
especially O
for O
his O
friends O
" O
has O
turned O
Santander B-LOC
into O
" O
a O
trap O
full O
of O
holes O
, O
when O
all O
the O
cities O
in O
Western O
Europe B-LOC
are O
trying O
to O
make O
their O
urban O
hubs O
more O
habitable O
" O
. O

According O
to O
his O
judgment O
, O
the O
reasons O
for O
the O
City B-ORG
Council O
to O
carry O
forward O
these O
works O
are O
“ O
crematistic O
, O
mercenary O
, O
but O
they O
have O
nothing O
to O
do O
with O
the O
future O
of O
Santander B-LOC
or O
with O
the O
well O
- O
being O
of O
the O
vast O
majority O
of O
its O
population O
” O
. O

EFE B-ORG
- O
Cantabria B-LOC
Frankfurt B-LOC
( O
RFA B-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFECOM B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
German O
telephone O
group O
Deutsche B-ORG
Telekom I-ORG
has O
acquired O
the O
remaining O
50 O
percent O
of O
the O
Swiss O
telecom O
operator O
Multilink B-ORG
, O
which O
previously O
owned O
France B-ORG
Telecom I-ORG
, O
and O
has O
become O
its O
sole O
owner O
, O
the O
German O
company O
said O
on O
Thursday O
. O

In O
return O
, O
Deutsche B-ORG
Telekom I-ORG
will O
sell O
the O
French O
consortium O
its O
25 O
% O
stake O
in O
the O
British O
joint O
venture O
MetroHoldings B-ORG
. O

Multilink B-ORG
was O
founded O
in O
1998 O
and O
offers O
telephone O
and O
data O
transmission O
services O
in O
Switzerland B-LOC
and O
abroad O
, O
in O
addition O
to O
having O
its O
own O
fiber O
optic O
urban O
network O
. O

Deutsche B-ORG
Telekom I-ORG
called O
this O
purchase O
, O
the O
price O
of O
which O
it O
did O
not O
specify O
, O
another O
step O
towards O
its O
internationalization O
by O
means O
of O
majority O
acquisitions O
aimed O
at O
having O
control O
of O
the O
management O
of O
those O
companies O
. O

- O
by O

by O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

The O
President O
of O
the O
Junta B-ORG
of I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
, O
Juan B-PER
Carlos I-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Ibarra I-PER
, O
will O
receive O
in O
the O
headquarters O
of O
the O
Presidency B-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Government O
of O
Extremadura O
the O
relatives O
of O
several O
of O
the O
condemned O
by O
the O
" O
Lasa B-MISC
- I-MISC
Zabala I-MISC
" O
process O
, O
among O
them O
Lourdes B-PER
Díez I-PER
Urraca I-PER
, O
wife O
of O
the O
former O
civil O
governor O
of O
Guipúzcoa B-LOC
Julen B-PER
Elgorriaga I-PER
; O
and O
Antonio B-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Galindo I-PER
, O
brother O
of O
General O
Enrique B-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Galindo I-PER
. O

( O
with O
a O
photo O
of O
the O
meeting O
) O
. O

- O
by O

by O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

The O
Plenary B-ORG
Assembly I-ORG
of I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
will O
debate O
, O
among O
others O
, O
a O
non O
- O
law O
proposition O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
- I-ORG
NI I-ORG
, O
PP B-ORG
and O
Mixed B-ORG
Deputies I-ORG
of I-ORG
IU I-ORG
groups O
in O
which O
the O
Central O
Government B-ORG
is O
urged O
to O
promulgate O
a O
Ministerial B-MISC
Order I-MISC
that O
collects O
the O
regionalization O
of O
the O
base O
surface O
for O
corn O
cultivation O
. O

and O
entrepreneurs O
. O

- O
by O

by O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

Commerce B-MISC
, O
Manuel B-PER
Amigo I-PER
, O
and O
the O
presidents O
of O
Caja B-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
and O
Caja B-ORG
Badajoz I-ORG
, O
Jesús B-PER
Medina I-PER
and O
José B-PER
Manuel I-PER
Sánchez I-PER
Rojas I-PER
, O
respectively O
, O
will O
sign O
a O
collaboration O
agreement O
to O
finance O
business O
projects O
of O
young O
entrepreneurs O
. O

Charles B-PER
V I-PER
of O
Congress O
. O

- O
by O

Jaraíz O
de O
la O
Vera B-LOC
( O
Caceres B-LOC
) O

- O
by O

The O
Historical B-ORG
Institute I-ORG
" O
Hoffmeyer O
" O
will O
host O
the O
inauguration O
and O
first O
session O
of O
the O
Congress B-MISC
of I-MISC
Modern I-MISC
History I-MISC
" O
Charles O
. O
and B-MISC
the I-MISC
end I-MISC
of I-MISC
an I-MISC
era I-MISC
. O
1500 O
- O
1558 O
" O
, O
which O
is O
part O
of O
the O
commemorative O
acts O
of O
the O
V B-MISC
Centenary I-MISC
of O
the O
birth O
of O
the O
Emperor O
. O

Press O
Release O
: O
10 O
p.m. O

- O
by O

The O
president O
of O
the O
Junta B-ORG
of I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
, O
Juan B-PER
Carlos I-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Ibarra I-PER
, O
will O
receive O
in O
the O
headquarters O
of O
the O
Presidency B-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Government O
of O
Extremadura O
the O
relatives O
of O
several O
of O
the O
convicted O
by O
the O
" O
Lasa B-MISC
- I-MISC
Zabala I-MISC
" O
process O
. O

10:00 O
am O
to O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

Commerce B-MISC
, O
Manuel B-PER
Amigo I-PER
, O
and O
the O
presidents O
of O
Caja B-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
and O
Caja B-ORG
Badajoz I-ORG
, O
Jesús B-ORG
Medina I-ORG
and O
José B-PER
Manuel I-PER
Sánchez I-PER
Rojas I-PER
, O
respectively O
, O
will O
sign O
a O
collaboration O
agreement O
. O

10:00 O
- O
Jaraíz B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Vera I-LOC
( O
Cáceres B-LOC
) O

- O
by O

The O
Congress O
“ O
Charles B-MISC
and I-MISC
the I-MISC
End I-MISC
of I-MISC
an I-MISC
Epoch I-MISC
” O
1500 O
- O
1558 O

10:00 O
am O
to O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

Transportation B-MISC
, O
Javier B-PER
Corominas I-PER
, O
will O
deliver O
94 O
houses O
of O
special O
regime O
built O
by O
the O
Magenta B-ORG
Group I-ORG
in O
La B-LOC
Corchera I-LOC
. O

10:30 O
am O
– O
Plasencia B-LOC
( O
Cáceres B-LOC
) O

- O
by O

The O
mayor O
, O
José B-PER
Luis I-PER
Díez I-PER
, O
will O
talk O
about O
various O
issues O
of O
municipal O
interest O
. O

11:00 O
am O
to O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

A O
plenary O
session O
of B-MISC
the I-MISC
Assembly I-MISC
of I-MISC
Extremadura I-MISC
will O
be O
held O
. O

12:00 O
am O
– O
Montijo B-LOC
( O
Badajoz B-LOC
) O

- O
by O

The O
Minister O
of O
Culture B-MISC
, O
Francisco B-PER
Muñoz I-PER
, O
will O
inaugurate O
the O
IV O
Local O
Book B-MISC
Fair I-MISC
. O

12:00 O
am O
– O
Azuaga B-LOC
( O
Badajoz B-LOC
) O

- O
by O

Inauguration O
of O
the O
19th O
Exhibition O
Fair B-MISC
of I-MISC
the I-MISC
Southern I-MISC
Campaign I-MISC
of I-MISC
Extremadura I-MISC
( O
FECSUR B-MISC
) O
. O

12:30 O
am O
to O
Merida B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

The O
Plenum B-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
City O
Council O
will O
discuss O
issues O
such O
as O
the O
recalification O
of O
lands O
adjacent O
to O
the O
College B-LOC
" I-LOC
Salesians I-LOC
" O
. O

8:30 O
am O
– O
Caceres B-LOC

- O
by O

The O
Minister O
of O
Culture B-MISC
, O
Francisco B-PER
Muñoz I-PER
, O
will O
attend O
the O
presentation O
of O
the O
book O
“ O
Beings B-MISC
. I-MISC
stars I-MISC
” O
, O
which O
analyzes O
the O
origins O
of O
the O
Universe B-MISC
, O
and O
the O
data O
on O
the O
research O
project O
“ O
The B-MISC
First I-MISC
Populators I-MISC
of I-MISC
Extremadura I-MISC
” O
. O

- O
by O

H O
is O
merit B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

Public O
television O
and O
information O
society O
, O
autonomous O
financing O
, O
the O
contents O
of O
the O
extra O
- O
school O
day O
and O
the O
creation O
of O
a O
Consultative B-ORG
Council I-ORG
are O
the O
first O
issues O
that O
will O
be O
negotiated O
from O
tomorrow O
by O
the O
PP B-ORG
and O
the O
Junta B-ORG
de I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
to O
reach O
a O
regional O
pact O
on O
13 O
issues O
of O
interest O
. O

- O
by O

H O
is O
Caceres B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

The O
“ O
Peninsular B-MISC
Debate I-MISC
” O
will O
continue O
. O

By O
Caius B-PER
Apicius I-PER
Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

A O
viciousness O
in O
which O
no O
one O
should O
ever O
incur O
whoever O
is O
a O
gastronomist O
and O
aspires O
to O
be O
recognized O
as O
such O
is O
that O
of O
patriotism O
, O
understood O
as O
the O
excessive O
and O
inopportune O
rumor O
of O
patriotism O
: O
the O
gastronomist O
is O
not O
apathetic O
, O
but O
must O
flee O
as O
from O
the O
plague O
of O
chovinism O
. O

Years O
ago O
, O
in O
one O
of O
his O
travel O
books O
, O
the O
Nobel O
Literature O
laureate O
Camilo B-PER
José I-PER
Cela I-PER
claimed O
that O
the O
patriot O
is O
the O
one O
who O
is O
proud O
of O
the O
place O
where O
he O
was O
born O
and O
defends O
him O
, O
attitude O
in O
which O
he O
is O
right O
, O
while O
the O
patriot O
– O
at O
the O
time O
, O
Cela B-PER
used O
the O
word O
‘ O
nationalist O
’ O
– O
is O
the O
one O
who O
proclaims O
against O
the O
wind O
that O
his O
homeland O
is O
in O
all O
things O
superior O
to O
the O
others O
, O
something O
in O
which O
– O
Cela B-PER
said O
– O
he O
might O
well O
not O
be O
right O
. O

In O
this O
food O
there O
is O
too O
much O
patriotism O
. O

One O
has O
no O
inconvenience O
in O
accepting O
that O
each O
defends O
the O
cuisine O
and O
the O
products O
of O
his O
land O
... O
as O
long O
as O
that O
defense O
does O
not O
imply O
contempt O
because O
it O
is O
alien O
to O
the O
gastronomic O
customs O
of O
his O
solar O
homeland O
. O

In O
this O
case O
, O
it O
will O
be O
necessary O
to O
pass O
from O
Cela B-PER
to O
Antonio B-PER
Machado I-PER
and O
remember O
that O
of O
" O
disdain O
as O
much O
as O
you O
ignore O
... O

“ O
The O
problem O
of O
gastronomic O
patriotism O
– O
and O
let O
us O
not O
deceive O
ourselves O
by O
any O
other O
– O
is O
precisely O
this O
: O
ignorance O
. O

Of O
course O
that O
same O
ignorance O
can O
cause O
many O
to O
fall O
into O
the O
opposite O
defect O
: O
the O
, O
say O
, O
papanatism O
that O
makes O
for O
these O
citizens O
everything O
foreign O
better O
. O

And O
... O
neither O
. O

A O
gastronomist O
is O
something O
like O
a O
traveler O
, O
but O
a O
traveler O
, O
not O
a O
tourist O
; O
a O
traveler O
, O
say O
, O
in O
the O
style O
of O
the O
nineteenth O
century O
, O
a O
person O
full O
of O
curiosity O
and O
liberated O
, O
as O
far O
as O
possible O
, O
from O
prejudices O
, O
willing O
to O
accept O
the O
good O
things O
of O
others O
without O
for O
that O
reason O
renegating O
of O
their O
own O
. O

But O
that O
universality O
of O
the O
gastronomist O
– O
the O
first O
to O
universalize O
gastronomy O
were O
the O
Romans O
– O
does O
not O
imply O
the O
renunciation O
to O
itself O
. O

Much O
less O
the O
absurd O
mixings O
, O
that O
kitchen O
that O
we O
today O
call O
‘ O
fusion O
’ O
, O
very O
defensive O
always O
. O
when O
it O
does O
not O
derive O
, O
as O
in O
so O
many O
cases O
, O
in O
the O
kitchen O
‘ O
confusion O
’ O
. O

We O
will O
always O
insist O
that O
a O
kitchen O
, O
to O
be O
truly O
great O
, O
must O
be O
faithful O
to O
its O
land O
, O
and O
also O
to O
its O
time O
. O

But O
it O
must O
, O
how O
not O
, O
be O
open O
to O
foreign O
incorporations O
. O

What O
would O
it O
be O
of O
European O
cuisine O
, O
for O
example O
, O
without O
potatoes O
; O
or O
of O
Mediterranean O
cuisine O
without O
tomatoes O
, O
products O
both O
that O
arrived O
in O
the O
Old B-MISC
World I-MISC
less O
than O
five O
centuries O
ago O
... O

Imagine O
that O
among O
those O
Spaniards O
, O
who O
brought O
those O
American O
gifts O
to O
Europe B-LOC
, O
the O
gastronomic O
patriotry O
would O
have O
been O
imposed O
: O
potatoes O
and O
tomatoes O
would O
have O
remained O
in O
botanical O
curiosities O
. O

There O
is O
no O
, O
there O
can O
be O
no O
, O
universal O
cuisine O
; O
remember O
that O
horror O
known O
as O
‘ O
international O
cuisine O
’ O
so O
common O
in O
hotel O
restaurants O
. O

But O
there O
ca O
n’t O
be O
a O
kitchen O
that O
’s O
closed O
in O
itself O
. O

It O
is O
not O
possible O
to O
ask O
, O
in O
the O
face O
of O
a O
new O
food O
, O
a O
new O
species O
, O
where O
does O
this O
come O
from O
, O
without O
first O
investigating O
what O
is O
truly O
important O
: O
is O
it O
rich O
? O

If O
you O
are O
rich O
, O
come O
from O
where O
you O
come O
. O

Of O
course O
, O
we O
must O
study O
how O
we O
adapt O
this O
new O
product O
to O
our O
more O
rooted O
culinary O
uses O
. O

So O
our O
kitchen O
evolves O
, O
enriches O
itself O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
closing O
in O
itself O
, O
ends O
up O
weakening O
and O
extinguishing O
; O
endogamy O
is O
not O
good O
for O
almost O
anything O
. O

So O
keep O
your O
mind O
open O
, O
and O
your O
senses O
even O
more O
. O

That O
, O
parafrasing O
Shakespeare B-PER
in O
Hamlet B-MISC
, O
there O
are O
more O
rich O
things O
on O
earth B-MISC
than O
your O
wisdom O
, O
or O
your O
personal O
experience O
reaches O
. O

Do O
not O
become O
eunuchs O
of O
taste O
for O
mere O
patriotism O
: O
so O
many O
rich O
things O
will O
be O
lost O
. O

Alcorcón B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
Alcorcon O
Glass O
Art B-ORG
Museum I-ORG
hosts O
from O
today O
until O
the O
next O
28 O
June O
an O
exhibition O
of O
glass O
sculptures O
by O
the O
Romanian O
artist O
Edward B-PER
Leibovtiz I-PER
, O
composed O
of O
35 O
pieces O
of O
different O
formats O
and O
whose O
size O
ranges O
between O
40 O
centimeters O
and O
2 O
meters O
of O
some O
of O
the O
figures O
. O

The O
pieces O
of O
this O
exhibition O
, O
organized O
by O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
Culture I-ORG
, O
have O
a O
figurative O
character O
and O
in O
them O
faces O
, O
bodies O
and O
different O
fantasies O
are O
appreciated O
, O
showing O
even O
erotic O
aspects O
. O

Edward B-PER
Leibovitz I-PER
, O
who O
currently O
lives O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
has O
exhibited O
in O
his O
30 O
years O
of O
work O
as O
a O
contemporary O
glass O
sculptor O
in O
numerous O
European O
, O
American O
and O
Asian O
museums O
in O
countries O
such O
as O
Japan B-LOC
, O
Germany B-LOC
, O
France B-LOC
, O
Belgium B-LOC
or O
Israel B-LOC
. O

Visitors O
to O
the O
exhibition O
, O
which O
will O
be O
inaugurated O
this O
afternoon O
, O
will O
be O
able O
to O
enjoy O
the O
various O
works O
of O
Leibovitz B-PER
, O
who O
notes O
that O
" O
I O
like O
to O
work O
on O
the O
composition O
of O
the O
piece O
and O
try O
to O
convey O
the O
fantasy O
of O
life O
with O
an O
absurd O
aspect O
" O
. O

The O
inauguration O
, O
scheduled O
for O
20 O
hours O
, O
will O
be O
attended O
by O
the O
artist O
and O
the O
mayor O
of O
Culture B-MISC
, O
Francisco B-PER
Torres I-PER
, O
from O
whose O
council B-MISC
has O
been O
invited O
to O
the O
ambassadors O
of O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
Israel B-LOC
and O
Romania B-LOC
, O
consulates O
that O
according O
to O
municipal O
sources O
have O
confirmed O
their O
presence O
through O
different O
representatives O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFECOM B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

Terra B-ORG
's O
maximum O
capital O
expansion O
for O
the O
exchange O
of O
shares O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
including O
the O
options O
on O
shares O
of O
the O
American O
company O
's O
workers O
, O
will O
not O
exceed O
340,922,712 O
shares O
that O
, O
at O
the O
price O
of O
yesterday O
's O
closing O
on O
the O
stock O
market O
( O
50,9 O
pesetas O
per O
share O
) O
, O
would O
be O
2,887 O
trillion O
pesetas O
. O

This O
is O
stated O
in O
an O
explanatory O
note O
from O
the O
Telefónica B-ORG
group O
to O
the O
National O
Securities O
Market B-ORG
Commission I-ORG
on O
the O
capital O
expansions O
that O
will O
be O
submitted O
for O
approval O
by O
the O
June O
General B-MISC
Meeting I-MISC
of I-MISC
Shareholders I-MISC
to O
carry O
out O
the O
operation O
of O
its O
subsidiary O
Terra B-ORG
Network I-ORG
on O
the O
purchase O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
the O
U.S. O
Internet B-MISC
portal O
. O

In O
that O
clarification O
note O
, O
Telefónica B-ORG
indicates O
that O
these O
are O
maximum O
capital O
expansions O
, O
to O
cover O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

The O
expansion O
of O
340.922.712 O
shares O
for O
the O
exchange O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
has O
been O
carried O
out O
, O
he O
says O
, O
considering O
that O
the O
American O
company O
has O
112.192.815 O
shares O
, O
and O
expected O
options O
for O
the O
acquisition O
of O
assets O
in O
the O
amount O
of O
9.7 O
million O
bonds O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
have O
stock O
options O
plans O
for O
23,640,000 O
bonds O
, O
and O
at O
the O
closure O
of O
the O
operation O
with O
Telefónica B-ORG
there O
may O
be O
another O
7,440,000 O
stock O
options O
. O

The O
maximum O
number O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
shares O
that O
could O
be O
issued O
in O
total O
for O
its O
exchange O
with O
Telefónica B-ORG
will O
not O
exceed O
158,568,703 O
shares O
, O
which O
would O
be O
exchanged O
for O
a O
maximum O
of O
2,15 O
shares O
of O
the O
Spanish O
company O
each O
. O

As O
for O
the O
issuance O
of O
38.346.984 O
shares O
warrants O
( O
rights O
) O
for O
the O
purchase O
of O
options O
on O
shares O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
and O
which O
could O
mean O
an O
increase O
in O
capital O
by O
82.45 O
million O
shares O
, O
the O
text O
clarifies O
that O
this O
is O
a O
maximum O
number O
that O
is O
already O
included O
in O
the O
expansion O
of O
340.922.712 O
shares O
. O

The O
capital O
expansion O
of O
35.48 O
million O
shares O
that O
will O
be O
submitted O
to O
approval O
by O
the O
shareholders O
' O
board O
, O
which O
yesterday O
would O
amount O
to O
300.514 O
million O
pesetas O
, O
and O
which O
will O
be O
made O
for O
a O
price O
of O
62 O
euros O
- O
higher O
than O
its O
quotation O
these O
days O
on O
the O
stock O
exchange O
- O
is O
the O
agreement O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
because O
it O
is O
the O
quotation O
on O
the O
day O
of O
the O
signing O
of O
the O
agreement O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
Terra B-ORG
is O
currently O
below O
the O
62 O
euros O
could O
cause O
the O
shareholders O
of O
the O
operator O
not O
to O
go O
to O
the O
capital O
expansion O
, O
which O
would O
force O
Telefónica B-ORG
to O
subscribe O
to O
this O
expansion O
, O
as O
it O
is O
included O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

This O
expansion O
, O
he O
explains O
, O
is O
the O
result O
of O
dividing O
the O
amount O
of O
the O
commitment O
of O
€ O
2.2 O
billion O
by O
the O
type O
of O
emission O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

Terra B-ORG
's O
maximum O
capital O
expansion O
for O
the O
exchange O
of O
shares O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
including O
the O
options O
on O
shares O
of O
the O
American O
company O
's O
workers O
, O
will O
not O
exceed O
340,922,712 O
shares O
that O
, O
at O
the O
price O
of O
yesterday O
's O
closing O
on O
the O
stock O
market O
( O
50,9 O
pesetas O
per O
share O
) O
, O
would O
be O
2,887 O
trillion O
pesetas O
. O

This O
is O
stated O
in O
an O
explanatory O
note O
from O
the O
Telefónica B-ORG
group O
to O
the O
National O
Securities O
Market B-ORG
Commission I-ORG
on O
the O
capital O
expansions O
that O
will O
be O
submitted O
for O
approval O
by O
the O
June O
General B-ORG
Meeting I-ORG
of I-ORG
Shareholders I-ORG
to O
carry O
out O
the O
operation O
of O
its O
subsidiary O
Terra B-ORG
Network I-ORG
on O
the O
purchase O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
the O
U.S. O
Internet B-MISC
portal O
. O

In O
that O
clarification O
note O
, O
Telefónica B-ORG
indicates O
that O
these O
are O
maximum O
capital O
expansions O
, O
to O
cover O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

The O
expansion O
of O
340.922.712 O
shares O
for O
the O
exchange O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
has O
been O
carried O
out O
, O
he O
says O
, O
considering O
that O
the O
American O
company O
has O
112.192.815 O
shares O
, O
and O
expected O
options O
for O
the O
acquisition O
of O
assets O
in O
the O
amount O
of O
9.7 O
million O
bonds O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
have O
stock O
options O
plans O
for O
23,640,000 O
bonds O
, O
and O
at O
the O
closure O
of O
the O
operation O
with O
Telefónica B-ORG
there O
may O
be O
another O
7,440,000 O
stock O
options O
. O

The O
maximum O
number O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
shares O
that O
could O
be O
issued O
in O
total O
for O
its O
exchange O
with O
Telefónica B-ORG
will O
not O
exceed O
158,568,703 O
shares O
, O
which O
would O
be O
exchanged O
for O
a O
maximum O
of O
2,15 O
shares O
of O
the O
Spanish O
company O
each O
. O

As O
for O
the O
issuance O
of O
38.346.984 O
shares O
warrants O
( O
rights O
) O
for O
the O
purchase O
of O
options O
on O
shares O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
and O
which O
could O
mean O
an O
increase O
in O
capital O
by O
82.45 O
million O
shares O
, O
the O
text O
clarifies O
that O
this O
is O
a O
maximum O
number O
that O
is O
already O
included O
in O
the O
expansion O
of O
340.922.712 O
shares O
. O

The O
capital O
expansion O
of O
35.48 O
million O
shares O
that O
will O
be O
submitted O
to O
approval O
by O
the O
shareholders O
' O
board O
, O
which O
yesterday O
would O
amount O
to O
300.514 O
million O
pesetas O
, O
and O
which O
will O
be O
made O
for O
a O
price O
of O
62 O
euros O
- O
higher O
than O
its O
quotation O
these O
days O
on O
the O
stock O
exchange O
- O
is O
the O
agreement O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
because O
it O
is O
the O
quotation O
on O
the O
day O
of O
the O
signing O
of O
the O
agreement O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
Terra B-ORG
is O
currently O
below O
the O
62 O
euros O
could O
cause O
the O
shareholders O
of O
the O
operator O
not O
to O
go O
to O
the O
capital O
expansion O
, O
which O
would O
force O
Telefónica B-ORG
to O
subscribe O
to O
this O
expansion O
, O
as O
it O
is O
included O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

This O
expansion O
, O
he O
explains O
, O
is O
the O
result O
of O
dividing O
the O
amount O
of O
the O
commitment O
of O
€ O
2.2 O
billion O
by O
the O
type O
of O
emission O
. O

The O
Duke B-PER
of I-PER
Lugo I-PER
. O

- O
by O

Headquarters B-LOC
of O
Lugo B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

Infanta B-PER
Elena I-PER
and O
her O
husband O
Jaime B-PER
de I-PER
Marichalar I-PER
, O
Duke O
of O
Lugo B-LOC
, O
begin O
a O
two O
- O
day O
visit O
to O
Galicia B-LOC
, O
in O
which O
it O
is O
planned O
that O
, O
in O
addition O
to O
inaugurating O
a O
school O
of O
the O
Cela B-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
, O
they O
will O
participate O
in O
an O
act O
of O
declaration O
of O
support O
for O
the O
Lucenian O
Roman O
wall O
as O
the O
heritage O
of O
humanity B-MISC
. O

The O
Council B-ORG
Junta I-ORG
. O

- O
by O

The O
President O
of O
the O
Xunta B-ORG
shall O
inform O
of O
the O
agreements O
taken O
in O
the O
Council O
of O
the O
Galician O
Government B-ORG
. O

The O
BG B-ORG
Group O
. O

- O
by O

and O
Madrid B-LOC
. O

- O
by O

Deputies O
of O
the O
BNG B-ORG
present O
in O
the O
Constitutional B-LOC
appeal O
for O
having O
been O
denied O
the O
obtaining O
of O
their O
own O
group O
( O
PP B-ORG
CONGRESS O
) O
. O

- O
by O

from O
Santiago B-LOC
/ O
A B-LOC
Coruña I-LOC
. O

- O
by O

The O
secretary O
of O
the O
Galician O
PP B-ORG
, O
Jesús B-PER
Palmou I-PER
, O
offers O
a O
statement O
to O
EFE B-ORG
to O
explain O
the O
details O
of O
the O
provincial O
congresses O
this O
weekend O
in O
A B-LOC
Coruña I-LOC
and O
Pontevedra B-LOC
. O

Exhibition O
of O
Photography O
. O

- O
by O

to B-LOC
the I-LOC
corona I-LOC
. O

- O
by O

The O
Museum B-ORG
of I-ORG
Fine I-ORG
Arts I-ORG
in O
A B-LOC
Coruña I-LOC
opened O
the O
photo O
exhibition O
“ O
Emmanuel B-MISC
Souguez I-MISC
. O
Photographs O
1928 O
- O
1958 O
” O
. O

and O
salutations O
. O

EFE B-ORG
GALICIA B-LOC
by O
Kathy B-PER
Seleme I-PER
Beirut B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

The O
22 O
years O
of O
Israeli O
occupation O
of O
southern O
Lebanon O
ended O
in O
a O
few O
hours O
, O
but O
the O
underlying O
problems O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
a O
country O
still O
hostage O
to O
its O
two O
powerful O
neighbors O
, O
Israel B-LOC
and O
Syria B-LOC
, O
that O
can O
use O
it O
at O
any O
time O
for O
their O
interests O
, O
persist O
. O

The O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
south O
, O
although O
planned O
and O
announced O
, O
took O
everyone O
untouched O
by O
its O
precipitation O
, O
six O
weeks O
ahead O
of O
what O
was O
announced O
by O
the O
Israeli B-ORG
Government I-ORG
, O
and O
by O
the O
chaotic O
manner O
in O
which O
it O
occurred O
. O

Israel B-LOC
withdrew O
in O
just O
over O
48 O
hours O
from O
the O
south O
after O
the O
collapse O
of O
its O
allies O
of O
the O
Southern B-ORG
Lebanon I-ORG
Army I-ORG
( O
ESL B-ORG
) O
, O
who O
had O
helped O
it O
maintain O
its O
occupation O
, O
and O
those O
he O
thought O
to O
leave O
in O
a O
" O
buffer O
zone O
" O
to O
protect O
its O
northern O
border O
, O
alongside O
the O
UN B-ORG
Interim I-ORG
Force I-ORG
for I-ORG
Lebanon I-ORG
( O
FINUL B-ORG
) O
. O

Paradoxically O
, O
he O
had O
to O
give O
the O
ground O
to O
his O
main O
enemy O
, O
the O
Shiite O
group O
Hezbollah B-ORG
( O
Party B-ORG
of I-ORG
God I-ORG
) O
, O
which O
since O
the O
second O
Israeli O
invasion O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
in O
1982 O
, O
headed O
the O
guerrilla O
organizations O
fighting O
the O
occupation O
. O

Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
backed O
by O
Beirut B-ORG
, O
Damascus O
and O
Tehran O
, O
took O
control O
of O
the O
liberated O
south O
in O
the O
absence O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
, O
which O
has O
yet O
to O
define O
the O
mission O
it O
will O
entrust O
to O
its O
" O
blue O
helmets O
" O
, O
whose O
effectiveness O
wants O
to O
increase O
from O
4,500 O
to O
7,935 O
. O

While O
Beirut B-ORG
considers O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
to O
be O
incomplete O
, O
because O
it O
did O
not O
include O
the O
controversial O
Chebaa B-LOC
farms O
, O
on O
the O
border O
with O
Syria B-LOC
, O
and O
the O
release O
of O
some O
20 O
Lebanese O
detained O
in O
Israel B-LOC
, O
it O
said O
it O
would O
cooperate O
with O
the O
UN B-ORG
. O

Israel B-ORG
and O
the O
UN B-ORG
assure O
these O
farms O
are O
Syrian O
, O
but O
Damascus O
and O
Beirut B-LOC
claim O
they O
are O
Lebanese O
and O
, O
for O
that O
purpose O
, O
the O
government B-ORG
has O
sent O
several O
documents O
to O
the O
United B-ORG
Nations I-ORG
to O
testify O
to O
their O
sovereignty O
. O

Hezbollah B-ORG
leader O
Sheikh O
Hasan B-PER
Nasrala I-PER
has O
announced O
that O
he O
will O
continue O
the O
struggle O
until O
the O
liberation O
of O
that O
territory O
, O
located O
at O
the O
foot O
of O
Mount B-LOC
Hermon I-LOC
and O
rich O
in O
aquifers O
. O

In O
response O
to O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
Israel B-ORG
has O
threatened O
with O
" O
painful O
responses O
" O
in O
the O
event O
that O
attacks O
on O
its O
territory O
continue O
, O
referring O
to O
the O
" O
Katiuska O
" O
rockets O
that O
that O
group O
is O
sporadically O
launching O
against O
the O
Israeli O
north O
. O

Apparently O
, O
Syria B-ORG
, O
which O
has O
a O
preponderant O
influence O
in O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
where O
it O
has O
some O
35,000 O
troops O
, O
has O
given O
for O
the O
time O
being O
a O
white O
letter O
to O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
a O
pro O
- O
Iran O
group O
in O
which O
Damascus O
also O
has O
a O
large O
influence O
. O

The O
Israeli B-ORG
withdrawal O
from O
the O
south O
was O
part O
of O
Israeli O
Prime O
Minister O
Ehud B-PER
Barak I-PER
’s O
strategy O
to O
force O
Syria B-ORG
into O
negotiations O
on O
the O
Golan B-LOC
, O
occupied O
by O
Israel B-ORG
in O
1967 O
and O
annexed O
in O
1981 O
. O

In O
theory O
, O
Syria B-ORG
is O
damaged O
by O
the O
unilateral O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
southern O
Lebanon O
, O
as O
it O
deprives O
Damascus B-ORG
of O
a O
letter O
it O
used O
, O
through O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
to O
put O
pressure O
on O
Israel B-ORG
. O

However O
, O
in O
practice O
, O
Damascus B-ORG
, O
which O
shows O
itself O
inflexible O
on O
the O
issue O
of O
returning O
the O
Golan B-LOC
to O
the O
pre O
- O
June O
1967 O
demarcation O
line O
, O
seems O
to O
have O
forced O
Israel B-ORG
to O
execute O
its O
threat O
and O
has O
been O
strengthened O
in O
its O
control O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
. O

If O
Israel B-ORG
occupied O
ten O
percent O
of O
Lebanon O
’s O
territory O
, O
the O
Syrian O
troops O
are O
deployed O
in O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
country O
and O
it O
is O
not O
ruled O
out O
that O
they O
can O
be O
assigned O
a O
mission O
in O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
so O
their O
withdrawal O
is O
complicated O
, O
despite O
the O
desire O
of O
a O
majority O
of O
Lebanese O
. O

The O
great O
powers O
have O
assigned O
Syria B-ORG
the O
role O
of O
guardian O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
and O
know O
that O
if O
it O
fails O
to O
reach O
an O
agreement O
with O
Israel B-ORG
, O
the O
Lebanese O
situation O
will O
remain O
uncertain O
and O
unpredictable O
. O

The O
only O
hope O
that O
the O
Lebanese O
situation O
will O
stabilize O
is O
that O
global O
peace O
in O
the O
Middle B-LOC
East I-LOC
will O
be O
achieved O
, O
so O
that O
this O
country O
, O
which O
has O
been O
the O
main O
victim O
, O
along O
with O
the O
Palestinians O
, O
of O
the O
Arab O
- O
Israeli O
conflict O
, O
will O
not O
continue O
to O
be O
so O
in O
the O
future O
. O
by O
Orlando B-PER
Lizama I-PER
Washington B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

U.S. B-ORG
President O
Bill B-PER
Clinton I-PER
recorded O
a O
major O
foreign O
policy O
triumph O
with O
the O
House B-ORG
of I-ORG
Representatives I-ORG
’ O
approval O
of O
a O
trade O
deal O
with O
China B-ORG
that O
will O
add O
to O
the O
economic O
success O
of O
his O
government O
. O

Political O
analysts O
indicated O
today O
that O
the O
decision O
of O
the O
House B-ORG
, O
which O
has O
the O
approval O
of O
the O
Senate B-ORG
, O
will O
open O
a O
new O
chapter O
in O
the O
relations O
between O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
and O
China B-ORG
and O
, O
above O
all O
, O
the O
world O
’s O
largest O
market O
for O
American O
products O
. O

By O
approving O
the O
granting O
of O
permanent O
trade O
privileges O
to O
China B-ORG
by O
237 O
votes O
to O
197 O
against O
, O
the O
House B-ORG
ended O
Wednesday O
the O
practice O
of O
discussing O
those O
privileges O
each O
year O
and O
ensured O
the O
application O
on O
Chinese O
goods O
of O
the O
same O
tariffs O
that O
are O
imposed O
on O
those O
of O
other O
countries O
. O

Also O
, O
after O
China B-ORG
achieved O
a O
similar O
agreement O
last O
week O
with O
the O
European B-ORG
Union I-ORG
, O
Beijing B-LOC
’s O
authorities O
ensured O
its O
country O
’s O
accession O
to O
the O
World B-ORG
Trade I-ORG
Organization I-ORG
( O
WTO B-ORG
) O
. O

In O
exchange O
for O
that O
, O
once O
the O
Senate B-ORG
officially O
approves O
it O
in O
June O
, O
China B-LOC
will O
open O
its O
1.3 O
billion O
consumer O
market O
to O
a O
wide O
range O
of O
U.S. O
products O
, O
from O
agricultural O
to O
telecommunications O
to O
automobiles O
. O

Without O
external O
conflicts O
and O
a O
booming O
economy O
, O
Clinton B-PER
had O
made O
approval O
the O
legislative O
priority O
of O
his O
government O
that O
will O
end O
in O
January O
next O
year O
, O
and O
after O
the O
vote O
he O
did O
not O
hide O
his O
happiness O
. O

“ O
The O
House B-ORG
of I-ORG
Representatives I-ORG
has O
taken O
a O
historic O
step O
towards O
continuing O
prosperity O
in O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
, O
reform O
in O
China B-ORG
and O
peace O
in O
the O
world O
, O
” O
said O
Clinton B-PER
, O
who O
in O
1993 O
signed O
the O
Free B-MISC
Trade I-MISC
Agreement I-MISC
( O
FTA B-MISC
) O
with O
Mexico B-ORG
and O
Canada B-ORG
. O

“ O
I O
’ve O
always O
been O
a O
believer O
that O
if O
we O
open O
markets O
abroad O
, O
we O
’ll O
give O
way O
to O
more O
opportunities O
in O
the O
country O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O

And O
in O
reference O
to O
criticisms O
about O
the O
lack O
of O
democracy O
and O
the O
human O
rights O
violations O
in O
China B-LOC
, O
the O
president O
indicated O
that O
the O
agreement O
will O
contribute O
to O
improving O
the O
situation O
. O

“ O
We O
’ll O
have O
more O
positive O
influence O
with O
a O
stretched O
hand O
than O
with O
a O
tight O
fist O
, O
” O
he O
added O
. O

Clinton B-PER
and O
his O
advisors O
had O
previously O
said O
that O
rejecting O
the O
agreement O
would O
have O
meant O
pushing O
relations O
between O
the O
two O
countries O
to O
an O
abyss O
that O
would O
threaten O
stability O
in O
Asia B-LOC
and O
aggravate O
tensions O
between O
China B-ORG
and O
Taiwan B-ORG
. O

" O
The O
approval O
has O
been O
a O
concrete O
outcome O
because O
it O
makes O
no O
sense O
to O
face O
the O
world O
's O
most O
populous O
country O
, O
" O
said O
Sidney B-PER
Weintraub I-PER
, O
of O
the O
Center B-ORG
for I-ORG
International I-ORG
Strategic I-ORG
Studies I-ORG
( O
CSIS B-ORG
) O
. O

“ O
Opening O
other O
markets O
is O
not O
a O
favor O
we O
do O
to O
other O
countries O
. O

It O
’s O
an O
opportunity O
we O
create O
for O
ourselves O
, O
” O
said O
Sherman B-PER
Katc I-PER
, O
an O
analyst O
at O
CSIS B-MISC
. O

However O
, O
there O
have O
also O
been O
criticisms O
, O
especially O
from O
those O
who O
reject O
China B-ORG
’s O
political O
ideology O
and O
the O
human O
rights O
situation O
, O
globalization O
and O
trade O
unions O
who O
fear O
the O
deal O
will O
cause O
the O
loss O
of O
jobs O
in O
the O
country O
. O

Senate B-ORG
Foreign I-ORG
Affairs I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
Chairman O
Jesse B-PER
Helms I-PER
has O
vowed O
to O
fight O
to O
prevent O
that O
branch O
of O
Congress B-ORG
from O
approving O
the O
deal O
. O

“ O
I O
do O
n’t O
want O
to O
wait O
for O
the O
party O
, O
but O
I O
feel O
compelled O
to O
make O
it O
clear O
that O
I O
do O
n’t O
intend O
for O
the O
Senate B-ORG
to O
bend O
to O
the O
plan O
to O
reward O
the O
Chinese O
Communists O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O

The O
chairman O
of O
the O
conservationist O
group O
Friends B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Earth I-ORG
, O
Brent B-PER
Blackwelder I-PER
, O
said O
the O
deal O
“ O
demonstrates O
that O
U.S. B-ORG
foreign O
policy O
has O
been O
captured O
by O
corporate O
pollutants O
and O
major O
campaign O
contributors O
. O
” O

To O
ensure O
approval O
, O
House B-ORG
lawmakers O
added O
to O
the O
draft O
a O
proposal O
to O
create O
a O
human O
rights O
observation O
group O
. O

But O
, O
according O
to O
Friends B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Earth I-ORG
, O
the O
project O
omitted O
references O
to O
environmental O
protection O
in O
China B-LOC
, O
“ O
where O
two O
million O
people O
die O
each O
year O
due O
to O
water O
and O
air O
pollution O
. O
” O

Where O
is O
freedom O
of O
expression O
? O
where O
is O
freedom O
of O
religion O
? O
where O
is O
freedom O
of O
assembly O
? O

In O
China B-ORG
not O
, O
" O
Georgia B-LOC
representative O
John B-PER
Lewis I-PER
said O
in O
a O
statement O
rejecting O
the O
agreement O
. O

“ O
If O
we O
defend O
human O
and O
civil O
rights O
in O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
and O
elsewhere O
in O
the O
world O
, O
we O
must O
defend O
them O
in O
China B-LOC
, O
” O
he O
added O
. O

In O
a O
debate O
that O
was O
made O
more O
considering O
economic O
than O
political O
interests O
, O
the O
approval O
was O
applauded O
by O
Texas B-LOC
Governor O
George B-PER
W. I-PER
Bush I-PER
, O
a O
Republican O
presidential O
candidate O
who O
faces O
Democrat O
and O
vice O
president O
Al B-PER
Gore I-PER
in O
the O
November O
elections O
. O

" O
It O
means O
a O
stronger O
economy O
for O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
, O
as O
well O
as O
more O
opportunities O
for O
freedom O
in O
China B-ORG
, O
" O
Claudia B-PER
Gutiérrez I-PER
said O
in O
Beijing B-LOC
on O
May O
25 O
. O

- O
by O

The O
Chinese O
government B-ORG
urged O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
to O
correct O
the O
" O
error O
" O
of O
including O
the O
creation O
of O
a O
human O
rights O
commission O
in O
the O
resolution O
granting O
this O
country O
the O
permanent O
status O
of O
normal O
trade O
relations O
( O
PNTR B-MISC
) O
. O

According O
to O
Foreign B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
spokeswoman O
Zhang B-PER
Qiyue I-PER
, O
Beijing B-ORG
has O
already O
filed O
its O
complaint O
with O
the O
U.S. O
executive O
on O
this O
matter O
, O
as O
it O
not O
only O
opposes O
the O
articles O
referring O
to O
the O
commission O
but O
“ O
will O
not O
accept O
them O
. O
” O

“ O
We O
urge O
the O
U.S. B-ORG
to O
correct O
its O
mistake O
, O
so O
that O
a O
healthy O
and O
peaceful O
development O
of O
bilateral O
economic O
and O
trade O
cooperation O
is O
ensured O
, O
” O
the O
Foreign B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
and O
the O
Foreign B-ORG
Trade I-ORG
Ministry O
said O
. O

The O
U.S. B-ORG
House I-ORG
of I-ORG
Representatives I-ORG
passed O
the O
resolution O
on O
Monday O
morning O
, O
after O
more O
than O
seven O
hours O
of O
debate O
, O
by O
237 O
votes O
in O
favor O
and O
197 O
against O
. O

To O
ensure O
the O
victory O
of O
this O
historic O
measure O
, O
firmly O
defended O
by O
U.S. O
President O
Bill B-PER
Clinton I-PER
over O
the O
past O
few O
months O
, O
Congressional B-ORG
leaders O
have O
agreed O
to O
create O
a O
legislative O
and O
executive O
committee O
that O
will O
annually O
oversee O
human O
rights O
policy O
in O
this O
country O
. O

Although O
Beijing B-LOC
called O
the O
U.S. O
resolution O
a O
“ O
wise O
measure O
, O
” O
it O
also O
accuses O
Washington B-ORG
of O
using O
human O
rights O
as O
an O
excuse O
to O
interfere O
in O
its O
internal O
affairs O
and O
harm O
its O
interests O
, O
“ O
something O
unacceptable O
for O
the O
Chinese O
government B-ORG
. O
” O

The O
Moftec B-ORG
promptly O
threatened O
retaliation O
if O
such O
a O
commission O
is O
actually O
launched O
to O
monitor O
the O
human O
rights O
situation O
. O

" O
China B-ORG
wishes O
to O
express O
its O
profound O
dissatisfaction O
with O
this O
resolution O
and O
reserves O
the O
right O
to O
react O
in O
the O
future O
" O
on O
a O
matter O
that O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
has O
a O
duty O
to O
resolve O
, O
" O
Hu B-PER
Chusheng I-PER
, O
a O
spokesman O
for O
the O
Moftec B-ORG
, O
warned O
. O

“ O
The O
grant O
to O
China B-ORG
of O
the O
PNTR B-MISC
is O
an O
obligation O
of O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
, O
following O
the O
rules O
of O
the O
World B-ORG
Trade I-ORG
Organization I-ORG
( O
WTO B-ORG
) O
, O
” O
the O
Foreign B-MISC
Representative O
said O
, O
“ O
since O
the O
permanent O
status O
constitutes O
the O
basis O
and O
a O
prerequisite O
” O
for O
the O
bilateral O
agreement O
on O
China B-ORG
’s O
access O
to O
the O
WTO B-ORG
signed O
on O
November O
15 O
in O
this O
capital O
to O
enter O
into O
force O
. O

Zhang B-PER
pointed O
out O
that O
the O
congressional O
resolution O
, O
which O
must O
be O
ratified O
by O
the O
Senate B-ORG
in O
mid O
- O
June O
, O
not O
only O
contributes O
to O
China B-ORG
and O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
to O
develop O
their O
economic O
and O
trade O
exchanges O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
equality O
and O
mutual O
benefit O
, O
but O
also O
helps O
to O
create O
the O
conditions O
for O
the O
healthy O
and O
stable O
development O
of O
bilateral O
relations O
. O

The O
spokeswoman O
urged O
the O
U.S. O
side O
to O
respect O
the O
three O
communiqués O
signed O
by O
both O
countries O
, O
the O
basic O
rules O
governing O
international O
relations O
and O
the O
WTO B-ORG
rules O
. O

With O
the O
approval O
of O
the O
PNTR B-MISC
, O
20 O
years O
of O
annual O
reviews O
of O
China B-LOC
’s O
trade O
status O
by O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
end O
and O
the O
doors O
are O
opened O
for O
the O
country O
to O
become O
WTO B-ORG
’s O
136th O
partner O
by O
the O
end O
of O
the O
year O
, O
an O
opportunity O
that O
was O
more O
at O
hand O
after O
Beijing B-ORG
signed O
a O
similar O
agreement O
with O
the O
European B-ORG
Union I-ORG
( O
EU B-ORG
) O
on O
Friday O
. O

With O
China B-ORG
’s O
entry O
into O
the O
regulatory O
body O
of O
world O
trade O
, O
the O
tariffs O
that O
this O
country O
must O
pay O
to O
access O
the O
US B-LOC
will O
be O
equal O
to O
those O
of O
virtually O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
nations O
, O
while O
Beijing B-ORG
will O
have O
to O
open O
its O
markets O
to O
sectors O
such O
as O
agriculture O
, O
telecommunications O
or O
insurance O
. O

While O
the O
detractors O
of O
the O
resolution O
believe O
that O
China B-ORG
's O
access O
to O
the O
WTO B-ORG
will O
aggravate O
the O
already O
giant O
trade O
deficit O
that O
the O
USins B-ORG
with O
this O
country O
, O
of O
$ O
68 O
billion O
last O
year O
, O
its O
defenders O
assure O
that O
not O
only O
will O
benefit O
the O
U.S. O
economy O
, O
but O
also O
national O
security O
, O
as O
political O
and O
economic O
reforms O
in O
this O
Asian O
giant O
will O
be O
promoted O
. O

Lisbon B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

The O
Portuguese O
press O
highlighted O
today O
the O
eighth O
victory O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
in O
a O
historic O
final O
of O
the O
Europa B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
that O
for O
the O
first O
time O
faced O
two O
teams O
from O
the O
same O
country O
. O

The O
judgments O
favorable O
to O
the O
game O
developed O
by O
the O
winning O
team O
are O
unanimous O
, O
" O
just O
insurmountable O
" O
, O
" O
the O
story O
won O
, O
the O
madridists O
religiously O
respected O
their O
past O
and O
built O
a O
cruel O
ending O
for O
the O
beautiful O
Valencia B-ORG
adventure O
" O
, O
commented O
" O
A B-ORG
Bola I-ORG
" O
on O
its O
first O
pages O
. O

" O
The O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
myth O
continues O
to O
rise O
" O
, O
" O
Raúl O
: O
the B-MISC
eighth I-MISC
wonder I-MISC
" O
titles O
" O
Récord B-MISC
" O
, O
which O
reports O
that O
the O
sporting O
show O
was O
" O
superb O
" O
by O
the O
quality O
of O
the O
game O
and O
a O
stadium O
divided O
between O
the O
two O
aficionados O
who O
passionately O
followed O
the O
incidences O
of O
the O
match O
. O

" O
Valencian O
rice O
was O
a O
sweet O
merengue O
" O
according O
to O
the O
" O
Journal B-MISC
of I-MISC
News I-MISC
" O
, O
which O
highlights O
the O
superiority O
of O
the O
madrid O
team O
over O
a O
Valencia B-ORG
who O
became O
younger O
from O
" O
lack O
of O
rhythm O
" O
and O
" O
lost O
almost O
all O
the O
inspiration O
of O
attack O
" O
. O

Freetown B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
murder O
in O
Sierra B-LOC
Leone I-LOC
of O
four O
pro O
- O
government O
forces O
soldiers O
and O
two O
journalists O
by O
the O
rebels O
of O
the O
United O
Revolutionary B-ORG
Forces I-ORG
( O
FRU B-ORG
) O
coincided O
with O
the O
recrudescence O
of O
the O
wave O
of O
violence O
that O
has O
been O
living O
this O
African O
country O
for O
almost O
a O
month O
. O

Spanish O
journalist O
Miguel B-PER
Gil I-PER
Moreno I-PER
, O
who O
worked O
as O
a O
cameraman O
for O
the O
U.S. O
agency O
Asociated B-ORG
Press I-ORG
TV I-ORG
, O
and O
his O
U.S. O
colleague O
Kurt B-PER
Schork I-PER
, O
a O
correspondent O
for O
the O
British O
news O
agency O
Reuters B-ORG
, O
were O
killed O
yesterday O
when O
the O
column O
of O
government O
troops O
next O
to O
which O
they O
traveled O
was O
assaulted O
by O
FRU B-ORG
rebels O
. O

In O
the O
incident O
, O
which O
took O
place O
at O
the O
crossroads O
of O
Rogberi B-LOC
, O
about O
80 O
kilometers O
northeast O
of O
Freetown B-LOC
, O
two O
other O
journalists O
, O
the O
Greek O
Yannis B-PER
Behrakis I-PER
and O
the O
South O
African O
Mark B-PER
Chisholm I-PER
, O
both O
Reuters B-ORG
correspondents O
, O
were O
also O
wounded O
. O

Also O
, O
and O
according O
to O
U.N. B-ORG
sources O
in O
the O
Sierra B-LOC
Leone I-LOC
capital O
, O
four O
Sierra O
Leone O
soldiers O
also O
fell O
dead O
in O
the O
embassies O
. O

The O
two O
wounded O
reporters O
were O
taken O
to O
a O
campaign O
hospital O
prepared O
by O
UN B-ORG
forces O
without O
fear O
for O
their O
lives O
, O
while O
the O
32 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Spanish O
journalist O
's O
body O
was O
in O
Freetown B-LOC
yesterday O
waiting O
to O
be O
repatriated O
, O
U.N. B-ORG
sources O
in O
the O
city O
said O
. O

The O
UN B-PER
Secretary I-PER
- O
General O
, O
Ghanaian O
Kofi B-PER
Annan I-PER
, O
expressed O
his O
sadness O
at O
the O
death O
of O
the O
two O
journalists O
, O
of O
whom O
he O
claimed O
“ O
they O
were O
professionals O
who O
sought O
to O
report O
on O
the O
bloody O
conflict O
that O
has O
already O
taken O
too O
many O
lives O
. O
” O

“ O
They O
were O
doing O
what O
any O
other O
journalist O
around O
the O
world O
is O
doing O
: O
taking O
risks O
so O
that O
we O
can O
be O
informed O
, O
” O
Annan B-PER
added O
in O
a O
statement O
. O

For O
his O
part O
, O
the O
president O
of O
Asociated B-ORG
Press I-ORG
, O
Louis B-PER
D. I-PER
Boccardi I-PER
, O
assured O
that O
“ O
Miguel B-PER
’s O
loss O
leaves O
them O
with O
an O
indescribable O
feeling O
of O
loss O
. O

Our O
pain O
is O
not O
relieved O
with O
the O
certainty O
that O
he O
was O
doing O
the O
work O
he O
loved O
when O
the O
tragedy O
ravaged O
him O
. O
” O

Gil B-PER
Moreno I-PER
, O
native O
of O
Barcelona B-LOC
, O
in O
northeastern O
Spain B-LOC
, O
had O
covered O
, O
among O
others O
, O
the O
conflicts O
of O
Kosovo B-LOC
, O
Chechnya B-LOC
, O
Iraq B-LOC
and O
Congo B-LOC
, O
but O
as O
Nigel B-PER
Baker I-PER
, O
news O
director O
of O
the O
U.S. O
news O
agency O
, O
stated O
, O
“ O
he O
never O
took O
a O
step O
without O
measuring O
the O
reasons O
for O
doing O
so O
and O
his O
options O
. O
” O

The O
Spanish O
reporter O
had O
received O
last O
month O
the O
camera O
of O
the O
year O
award O
by O
the O
" O
Royal B-ORG
Television I-ORG
Society I-ORG
" O
. O

The O
other O
victim O
, O
53 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Kurt B-PER
Shork I-PER
, O
worked O
for O
Reuters B-ORG
for O
the O
last O
decade O
. O

“ O
Kurt B-PER
was O
a O
brave O
reporter O
, O
a O
brave O
man O
, O
who O
better O
than O
other O
journalists O
knew O
how O
to O
reflect O
the O
difficult O
situation O
of O
the O
Kurdish O
population O
during O
the O
Gulf B-MISC
War I-MISC
and O
of O
the O
victims O
of O
the O
Balkan B-LOC
conflict O
afterwards O
, O
” O
said O
the O
agency O
’s O
editor O
- O
in O
- O
chief O
, O
Geert B-PER
Linnebank I-PER
. O

The O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
issued O
a O
statement O
condemning O
the O
incident O
. O

“ O
We O
condemn O
this O
violent O
attack O
in O
the O
most O
vigorous O
terms O
possible O
, O
both O
the O
U.S. B-ORG
Embassy I-ORG
in O
Freetown B-LOC
and O
the O
State B-ORG
Department I-ORG
in O
Washington B-LOC
are O
ready O
to O
help O
families O
in O
this O
difficult O
time O
, O
” O
said O
Philip B-PER
Reeker I-PER
, O
a O
State B-ORG
Department I-ORG
spokesman O
. O

Journalists O
were O
assaulted O
by O
FRU B-ORG
rebels O
as O
they O
traveled O
in O
two O
military O
trucks O
alongside O
a O
column O
of O
pro O
- O
government O
soldiers O
at O
the O
crossroads O
of O
Rogberi B-LOC
, O
near O
the O
town O
of O
Masaka B-LOC
, O
about O
80 O
kilometers O
northeast O
of O
Freetown B-LOC
. O

In O
this O
area O
, O
of O
high O
strategic O
value O
, O
other O
clashes O
had O
previously O
been O
registered O
between O
" O
blue O
helmets O
" O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
rebel O
groups O
. O

On O
Monday O
, O
troops O
of O
the O
Sierra O
Leone O
Army B-ORG
had O
taken O
the O
crossroads O
of O
Rogberi B-LOC
, O
where O
several O
bodies O
, O
in O
advanced O
state O
of O
decomposition O
, O
dressed O
in O
uniforms O
of O
" O
blue O
helmets O
" O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
that O
could O
correspond O
to O
the O
members O
of O
this O
international O
body O
kidnapped O
by O
the O
rebels O
three O
weeks O
ago O
were O
found O
. O

The O
FRU B-ORG
still O
holds O
290 O
blue O
helmets O
, O
and O
according O
to O
Liberian O
President O
Charles B-PER
Taylor I-PER
, O
who O
acts O
as O
a O
mediator O
between O
the O
United O
Nations B-ORG
and O
the O
Sierra O
Leone O
rebels O
, O
they O
will O
not O
release O
more O
hostages O
until O
government O
forces O
stop O
their O
offensive O
against O
the O
FRU B-ORG
and O
stop O
their O
unstoppable O
advance O
towards O
the O
guerrilla O
feuds O
inside O
the O
country O
. O

Roma B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
- O
" O
Europe B-MISC
is I-MISC
back I-MISC
from I-MISC
Real I-MISC
Madrid I-MISC
" O
, O
is O
the O
title O
with O
which O
the O
Italian O
press O
highlights O
the O
triumph O
of O
the O
team O
of O
the O
Spanish B-LOC
capital O
in O
the O
Champions O
League O
final O
against O
the O
other O
Spanish O
club O
, O
Valencia B-ORG
, O
of O
which O
the O
newspapers O
say O
did O
not O
show O
itself O
brilliant O
game O
he O
did O
against O
Barcelona B-ORG
or O
Lazio B-ORG
. O

Although O
it O
appears O
in O
a O
screenshot O
of O
the O
first O
pages O
, O
the O
final O
of O
the O
Champions O
Cup B-MISC
does O
not O
occupy O
the O
big O
titles O
of O
the O
cover O
of O
the O
Italian O
sports O
newspapers O
, O
which O
in O
the O
case O
of O
" O
La B-ORG
Gazzetta I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
borders O
it O
to O
page O
15 O
and O
in O
the O
" O
Corriere B-ORG
dellos I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
to O
page O
17 O
. O

There O
was O
no O
Italian O
club O
among O
the O
finalists O
. O

" O
The B-MISC
Real I-MISC
conquers I-MISC
its I-MISC
eighth I-MISC
victory I-MISC
in I-MISC
the O
championship O
cup O
. O
The O
Valencia O
defeated O
by O
3 O
- O
0 O
" O
, O
is O
the O
title O
of O
" O
La B-ORG
Gazzetta I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
, O
which O
on O
the O
inside O
page O
adds O
: O
" O
The O
eighth O
wonder O
of O
the O
Real B-ORG
, O
the O
Valencia B-ORG
wakes O
up O
from O
the O
dream O
" O
. O

According O
to O
the O
milanese O
newspaper O
, O
the O
" O
most O
expert O
" O
team O
, O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
, O
was O
awarded O
, O
" O
who O
imposed O
on O
a O
Valencia B-ORG
who O
shook O
. O
" O

He O
added O
that O
the O
madridists O
imposed O
themselves O
in O
the O
duels O
and O
that O
in O
the O
center O
of O
the O
field O
they O
dominated O
Redondo B-PER
and O
McManaman B-PER
. O

After O
highlighting O
Raul B-PER
's O
game O
, O
" O
La B-ORG
Gazzetta I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
says O
that O
the O
young O
Madrid O
player O
" O
is O
a O
step O
" O
from O
the O
Ballon B-MISC
d'Or I-MISC
and O
that O
he O
deserves O
to O
be O
in O
the O
gallery O
of O
the O
Real B-MISC
Madrid I-MISC
Grandes I-MISC
, O
between O
Di B-PER
Stefano I-PER
and O
Kopa B-PER
. O

" O
Hurricane B-MISC
Real I-MISC
over I-MISC
Valencia I-MISC
" O
is O
the O
title O
of O
" O
Corriere B-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
, O
the O
Roman O
newspaper O
that O
states O
that O
the O
madridists O
gave O
" O
a O
severe O
lesson O
to O
the O
team O
alienated O
by O
Cuper B-PER
" O
. O

The O
morning O
says O
that O
for O
the O
Real B-ORG
the O
achievement O
of O
the O
cup O
means O
rescue O
from O
a O
bad O
season O
and O
that O
the O
Valencia B-ORG
relied O
too O
much O
on O
their O
counterballs O
, O
which O
did O
not O
stop O
Moriente B-PER
, O
McManaman B-PER
and O
Raul B-PER
to O
" O
sign O
" O
the O
eighth O
cup O
of O
champions O
. O

He O
highlights O
young O
goalkeeper O
Iker B-PER
Casillas I-PER
( O
called O
him O
the O
baby O
- O
champion O
) O
and O
Helguera B-PER
and O
especially O
Raul B-PER
, O
who O
he O
defines O
as O
a O
" O
total O
champion O
" O
who O
marks O
goals O
of O
all O
types O
and O
ways O
, O
" O
He O
has O
a O
force O
and O
a O
crazy O
desire O
to O
beat O
. O
" O

For O
" O
Corriere B-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
, O
the O
triumph O
of O
Madrid B-ORG
implies O
the O
revenge O
of O
Del B-PER
Bosque I-PER
( O
the O
coach O
) O
, O
who O
lost O
as O
a O
player O
of O
Real B-ORG
in O
Paris B-LOC
the O
1981 O
final O
against O
Liverpool B-ORG
, O
and O
the O
surrender O
of O
Cuper B-PER
. O

San B-LOC
Sebastián I-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
judge O
who O
investigates O
the O
death O
of O
Mikel B-PER
Zabalza I-PER
in O
1985 O
has O
cited O
to O
declare O
as O
accused O
in O
this O
case O
the O
former O
civilian O
guards O
Enrique B-PER
Dorado I-PER
and O
Felipe B-PER
Bayo I-PER
, O
recently O
convicted O
by O
the O
murders O
of O
Lasa B-PER
and O
Zabala B-PER
, O
according O
to O
legal O
sources O
. O

In O
a O
case O
notified O
yesterday O
, O
the O
titular O
of O
the O
Instruction B-ORG
Court I-ORG
Number I-ORG
1 I-ORG
of O
San B-LOC
Sebastián I-LOC
, O
Augusto B-PER
Maeso I-PER
, O
who O
is O
currently O
in O
the O
First B-ORG
Section I-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Provincial I-ORG
Court I-ORG
in O
commission O
of O
services O
, O
reminds O
that O
during O
the O
instruction O
of O
the O
summary O
the O
names O
of O
Dorado B-PER
and O
Bayo B-PER
, O
who O
have O
been O
called O
to O
declare O
the O
next O
19 O
September O
, O
were O
quoted O
by O
various O
witnesses O
and O
appeared O
in O
press O
releases O
. O

Maeso B-PER
considers O
that O
some O
of O
these O
testimonies O
" O
question O
" O
the O
veracity O
of O
the O
official O
version O
, O
which O
defends O
that O
Zabalza B-PER
died O
drowned O
in O
falling O
to O
the O
river B-LOC
Bidasoa I-LOC
when O
he O
tried O
to O
escape O
from O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Guard I-ORG
agents O
he O
guided O
in O
the O
search O
for O
a O
" O
zulo O
" O
of O
ETA B-ORG
. O

According O
to O
the O
judge O
, O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
young O
man O
was O
applied O
to O
the O
anti O
- O
terrorist O
legislation O
after O
his O
detention O
for O
his O
alleged O
relationship O
with O
ETA B-ORG
and O
that O
he O
had O
revealed O
the O
location O
of O
a O
" O
zulo O
" O
are O
data O
that O
" O
advise O
security O
measures O
that O
avoid O
escapes O
in O
the O
supposed O
place O
where O
it O
would O
be O
" O
this O
hiding O
" O
, O
while O
Zabalza B-PER
was O
led O
by O
" O
only O
three O
members O
of O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Guard I-ORG
" O
. O

One O
of O
the O
testimonies O
on O
which O
the O
case O
is O
supported O
is O
a O
statement O
by O
Dorado B-PER
himself O
, O
who O
admitted O
to O
two O
journalists O
of O
El B-ORG
Mundo I-ORG
that O
Zabalza B-PER
died O
in O
the O
headquarters O
of O
Intxaurrondo B-LOC
when O
Bayo B-PER
practiced O
torture O
known O
as O
" O
the O
bath O
" O
. O

Moscow B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

Russia B-LOC
's O
gold O
and O
foreign O
exchange O
reserves O
rose O
by O
$ O
600 O
million O
to O
$ O
18.3 O
billion O
as O
of O
May O
19 O
, O
the O
central B-ORG
bank I-ORG
said O
in O
a O
statement O
. O

According O
to O
the O
report O
, O
as O
of O
May O
12 O
, O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
’s O
gold O
and O
foreign O
exchange O
reserves O
were O
$ O
17.7 O
billion O
. O

The O
currency O
assets O
held O
by O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
and O
the O
Ministry B-ORG
of I-ORG
Finance I-ORG
are O
calculated O
in O
U.S. O
dollars O
and O
their O
value O
depends O
on O
the O
official O
exchange O
rate O
ruble O
- O
dollar O
established O
by O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
at O
the O
time O
of O
its O
accounting O
. O

Gold O
reserves O
are O
valued O
at O
$ O
300 O
per O
ounce O
of O
gold O
. O

Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
( O
Badajoz B-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O

- O
by O

The O
socialist O
groups O
of O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
and O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
have O
agreed O
to O
create O
a O
political O
commission O
of O
parity O
whose O
function O
will O
be O
to O
elaborate O
joint O
proposals O
to O
present O
them O
in O
their O
respective O
Councils B-ORG
, O
the O
Junta B-ORG
de I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
and O
the O
Central O
Government B-ORG
. O

This O
has O
been O
announced O
by O
the O
general O
secretaries O
in O
the O
respective O
localities O
, O
Francisco B-PER
García I-PER
Ramos I-PER
, O
by O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
, O
and O
Juan B-PER
Manzano I-PER
, O
by O
Dombenitense O
, O
in O
a O
press O
conference O
in O
which O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
spokesman O
in O
the O
Don B-ORG
Benito I-ORG
City I-ORG
Hall O
, O
Julio B-PER
Carmona I-PER
, O
and O
the O
number O
two O
of O
the O
villanovens O
socialists O
, O
Raúl B-PER
Borrasca I-PER
, O
have O
also O
been O
present O
. O

The O
aforementioned O
commission O
will O
be O
made O
up O
of O
four O
representatives O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
of O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
and O
another O
four O
of O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
and O
will O
also O
be O
responsible O
for O
raising O
their O
proposals O
to O
the O
provincial O
, O
regional O
and O
even O
national O
bodies O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
itself O
. O

The O
combined O
force O
of O
the O
socialists O
in O
both O
municipalities O
is O
17 O
councillors O
, O
9 O
in O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
and O
8 O
in O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
. O

The O
number O
of O
affiliates O
between O
the O
two O
populations O
is O
more O
than O
500 O
. O

The O
idea O
of O
creating O
this O
alliance O
arose O
about O
three O
weeks O
ago O
through O
a O
phone O
call O
made O
by O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
’s O
socialist O
spokesman O
, O
Julio B-PER
Carmona I-PER
, O
to O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
’s O
socialist O
spokesman O
, O
Francisco B-PER
García I-PER
Ramos I-PER
. O

The O
next O
step O
was O
the O
convening O
of O
both O
local O
executives O
, O
who O
have O
held O
several O
meetings O
before O
publicly O
spreading O
the O
understanding O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

The O
Minister O
of O
Justice B-MISC
, O
Angel B-PER
Acebes I-PER
, O
pointed O
out O
today O
that O
the O
judge O
Manuel B-PER
García I-PER
Castellón I-PER
, O
who O
will O
be O
the O
Spanish O
link O
magistrate O
in O
France B-LOC
, O
will O
not O
exercise O
any O
type O
of O
jurisdictional O
function O
but O
cooperation O
and O
collaboration O
. O

In O
statements O
to O
the O
Cope B-ORG
chain O
, O
Acebes B-PER
explained O
that O
the O
job O
of O
the O
linking O
magistrate O
consists O
of O
exercising O
a O
series O
of O
functions O
of O
cooperation O
between O
States B-ORG
in O
a O
particular O
matter O
, O
in O
this O
case O
with O
France B-ORG
in O
the O
fight O
against O
terrorism O
. O

The O
link O
magistrates O
try O
to O
boost O
, O
accelerate O
procedures O
, O
contacts O
between O
competent O
services O
when O
delays O
occur O
and O
know O
the O
laws O
of O
both O
countries O
, O
Acebes B-PER
said O
, O
who O
said O
they O
are O
" O
typical O
tasks O
of O
collaboration O
and O
cooperation O
" O
. O

He O
clarified O
that O
García B-PER
Castellón I-PER
will O
not O
exercise O
any O
type O
of O
jurisdictional O
function O
and O
recalled O
that O
the O
regulation O
that O
regulates O
these O
link O
magistrates O
allows O
him O
not O
to O
be O
a O
judge O
, O
because O
he O
could O
have O
been O
appointed O
a O
prosecutor O
. O

Even O
, O
he O
added O
, O
in O
other O
countries O
it O
is O
not O
even O
necessary O
for O
this O
function O
to O
be O
developed O
by O
a O
magistrate O
or O
a O
prosecutor O
, O
but O
it O
is O
enough O
that O
it O
is O
a O
specialist O
in O
law B-MISC
. O

" O
It O
does O
not O
resolve O
any O
matter O
or O
exercise O
other O
powers O
of O
judges O
of O
one O
country O
or O
another O
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O

This O
figure O
is O
regulated O
by O
a O
law O
that O
was O
passed O
in O
1998 O
and O
that O
establishes O
its O
legal O
regime O
and O
its O
election O
system O
, O
the O
Justice B-MISC
Minister O
said O
, O
adding O
that O
its O
appointment O
is O
a O
government B-ORG
competence O
and O
that O
he O
previously O
spoke O
with O
the O
General B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Judiciary O
. O

London B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

Iraqi O
President O
Saddam B-MISC
Hussein I-MISC
is O
reconstructing O
his O
arsenals O
of O
mass O
destruction O
and O
is O
once O
again O
a O
threat O
to O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
world O
, O
British O
Deputy O
Foreign B-ORG
Minister O
Peter B-PER
Hain I-PER
said O
on O
Thursday O
. O

In O
a O
statement O
to O
the O
BBC B-ORG
, O
Hain B-PER
said O
Hussein B-PER
should O
allow O
access O
to O
Iraqi O
territory O
for O
UN B-ORG
weapons O
inspectors O
to O
destroy O
chemical O
and O
biological O
weapons O
. O

Hain B-PER
’s O
warnings O
came O
to O
light O
after O
former O
UN B-ORG
weapons O
inspector O
Richard B-PER
Butler I-PER
expressed O
concerns O
about O
the O
Baghdad B-LOC
regime O
’s O
military O
capabilities O
. O

" O
This O
is O
very O
worrying O
and O
that O
's O
why O
we O
have O
taken O
a O
very O
firm O
stance O
by O
saying O
that O
weapons O
inspections O
by O
the O
UN B-ORG
should O
be O
allowed O
, O
" O
he O
added O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

The O
Champions B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
ended O
with O
a O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
win O
against O
Valencia B-ORG
by O
three O
goals O
to O
zero O
and O
the O
celebration O
of O
this O
triumph O
in O
Madrid B-LOC
and O
in O
the O
French O
city O
of O
Paris B-LOC
, O
focuses O
the O
attention O
of O
sports O
newspapers O
. O

“ O
More B-MISC
chulo I-MISC
than I-MISC
a I-MISC
eight I-MISC
” O
titles O
the O
daily O
“ O
Marca B-ORG
” O
to O
focus O
on O
the O
triumph O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
that O
achieves O
the O
8th B-MISC
European I-MISC
Cup I-MISC
and O
becomes O
the O
team O
that O
has O
taken O
the O
most O
triumphs O
in O
this O
competition O
. O

The O
Copa B-MISC
del I-MISC
Rey I-MISC
final O
between O
Espanyol B-ORG
and O
Atlético B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
the O
question O
of O
whether O
the O
new O
coach O
of O
Atlético B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
, O
Fernando B-PER
Zambrano I-PER
, O
will O
be O
able O
to O
count O
on O
the O
presence O
of O
Solari B-PER
or O
Kiko B-PER
, O
and O
the O
Russian O
tennis O
player O
Anna B-PER
Kournikova I-PER
who O
is O
preparing O
for O
the O
Roland B-MISC
Garros I-MISC
tournament O
in O
Mallorca B-LOC
, O
configure O
the O
thick O
informative O
of O
the O
rotative O
. O

Diario O
As B-ORG
centers O
on O
the O
triumph O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
who O
achieves O
the O
eighth O
European B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
after O
defeating O
Valencia B-ORG
by O
three O
goals O
at O
zero O
in O
the O
final O
that O
took O
place O
in O
Paris B-LOC
. O

The O
statements O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
president O
Lorenzo B-PER
Sanz I-PER
and O
team O
coach O
Vicente B-PER
Del I-PER
Bosque I-PER
after O
the O
match O
in O
Paris B-LOC
, O
the O
ACB B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
faces O
Real B-ORG
Madrid O
and O
Barcelona B-ORG
, O
the O
Italian O
club O
Juventus B-ORG
that O
“ O
offers O
7.500 O
million O
for O
Anelka B-PER
” O
and O
the O
Copa B-MISC
del I-MISC
Rey I-MISC
final O
match O
that O
faces O
Atlético B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
with O
Espanyol B-ORG
complete O
the O
newspaper O
’s O
sporting O
current O
. O

The O
triumph O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
against O
Valencia B-ORG
by O
three O
goals O
to O
zero O
in O
the O
Champions B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
was O
played O
in O
Paris B-LOC
focuses O
the O
attention O
of O
newspapers O
that O
are O
edited O
in O
Barcelona B-LOC
. O

“ O
Real B-MISC
Madrid I-MISC
surpassed I-MISC
a I-MISC
Valencia I-MISC
to I-MISC
whom I-MISC
the I-MISC
challenge I-MISC
came I-MISC
great I-MISC
” O
titles O
“ O
Mundo B-ORG
Deportivo I-ORG
” O
to O
focus O
on O
the O
little O
resistance O
that O
Valencia B-ORG
showed O
in O
the O
European B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
final O
that O
was O
played O
in O
Paris B-LOC
and O
in O
which O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
came O
out O
victorious O
. O

The O
latest O
election O
news O
of O
the O
Barcelona O
club O
that O
focuses O
on O
a O
“ O
consensus O
for O
Guardiola B-PER
, O
Figo B-PER
and O
Rivaldo B-PER
to O
follow O
” O
, O
the O
Celta B-ORG
coach O
, O
Víctor B-PER
Fernández I-PER
, O
who O
will O
be O
renewed O
for O
the O
upcoming O
season O
and O
the O
ACB B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
faces O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
Barca B-ORG
complete O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
sporting O
current O
of O
the O
rotative O
. O

The O
" O
Sport B-ORG
" O
daily O
focuses O
on O
the O
Champions B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
played O
yesterday O
between O
Real B-ORG
Madrid O
and O
Valencia B-ORG
and O
on O
the O
two O
reactions O
of O
the O
teams O
: O
on O
the O
one O
hand O
, O
euphoria O
and O
tears O
for O
losers O
on O
the O
other O
. O

The O
Copa B-MISC
del I-MISC
Rey I-MISC
final O
between O
Atlético B-ORG
de I-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
Espanyol B-ORG
, O
the O
new O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
ticket O
, O
Albert B-PER
Celades I-PER
, O
the O
Barcelona B-ORG
fans O
who O
are O
asking O
for O
the O
contract O
to O
be O
improved O
to O
the O
player O
Luis B-PER
Figo I-PER
so O
that O
it O
does O
not O
go O
and O
the O
ACB B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
faces O
Real B-ORG
Madrid O
and O
Barca B-ORG
focuses O
the O
attention O
of O
this O
newspaper O
. O

Tokyo B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
euro O
fell O
today O
in O
Tokyo B-LOC
against O
the O
Japanese O
yen O
and O
was O
quoted O
at O
97.22 O
yen O
, O
up O
from O
96.25 O
at O
the O
start O
of O
the O
day O
. O

With O
the O
U.S. O
dollar O
, O
the O
euro O
remained O
at O
0.901 O
units O
, O
below O
the O
0.903 O
units O
of O
opening O
. O

Tokyo B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFECOM B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
euro O
fell O
today O
in O
Tokyo B-LOC
against O
the O
Japanese O
yen O
and O
was O
quoted O
at O
97.22 O
yen O
, O
up O
from O
96.25 O
at O
the O
start O
of O
the O
day O
. O

With O
the O
U.S. O
dollar O
, O
the O
euro O
remained O
at O
0.901 O
units O
, O
below O
the O
0.903 O
units O
of O
opening O
. O

Manila B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

A O
man O
armed O
with O
a O
grenade O
jumped O
in O
parachutes O
over O
a O
neighborhood O
of O
Manila B-LOC
to O
escape O
the O
plane O
he O
had O
attempted O
to O
hijack O
Philippine B-ORG
Airlines I-ORG
( O
PAL B-ORG
) O
, O
local O
broadcaster O
DZMM B-ORG
. O

The O
hijacker O
, O
according O
to O
that O
version O
, O
did O
not O
cause O
damage O
to O
the O
crew O
of O
the O
aircraft O
and O
jumped O
over O
the O
capital O
district O
of O
Antipolo B-LOC
, O
and O
shortly O
after O
that O
the O
aircraft O
took O
land O
without O
problems O
at O
the O
same O
Manila B-LOC
airport O
. O

The O
aircraft O
, O
an O
Airbus B-MISC
330 O
carrying O
280 O
passengers O
, O
took O
off O
from O
Davao B-LOC
airport O
, O
in O
Mindanao B-LOC
, O
at O
14:00 O
local O
time O
( O
06:00 O
GMT O
) O
and O
was O
scheduled O
to O
land O
in O
Manila B-LOC
half O
an O
hour O
later O
. O

The O
Director O
of O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Aviation I-ORG
Office I-ORG
, O
Antonio B-PER
Gana I-PER
, O
said O
the O
hijacker O
asked O
the O
pilot O
to O
return O
to O
Davao B-LOC
, O
about O
1,000 O
kilometers O
south O
of O
Manila B-LOC
, O
but O
the O
lack O
of O
fuel O
forced O
him O
to O
follow O
the O
route O
to O
Manila B-LOC
, O
where O
his O
arrival O
is O
expected O
. O

In O
a O
statement O
to O
state O
broadcaster O
DZRB B-ORG
, O
Ricardo B-PER
Puno I-PER
, O
spokesman O
for O
Philippine O
President O
Joseph B-PER
Estrada I-PER
, O
said O
the O
hijacker O
was O
part O
of O
the O
passage O
and O
carried O
a O
hand O
grenade O
and O
a O
parachute O
. O

According O
to O
Puno B-PER
, O
the O
aircraft O
pirate O
asked O
to O
let O
him O
jump O
in O
parachutes O
from O
the O
aircraft O
, O
but O
due O
to O
the O
altitude O
of O
flight O
it O
was O
not O
possible O
to O
open O
the O
doors O
of O
the O
aircraft O
, O
so O
the O
" O
Airbus B-MISC
" O
headed O
to O
Manila B-LOC
. O

However O
, O
after O
descending O
the O
aircraft O
to O
about O
1,800 O
meters O
, O
the O
pirate O
insisted O
on O
his O
purpose O
and O
managed O
to O
jump O
in O
parachutes O
. O

Jerusalem B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
has O
adapted O
its O
concept O
of O
security O
to O
the O
new O
reality O
created O
after O
the O
evacuation O
of O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
which O
consists O
of O
defending O
its O
border O
within O
its O
own O
soil O
instead O
of O
fighting O
the O
integrist O
group O
Hezbollah B-ORG
on O
Lebanese O
territory O
, O
its O
commander O
explained O
today O
. O

Israeli O
army B-ORG
chief O
, O
General O
Shaul B-PER
Mofaz I-PER
, O
said O
it O
included O
the O
order O
to O
open O
fire O
, O
although O
he O
estimated O
that O
" O
the O
soldiers O
must O
be O
very O
careful O
not O
to O
make O
mistakes O
that O
lead O
to O
an O
escalation O
of O
violence O
. O
" O

That O
means O
that O
the O
Israeli O
soldiers O
will O
not O
shoot O
as O
soon O
as O
they O
see O
Hezbollah B-ORG
guerrillas O
- O
as O
they O
did O
so O
far O
in O
the O
southern O
Lebanon O
- O
as O
well O
as O
will O
not O
interfere O
with O
the O
Syrian O
troops O
, O
whose O
country O
actually O
controls O
Lebanon B-LOC
. O

Mofaz B-PER
said O
he O
" O
must O
be O
very O
alert O
" O
and O
added O
that O
in O
the O
coming O
days O
representatives O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
will O
examine O
the O
exact O
lines O
of O
the O
international O
border O
with O
Lebanon B-LOC
and O
, O
if O
necessary O
, O
adjust O
its O
deployment O
. O

Meanwhile O
, O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
was O
still O
deploying O
today O
– O
the O
day O
after O
the O
withdrawal O
– O
in O
the O
north O
of O
its O
country O
, O
adjacent O
to O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
. O

According O
to O
Mofaz B-PER
, O
“ O
The O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
left O
Lebanon B-LOC
( O
on O
Wednesday O
morning O
) O
appropriately O
and O
without O
casualties O
in O
its O
ranks O
, O
despite O
it O
being O
a O
retreat O
under O
fire O
” O
of O
the O
Lebanese O
pro O
- O
Iran O
group O
Hezbollah B-ORG
( O
Party B-ORG
of I-ORG
God I-ORG
) O
, O
which O
took O
control O
of O
the O
abandoned O
area O
in O
the O
south O
of O
the O
neighbouring O
Arab O
country O
. O

The O
general O
noted O
that O
at O
least O
twelve O
guerrillas O
from O
the O
Shiite O
Hezbollah B-ORG
group O
were O
killed O
in O
the O
fighting O
, O
which O
was O
made O
in O
addition O
with O
weapons O
left O
on O
the O
ground O
by O
Israeli O
soldiers O
and O
militiamen O
from O
the O
Southern B-ORG
Lebanese I-ORG
Army I-ORG
( O
ESL B-ORG
) O
, O
an O
Israeli B-ORG
ally O
. O

The O
commander O
- O
in O
- O
chief O
of O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
stressed O
that O
it O
was O
important O
for O
its O
troops O
to O
go O
out O
in O
a O
quick O
operation O
, O
in O
the O
dark O
and O
before O
it O
clarified O
, O
and O
that O
it O
was O
not O
justified O
that O
the O
soldiers O
put O
their O
lives O
at O
risk O
for O
weapons O
left O
on O
the O
ground O
. O

Finally O
, O
Mofaz B-PER
warned O
that O
“ O
I O
do O
not O
recommend O
anyone O
, O
including O
the O
Palestinians O
, O
to O
draw O
wrong O
conclusions O
about O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
’s O
response O
capacity O
. O
” O

In O
this O
regard O
, O
well O
- O
known O
Palestinian O
journalist O
Daud B-PER
Kutab I-PER
asks O
himself O
, O
in O
a O
column O
published O
today O
by O
the O
Israeli O
daily O
" O
Jerusalem B-ORG
Post I-ORG
" O
: O
" O
How O
can O
we O
convince O
people O
that O
nonviolent O
resistance O
works O
, O
when O
we O
see O
that O
armed O
resistance O
( O
of O
Hezbollah B-ORG
) O
results O
while O
negotiations O
fail O
? O

“ O
. O

As O
for O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
Israel B-ORG
recognizes O
its O
sovereignty O
over O
its O
entire O
territory O
, O
but O
demands O
that O
Beirut B-ORG
guarantee O
a O
safe O
border O
and O
, O
if O
this O
is O
not O
achieved O
, O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
is O
prepared O
for O
a O
series O
of O
responses O
and O
retaliations O
. O

This O
has O
been O
warned O
in O
recent O
days O
by O
Israeli O
Prime O
Minister O
Ehud B-PER
Barak I-PER
, O
as O
well O
as O
Mofaz B-PER
himself O
, O
Foreign B-ORG
Minister O
David B-PER
Levy I-PER
, O
and O
other O
rulers O
, O
who O
have O
held O
the O
Lebanese O
and O
Syrian O
governments B-ORG
responsible O
forining O
calm O
at O
the O
border O
. O

That O
is O
, O
if O
it O
is O
fired O
from O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
against O
northern O
Israel B-LOC
, O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
will O
immediately O
launch O
a O
retaliation O
against O
Lebanese O
, O
Syrian O
and O
even O
Iranian O
interests O
throughout O
that O
neighbouring O
Arab O
country O
. O

To O
defend O
the O
borders O
, O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
decided O
to O
install O
fortified O
positions O
in O
its O
own O
locations O
in O
the O
north O
of O
its O
territory O
, O
where O
its O
more O
than O
250,000 O
inhabitants O
have O
often O
been O
blank O
of O
attacks O
from O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
in O
particular O
from O
“ O
Katiusha B-MISC
” O
rockets O
fired O
by O
Hezbollah B-ORG
. O

Military O
commentators O
note O
today O
that O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
will O
have O
more O
troops O
to O
the O
south O
, O
ready O
to O
respond O
with O
new O
techniques O
, O
as O
well O
as O
with O
great O
speed O
and O
mobility O
, O
whileining O
a O
“ O
low O
profile O
” O
on O
the O
border O
itself O
. O

In O
the O
face O
of O
this O
new O
situation O
, O
the O
military O
commentator O
of O
the O
prestigious O
Israeli O
newspaper O
Haaretz B-ORG
, O
Zeev B-PER
Schiff I-PER
, O
comes O
to O
the O
conclusion O
that O
“ O
the O
withdrawal O
from O
Lebanon B-LOC
does O
not O
mean O
the O
end O
of O
the O
conflict O
. O
” O

Ceuta B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O

- O
by O

Two O
young O
people O
, O
both O
natives O
of O
Morocco B-LOC
, O
face O
a O
six O
- O
year O
prison O
sentence O
accused O
of O
claving O
a O
knife O
in O
the O
head O
to O
another O
young O
man O
, O
also O
a O
Moroccan O
, O
whom O
they O
stole O
1,500 O
pesetas O
when O
he O
was O
on O
a O
Ceutí O
beach O
. O

According O
to O
judicial O
sources O
, O
the O
Ceuta O
Criminal B-ORG
Court I-ORG
number I-ORG
2 I-ORG
has O
tried O
R. B-PER
E. I-PER
Ch I-PER
. O
and O
M. B-PER
M. I-PER
, O
for O
whom O
the O
prosecutor O
asks O
for O
six O
years O
in O
prison O
, O
two O
for O
injuries O
and O
four O
for O
theft O
. O

The O
judged O
facts O
occurred O
on O
2 O
January O
when O
allegedly O
both O
young O
people O
attacked O
a O
third O
person O
in O
the O
vicinity O
of O
the O
beach B-LOC
of I-LOC
La I-LOC
Ribera I-LOC
, O
and O
stole O
him O
1,500 O
pesetas O
and O
two O
sleep O
bags O
after O
striking O
him O
a O
stroke O
in O
the O
head O
that O
caused O
his O
hospitalization O
. O

The O
defense O
has O
sought O
the O
absolution O
of O
the O
two O
young O
men O
, O
considering O
that O
there O
is O
not O
enough O
evidence O
to O
determine O
the O
guilt O
of O
their O
defendants O
, O
who O
were O
recognized O
by O
the O
victim O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

The O
Malaguean O
group O
Digital B-ORG
21 I-ORG
wants O
to O
show O
in O
their O
debut O
album O
that O
" O
digital O
and O
analogue O
are O
not O
ripped O
, O
" O
according O
to O
their O
leader O
, O
singer O
, O
composer O
and O
guitarist O
, O
Miguel B-PER
López I-PER
, O
who O
assures O
that O
their O
music O
" O
offers O
the O
contemporary O
of O
machines O
and O
the O
strength O
of O
guitar O
and O
drummer O
" O
. O

Paco B-PER
( O
guitar O
) O
, O
Salva B-PER
( O
battery O
) O
and O
Alberto B-PER
( O
bass O
) O
form O
, O
along O
with O
Miguel B-PER
, O
Digital B-ORG
21 I-ORG
, O
a O
band O
that O
" O
at O
the O
doors O
of O
the O
21st O
century O
" O
wants O
to O
demonstrate O
that O
" O
despite O
the O
importance O
that O
computers O
and O
loops O
have O
when O
composing O
, O
traditional O
instruments O
continue O
to O
keep O
the O
freshness O
of O
music O
, O
and O
although O
sometimes O
voices O
are O
distorted O
, O
melodies O
and O
songs O
are O
the O
most O
important O
" O
. O

Bands O
such O
as O
Radiohead B-ORG
, O
Portishead B-ORG
, O
Smashing B-ORG
Punpkins I-ORG
and O
Chemikal B-ORG
Brothers I-ORG
, O
and O
musician O
Beck B-PER
, O
are O
some O
of O
the O
influences O
of O
this O
Malaguean O
group O
, O
which O
, O
although O
it O
does O
not O
refuse O
to O
sing O
in O
Spanish O
, O
is O
one O
of O
the O
ones O
it O
records O
in O
English O
. O

“ O
It O
’s O
not O
for O
anything O
in O
particular O
, O
we O
have O
songs O
in O
Spanish O
, O
that O
we O
play O
live O
, O
but O
we O
thought O
that O
for O
the O
album O
it O
was O
better O
to O
do O
it O
all O
in O
one O
language O
. O
” O

Tomorrow O
, O
Friday O
, O
the O
madrilen O
room B-LOC
Caracol I-LOC
was O
chosen O
for O
the O
official O
presentation O
of O
the O
album O
" O
Digital B-MISC
21 I-MISC
" O
, O
later O
the O
Malaguean O
formation O
traveled O
to O
Santiago B-LOC
de I-LOC
Compostela I-LOC
to O
participate O
on O
July O
13 O
at O
the O
Celtirock B-MISC
Festival I-MISC
and O
on O
August O
3 O
will O
form O
part O
of O
the O
" O
Benicassim B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
" O
poster O
. O

Digital B-ORG
21 I-ORG
was O
not O
born O
with O
the O
spirit O
of O
professionalization O
, O
but O
of O
putting O
their O
music O
on O
the O
table O
and O
the O
stage O
, O
but O
after O
the O
success O
they O
have O
had O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
where O
they O
just O
offered O
their O
second O
tour O
of O
four O
performances O
, O
they O
decided O
why O
not O
to O
devote O
themselves O
to O
this O
. O
” O

Seville B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
mobile O
phone O
company O
Amena B-ORG
will O
continue O
its O
criminal O
action O
against O
the O
company O
Airtel B-ORG
for O
a O
alleged O
scam O
, O
which O
motivated O
the O
declaration O
in O
a O
Sevilla B-LOC
court O
, O
as O
charged O
, O
of O
four O
Andalusian O
managers O
of O
Airtel B-ORG
, O
a O
spokesman O
for O
Amena B-ORG
told O
Efe I-ORG
. O

The O
alleged O
crimes O
, O
according O
to O
Amena B-ORG
's O
complaint O
to O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Guard I-ORG
, O
took O
place O
at O
the O
end O
of O
last O
year O
, O
when O
Airtel B-ORG
bought O
through O
intermediaries O
about O
60,000 O
mobile O
phones O
that O
Amena B-ORG
had O
put O
on O
sale O
at O
a O
lower O
market O
price O
to O
capture O
customers O
. O

It O
would O
also O
have O
manipulated O
the O
lines O
rented O
by O
Amena B-ORG
to O
Airtel B-ORG
in O
Andalusia B-LOC
in O
order O
to O
charge O
for O
non O
- O
existent O
use O
, O
collapse O
them O
and O
cause O
the O
loss O
of O
users O
. O

According O
to O
the O
operator O
, O
her O
complaint O
was O
intended O
to O
clarify O
some O
constitutive O
facts O
of O
a O
conduct O
typified O
criminally O
as O
a O
crime O
of O
fraud O
and O
damages O
. O

Airtel B-ORG
has O
compensated O
Amena B-ORG
, O
according O
to O
this O
second O
operator O
, O
for O
the O
civil O
liability O
derived O
from O
the O
alleged O
crimes O
committed O
. O

Therefore O
, O
Amena B-ORG
has O
waived O
the O
subsidiary O
civil O
liability O
action O
that O
could O
derive O
from O
the O
criminal O
process O
, O
although O
she O
confides O
" O
fully O
" O
that O
the O
investigations O
developed O
by O
the O
judges O
and O
criminal O
courts O
, O
which O
are O
currently O
under O
summary O
secrecy O
, O
clarify O
" O
completely O
" O
the O
facts O
, O
she O
said O
in O
a O
statement O
. O

Melbourne B-LOC
( O
Australia B-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
Great B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Chiefs I-ORG
of O
Fiji B-LOC
today O
allowed O
some O
members O
of O
the O
coup O
attempt O
led O
by O
businessman O
George B-PER
Speight I-PER
to O
participate O
in O
the O
transitional O
government O
to O
be O
formed O
by O
the O
country O
’s O
president O
, O
Kamisese B-PER
Mara I-PER
. O

This O
is O
one O
of O
several O
resolutions O
approved O
today O
by O
the O
Great B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Chiefs I-ORG
, O
in O
addition O
to O
asking O
for O
an O
amendment O
to O
the O
Constitution B-MISC
, O
to O
end O
the O
democratically O
elected O
government O
in O
last O
year O
’s O
elections O
, O
and O
to O
recommend O
the O
head O
of O
state B-ORG
to O
forgive O
all O
coupists O
. O

A O
delegation O
from O
the O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
addressed O
Parliament B-ORG
after O
the O
meeting O
to O
communicate O
its O
decisions O
to O
Speight B-PER
and O
ask O
him O
to O
release O
all O
the O
hostages O
he O
has O
held O
since O
Friday O
, O
including O
Prime O
Minister O
Mahendra B-PER
Chaudhry I-PER
. O

The O
three O
- O
day O
deliberations O
of O
the O
Great B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Chiefs I-ORG
have O
concluded O
with O
an O
unexpected O
culprit O
, O
not O
the O
coup O
d’état O
Speight B-PER
, O
but O
Chaudhry B-PER
, O
who O
did O
not O
have O
“ O
the O
humility O
and O
political O
courage O
to O
listen O
to O
the O
growing O
popular O
discontent O
” O
, O
according O
to O
the O
resolution O
of O
the O
42 O
heads O
of O
the O
country O
’s O
different O
ethnic O
communities O
. O

The O
decision O
to O
amend O
the O
current O
Constitution B-MISC
, O
approved O
in O
1997 O
, O
has O
been O
due O
, O
according O
to O
the O
president O
of O
the O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
, O
Sitiveni B-PER
Rabuka I-PER
, O
to O
failure O
in O
its O
task O
. O

“ O
We O
need O
to O
change O
the O
document O
that O
has O
brought O
us O
to O
the O
current O
situation O
. O

I O
thought O
it O
was O
a O
very O
good O
constitution B-MISC
and O
that O
it O
brought O
the O
unity O
of O
all O
communities O
, O
but O
the O
parties O
have O
rejected O
it O
, O
” O
Rabuka B-PER
explained O
to O
the O
press O
at O
Suva B-LOC
. O

The O
Magna B-MISC
Carta I-MISC
of O
1997 O
modified O
that O
of O
1987 O
which O
prevented O
the O
community O
of O
Hindu O
origin O
from O
accessing O
political O
positions O
, O
allowing O
Chaudhry B-PER
to O
become O
in O
May O
last O
year O
the O
first O
member O
of O
that O
ethnicity O
to O
be O
prime O
minister O
in O
the O
history O
of O
Fiji B-LOC
. O

The O
decisions O
adopted O
by O
the O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Fiji I-ORG
disobey O
all O
recommendations O
given O
by O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORG
, O
as O
well O
as O
other O
countries O
, O
in O
relation O
to O
respecting O
constitutionality O
and O
the O
government O
of O
Chaudhry B-PER
, O
who O
was O
democratically O
elected O
. O

The O
Great O
Chiefs O
' O
resolutions O
were O
announced O
shortly O
after O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORG
president O
, O
New O
Zealander O
Don B-PER
McKinnon I-PER
, O
left O
Suva B-LOC
with O
a O
warning O
to O
Fiji B-ORG
not O
to O
abandon O
the O
path O
of O
democracy O
. O

Damascus B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

Syria B-ORG
believes O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
completed O
on O
Wednesday O
, O
" O
signs O
that O
Israel B-ORG
has O
been O
defeated O
politically O
and O
militarily O
, O
" O
the O
official O
Syrian O
press O
. O

“ O
The O
day O
of O
liberation O
will O
be O
unforgettable O
for O
the O
people O
and O
the O
resistance O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
as O
well O
as O
for O
all O
freedom O
fighters O
around O
the O
world O
, O
” O
says O
the O
daily O
Al B-ORG
Zaura I-ORG
, O
an O
organ O
of O
the O
Syrian B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
of I-ORG
Defense I-ORG
. O

Israel B-ORG
has O
completed O
its O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
1,000 O
- O
square O
- O
kilometer O
area O
it O
has O
occupied O
in O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
since O
1978 O
. O

For O
the O
Syrian O
rotating O
, O
the O
Israeli O
retreat O
, O
which O
ends O
with O
22 O
years O
of O
occupation O
, O
“ O
meant O
not O
only O
a O
military O
defeat O
for O
Israel B-ORG
, O
but O
also O
a O
political O
defeat O
. O
” O

Another O
newspaper O
, O
Tishrin B-ORG
, O
an O
organ O
of O
the O
Syrian O
government B-ORG
, O
believes O
that O
“ O
the O
policy O
of O
oppression O
and O
terrorism O
that O
the O
Israelis O
practiced O
in O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
did O
not O
guarantee O
security O
for O
them O
nor O
prevented O
the O
Lebanese O
from O
recovering O
their O
rights O
and O
liberating O
their O
land O
. O
” O

For O
its O
part O
, O
the O
newspaper O
" O
Baaz B-ORG
" O
, O
which O
reflects O
the O
views O
of O
the O
ruling O
party O
of O
the O
same O
name O
, O
considers O
that O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
southern O
Lebanon O
" O
does O
not O
mean O
an O
isolation O
for O
Syria B-ORG
" O
in O
peace O
negotiations O
with O
the O
Jewish O
state B-ORG
. O

Damascus B-ORG
, O
which O
hasined O
some O
35,000 O
troops O
in O
Lebanon B-LOC
since O
1976 O
, O
and O
is O
considered O
the O
main O
political O
arbiter O
in O
this O
country O
, O
insisted O
on O
negotiating O
, O
along O
with O
Beirut B-ORG
, O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
southern O
Lebanon O
and O
the O
Syrian O
Golan B-LOC
plateau O
, O
occupied O
since O
1967 O
. O

“ O
Syria B-ORG
still O
opens O
the O
door O
to O
the O
resumption O
of O
negotiations O
” O
with O
Israel B-ORG
, O
Baaz B-ORG
adds O
. O

The O
Syrian O
- O
Israeli O
dialogue O
has O
been O
suspended O
since O
last O
January O
due O
to O
differences O
between O
the O
two O
sides O
over O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
Golan B-LOC
Heights O
. O

Damascus B-ORG
insists O
that O
Israel B-ORG
undertake O
to O
abandon O
all O
of O
the O
Golan B-LOC
before O
negotiating O
the O
establishment O
of O
relations O
between O
the O
two O
neighbouring O
states B-ORG
, O
a O
condition O
that O
Israel O
rejects O
. O

Porzuna B-LOC
( O
City B-LOC
Real I-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

The O
City B-ORG
of I-ORG
Porzuna I-ORG
( O
City B-LOC
Real I-LOC
) O
has O
organized O
a O
day O
on O
education O
and O
family O
with O
the O
aim O
of O
addressing O
the O
progressive O
increase O
in O
school O
failure O
and O
abandonment O
. O

The O
day O
was O
celebrated O
yesterday O
with O
the O
participation O
of O
parents O
and O
teachers O
of O
the O
close O
to O
a O
thousand O
students O
who O
are O
enrolled O
in O
the O
public O
school O
" O
Nostra B-ORG
Señora I-ORG
del I-ORG
Rosario I-ORG
" O
and O
in O
the O
Institute B-ORG
of I-ORG
Secondary I-ORG
Education I-ORG
" O
Ribera B-ORG
del I-ORG
Bullaque I-ORG
" O
, O
according O
to O
EFE B-ORG
, O
the O
mayor O
of O
Porzuna B-LOC
, O
Welcome B-PER
García I-PER
. O

The O
Education O
Delegate O
of B-MISC
the I-MISC
Junta I-MISC
de I-MISC
Comunidades I-MISC
, O
José B-PER
Fuentes I-PER
Pastrana I-PER
, O
was O
in O
charge O
of O
inaugurating O
the O
day O
during O
which O
presentations O
, O
round O
tables O
and O
debates O
were O
developed O
. O

Welcome B-PER
García I-PER
explained O
that O
the O
main O
purpose O
that O
has O
been O
pursued O
has O
been O
to O
analyze O
the O
progressive O
increase O
in O
school O
abandonment O
that O
occurs O
in O
the O
Institute B-ORG
of I-ORG
Secondary I-ORG
Education O
, O
with O
the O
aim O
of O
seeking O
solutions O
that O
minimize O
this O
situation O
. O

According O
to O
the O
mayor O
of O
Porzuna B-LOC
, O
both O
the O
family O
and O
the O
educational O
system O
and O
institutions O
should O
play O
an O
important O
role O
in O
the O
attempt O
to O
" O
brake O
" O
school O
abandonment O
, O
so O
a O
greater O
involvement O
in O
their O
educational O
responsibility O
is O
needed O
. O

The O
mayor O
of O
Porzuna B-LOC
explained O
that O
72 O
percent O
of O
current O
unemployed O
under O
the O
age O
of O
25 O
left O
school O
on O
their O
day O
and O
added O
that O
to O
reduce O
this O
figure O
one O
of O
the O
priorities O
is O
to O
raise O
awareness O
of O
the O
family O
to O
try O
to O
ensure O
that O
young O
people O
continue O
to O
be O
linked O
to O
educational O
centres O
and O
be O
able O
to O
conclude O
their O
training O
cycle O
. O

Welcome B-PER
García I-PER
noted O
that O
among O
the O
measures O
proposed O
in O
these O
days O
to O
avoid O
school O
abandonment O
is O
to O
diversify O
the O
offer O
of O
formative O
modules O
. O

Lastly O
, O
he O
commented O
on O
the O
intention O
of O
the O
Porzuna B-ORG
City I-ORG
Council O
to O
work O
on O
this O
line O
of O
action O
and O
assured O
that O
" O
from O
the O
municipal O
institution O
we O
will O
make O
an O
effective O
and O
active O
effort O
in O
this O
matter O
" O
. O

Sabadell B-LOC
( O
Barcelona B-LOC
) O
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O

- O
by O

The O
Royal O
Philharmonic O
Orchestra B-ORG
of I-ORG
Galicia I-ORG
will O
offer O
tomorrow O
in O
the O
municipal O
theater O
La B-LOC
Farándula I-LOC
of I-LOC
Sabadell I-LOC
a O
concert O
with O
works O
of O
Mendelssohn B-PER
, O
Gaos B-PER
and O
Stravinsky B-PER
, O
according O
to O
municipal O
sources O
The O
concert O
will O
take O
place O
in O
the O
framework O
of O
the O
programming O
of O
acts O
" O
Galicia B-MISC
today I-MISC
, O
Galicia O
hoxe O
" O
that O
organizes O
the O
municipality O
and O
the O
Centro B-ORG
Galego I-ORG
Nos I-ORG
. O

Directed O
by O
Maxim B-PER
Zumalave I-PER
and O
with O
the O
presence O
of O
violinist O
Herwig B-PER
Zack I-PER
and O
pianist O
Bernd B-PER
Zack I-PER
, O
the O
orchestra O
will O
perform O
F. B-PER
Mendelssohn I-PER
’s O
concerts O
for O
violin O
and O
piano O
in O
re O
minor O
; O
Granada O
, O
a B-MISC
sunset I-MISC
in I-MISC
the I-MISC
Alhambra I-MISC
by O
A. B-PER
Gaos I-PER
and O
The B-MISC
bird I-MISC
of I-MISC
fire I-MISC
by O
Igor B-PER
Stravinsky I-PER
. O

The O
orchestra O
, O
which O
manages O
the O
Auditorium B-ORG
of I-ORG
Galicia I-ORG
, O
was O
established O
publicly O
in O
February O
1996 O
with O
a O
concert O
directed O
by O
its O
owner O
, O
the O
German O
master O
Helmuth B-PER
Rilling I-PER
. O

During O
this O
period O
of O
time O
he O
has O
acted O
in O
the O
main O
concerts O
of O
classical O
music O
that O
have O
been O
held O
in O
Spain B-LOC
and O
in O
different O
countries O
and O
has O
been O
the O
object O
of O
multiple O
recognitions O
for O
his O
musical O
quality O
. O

- O
by O

by O
EFE B-ORG
. O

CSA O
/ O
SC O
/ O
FJN O
/ O
JF O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
26 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

The O
young O
people O
detained O
last O
morning O
for O
the O
disorders O
that O
occurred O
during O
the O
party O
celebrated O
by O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
supporters O
in O
the O
vicinity O
of O
the O
Plaza B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Cibeles I-LOC
rise O
to O
nineteen O
, O
police B-ORG
sources O
told O
EFE I-ORG
. O

The O
detainees O
remain O
in O
police O
offices O
and O
are O
waiting O
for O
their O
lawyers O
to O
be O
arrested O
. O

Most O
of O
them O
are O
expected O
to O
be O
released O
on O
charges O
as O
they O
are O
accused O
of O
public O
disorder O
and O
damages O
. O

Only O
one O
of O
the O
detainees O
, O
the O
same O
sources O
said O
, O
is O
accused O
of O
injuring O
an O
officer O
. O

Madrid B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

Francisco B-PER
Arias I-PER
Cárdenas I-PER
, O
the O
main O
opponent O
of O
President O
Hugo B-PER
Chávez I-PER
in O
the O
Venezuelan O
elections O
on O
Sunday O
, O
says O
he O
will O
cut O
the O
presidential O
term O
and O
review O
the O
Constitution B-MISC
if O
he O
wins O
the O
elections O
. O

In O
an O
interview O
published O
today O
by O
the O
Madrid O
newspaper O
" O
El B-ORG
Pais I-ORG
" O
, O
the O
Democratic O
Christian O
politician O
rejects O
" O
the O
overwhelmed O
leftism O
" O
of O
President O
Chávez B-PER
, O
of O
whom O
he O
was O
a O
quarterback O
companion O
in O
1992 O
and O
now O
his O
main O
adversary O
. O

“ O
The O
first O
thing O
I O
offer O
the O
Venezuelans O
is O
tranquility O
, O
less O
talk O
, O
change O
in O
peace O
, O
” O
Arias B-PER
says O
. O

The O
presidential O
candidate O
promises O
to O
thoroughly O
amend O
the O
Constitution B-MISC
approved O
on O
December O
15 O
, O
cut O
the O
presidential O
term O
, O
open O
the O
economy O
, O
and O
limit O
the O
size O
of O
the O
state B-ORG
in O
the O
functioning O
of O
the O
economy O
. O

“ O
The O
state B-ORG
should O
not O
be O
an O
entrepreneur O
. O
” O

Arias B-PER
, O
whom O
polls O
give O
as O
a O
loser O
in O
the O
elections O
, O
takes O
attention O
to O
those O
forecasts O
and O
warns O
that O
" O
there O
is O
a O
silent O
vote O
that O
is O
with O
us O
, O
and O
that O
it O
will O
be O
manifested O
on O
the O
day O
of O
the O
elections O
( O
... O
) O
We O
will O
be O
very O
attentive O
to O
the O
traps O
" O
. O

And O
it O
is O
that O
Arias B-PER
warns O
that O
the O
elections O
are O
produced O
in O
circumstances O
in O
which O
" O
all O
powers O
, O
including O
the O
electoral O
, O
are O
in O
the O
hands O
of O
a O
candidate O
" O
, O
although O
he O
emphasizes O
that O
" O
we O
are O
putting O
the O
means O
to O
prevent O
it O
from O
thriving O
any O
attempt O
that O
can O
have O
who O
has O
prepared O
all O
this O
process O
to O
scam O
the O
popular O
will O
" O
. O

He O
accuses O
the O
Chávez B-ORG
government I-ORG
of O
not O
having O
adopted O
economic O
decisions O
“ O
and O
those O
that O
are O
taken O
– O
he O
assures O
– O
are O
errands O
. O
” O

“ O
There O
is O
a O
counter O
- O
sense O
when O
the O
public O
is O
handled O
as O
permanent O
confrontation O
, O
when O
investment O
is O
discouraged O
, O
when O
state B-ORG
resources O
are O
retained O
for O
investments O
to O
opponent O
governors O
and O
mayors O
so O
that O
they O
do O
works O
that O
can O
present O
results O
to O
voters O
, O
” O
he O
says O
. O

As O
for O
his O
draft O
reform O
of O
the O
new O
Constitution B-LOC
, O
he O
explains O
that O
he O
wants O
to O
decrease O
the O
presidential O
term O
, O
" O
which O
is O
excessive O
, O
" O
and O
modify O
, O
for O
example O
, O
" O
the O
power O
to O
dismantle O
Congress B-ORG
, O
decentralization O
, O
the O
management O
of O
the O
State B-ORG
Council I-ORG
, O
the O
transfer O
of O
resources O
. O
" O

These O
are O
very O
serious O
matters O
. O
” O

Barcelona B-LOC
, O
23 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

- O
by O

An O
alternating O
air O
mattress O
that O
allows O
you O
to O
adjust O
the O
pressure O
to O
prevent O
it O
from O
producing O
injuries O
in O
sick O
people O
and O
a O
" O
hydrosonido O
" O
bathtub O
capable O
of O
making O
a O
perfect O
hygiene O
of O
a O
patient O
without O
rubbing O
are O
some O
of O
the O
innovations O
that O
in O
medical O
- O
sanitary O
matters O
are O
presented O
at O
the O
Médical B-MISC
Forum I-MISC
Expo I-MISC
in I-MISC
Barcelona I-MISC
. O

A O
total O
of O
132 O
specialized O
companies O
participate O
in O
Barcelona B-LOC
in O
this O
large O
exhibition O
, O
which O
presents O
the O
latest O
technological O
advances O
in O
hospital O
equipment O
and O
medical O
and O
surgical O
material O
, O
an O
event O
that O
coincides O
with O
the O
celebration O
of O
a O
forum O
of O
health O
debate O
on O
the O
harmonization O
of O
the O
health O
rights O
of O
European O
citizens O
. O

A O
wooden O
and O
acid O
crystal O
wardrobe O
that O
can O
be O
adapted O
to O
any O
space O
or O
an O
ecological O
disinfectant O
that O
allows O
you O
to O
wash O
, O
empty O
and O
disinfect O
cloves O
and O
bottles O
of O
urine O
, O
are O
also O
part O
of O
the O
twenty O
most O
novel O
products O
presented O
at O
this O
competition O
, O
to O
which O
more O
than O
5,000 O
professional O
visitors O
are O
expected O
to O
attend O
. O

Another O
prominent O
novelty O
is O
a O
rehabilitation O
pool O
for O
different O
levels O
of O
disability O
with O
glass O
walls O
, O
which O
has O
an O
automatic O
system O
of O
hygiene O
control O
and O
incontinence O
according O
to O
the O
water O
level O
. O

In O
the O
field O
of O
sterilization O
, O
operating O
tables O
and O
lamps O
with O
endoscope O
disinfectant O
washing O
machine O
compete O
with O
chariots O
, O
sealing O
baskets O
and O
chemical O
and O
biological O
controls O
. O

It O
also O
presents O
a O
basic O
that O
incorporates O
a O
technique O
that O
analyzes O
and O
measures O
the O
total O
body O
water O
, O
free O
fat O
mass O
and O
fat O
of O
a O
person O
's O
human O
body O
, O
and O
that O
calculates O
the O
level O
of O
fat O
of O
people O
with O
overweight O
according O
to O
gender O
, O
height O
and O
age O
. O
