State B-PER
Attorney I-PER
General I-PER
Daryl B-PER
Williams I-PER
today O
stressed O
the O
need O
to O
take O
measures O
to O
protect O
the O
Australian O
judicial O
system O
from O
a O
website O
that O
makes O
it O
impossible O
to O
comply O
with O
the O
basic O
principles O
of O
the O
Act B-MISC
. O

The O
Advocate B-PER
General I-PER
's O
request O
takes O
place O
after O
a O
judge O
of O
the O
Victoria B-LOC
State O
Supreme O
Court O
( O
Australia B-LOC
) O
was O
forced O
to O
dissolve O
a O
popular O
judge O
and O
suspend O
the O
trial O
on O
the O
defence O
's O
argument O
that O
the O
people O
who O
composed O
it O
could O
have O
obtained O
information O
about O
the O
accused O
through O
the O
CrimeNet B-MISC
page O
. O

This O
website O
has O
a O
month O
of O
existence O
, O
time O
in O
which O
it O
has O
been O
visited O
more O
than O
a O
million O
times O
, O
and O
provides O
information O
about O
thousands O
of O
crimes O
and O
criminals O
already O
tried O
or O
still O
prosecuted O
, O
data O
that O
comes O
from O
articles O
in O
newspapers O
and O
judicial O
archives O
. O

For O
his O
part O
, O
Victoria O
’s O
Attorney B-PER
General I-PER
, O
Rob B-PER
Hulls I-PER
, O
stated O
that O
there O
is O
no O
one O
to O
check O
that O
the O
information O
contained O
in O
CrimeNet B-MISC
is O
true O
. O

The O
above O
- O
mentioned O
website O
is O
also O
considered O
the O
cause O
of O
the O
premature O
conclusion O
in O
a O
murder O
case O
recently O
tried O
in O
Melbourne B-LOC
, O
the O
capital O
of O
the O
state O
of O
Victoria B-LOC
. O

The O
United B-ORG
Left I-ORG
of I-ORG
Santander I-ORG
today O
presented O
its O
new O
quarterly O
newsletter O
" O
Ciudad B-MISC
" O
, O
a O
publication O
of O
which O
10,000 O
copies O
will O
be O
distributed O
preferably O
in O
the O
districts O
of O
the O
municipality O
where O
the O
collection O
has O
the O
greatest O
support O
of O
the O
citizens O
. O

The O
spokesman O
of O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Political I-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
IU I-ORG
in O
Santander B-LOC
, O
Ernesto B-PER
Gómez I-PER
de I-PER
la I-PER
Hera I-PER
, O
explained O
today O
at O
a O
press O
conference O
that O
this O
newsletter O
seeks O
, O
more O
than O
to O
inform O
, O
open O
debate O
spaces O
and O
serve O
as O
" O
seed O
of O
political O
mobilization O
" O
in O
the O
city O
. O

Gómez B-PER
de I-PER
la I-PER
Hera I-PER
commented O
that O
the O
contents O
of O
the O
publication O
" O
Ciudad B-MISC
" O
respond O
to O
the O
program O
he O
wrapped O
up O
as O
a O
candidate O
in O
the O
1999 O
municipal O
elections O
, O
in O
which O
IU B-ORG
lost O
its O
representation O
in O
the O
Town B-ORG
Hall O
, O
and O
trusted O
that O
its O
dissemination O
will O
be O
more O
extensive O
once O
the O
coalition O
solves O
its O
economic O
crisis O
. O

For O
the O
time O
being O
, O
" O
City B-MISC
" O
will O
be O
distributed O
preferentially O
in O
the O
districts O
with O
more O
voters O
of O
IU B-ORG
, O
among O
which O
the O
municipal O
spokesman O
of O
the O
coalition O
cited O
the O
north O
side O
of O
Alta B-LOC
Street I-LOC
, O
Cazoña B-LOC
and O
the O
area O
comprised O
between O
Castilla B-LOC
and O
Hermida B-LOC
Streets O
. O

" O
City B-MISC
" O
, O
a O
bulletin O
composed O
of O
two O
half O
- O
folded O
leaves O
, O
goes O
to O
the O
street O
in O
its O
first O
issue O
criticizing O
the O
construction O
of O
underground O
parking O
lots O
, O
the O
disturbances O
that O
are O
causing O
to O
the O
neighbours O
and O
the O
way O
they O
will O
be O
exploited O
. O

Gómez B-PER
de I-PER
la I-PER
Hera I-PER
considers O
that O
" O
the O
PP B-ORG
's O
policy O
of O
making O
money O
absolutely O
from O
everything O
and O
that O
that O
money O
is O
distributed O
primarily O
to O
his O
friends O
" O
has O
turned O
Santander B-LOC
into O
" O
a O
trap O
full O
of O
traps O
, O
when O
all O
the O
cities O
of O
Western O
Europe B-LOC
are O
trying O
to O
make O
their O
urban O
centres O
more O
habitable O
" O
. O

In O
his O
opinion O
, O
the O
reasons O
of O
the O
Town B-ORG
Hall O
to O
carry O
out O
these O
works O
are O
" O
crematistic O
, O
mercenaries O
, O
but O
have O
nothing O
to O
do O
with O
the O
future O
of O
Santander B-LOC
or O
with O
the O
well O
- O
being O
of O
the O
vast O
majority O
of O
its O
population O
" O
. O

The O
German O
telephone O
group O
Deutsche B-ORG
Telekom I-ORG
has O
acquired O
the O
remaining O
50 O
% O
of O
the O
Swiss O
telecommunications O
operator O
Multilink B-ORG
, O
which O
until O
now O
owned O
France B-ORG
Telecom I-ORG
, O
and O
has O
become O
its O
sole O
owner O
, O
reported O
today O
, O
Thursday O
, O
the O
German O
company O
. O

In O
return O
, O
Deutsche B-ORG
Telekom I-ORG
will O
sell O
to O
the O
French O
consortium O
its O
25 O
% O
stake O
in O
the O
British O
joint O
venture O
MetroHoldings B-ORG
. O

Multilink B-ORG
was O
established O
in O
1998 O
and O
offers O
telephone O
and O
data O
transmission O
services O
in O
Switzerland B-LOC
and O
abroad O
, O
as O
well O
as O
having O
its O
own O
urban O
fiber O
optic O
network O
. O

Deutsche B-ORG
Telekom I-ORG
described O
this O
purchase O
, O
the O
price O
of O
which O
it O
did O
not O
specify O
, O
as O
another O
step O
towards O
its O
internationalization O
through O
majority O
acquisitions O
aimed O
at O
controlling O
the O
management O
of O
these O
companies O
. O

The O
President O
of O
the O
Junta B-ORG
de I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
, O
Juan B-PER
Carlos I-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Ibarra I-PER
, O
will O
receive O
at O
the O
headquarters O
of O
the O
Presidency B-ORG
of O
the O
extremist O
government O
relatives O
of O
several O
of O
the O
convicted O
by O
the O
process O
" O
Lasa B-MISC
- I-MISC
Zabala I-MISC
" O
, O
among O
them O
Lourdes B-PER
Díez I-PER
Urraca I-PER
, O
wife O
of O
the O
former O
civil O
governor O
of O
Guipúzcoa B-LOC
Julen B-PER
Elgorriaga I-PER
; O
and O
Antonio B-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Galindo I-PER
, O
brother O
of O
General O
Enrique B-PER
Rodríguez I-PER
Galindo I-PER
. O

( O
with O
picture O
) O
( O
PLENO O
ASAMBLEA O
) O
. O

The O
plenary O
session B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Assembly I-ORG
of I-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
will O
discuss O
, O
among O
other O
things O
, O
a O
non O
- O
legislative O
proposal O
by O
the O
groups O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
- I-ORG
NI I-ORG
, O
PP B-ORG
and O
Mixed O
- O
Members B-ORG
of I-ORG
IU I-ORG
in O
which O
the O
central O
government B-ORG
is O
urged O
to O
enact O
a O
ministerial B-MISC
order I-MISC
that O
cuts O
the O
regionalisation O
of O
the O
base O
area O
for O
maize O
cultivation O
. O

( O
EMPLOYEES O
) O
. O

The O
Counsellor O
of O
Economy B-MISC
, I-MISC
Industry I-MISC
and O
Trade O
, O
Manuel B-PER
Amigo I-PER
, O
and O
the O
Presidents O
of O
Caja B-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
and O
Caja B-ORG
Badajoz I-ORG
, O
Jesús B-PER
Medina I-PER
and O
José B-PER
Manuel I-PER
Sánchez I-PER
Rojas I-PER
, O
respectively O
, O
will O
sign O
a O
cooperation O
agreement O
to O
finance O
business O
projects O
of O
young O
entrepreneurs O
. O

( O
CARLOS B-PER
V I-PER
- O
CONGRESS O
) O
. O

The O
Historical B-ORG
Institute I-ORG
" O
Hoffmeyer O
" O
will O
welcome O
the O
inauguration O
and O
first O
session O
of O
the O
Congress B-MISC
of I-MISC
Modern I-MISC
History I-MISC
" O
Carlos O
. O
and B-MISC
the I-MISC
end I-MISC
of I-MISC
a I-MISC
time I-MISC
. O
1500 O
- O
1558 O
" O
, O
which O
is O
marked O
in O
the O
commemorative O
acts O
of O
the O
V B-MISC
Century I-MISC
of O
the O
birth O
of O
the O
emperor O
. O

The O
Counsellor O
of O
Economy B-MISC
, I-MISC
Industry I-MISC
and O
Trade O
, O
Manuel B-PER
Amigo I-PER
, O
and O
the O
Presidents O
of O
Caja B-ORG
Extremadura I-ORG
and O
Caja B-ORG
Badajoz I-ORG
, O
Jesús B-ORG
Medina I-ORG
and O
José B-PER
Manuel I-PER
Sánchez I-PER
Rojas I-PER
, O
respectively O
, O
will O
sign O
a O
cooperation O
agreement O
. O

The O
Congress O
will O
begin O
" O
Carlos O
. O
and B-MISC
the I-MISC
end I-MISC
of I-MISC
a I-MISC
time I-MISC
. O
1500 O
- O
1558 O
" O
. O

Transportation B-MISC
, O
Javier B-PER
Corominas I-PER
, O
will O
deliver O
94 O
special O
housings O
built O
by O
the O
Magenta B-ORG
Group I-ORG
in O
La B-LOC
Corchera I-LOC
. O

The O
mayor O
, O
José B-PER
Luis I-PER
Díez I-PER
, O
will O
talk O
about O
various O
issues O
of O
municipal O
interest O
. O

There O
will O
be O
a O
plenary O
session O
of B-MISC
the I-MISC
Assembly I-MISC
of I-MISC
Extremadura I-MISC
. O

The O
Culture B-MISC
Adviser O
, O
Francisco B-PER
Muñoz I-PER
, O
will O
inaugurate O
the O
IV O
Local O
Book B-MISC
Fair I-MISC
. O

The O
plenary O
session B-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Town O
Hall O
will O
discuss O
issues O
such O
as O
the O
re O
- O
greening O
of O
areas O
adjacent O
to O
the O
Salesian B-LOC
College I-LOC
. O

The O
cultural B-MISC
adviser O
, O
Francisco B-PER
Muñoz I-PER
, O
will O
attend O
the O
presentation O
of O
the O
book O
" O
Seres B-MISC
. I-MISC
Estrellas I-MISC
" O
, O
which O
analyses O
the O
origins O
of O
the O
universe B-MISC
, O
and O
the O
data O
on O
the O
research O
project O
" O
The B-MISC
First I-MISC
Residents I-MISC
of I-MISC
Extremadura I-MISC
" O
. O

Public O
television O
and O
the O
information O
society O
, O
regional O
funding O
, O
the O
contents O
of O
the O
extracurricular O
day O
and O
the O
creation O
of O
a O
Consultative B-ORG
Council I-ORG
are O
the O
first O
issues O
to O
be O
negotiated O
from O
tomorrow O
by O
the O
PP B-ORG
and O
the O
Extremadura B-ORG
Council I-ORG
in O
order O
to O
reach O
a O
regional O
pact O
on O
13 O
issues O
of O
interest O
. O

The O
activities O
of O
" O
Now O
. O
The B-MISC
Peninsular I-MISC
Debate I-MISC
" O
will O
continue O
. O

A O
vice O
in O
which O
no O
one O
who O
is O
known O
as O
a O
geologist O
and O
aspires O
to O
be O
recognised O
as O
such O
must O
never O
enter O
is O
that O
of O
patriotism O
, O
understood O
as O
the O
excessive O
and O
inappropriate O
ardor O
of O
patriotism O
: O
the O
geologist O
is O
not O
apprehensive O
, O
but O
must O
flee O
as O
from O
the O
plague O
of O
communism O
. O

Years O
ago O
, O
in O
one O
of O
his O
travel O
books O
, O
the O
Nobel O
laureate O
of B-PER
literature I-PER
Camilo I-PER
José I-PER
Cela I-PER
stated O
that O
the O
patriot O
is O
who O
is O
proud O
of O
the O
place O
where O
he O
was O
born O
and O
defends O
it O
, O
attitude O
in O
which O
he O
is O
right O
, O
while O
the O
patriot O
- O
at O
the O
time O
, O
Cela B-PER
used O
the O
word O
' O
nationalist O
' O
- O
is O
the O
one O
who O
proclaims O
against O
the O
wind O
. O
sea O
that O
his O
homeland O
is O
in O
everything O
superior O
to O
the O
others O
, O
which O
- O
said O
Cela B-PER
- O
well O
might O
not O
be O
right O
. O

There O
is O
too O
much O
patriotism O
in O
this O
food O
. O

One O
has O
no O
problem O
in O
accepting O
that O
everyone O
defends O
the O
cuisine O
and O
products O
of O
their O
land O
... O
provided O
that O
this O
defence O
does O
not O
imply O
contempt O
because O
it O
is O
alien O
to O
the O
culinary O
customs O
of O
their O
solar O
homeland O
. O

In O
this O
case O
, O
it O
will O
have O
to O
pass O
from O
Cela B-PER
to O
Antonio B-PER
Machado I-PER
and O
remember O
that O
of O
" O
contempt O
what O
ignores O
... O

" O
The O
problem O
of O
gastronomy O
patriotism O
- O
and O
, O
let O
us O
not O
be O
fooled O
, O
of O
any O
other O
- O
is O
precisely O
this O
: O
ignorance O
. O

Of O
course O
that O
same O
ignorance O
can O
make O
many O
fall O
into O
the O
opposite O
flaw O
: O
the O
, O
let O
us O
say O
, O
boarding O
which O
makes O
for O
these O
citizens O
everything O
abroad O
is O
better O
. O

Well O
... O
neither O
. O

A O
astronomer O
is O
something O
like O
a O
traveler O
, O
but O
a O
traveler O
, O
not O
a O
tourist O
; O
a O
traveler O
, O
say O
, O
in O
the O
19th O
century O
style O
, O
a O
person O
full O
of O
curiosity O
and O
freed O
, O
if O
possible O
, O
of O
prejudices O
, O
willing O
to O
accept O
the O
good O
things O
of O
others O
without O
thereby O
rejecting O
their O
own O
. O

But O
this O
universality O
of O
the O
gastronomer O
- O
the O
first O
to O
universalize O
gastronomy O
were O
the O
Romans O
- O
does O
not O
imply O
giving O
up O
on O
oneself O
. O

Much O
less O
the O
absurd O
mescolanzas O
, O
that O
kitchen O
today O
we O
call O
' O
of O
fusion O
' O
, O
very O
defendable O
always O
. O
when O
it O
does O
not O
derive O
, O
as O
in O
so O
many O
cases O
, O
in O
kitchen O
' O
of O
confusion O
' O
. O

We O
will O
always O
insist O
that O
a O
kitchen O
, O
to O
be O
truly O
great O
, O
has O
to O
be O
faithful O
to O
its O
land O
, O
and O
also O
to O
its O
time O
. O

But O
it O
must O
, O
how O
not O
, O
be O
open O
to O
forensic O
incorporations O
. O

What O
would O
be O
of O
European O
cuisine O
, O
for O
example O
, O
without O
potatoes O
; O
or O
of O
Mediterranean O
cuisine O
without O
tomatoes O
, O
both O
products O
that O
arrived O
in O
the O
Old B-MISC
World I-MISC
less O
than O
five O
centuries O
ago O
... O

Imagine O
that O
among O
those O
Spaniards O
, O
who O
were O
the O
ones O
who O
brought O
those O
American O
gifts O
to O
Europe B-LOC
, O
would O
have O
been O
imposed O
gastronomy O
patriotism O
: O
potatoes O
and O
tomatoes O
would O
have O
remained O
in O
botanical O
curiosities O
. O

There O
is O
, O
there O
can O
not O
be O
, O
a O
universal O
cuisine O
; O
remember O
that O
horror O
known O
as O
' O
international O
cuisine O
' O
so O
common O
in O
hotel O
restaurants O
. O

But O
there O
can O
also O
be O
a O
kitchen O
locked O
in O
itself O
. O

You O
can O
not O
ask O
, O
in O
front O
of O
a O
new O
food O
, O
a O
new O
hairstyle O
, O
where O
does O
this O
come O
from O
? O
, O
without O
researching O
before O
the O
really O
important O
: O
is O
it O
rich O
? O

Well O
, O
if O
you O
are O
rich O
... O
go O
ahead O
, O
come O
from O
where O
you O
come O
from O
. O

Of O
course O
, O
we O
have O
to O
study O
how O
we O
adapt O
this O
new O
product O
to O
our O
most O
hardened O
culinary O
uses O
. O

Thus O
, O
our O
cuisine O
evolves O
, O
it O
enriches O
. O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
wrapping O
itself O
, O
ends O
up O
weakening O
and O
extinguishing O
; O
endogamia O
is O
not O
good O
for O
almost O
nothing O
. O

Have O
, O
therefore O
, O
the O
open O
mind O
, O
and O
the O
more O
senses O
still O
. O

That O
, O
paraphrasing O
Shakespeare B-PER
in'Hamlet B-MISC
' O
, O
there O
are O
more O
rich O
things O
on O
Earth B-MISC
than O
reach O
your O
wisdom O
, O
or O
your O
personal O
experience O
. O

Do O
not O
become O
eunuchs O
of O
the O
taste O
for O
pure O
patriotism O
: O
so O
many O
rich O
things O
will O
be O
lost O
... O

The O
Alcorcón O
Glass O
Art B-ORG
Museum I-ORG
welcomes O
an O
exhibition O
of O
glass O
sculptures O
by O
the O
Romanian O
artist O
Edward B-PER
Leibovtiz I-PER
, O
composed O
of O
35 O
pieces O
of O
different O
formats O
and O
whose O
size O
ranges O
from O
40 O
centimeters O
to O
2 O
meters O
of O
some O
of O
the O
figures O
. O

The O
pieces O
of O
this O
exhibition O
, O
organized O
by O
the O
Cultural B-ORG
Directorate I-ORG
, O
have O
a O
figurative O
character O
and O
they O
appreciate O
faces O
, O
bodies O
and O
different O
fantasies O
, O
showing O
even O
erotic O
aspects O
. O

Edward B-PER
Leibovitz I-PER
, O
who O
currently O
resides O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
has O
exhibited O
in O
his O
30 O
years O
of O
work O
as O
a O
contemporary O
glass O
sculptor O
in O
many O
European O
, O
American O
and O
Asian O
museums O
from O
countries O
such O
as O
Japan B-LOC
, O
Germany B-LOC
, O
France B-LOC
, O
Belgium B-LOC
or O
Israel B-LOC
. O

Visitors O
to O
the O
exhibition O
, O
which O
will O
open O
this O
evening O
, O
will O
be O
able O
to O
enjoy O
the O
various O
works O
of O
Leibovitz B-PER
, O
who O
points O
out O
that O
" O
I O
like O
to O
work O
the O
composition O
of O
the O
piece O
and O
treat O
to O
convey O
the O
fantasy O
of O
life O
with O
an O
absurd O
aspect O
" O
. O

The O
opening O
ceremony O
, O
scheduled O
for O
20 O
hours O
, O
will O
be O
attended O
by O
the O
artist O
and O
cultural B-MISC
commissioner O
, O
Francisco B-PER
Torres I-PER
, O
from O
whose O
commission B-MISC
has O
been O
invited O
to O
the O
ambassadors O
of O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
Israel B-LOC
and O
Romania B-LOC
, O
consulates O
that O
according O
to O
municipal O
sources O
have O
confirmed O
their O
presence O
through O
various O
representatives O
. O

The O
maximum O
capital O
enlargement O
of O
Earth B-ORG
for O
the O
stock O
exchange O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
including O
the O
stock O
options O
of O
the O
workers O
of O
the O
American O
company O
, O
will O
not O
exceed O
340.922.712 O
shares O
which O
, O
at O
the O
price O
of O
yesterday O
's O
stock O
closure O
( O
50.9 O
pesetas O
per O
share O
) O
, O
would O
be O
2.887 O
trillion O
pesetas O
. O

This O
is O
stated O
in O
a O
clarifying O
note O
from O
Telefónica B-ORG
Group O
to O
the O
National O
Securities O
and O
Markets B-ORG
Commission I-ORG
on O
the O
capital O
enlargements O
that O
will O
be O
subject O
to O
approval O
by O
the O
June O
General B-MISC
Board I-MISC
of I-MISC
Shareholders I-MISC
to O
carry O
out O
the O
operation O
of O
its O
subsidiary O
Terra B-ORG
Network I-ORG
on O
the O
purchase O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
an O
American O
Internet B-MISC
portal O
. O

In O
that O
clarification O
note O
, O
Telefónica B-ORG
indicates O
that O
these O
are O
maximum O
capital O
increases O
, O
to O
cover O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

The O
expansion O
of O
340.922.712 O
shares O
for O
the O
deal O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
has O
been O
made O
, O
says O
, O
taking O
into O
account O
that O
the O
American O
company O
has O
112.192.815 O
shares O
, O
and O
options O
for O
the O
acquisition O
of O
assets O
amounting O
to O
9.7 O
million O
titles O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
have O
stock O
options O
plans O
for O
23.640.000 O
titles O
, O
and O
at O
the O
end O
of O
the O
Telefónica B-ORG
operation O
there O
may O
be O
another O
7.440.000 O
stock O
options O
. O

The O
note O
points O
out O
that O
the O
maximum O
number O
of O
shares O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
that O
could O
be O
issued O
in O
total O
for O
its O
connection O
with O
Telefónica B-ORG
will O
not O
exceed O
158,568,703 O
shares O
, O
which O
would O
be O
exchanged O
for O
a O
maximum O
of O
2.15 O
shares O
of O
the O
Spanish O
company O
each O
. O

As O
regards O
the O
issuance O
of O
38,346,984 O
warrant O
shares O
( O
rights O
) O
for O
the O
purchase O
of O
options O
on O
shares O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
and O
which O
could O
result O
in O
a O
capital O
enlargement O
of O
82,45 O
million O
shares O
, O
the O
text O
clarifies O
that O
this O
is O
a O
maximum O
number O
that O
is O
already O
included O
in O
the O
enlargement O
of O
340.922,712 O
shares O
. O

The O
capital O
enlargement O
of O
35.48 O
million O
shares O
which O
will O
be O
subject O
to O
approval O
by O
the O
board O
of O
shareholders O
, O
which O
as O
of O
yesterday O
would O
amount O
to O
300.514 O
million O
pesetas O
, O
and O
which O
will O
be O
carried O
out O
at O
a O
price O
of O
62 O
euros O
- O
above O
its O
stock O
price O
these O
days O
- O
is O
the O
pact O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
because O
it O
is O
the O
stock O
price O
of O
the O
day O
of O
signing O
the O
agreement O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
Terra B-ORG
is O
currently O
under O
EUR O
62 O
could O
cause O
the O
operator O
’s O
shareholders O
not O
to O
come O
to O
the O
capital O
enlargement O
, O
which O
would O
oblige O
Telefónica B-ORG
to O
subscribe O
to O
this O
enlargement O
as O
well O
, O
as O
this O
is O
stated O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

This O
enlargement O
, O
explains O
, O
is O
the O
result O
of O
dividing O
the O
amount O
of O
the O
enlargement O
committed O
of O
EUR O
2.200 O
million O
by O
the O
type O
of O
emissions O
. O

The O
maximum O
capital O
enlargement O
of O
Earth B-ORG
for O
the O
stock O
exchange O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
including O
the O
stock O
options O
of O
the O
workers O
of O
the O
American O
company O
, O
will O
not O
exceed O
340.922.712 O
shares O
which O
, O
at O
the O
price O
of O
yesterday O
's O
stock O
closure O
( O
50.9 O
pesetas O
per O
share O
) O
, O
would O
be O
2.887 O
trillion O
pesetas O
. O

This O
is O
stated O
in O
a O
clarifying O
note O
from O
Telefónica B-ORG
Group O
to O
the O
National O
Securities O
and O
Markets B-ORG
Commission I-ORG
on O
the O
capital O
enlargements O
that O
will O
be O
subject O
to O
approval O
by O
the O
June O
General B-ORG
Board I-ORG
of I-ORG
Shareholders I-ORG
to O
carry O
out O
the O
operation O
of O
its O
subsidiary O
Terra B-ORG
Network I-ORG
on O
the O
purchase O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
an O
American O
Internet B-MISC
portal O
. O

In O
that O
clarification O
note O
, O
Telefónica B-ORG
indicates O
that O
these O
are O
maximum O
capital O
increases O
, O
to O
cover O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

The O
expansion O
of O
340.922.712 O
shares O
for O
the O
deal O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
has O
been O
made O
, O
says O
, O
taking O
into O
account O
that O
the O
American O
company O
has O
112.192.815 O
shares O
, O
and O
options O
for O
the O
acquisition O
of O
assets O
amounting O
to O
9.7 O
million O
titles O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
have O
stock O
options O
plans O
for O
23.640.000 O
titles O
, O
and O
at O
the O
end O
of O
the O
Telefónica B-ORG
operation O
there O
may O
be O
another O
7.440.000 O
stock O
options O
. O

The O
note O
points O
out O
that O
the O
maximum O
number O
of O
shares O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
that O
could O
be O
issued O
in O
total O
for O
its O
connection O
with O
Telefónica B-ORG
will O
not O
exceed O
158,568,703 O
shares O
, O
which O
would O
be O
exchanged O
for O
a O
maximum O
of O
2.15 O
shares O
of O
the O
Spanish O
company O
each O
. O

As O
regards O
the O
issuance O
of O
38,346,984 O
warrant O
shares O
( O
rights O
) O
for O
the O
purchase O
of O
options O
on O
shares O
of O
Lycos B-ORG
employees O
and O
which O
could O
result O
in O
a O
capital O
enlargement O
of O
82,45 O
million O
shares O
, O
the O
text O
clarifies O
that O
this O
is O
a O
maximum O
number O
that O
is O
already O
included O
in O
the O
enlargement O
of O
340.922,712 O
shares O
. O

The O
capital O
enlargement O
of O
35.48 O
million O
shares O
which O
will O
be O
subject O
to O
approval O
by O
the O
board O
of O
shareholders O
, O
which O
as O
of O
yesterday O
would O
amount O
to O
300.514 O
million O
pesetas O
, O
and O
which O
will O
be O
carried O
out O
at O
a O
price O
of O
62 O
euros O
- O
above O
its O
stock O
price O
these O
days O
- O
is O
the O
pact O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
, O
because O
it O
is O
the O
stock O
price O
of O
the O
day O
of O
signing O
the O
agreement O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
Terra B-ORG
is O
currently O
under O
EUR O
62 O
could O
cause O
the O
operator O
’s O
shareholders O
not O
to O
come O
to O
the O
capital O
enlargement O
, O
which O
would O
oblige O
Telefónica B-ORG
to O
subscribe O
to O
this O
enlargement O
as O
well O
, O
as O
this O
is O
stated O
in O
the O
agreements O
with O
Lycos B-ORG
. O

This O
enlargement O
, O
explains O
, O
is O
the O
result O
of O
dividing O
the O
amount O
of O
the O
enlargement O
committed O
of O
EUR O
2.200 O
million O
by O
the O
type O
of O
emissions O
. O

( O
ONE B-PER
LUGUE I-PER
) O
. O

Princess B-PER
Elena I-PER
and O
her O
husband O
Jaime B-PER
de I-PER
Marichalar I-PER
, O
Dukes O
of O
Lugo B-LOC
, O
begin O
a O
two O
- O
day O
visit O
to O
Galicia B-LOC
, O
in O
which O
it O
is O
planned O
that O
, O
in O
addition O
to O
opening O
a O
lecture O
of O
the O
Cela B-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
, O
they O
participate O
in O
an O
act O
of O
declaration O
of O
support O
to O
the O
Roman O
Wall O
Lucense O
as O
a O
heritage O
of O
humanity B-MISC
. O

( O
CONSELLO O
XUNTA B-ORG
) O
. O

The O
president O
of O
the O
recruitment O
board B-ORG
will O
inform O
you O
of O
the O
agreements O
made O
on O
the O
advice O
of O
the O
Galician O
Government B-ORG
. O

( O
BNG B-ORG
GROUP O
) O
. O

Members O
of O
the O
BNG B-ORG
present O
in O
the O
Constitution B-LOC
the O
appeal O
for O
having O
been O
denied O
the O
acquisition O
of O
own O
group O
( O
PP B-ORG
CONGRESOS O
) O
. O

The O
secretary O
of O
the O
Galician O
PP B-ORG
, O
Jesús B-PER
Palmou I-PER
, O
offers O
statements O
to O
EFE B-ORG
to O
explain O
the O
details O
of O
provincial O
congresses O
this O
weekend O
in O
A B-LOC
Coruña I-LOC
and O
Pontevedra B-LOC
. O

The O
Museum B-ORG
of I-ORG
Fine I-ORG
Arts I-ORG
of O
A B-LOC
Coruña I-LOC
inaugurates O
the O
photographic O
exhibition O
" O
Emmanuel B-MISC
Souguez I-MISC
. O
Photographies O
1928 O
- O
1958 O
" O
. O

EFE B-ORG
Associated O
Press B-LOC
by O
Kathy B-PER
Seleme I-PER
Beirut B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

The O
22 O
years O
of O
Israeli O
occupation O
of O
southern O
Lebanon O
ended O
in O
a O
few O
hours O
, O
but O
the O
fundamental O
problems O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
a O
country O
still O
hostage O
to O
its O
two O
powerful O
neighbours O
, O
Israel B-LOC
and O
Syria B-LOC
, O
that O
can O
use O
it O
at O
any O
time O
for O
their O
interests O
. O

The O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
south O
, O
although O
planned O
and O
announced O
, O
was O
condemned O
by O
everyone O
for O
its O
precipitation O
, O
six O
weeks O
before O
it O
was O
announced O
by O
the O
Israeli B-ORG
Government I-ORG
, O
and O
for O
the O
chaotic O
way O
it O
occurred O
. O

Israel B-LOC
retreated O
just O
over O
48 O
hours O
south O
after O
the O
collapse O
of O
its O
allies O
in O
the O
Southern B-ORG
Lebanon I-ORG
Army I-ORG
( O
ESL B-ORG
) O
, O
who O
had O
helped O
it O
maintain O
its O
occupation O
, O
and O
whom O
it O
was O
planning O
to O
leave O
in O
a O
" O
tampo O
area O
" O
to O
protect O
its O
northern O
border O
, O
along O
with O
the O
United O
Nations B-ORG
Interim I-ORG
Force I-ORG
for I-ORG
Lebanon I-ORG
( O
UNIFIL B-ORG
) O
. O

Paradoxically O
, O
he O
had O
to O
surrender O
the O
land O
to O
his O
main O
enemy O
, O
the O
Chinese O
Hezbollah B-ORG
( O
Party B-ORG
of I-ORG
God I-ORG
) O
, O
which O
, O
since O
the O
second O
Israeli O
invasion O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
in O
1982 O
, O
led O
the O
guerrilla O
organizations O
fighting O
the O
occupation O
. O

Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
supported O
by O
Beirut B-ORG
, O
Damascus O
and O
Tehran B-ORG
, O
took O
control O
of O
the O
liberated O
south O
in O
the O
absence O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
, O
which O
has O
not O
yet O
defined O
the O
mission O
that O
will O
entrust O
to O
its O
" O
blue O
helmets O
" O
, O
whose O
personnel O
wants O
to O
increase O
from O
4,500 O
to O
7,935 O
. O

Although O
Beirut B-ORG
considers O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
incomplete O
, O
because O
it O
did O
not O
include O
the O
controversial O
farms O
in O
Chebaa B-LOC
, O
on O
the O
Syrian B-LOC
border O
, O
and O
the O
release O
of O
some O
20 O
Lebanese O
detained O
in O
Israel B-LOC
, O
it O
assured O
that O
it O
would O
cooperate O
with O
the O
UN B-ORG
. O

Israel B-ORG
and O
the O
UN B-ORG
assure O
that O
these O
farms O
are O
Syrian O
, O
but O
Damascus B-LOC
and O
Beirut B-LOC
claim O
that O
they O
are O
Lebanese O
and O
, O
to O
this O
effect O
, O
the O
government B-ORG
has O
sent O
several O
documents O
to O
the O
UN B-ORG
to O
affirm O
their O
sovereignty O
. O

The O
leader O
of O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
Sheikh O
Hasan B-PER
Nasrala I-PER
, O
announced O
for O
his O
part O
that O
he O
would O
continue O
the O
fight O
until O
the O
liberation O
of O
that O
territory O
, O
located O
at O
the O
foot O
of O
Mount B-LOC
Hermon I-LOC
and O
rich O
in O
waters O
. O

In O
response O
to O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
Israel B-ORG
threatened O
with O
" O
painful O
responses O
" O
in O
the O
event O
of O
continued O
attacks O
on O
its O
territory O
, O
referring O
to O
the O
" O
katiuska O
" O
rockets O
that O
that O
group O
launches O
unquestionably O
against O
the O
north O
of O
Israel O
. O

Apparently O
, O
Syria B-ORG
, O
which O
exercises O
a O
dominant O
influence O
in O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
where O
it O
has O
prominent O
about O
35,000 O
soldiers O
, O
has O
for O
the O
time O
being O
given O
a O
white O
letter O
to O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
a O
pro O
- O
Iranian O
group O
in O
which O
also O
has O
a O
great O
influence O
Damascus B-ORG
. O

The O
withdrawal O
of O
Israel B-ORG
from O
the O
south O
was O
part O
of O
the O
strategy O
of O
Israeli O
Prime O
Minister O
Ehud B-PER
Barak I-PER
to O
force O
Syria B-ORG
into O
negotiations O
on O
the O
Golan B-LOC
, O
occupied O
by O
Israel B-ORG
in O
1967 O
and O
annexed O
in O
1981 O
. O

In O
theory O
, O
Syria B-ORG
is O
harmed O
by O
the O
unilateral O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
southern O
Lebanon O
, O
since O
it O
deprives O
Damascus B-ORG
of O
a O
letter O
that O
it O
used O
, O
through O
Hezbollah B-ORG
, O
to O
put O
pressure O
on O
Israel B-ORG
. O

However O
, O
in O
practice O
, O
Damascus B-ORG
, O
which O
is O
inflexible O
on O
the O
question O
of O
the O
return O
of O
the O
Golan B-LOC
to O
the O
line O
of O
demarcation O
prior O
to O
June O
1967 O
, O
seems O
to O
have O
forced O
Israel B-ORG
to O
carry O
out O
its O
threat O
and O
has O
resulted O
in O
strengthened O
its O
control O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
. O

If O
Israel B-ORG
occupied O
ten O
per O
cent O
of O
Lebanese O
territory O
, O
Syrian O
troops O
are O
deployed O
in O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
country O
and O
it O
is O
not O
ruled O
out O
that O
they O
can O
be O
assigned O
a O
mission O
in O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
making O
their O
withdrawal O
complicated O
, O
despite O
the O
wishes O
of O
a O
majority O
of O
Lebanese O
. O

The O
major O
powers O
have O
assigned O
Syria B-ORG
the O
role O
of O
Lebanon O
's O
guardian O
and O
they O
know O
that O
if O
they O
do O
not O
reach O
an O
agreement O
with O
Israel B-ORG
, O
the O
Lebanese O
situation O
will O
remain O
insecure O
and O
unpredictable O
. O

The O
only O
hope O
for O
the O
Lebanese O
situation O
to O
stabilize O
is O
for O
a O
global O
peace O
in O
the O
Middle B-LOC
East I-LOC
, O
so O
that O
this O
country O
, O
which O
has O
been O
the O
main O
victim O
, O
along O
with O
the O
Palestinians O
, O
of O
the O
Arab O
- O
Israeli O
conflict O
, O
does O
not O
remain O
so O
in O
the O
future O
. O
by O
Orlando B-PER
Lizama I-PER
Washington B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

The O
US B-ORG
president O
, O
Bill B-PER
Clinton I-PER
, O
marked O
an O
important O
victory O
in O
foreign O
policy O
with O
the O
approval O
in O
the O
House B-ORG
of I-ORG
Representatives I-ORG
of O
a O
trade O
agreement O
with O
China B-ORG
that O
will O
add O
to O
the O
economic O
success O
of O
his O
government O
. O

Political O
analysts O
indicated O
today O
that O
the O
decision O
of O
the O
House B-ORG
, O
which O
has O
secured O
the O
approval O
of O
the O
Senate B-ORG
, O
will O
open O
a O
new O
chapter O
in O
relations O
between O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
and O
China B-ORG
and O
, O
above O
all O
, O
the O
world O
's O
largest O
market O
for O
American O
products O
. O

By O
approving O
the O
granting O
of O
permanent O
trade O
privileges O
to O
China B-ORG
by O
237 O
votes O
in O
favour O
to O
197 O
against O
, O
the O
House B-ORG
ended O
Wednesday O
's O
practice O
of O
discussing O
these O
privileges O
every O
year O
and O
assured O
the O
application O
to O
Chinese O
products O
of O
the O
same O
tariffs O
that O
are O
imposed O
on O
those O
of O
other O
countries O
. O

Also O
, O
after O
China B-ORG
reached O
a O
similar O
agreement O
with O
the O
European B-ORG
Union I-ORG
last O
week O
, O
the O
Beijing B-LOC
authorities O
secured O
its O
country O
's O
entry O
into O
the O
World B-ORG
Trade I-ORG
Organization I-ORG
( O
WTO B-ORG
) O
. O

Instead O
, O
once O
the O
Senate B-ORG
formally O
approves O
it O
in O
June O
, O
China B-LOC
will O
open O
its O
1.3 O
billion O
consumer O
market O
to O
a O
wide O
range O
of O
American O
products O
, O
from O
agriculture O
to O
telecommunications O
to O
cars O
. O

Without O
external O
conflicts O
and O
a O
booming O
economy O
, O
Clinton B-PER
had O
made O
approval O
the O
legislative O
priority O
of O
her O
government O
that O
will O
end O
in O
January O
next O
year O
, O
and O
after O
the O
vote O
did O
not O
hide O
her O
happiness O
. O

" O
The O
House B-ORG
of I-ORG
Representatives I-ORG
has O
taken O
an O
historic O
step O
towards O
the O
continuation O
of O
prosperity O
in O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
, O
reform O
in O
China B-ORG
and O
peace O
in O
the O
world O
, O
" O
said O
Clinton B-PER
, O
who O
in O
1993 O
signed O
the O
Free B-MISC
Trade I-MISC
Treaty I-MISC
( O
FTA B-MISC
) O
with O
Mexico B-ORG
and O
Canada B-ORG
. O

" O
I O
have O
always O
been O
a O
believer O
that O
if O
we O
open O
markets O
abroad O
, O
we O
give O
way O
to O
more O
opportunities O
in O
the O
country O
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O

And O
referring O
to O
criticisms O
of O
the O
lack O
of O
democracy O
and O
alleged O
human O
rights O
violations O
in O
China B-LOC
, O
the O
Commissioner O
said O
that O
the O
agreement O
would O
help O
improve O
the O
situation O
. O

" O
We O
will O
have O
a O
more O
positive O
influence O
with O
an O
extended O
hand O
than O
with O
the O
clasped O
hand O
" O
, O
added O
. O

Clinton B-PER
and O
his O
advisers O
had O
previously O
said O
that O
rejecting O
the O
agreement O
would O
mean O
pushing O
relations O
between O
the O
two O
countries O
into O
a O
deadlock O
that O
would O
threaten O
stability O
in O
Asia B-LOC
and O
exacerbate O
tensions O
between O
China B-ORG
and O
Taiwan B-ORG
. O

" O
The O
approval O
has O
been O
a O
concrete O
result O
because O
it O
makes O
no O
sense O
to O
face O
the O
world O
's O
most O
populous O
country O
, O
" O
said O
Sidney B-PER
Weintraub I-PER
of O
the O
Centre B-ORG
for I-ORG
International I-ORG
Strategic I-ORG
Studies I-ORG
( O
CSIS B-ORG
) O
. O

" O
Opening O
up O
other O
markets O
is O
not O
a O
favor O
we O
do O
to O
other O
countries O
. O

It O
's O
an O
opportunity O
we O
create O
for O
ourselves O
, O
" O
said O
Sherman B-PER
Katc I-PER
, O
a O
CSIS B-MISC
analyst O
. O

However O
, O
there O
was O
also O
criticism O
, O
especially O
of O
those O
who O
reject O
China B-ORG
's O
political O
ideology O
and O
human O
rights O
situation O
, O
globalization O
and O
trade O
unions O
who O
fear O
that O
the O
agreement O
will O
lead O
to O
the O
loss O
of O
jobs O
in O
the O
country O
. O

The O
president O
of O
the O
influential O
Senate B-ORG
Foreign I-ORG
Relations I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
, O
Jesse B-PER
Helms I-PER
, O
promised O
that O
he O
would O
fight O
to O
prevent O
that O
branch O
of O
Congress B-ORG
from O
approving O
the O
agreement O
. O

" O
I O
do O
n't O
want O
to O
spoil O
the O
party O
, O
but O
I O
feel O
compelled O
to O
make O
it O
clear O
that O
I O
have O
no O
intention O
of O
the O
Senate B-ORG
duplicating O
the O
plan O
to O
reward O
the O
Chinese O
Communists O
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O

The O
president O
of O
the O
conservative O
Friends B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Earth I-ORG
group O
, O
Brent B-PER
Blackwelder I-PER
, O
said O
the O
agreement O
" O
shows O
that O
the O
US B-ORG
foreign O
policy O
has O
been O
captured O
by O
corporate O
contaminants O
and O
big O
campaign O
contributors O
" O
. O

To O
ensure O
approval O
, O
the O
legislators O
of O
the O
House B-ORG
added O
to O
the O
draft O
a O
proposal O
to O
create O
a O
human O
rights O
observation O
group O
. O

But O
, O
according O
to O
Friends B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Earth I-ORG
, O
the O
project O
omitted O
references O
to O
environmental O
protection O
in O
China B-LOC
, O
" O
where O
two O
million O
people O
die O
each O
year O
due O
to O
water O
and O
air O
pollution O
" O
. O

" O
Where O
is O
freedom O
of O
expression O
? O
Where O
is O
freedom O
of O
worship O
? O
Where O
is O
freedom O
of O
assembly O
? O
. O

In O
China B-ORG
not O
" O
, O
said O
the O
representative O
for O
Georgia B-LOC
John B-PER
Lewis I-PER
when O
expressing O
his O
rejection O
of O
the O
agreement O
. O

" O
If O
we O
defend O
human O
and O
civil O
rights O
in O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
and O
elsewhere O
in O
the O
world O
, O
we O
must O
defend O
them O
in O
China B-LOC
, O
" O
he O
added O
. O

In O
a O
debate O
that O
took O
more O
economic O
than O
political O
interests O
into O
account O
, O
the O
approval O
was O
applauded O
by O
Texas B-LOC
Governor O
George B-PER
W. I-PER
Bush I-PER
, O
the O
Republican O
presidential O
candidate O
who O
faces O
Democrat O
and O
Vice O
President O
Al B-PER
Gore I-PER
in O
the O
November O
elections O
. O

" O
It O
means O
a O
stronger O
economy O
for O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
, O
as O
well O
as O
more O
opportunities O
for O
freedom O
in O
China B-ORG
" O
, O
said O
. O
by O
Claudia B-PER
Gutiérrez I-PER
Beijing B-LOC
, O
25 O
May O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
. O

The O
Chinese O
Government B-ORG
today O
urged O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
to O
correct O
the O
" O
mistake O
" O
of O
having O
included O
the O
creation O
of O
a O
human O
rights O
committee O
in O
the O
resolution O
granting O
this O
country O
permanent O
status O
of O
normal O
trade O
relationship O
( O
PNTR B-MISC
) O
. O

According O
to O
the O
spokesperson O
of O
the O
Foreign B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
, O
Zhang B-PER
Qiyue I-PER
, O
Beijing B-ORG
has O
already O
submitted O
its O
complaint O
to O
the O
US O
executive O
in O
relation O
to O
this O
matter O
, O
as O
it O
not O
only O
opposes O
the O
articles O
referring O
to O
that O
committee O
but O
that O
" O
will O
not O
accept O
them O
" O
. O

" O
We O
urge O
the O
US B-ORG
to O
correct O
its O
mistake O
, O
so O
as O
to O
ensure O
a O
healthy O
and O
peaceful O
development O
of O
bilateral O
economic O
and O
trade O
cooperation O
" O
, O
said O
today O
both O
the O
Ministry B-ORG
of I-ORG
Foreign I-ORG
Affairs I-ORG
and O
the O
Ministry O
of O
Foreign O
Trade B-ORG
. O

The O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
House I-ORG
of I-ORG
Representatives O
approved O
this O
resolution O
last O
morning O
( O
local O
time O
) O
after O
more O
than O
seven O
hours O
of O
debate O
, O
by O
237 O
votes O
in O
favour O
and O
197 O
against O
. O

To O
ensure O
the O
victory O
of O
this O
historic O
measure O
, O
defended O
resolutely O
before O
Republicans O
by O
US O
President O
Bill B-PER
Clinton I-PER
, O
during O
the O
last O
few O
months O
, O
Congress B-ORG
leaders O
agreed O
to O
create O
a O
committee O
of O
the O
legislature O
and O
the O
executive O
that O
will O
oversee O
the O
human O
rights O
policy O
in O
this O
country O
annually O
. O

Although O
Beijing B-LOC
today O
described O
the O
US O
resolution O
as O
a O
" O
wise O
measure O
, O
" O
it O
also O
accuses O
Washington B-ORG
of O
using O
human O
rights O
as O
an O
excuse O
to O
interfere O
in O
its O
internal O
affairs O
and O
harm O
its O
interests O
, O
" O
something O
unacceptable O
to O
the O
Chinese O
government B-ORG
. O
" O

The O
Moftec B-ORG
did O
not O
hesitate O
to O
threaten O
with O
reprisals O
if O
such O
a O
committee O
is O
indeed O
set O
up O
to O
investigate O
the O
human O
rights O
situation O
. O

" O
China B-ORG
wishes O
to O
express O
its O
deep O
dissatisfaction O
with O
this O
resolution O
and O
reserves O
the O
right O
to O
react O
in O
the O
future O
" O
on O
a O
matter O
that O
" O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
has O
a O
duty O
to O
resolve O
" O
, O
said O
Hu B-PER
Chusheng I-PER
, O
spokesman O
for O
Moftec B-ORG
. O

" O
The O
granting O
of O
PNTR B-MISC
to O
China O
is O
an O
obligation O
of O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
, O
in O
accordance O
with O
the O
rules O
of O
the O
World B-ORG
Trade I-ORG
Organization I-ORG
( O
WTO B-ORG
) O
" O
, O
the O
foreign O
representative O
said O
, O
" O
since O
permanent O
status O
is O
the O
basis O
and O
a O
prerequisite O
" O
for O
the O
entry O
into O
force O
of O
the O
bilateral O
agreement O
on O
China B-ORG
's O
accession O
to O
the O
WTO B-ORG
signed O
last O
15 O
November O
in O
this O
capital O
. O

Zhang B-PER
pointed O
out O
that O
the O
Congress B-ORG
resolution O
, O
which O
is O
due O
to O
be O
ratified O
by O
the O
Senate B-ORG
in O
mid O
- O
June O
, O
not O
only O
contributes O
to O
China B-ORG
and O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
developing O
their O
economic O
and O
trade O
exchanges O
based O
on O
equality O
and O
mutual O
benefit O
, O
but O
also O
helps O
create O
the O
conditions O
for O
the O
healthy O
and O
stable O
development O
of O
bilateral O
relations O
. O

The O
spokeswoman O
urged O
the O
US O
side O
to O
respect O
the O
three O
communiqués O
signed O
by O
both O
countries O
, O
the O
basic O
rules O
governing O
international O
relations O
and O
WTO B-ORG
rules O
. O

With O
the O
approval O
of O
the O
PNTR B-MISC
it O
ends O
20 O
years O
of O
annual O
reviews O
of O
China B-LOC
's O
trade O
status O
by O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
and O
opens O
the O
doors O
for O
this O
country O
to O
become O
the O
number O
136 O
WTO B-ORG
partner O
before O
the O
end O
of O
the O
year O
, O
an O
opportunity O
that O
remained O
more O
within O
reach O
after O
Beijing B-ORG
signed O
a O
similar O
agreement O
with O
the O
European B-ORG
Union I-ORG
( O
EU B-ORG
) O
last O
Friday O
in O
this O
capital O
. O

With O
China B-ORG
's O
entry O
into O
the O
world O
trade O
regulatory O
body O
, O
the O
tariffs O
that O
this O
country O
must O
pay O
to O
access O
the O
US B-LOC
will O
be O
equivalent O
to O
those O
of O
virtually O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
nations O
, O
while O
Beijing B-ORG
will O
have O
to O
open O
its O
markets O
to O
sectors O
such O
as O
agriculture O
, O
telecommunications O
or O
insurance O
of O
that O
country O
. O

While O
opponents O
of O
the O
resolution O
say O
that O
China B-ORG
's O
accession O
to O
the O
WTO B-ORG
will O
exacerbate O
the O
already O
huge O
trade O
deficit O
that O
the O
US B-ORG
maintains O
with O
this O
country O
, O
of O
$ O
68 O
billion O
last O
year O
, O
their O
advocates O
assure O
that O
not O
only O
the O
American O
economy O
will O
benefit O
, O
but O
also O
national O
security O
, O
as O
political O
and O
economic O
reforms O
will O
be O
pushed O
in O
this O
Asian O
giant O
. O

The O
Portuguese O
press O
today O
highlighted O
the O
eighth O
victory O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
in O
a O
historic O
final O
of O
the O
European B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
that O
for O
the O
first O
time O
faced O
two O
teams O
of O
the O
same O
country O
. O

They O
are O
unanimous O
in O
their O
judgments O
favourable O
to O
the O
game O
developed O
by O
the O
winning O
team O
, O
" O
simply O
insurmountable O
" O
, O
" O
history O
won O
, O
the O
madridistas O
religiously O
respected O
their O
past O
and O
built O
a O
cruel O
end O
to O
the O
beautiful O
adventure O
of O
Valencia B-ORG
" O
, O
commented O
" O
A B-ORG
Bola I-ORG
" O
in O
its O
first O
pages O
. O

" O
The O
myth O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
continues O
to O
increase O
" O
, O
" O
Raúl O
: O
the B-MISC
eighth I-MISC
wonder I-MISC
" O
titled O
" O
Record B-MISC
" O
, O
which O
reports O
that O
the O
sports O
show O
was O
" O
sober O
" O
by O
the O
quality O
of O
the O
game O
and O
a O
stadium O
divided O
between O
the O
two O
passions O
who O
passionately O
followed O
the O
incidences O
of O
the O
meeting O
. O

" O
Valencian O
rice O
was O
a O
sweet O
merengue O
" O
according O
to O
the O
" O
Journal B-MISC
de I-MISC
Noticias I-MISC
" O
, O
which O
highlights O
the O
superiority O
of O
the O
Madrid O
team O
against O
a O
Valencia B-ORG
that O
liked O
" O
lack O
of O
rhythm O
" O
and O
" O
lost O
almost O
all O
the O
inspiration O
of O
attack O
" O
. O

The O
murder O
in O
Sierra B-LOC
Leone I-LOC
of O
four O
pro O
- O
government O
forces O
soldiers O
and O
two O
journalists O
by O
the O
rebels O
of O
the O
United O
Nations B-ORG
Revolutionary I-ORG
Forces I-ORG
( O
FRU B-ORG
) O
coincided O
with O
the O
intensification O
of O
the O
wave O
of O
violence O
that O
this O
African O
country O
has O
been O
experiencing O
for O
almost O
a O
month O
. O

Spanish O
journalist O
Miguel B-PER
Gil I-PER
Moreno I-PER
, O
who O
worked O
as O
a O
cameraman O
for O
the O
American O
agency O
Associated B-ORG
Press I-ORG
TV I-ORG
, O
and O
his O
American O
colleague O
Kurt B-PER
Schork I-PER
, O
a O
correspondent O
for O
the O
British O
news O
agency O
Reuters B-ORG
, O
were O
murdered O
yesterday O
when O
the O
column O
of O
government O
troops O
alongside O
which O
they O
were O
travelling O
was O
attacked O
by O
FRU B-ORG
rebels O
. O

In O
the O
incident O
, O
which O
took O
place O
at O
the O
road O
crossing O
of O
Rogberi B-LOC
, O
about O
80 O
kilometers O
northwest O
of O
Freetown B-LOC
, O
also O
injured O
slightly O
two O
other O
journalists O
, O
Greek O
Yannis B-PER
Behrakis I-PER
and O
South O
African O
Mark B-PER
Chisholm I-PER
, O
both O
Reuters B-ORG
correspondents O
. O

Also O
, O
and O
according O
to O
UN B-ORG
sources O
in O
the O
capital O
of O
Sierra B-LOC
Leone I-LOC
, O
four O
Sierra O
Leonean O
soldiers O
also O
died O
after O
the O
ambush O
. O

The O
two O
injured O
reporters O
were O
transferred O
to O
a O
campaign O
hospital O
prepared O
by O
UN B-ORG
forces O
without O
fear O
for O
their O
lives O
, O
while O
the O
body O
of O
the O
32 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Spanish O
journalist O
was O
yesterday O
in O
Freetown B-LOC
awaiting O
repatriation O
, O
UN B-ORG
sources O
told O
EFE I-ORG
in O
the O
city O
. O

No O
longer O
known O
about O
the O
incident O
, O
the O
UN B-PER
Secretary I-PER
- O
General O
, O
Ghanaian O
Kofi B-PER
Annan I-PER
, O
expressed O
his O
sadness O
over O
the O
death O
of O
the O
two O
journalists O
, O
of O
whom O
he O
said O
" O
they O
were O
professionals O
seeking O
to O
report O
on O
the O
bloody O
conflict O
that O
has O
already O
claimed O
too O
many O
lives O
" O
. O

" O
They O
were O
doing O
what O
any O
other O
journalist O
around O
the O
world O
does O
: O
taking O
risks O
so O
that O
we O
could O
be O
informed O
, O
" O
Annan B-PER
added O
in O
a O
statement O
. O

For O
his O
part O
, O
the O
president O
of O
Asociated B-ORG
Press I-ORG
, O
Louis B-PER
D. I-PER
Boccardi I-PER
, O
assured O
that O
" O
Miguel B-PER
's O
loss O
leaves O
you O
with O
an O
indescribable O
sense O
of O
loss O
. O

Our O
pain O
is O
not O
relieved O
by O
the O
certainty O
that O
he O
was O
doing O
the O
work O
he O
loved O
when O
the O
tragedy O
hit O
him O
. O
" O

Gil B-PER
Moreno I-PER
, O
a O
natural O
of O
Barcelona B-LOC
, O
in O
northwestern O
Spain B-LOC
, O
had O
covered O
, O
among O
others O
, O
the O
conflicts O
in O
Kosovo B-LOC
, O
Chechnya B-LOC
, O
Iraq B-LOC
and O
Congo B-LOC
, O
but O
as O
Nigel B-PER
Baker I-PER
, O
news O
director O
of O
the O
American O
agency O
, O
said O
" O
he O
never O
took O
a O
step O
without O
measuring O
the O
reasons O
for O
doing O
so O
and O
his O
options O
" O
. O

The O
Spanish O
reporter O
had O
received O
last O
month O
the O
camera O
of O
the O
year O
award O
by O
the O
" O
Royal B-ORG
Television I-ORG
Society I-ORG
" O
. O

Kurt B-PER
Shork I-PER
, O
the O
other O
victim O
, O
53 O
years O
old O
, O
worked O
for O
Reuters B-ORG
over O
the O
last O
decade O
. O

" O
Kurt B-PER
was O
a O
courageous O
reporter O
, O
a O
courageous O
man O
, O
who O
perhaps O
better O
than O
other O
journalists O
managed O
to O
reflect O
the O
difficult O
situation O
of O
the O
Kurdish O
population O
during O
the O
Gulf B-MISC
War I-MISC
and O
the O
victims O
of O
the O
Balkan B-LOC
conflict O
afterwards O
" O
, O
said O
the O
editor O
- O
in O
- O
chief O
of O
the O
British O
agency O
, O
Geert B-PER
Linnebank I-PER
. O

The O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
also O
issued O
a O
statement O
yesterday O
strongly O
condemning O
the O
incident O
. O

" O
We O
condemn O
this O
violent O
attack O
in O
the O
strongest O
possible O
terms O
, O
both O
the O
US B-ORG
Embassy I-ORG
in O
Freetown B-LOC
and O
the O
State B-ORG
Department I-ORG
in O
Washington B-LOC
are O
ready O
to O
help O
families O
at O
this O
difficult O
time O
, O
" O
said O
Philip B-PER
Reeker I-PER
, O
State B-ORG
Department I-ORG
spokesman O
. O

The O
journalists O
were O
attacked O
by O
the O
FRU B-ORG
rebels O
when O
they O
were O
travelling O
in O
two O
military O
trucks O
alongside O
a O
column O
of O
pro O
- O
government O
soldiers O
at O
the O
road O
crossing O
of O
Rogberi B-LOC
, O
near O
the O
town O
of O
Masaka B-LOC
, O
about O
80 O
km O
northwest O
of O
Freetown B-LOC
. O

In O
this O
area O
, O
of O
high O
strategic O
value O
, O
had O
previously O
been O
recorded O
other O
clashes O
between O
" O
blue O
helmets O
" O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
rebel O
groups O
. O

Last O
Monday O
, O
troops O
of O
the O
Sierra O
Leonean O
Army B-ORG
had O
taken O
the O
crossing O
of O
Rogberi B-LOC
, O
where O
on O
the O
same O
day O
several O
dead O
bodies O
, O
in O
advanced O
decomposition O
, O
dressed O
in O
uniforms O
of O
" O
blue O
helmets O
" O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
that O
could O
correspond O
to O
the O
members O
of O
this O
international O
body O
kidnapped O
by O
the O
rebels O
three O
weeks O
ago O
. O

The O
FRU B-ORG
still O
retains O
290 O
blue O
helmets O
, O
and O
according O
to O
Liberian O
President O
Charles B-PER
Taylor I-PER
, O
who O
acts O
as O
a O
mediator O
between O
the O
United B-ORG
Nations I-ORG
and O
the O
Sierra O
Leonean O
rebels O
, O
they O
will O
not O
release O
more O
hostages O
until O
the O
government O
forces O
stop O
their O
offensive O
against O
the O
FRU B-ORG
and O
stop O
their O
unstoppable O
progress O
towards O
the O
guerrilla O
feuds O
inside O
the O
country O
. O

Rome B-LOC
, O
May O
25 O
( O
EFE B-ORG
) O
- O
" O
Europe B-MISC
is I-MISC
again I-MISC
from I-MISC
Real I-MISC
Madrid I-MISC
, O
" O
is O
the O
headline O
with O
which O
the O
Italian O
press O
highlights O
the O
triumph O
of O
the O
team O
of O
the O
Spanish B-LOC
capital O
in O
the O
final O
of O
the O
Champions O
League O
against O
the O
other O
Spanish O
club O
, O
Valencia B-ORG
, O
of O
which O
the O
newspapers O
say O
did O
not O
show O
the O
brilliant O
game O
he O
made O
against O
Barcelona B-ORG
or O
Lazio B-ORG
. O

Although O
it O
appears O
in O
a O
cover O
of O
the O
first O
pages O
, O
the O
end O
of O
the O
Cup B-MISC
of O
Champions O
does O
not O
occupy O
the O
major O
headlines O
of O
the O
Italian O
sports O
newspapers O
, O
which O
in O
the O
case O
of O
" O
Gazzetta B-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
confines O
it O
to O
page O
15 O
and O
in O
the O
of O
" O
Corriere B-ORG
dellos I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
to O
page O
17 O
. O

This O
is O
because O
there O
was O
no O
Italian O
club O
among O
the O
finalists O
. O

" O
Real B-MISC
conquers I-MISC
its I-MISC
eighth I-MISC
victory I-MISC
in I-MISC
cup I-MISC
of I-MISC
champions I-MISC
. O
Valencia O
defeated O
by O
3 O
- O
0 O
" O
, O
is O
the O
title O
of O
" O
La B-ORG
Gazzetta I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
, O
which O
on O
the O
inside O
page O
adds O
: O
" O
The O
eighth O
wonder O
of O
Real B-ORG
, O
Valencia B-ORG
wakes O
up O
from O
the O
dream O
" O
. O

According O
to O
the O
Milan O
daily O
, O
came O
awarded O
the O
team O
" O
most O
expert O
" O
, O
the O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
, O
" O
which O
was O
imposed O
on O
a O
Valencia B-ORG
that O
jumped O
" O
. O

Additionally O
, O
the O
madridistas O
settled O
in O
the O
Duels O
and O
that O
in O
the O
center O
of O
the O
field O
dominated O
Redondo B-PER
and O
McManaman B-PER
. O

After O
highlighting O
Raul B-PER
's O
game O
, O
" O
La B-ORG
Gazzetta I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
claims O
that O
the O
young O
Madrid O
player O
" O
is O
at O
a O
step O
" O
from O
the O
Golden B-MISC
Ball O
and O
deserves O
to O
be O
in O
the O
gallery O
of O
the O
Greats B-MISC
of I-MISC
Real I-MISC
Madrid I-MISC
, O
between O
Di B-PER
Stefano I-PER
and O
Kopa B-PER
. O

" O
Real O
Hurricane O
on B-MISC
Valencia I-MISC
" O
is O
the O
title O
of O
" O
Corriere B-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
, O
the O
Roman O
daily O
that O
claim O
that O
the O
Madriders O
gave O
" O
a O
severe O
lesson O
to O
the O
team O
encouraged O
by O
Cuper B-PER
" O
. O

The O
morning O
claims O
that O
for O
the O
Real B-ORG
the O
achievement O
of O
the O
cup O
means O
relinquishing O
a O
bad O
season O
and O
that O
Valencia B-ORG
relied O
too O
much O
on O
its O
counterparts O
, O
who O
did O
not O
detain O
Moriente B-PER
, O
McManaman B-PER
and O
Raul B-PER
to O
" O
sign O
" O
the O
eighth O
cup O
of O
champions O
. O

Highlights O
the O
young O
porter O
Iker B-PER
Casillas I-PER
( O
he O
calls O
him O
the O
baby- O
champ O
) O
and O
Helguera B-PER
and O
especially O
Raul B-PER
, O
whom O
he O
defines O
as O
a O
" O
total O
champion O
" O
that O
marks O
goals O
of O
all O
types O
and O
ways O
, O
" O
He O
has O
a O
strength O
and O
crazy O
desires O
to O
win O
" O
. O

For O
" O
Corriere B-ORG
dello I-ORG
Sport I-ORG
" O
, O
the O
triumph O
of O
Madrid B-ORG
means O
the O
revanch O
of O
Del B-PER
Bosque I-PER
( O
the O
coach O
) O
, O
who O
lost O
as O
a O
player O
of O
the O
Real B-ORG
in O
Paris B-LOC
the O
final O
of O
1981 O
against O
the O
Liverpol B-ORG
, O
and O
the O
rendition O
of O
Cuper B-PER
. O

The O
judge O
investigating O
the O
death O
of O
Mikel B-PER
Zabalza I-PER
in O
1985 O
cited O
to O
declare O
as O
accused O
in O
this O
case O
the O
former O
civil O
guards O
Enrique B-PER
Dorado I-PER
and O
Felipe B-PER
Bayo I-PER
, O
recently O
convicted O
for O
the O
murders O
of O
Lasa B-PER
and O
Zabala B-PER
, O
according O
to O
legal O
sources O
confirmed O
today O
. O

In O
an O
auto O
notified O
yesterday O
, O
the O
head O
of O
the O
Judge B-ORG
of I-ORG
Instruction I-ORG
No I-ORG
. O
1 O
of O
San B-LOC
Sebastián I-LOC
, O
Augusto B-PER
Maeso I-PER
, O
who O
is O
currently O
in O
the O
First B-ORG
Section I-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Provincial I-ORG
Court I-ORG
in O
commission O
of O
services O
, O
recalls O
that O
during O
the O
briefing O
of O
the O
summary O
the O
names O
of O
Dorado B-PER
and O
Bayo B-PER
, O
who O
have O
been O
called O
to O
declare O
next O
September O
19 O
, O
were O
cited O
by O
various O
witnesses O
and O
appeared O
in O
press O
reports O
. O

Maeso B-PER
considers O
that O
some O
of O
these O
testimonies O
" O
question O
" O
the O
authenticity O
of O
the O
official O
version O
, O
which O
argues O
that O
Zabalza B-PER
died O
drowned O
falling O
into O
the O
Bidasoa B-LOC
River I-LOC
when O
he O
tried O
to O
escape O
from O
the O
civil B-ORG
guard I-ORG
officers O
he O
was O
guiding O
in O
the O
search O
for O
an O
ETA B-ORG
" O
zulo O
" O
. O

In O
the O
judge O
's O
opinion O
, O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
young O
man O
was O
subjected O
to O
anti O
- O
terrorist O
legislation O
after O
his O
detention O
for O
his O
alleged O
relationship O
with O
ETA B-ORG
and O
that O
he O
had O
disclosed O
the O
location O
of O
a O
" O
zulo O
" O
are O
data O
that O
" O
advise O
security O
measures O
to O
avoid O
fleeing O
in O
the O
supposed O
place O
where O
he O
would O
find O
" O
this O
hideout O
, O
while O
Zabalza B-PER
was O
driven O
by O
" O
only O
three O
members O
of O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Guard I-ORG
" O
. O

One O
of O
the O
testimonies O
supporting O
the O
car O
is O
a O
statement O
by O
Dorado B-PER
himself O
, O
who O
admitted O
to O
two O
journalists O
of O
El B-ORG
Mundo I-ORG
that O
Zabalza B-PER
died O
in O
the O
quarter O
of O
Intxaurrondo B-LOC
when O
Bayo B-PER
practised O
torture O
known O
as O
" O
the O
bath O
" O
. O

Russia B-LOC
’s O
gold O
and O
currency O
reserves O
rose O
by O
$ O
600 O
million O
and O
by O
May O
19 O
were O
equivalent O
to O
$ O
18.300 O
million O
, O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
reported O
today O
. O

According O
to O
the O
report O
, O
by O
12 O
May O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
's O
gold O
and O
currency O
reserves O
were O
$ O
17.700 O
million O
. O

The O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
and O
the O
Ministry B-ORG
of I-ORG
Finance I-ORG
's O
currency O
assets O
are O
calculated O
in O
US O
dollars O
and O
their O
value O
depends O
on O
the O
official O
exchange O
rate O
of O
ruble O
- O
dollar O
established O
by O
the O
Central B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
at O
the O
time O
of O
their O
accounting O
. O

Gold O
reserves O
are O
valued O
at O
US$ O
300 O
for O
each O
once O
of O
gold O
. O

The O
Socialist O
groups O
of O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
and O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
have O
agreed O
to O
create O
a O
political O
committee O
of O
a O
parliamentary O
nature O
whose O
role O
will O
be O
to O
draw O
up O
joint O
proposals O
to O
be O
presented O
in O
their O
respective O
municipalities B-ORG
, O
the O
Extremadura B-ORG
Board I-ORG
and O
the O
central O
government B-ORG
. O

This O
was O
announced O
by O
the O
secretaries O
- O
general O
in O
the O
respective O
localities O
, O
Francisco B-PER
García I-PER
Ramos I-PER
, O
on O
the O
part O
of O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
, O
and O
Juan B-PER
Manzano I-PER
, O
on O
the O
part O
of O
Dombenitense O
, O
at O
a O
press O
conference O
in O
which O
also O
the O
spokesman O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
in O
the O
Town O
Hall O
of B-ORG
Don I-ORG
Benito I-ORG
, O
Julio B-PER
Carmona I-PER
, O
and O
the O
number O
two O
of O
the O
socialists O
of O
Villanueva O
, O
Raúl B-PER
Borrasca I-PER
. O

The O
above O
- O
mentioned O
committee O
will O
be O
composed O
of O
four O
representatives O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
of O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
and O
four O
others O
of O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
and O
will O
also O
be O
responsible O
for O
raising O
its O
proposals O
to O
the O
provincial O
, O
regional O
and O
even O
national O
bodies O
of O
the O
PSOE B-ORG
itself O
. O

The O
combined O
strength O
of O
the O
Socialists O
in O
both O
municipalities O
is O
17 O
councillors O
, O
9 O
in O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
and O
8 O
in O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
. O

The O
number O
of O
members O
between O
the O
two O
populations O
is O
more O
than O
500 O
. O

The O
idea O
of O
creating O
this O
alliance O
came O
about O
three O
weeks O
ago O
through O
a O
telephone O
call O
made O
by O
the O
Socialist O
spokesman O
of O
Don B-LOC
Benito I-LOC
, O
Julio B-PER
Carmona I-PER
, O
to O
the O
Socialist O
spokesman O
of O
Villanueva B-LOC
de I-LOC
la I-LOC
Serena I-LOC
, O
Francisco B-PER
García I-PER
Ramos I-PER
, O
according O
to O
this O
latter O
leader O
. O

The O
next O
step O
was O
to O
call O
both O
local O
executives O
, O
who O
held O
several O
meetings O
before O
publicly O
disseminating O
the O
understanding O
. O

The O
Minister O
of O
Justice B-MISC
, O
Angel B-PER
Acebes I-PER
, O
today O
stressed O
that O
Judge O
Manuel B-PER
García I-PER
Castellón I-PER
, O
who O
will O
be O
the O
Spanish O
liaison O
magistrate O
in O
France B-LOC
, O
will O
not O
exercise O
any O
kind O
of O
jurisdictional O
function O
but O
of O
cooperation O
and O
collaboration O
. O

In O
statements O
to O
the O
Cope B-ORG
Canal O
collected O
by O
EFE B-ORG
, O
Acebes B-PER
explained O
that O
the O
work O
of O
the O
liaison O
magistrate O
consists O
of O
performing O
a O
number O
of O
functions O
of O
cooperation O
between O
states B-ORG
in O
a O
particular O
matter O
, O
in O
this O
case O
with O
France B-ORG
in O
the O
fight O
against O
terrorism O
. O

The O
liaison O
magistrates O
try O
to O
promote O
, O
to O
speed O
up O
procedures O
, O
contacts O
between O
the O
competent O
services O
when O
delays O
occur O
and O
know O
the O
laws O
of O
both O
countries O
, O
said O
Acebes B-PER
, O
who O
said O
that O
are O
" O
typical O
work O
of O
collaboration O
and O
cooperation O
" O
. O

He O
clarified O
that O
García B-PER
Castellón I-PER
would O
not O
exercise O
any O
jurisdictional O
function O
and O
recalled O
that O
the O
order O
governing O
these O
liaison O
magistrates O
allows O
him O
not O
to O
be O
a O
judge O
, O
as O
a O
prosecutor O
could O
have O
been O
appointed O
. O

Even O
, O
he O
added O
, O
in O
other O
countries O
it O
is O
not O
even O
necessary O
for O
this O
function O
to O
be O
developed O
by O
a O
magistrate O
or O
a O
prosecutor O
, O
but O
it O
is O
enough O
to O
be O
a O
specialist O
in O
law B-MISC
. O

" O
It O
does O
not O
resolve O
any O
matter O
or O
exercise O
any O
other O
jurisdiction O
of O
judges O
of O
one O
country O
or O
another O
" O
, O
he O
said O
. O

This O
figure O
is O
regulated O
by O
a O
law O
that O
was O
adopted O
in O
1998 O
and O
which O
establishes O
its O
legal O
regime O
and O
its O
election O
system O
, O
said O
the O
Minister O
of O
Justice B-MISC
, O
who O
added O
that O
his O
appointment O
is O
a O
competence O
of O
the O
government B-ORG
and O
that O
he O
had O
previously O
spoken O
to O
the O
General B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Judiciary O
. O

Iraqi O
President O
Saddam B-MISC
Hussein I-MISC
is O
rebuilding O
his O
weapons O
of O
mass O
destruction O
and O
is O
once O
again O
a O
threat O
to O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
world O
, O
said O
British O
Deputy O
Foreign B-ORG
Minister O
Peter B-PER
Hain I-PER
on O
Thursday O
. O

In O
statements O
to O
the O
BBC B-ORG
, O
Hain B-PER
said O
that O
Hussein B-PER
must O
allow O
UN B-ORG
weapons O
inspectors O
to O
enter O
Iraqi O
territory O
to O
destroy O
chemical O
and O
biological O
weapons O
. O

Hain B-PER
's O
warnings O
came O
after O
former O
UN B-ORG
weapons O
inspector O
Richard B-PER
Butler I-PER
voiced O
concerns O
about O
the O
military O
capability O
of O
the O
Baghdad B-LOC
regime O
. O

" O
This O
is O
very O
worrying O
and O
that O
is O
why O
we O
have O
taken O
a O
very O
strong O
position O
saying O
that O
UN B-ORG
arms O
inspections O
should O
be O
allowed O
" O
, O
added O
the O
deputy O
minister O
. O

The O
final O
of O
the O
Champions B-MISC
League I-MISC
that O
ended O
with O
a O
victory O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
against O
Valencia B-ORG
by O
three O
goals O
to O
zero O
and O
the O
celebration O
of O
this O
triumph O
in O
Madrid B-LOC
and O
the O
French O
city O
of O
Paris B-LOC
, O
focuses O
the O
attention O
of O
the O
sports O
newspapers O
. O

" O
More B-MISC
chulo I-MISC
que I-MISC
un I-MISC
ocho I-MISC
" O
titles O
the O
daily O
" O
Marca B-ORG
" O
to O
focus O
on O
the O
triumph O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
that O
wins O
the O
Eighth B-MISC
European I-MISC
Cup I-MISC
and O
becomes O
the O
team O
that O
more O
triumphs O
have O
been O
carried O
out O
in O
this O
competition O
. O

The O
final O
of O
the O
Copa B-MISC
del I-MISC
Rey I-MISC
contested O
by O
Espanyol B-ORG
and O
Atlético B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
the O
doubt O
whether O
the O
new O
coach O
of O
Atlético B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
, O
Fernando B-PER
Zambrano I-PER
, O
will O
be O
able O
to O
count O
on O
the O
presence O
of O
Solari B-PER
or O
Kiko B-PER
, O
and O
Russian O
tennis O
player O
Anna B-PER
Kournikova I-PER
who O
is O
preparing O
for O
the O
Roland B-MISC
Garros I-MISC
tournament O
in O
Mallorca B-LOC
, O
set O
the O
heavy O
information O
of O
the O
rotating O
. O

Journal O
" O
As B-ORG
" O
focuses O
on O
the O
victory O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
that O
achieves O
the O
eighth O
European B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
after O
defeating O
Valencia B-ORG
by O
three O
goals O
to O
zero O
in O
the O
final O
that O
was O
held O
in O
Paris B-LOC
. O

The O
statements O
by O
the O
president O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
, O
Lorenzo B-PER
Sanz I-PER
, O
and O
the O
team O
technician O
, O
Vicente B-PER
Del I-PER
Bosque I-PER
, O
after O
the O
match O
that O
was O
held O
in O
Paris B-LOC
, O
the O
ACB B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
faces O
Real B-ORG
Madrid O
and O
Barcelona B-ORG
, O
the O
Italian O
club O
Juventus B-ORG
that O
" O
offers O
7.500 O
million O
by O
Anelka B-PER
" O
and O
the O
Copa B-MISC
del I-MISC
Rey I-MISC
final O
match O
that O
faces O
Atlético B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
with O
Espanyol B-ORG
complete O
the O
sports O
news O
of O
the O
newspaper O
. O

Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
's O
triumph O
over O
Valencia B-ORG
by O
three O
goals O
to O
zero O
in O
the O
Champions B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
held O
in O
Paris B-LOC
draws O
the O
attention O
of O
the O
newspapers O
publishing O
in O
Barcelona B-LOC
. O

" O
Real O
Madrid O
overcame O
. O
a B-MISC
Valencia I-MISC
to I-MISC
which I-MISC
the I-MISC
challenge I-MISC
came I-MISC
big I-MISC
" O
titled O
" O
World B-ORG
Deportivo I-ORG
" O
to O
focus O
on O
the O
little O
resistance O
that O
Valencia B-ORG
showed O
in O
the O
final O
of O
the O
European B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
that O
was O
held O
in O
Paris B-LOC
and O
in O
which O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
came O
victorious O
. O

The O
latest O
electoral O
news O
of O
the O
Barcelona O
club O
that O
focus O
on O
a O
" O
consensus O
to O
follow O
Guardiola B-PER
, O
Figo B-PER
and O
Rivaldo B-PER
" O
, O
the O
manager O
of O
Celta B-ORG
, O
Víctor B-PER
Fernández I-PER
, O
who O
will O
be O
renewed O
for O
the O
next O
season O
and O
the O
ACB B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
faces O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
Barca B-ORG
complete O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
sporting O
news O
of O
the O
rotating O
. O

The O
daily O
" O
Sport B-ORG
" O
focuses O
on O
the O
Champions B-MISC
League I-MISC
final O
that O
competed O
yesterday O
Real B-ORG
Madrid O
and O
Valencia B-ORG
and O
on O
the O
two O
reactions O
of O
the O
teams O
: O
on O
the O
one O
hand O
, O
euphoria O
and O
tears O
for O
the O
losers O
on O
the O
other O
. O

The O
final O
of O
the O
Copa B-MISC
del I-MISC
Rey I-MISC
contested O
by O
Atlético B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
and O
Espanyol B-ORG
, O
the O
new O
signing O
of O
Real B-ORG
Madrid I-ORG
, O
Albert B-PER
Celades I-PER
, O
the O
fans O
of O
Barcelona B-ORG
who O
demand O
that O
the O
contract O
be O
improved O
to O
player O
Luis B-PER
Figo I-PER
so O
that O
he O
does O
not O
leave O
and O
the O
final O
of O
the O
ACB B-MISC
League I-MISC
that O
faces O
Real B-ORG
Madrid O
and O
Barca B-ORG
focuses O
the O
attention O
of O
this O
newspaper O
. O

The O
euro O
fell O
today O
in O
Tokyo B-LOC
against O
the O
Japanese O
yen O
and O
was O
quoted O
at O
97.22 O
yen O
in O
the O
afternoon O
, O
compared O
to O
96.25 O
at O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
day O
. O

With O
the O
US O
dollar O
the O
euro O
remained O
at O
0.901 O
units O
, O
below O
the O
0.903 O
of O
the O
opening O
. O

The O
euro O
fell O
today O
in O
Tokyo B-LOC
against O
the O
Japanese O
yen O
and O
was O
quoted O
at O
97.22 O
yen O
in O
the O
afternoon O
, O
compared O
to O
96.25 O
at O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
day O
. O

With O
the O
US O
dollar O
the O
euro O
remained O
at O
0.901 O
units O
, O
below O
the O
0.903 O
of O
the O
opening O
. O

A O
man O
armed O
with O
a O
grenade O
jumped O
today O
in O
parachutes O
over O
a O
neighbourhood O
of O
Manila B-LOC
to O
escape O
from O
an O
airplane O
that O
had O
tried O
to O
kidnap O
Philippine B-ORG
Airlines I-ORG
( O
PAL B-ORG
) O
, O
reported O
the O
local O
broadcaster O
DZMM B-ORG
. O

The O
hijacker O
, O
according O
to O
that O
version O
, O
did O
not O
cause O
damage O
to O
the O
crew O
of O
the O
plane O
and O
jumped O
over O
the O
capital O
district O
of O
Antipolo B-LOC
, O
and O
shortly O
after O
the O
plane O
landed O
without O
problems O
at O
the O
same O
airport O
in O
Manila B-LOC
. O

The O
plane O
, O
an O
Airbus B-MISC
330 O
with O
280 O
passengers O
, O
left O
Davao B-LOC
Airport O
, O
in O
Mindanao B-LOC
, O
at O
14.00 O
local O
time O
( O
06.00 O
GMT O
) O
and O
was O
scheduled O
to O
land O
in O
Manila B-LOC
hour O
. O
half O
later O
. O

The O
director O
of O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Aviation I-ORG
Office I-ORG
, O
Antonio B-PER
Gana I-PER
, O
said O
that O
the O
hijacker O
asked O
the O
pilot O
to O
fly O
to O
Davao B-LOC
, O
about O
1,000 O
km O
south O
of O
Manila B-LOC
, O
but O
the O
lack O
of O
fuel O
forced O
to O
continue O
the O
route O
to O
Manila B-LOC
, O
where O
his O
arrival O
is O
expected O
. O

In O
a O
statement O
to O
the O
state O
broadcaster O
DZRB B-ORG
, O
Ricardo B-PER
Puno I-PER
, O
spokesman O
for O
the O
Filipino O
president O
, O
Joseph B-PER
Estrada I-PER
, O
said O
that O
the O
kidnapper O
was O
part O
of O
the O
passport O
and O
carried O
a O
hand O
grenade O
and O
a O
parachute O
. O

According O
to O
Puno B-PER
, O
the O
air O
pirate O
demanded O
that O
he O
be O
allowed O
to O
jump O
in O
parachutes O
from O
the O
plane O
, O
but O
due O
to O
flight O
altitude O
it O
was O
not O
possible O
to O
open O
the O
doors O
of O
the O
aircraft O
, O
so O
the O
" O
Airbus B-MISC
" O
travelled O
to O
Manila B-LOC
. O

However O
, O
after O
landing O
the O
aircraft O
at O
about O
1,800 O
meters O
, O
the O
air O
pirate O
insisted O
on O
his O
purpose O
and O
managed O
to O
jump O
into O
parachutes O
. O

The O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
has O
adapted O
its O
concept O
of O
security O
to O
the O
new O
reality O
created O
after O
the O
evacuation O
of O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
which O
consists O
in O
defending O
its O
border O
within O
its O
own O
soil O
instead O
of O
fighting O
the O
Hezbollah B-ORG
integral O
group O
on O
Lebanese O
territory O
, O
its O
commander O
explained O
today O
. O

The O
Chief O
of O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
, O
General O
Shaul B-PER
Mofaz I-PER
, O
said O
this O
included O
the O
order O
to O
open O
fire O
, O
although O
he O
ruled O
that O
" O
the O
soldiers O
must O
be O
very O
careful O
not O
to O
make O
mistakes O
that O
lead O
to O
an O
escalation O
of O
violence O
" O
. O

That O
means O
that O
Israeli O
soldiers O
will O
not O
shoot O
as O
soon O
as O
they O
see O
Hezbollah B-ORG
guerrillas O
- O
as O
they O
have O
done O
so O
far O
in O
the O
southern O
Lebanon O
- O
and O
they O
will O
not O
interfere O
with O
Syrian O
troops O
, O
whose O
country O
actually O
controls O
Lebanon B-LOC
. O

Mofaz B-PER
said O
that O
" O
we O
must O
be O
very O
alert O
" O
and O
added O
that O
in O
the O
coming O
days O
representatives O
of O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
will O
examine O
the O
exact O
lines O
of O
the O
international O
border O
with O
Lebanon B-LOC
and O
, O
if O
necessary O
, O
will O
adjust O
their O
deployment O
. O

Meanwhile O
, O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
was O
still O
deploying O
today O
- O
the O
day O
after O
the O
withdrawal O
- O
in O
the O
north O
of O
their O
country O
, O
bordering O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
. O

According O
to O
Mofaz B-PER
, O
" O
the O
Israeli O
army B-ORG
left O
Lebanon B-LOC
( O
at O
the O
dawn O
of O
yesterday O
Wednesday O
) O
appropriately O
and O
without O
casualties O
in O
its O
ranks O
, O
although O
it O
was O
a O
fired O
withdrawal O
" O
of O
the O
Lebanese O
pro O
- O
Iranian O
Hezbollah B-ORG
( O
God B-ORG
's I-ORG
Party I-ORG
) O
group O
, O
which O
was O
done O
with O
control O
of O
the O
abandoned O
area O
in O
the O
south O
of O
the O
neighbouring O
Arab O
country O
. O

The O
General O
pointed O
out O
that O
at O
least O
twelve O
guerrillas O
from O
the O
Chinese O
Hezbollah B-ORG
group O
died O
in O
the O
fighting O
, O
which O
was O
also O
done O
with O
weapons O
left O
on O
the O
ground O
by O
Israeli O
soldiers O
and O
militias O
of O
the O
Southern B-ORG
Lebanon I-ORG
Army I-ORG
( O
ESL B-ORG
) O
, O
an O
ally O
of O
Israel B-ORG
. O

The O
Chief O
Commander O
of O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
stressed O
that O
it O
was O
important O
for O
his O
troops O
to O
leave O
in O
a O
rapid O
operation O
, O
in O
the O
dark O
and O
before O
it O
was O
cleared O
, O
and O
that O
there O
was O
no O
justification O
for O
soldiers O
to O
put O
their O
lives O
at O
risk O
because O
of O
the O
remaining O
weapons O
on O
the O
ground O
. O

Finally O
, O
Mofaz B-PER
warned O
that O
" O
I O
do O
not O
recommend O
anyone O
, O
including O
the O
Palestinians O
, O
to O
draw O
the O
wrong O
conclusions O
about O
the O
ability O
of O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
to O
respond O
" O
. O

In O
this O
regard O
, O
the O
well O
- O
known O
Palestinian O
journalist O
Daud B-PER
Kutab I-PER
asks O
, O
in O
a O
column O
published O
today O
by O
the O
Israeli O
daily O
Jerusalem B-ORG
Post I-ORG
: O
" O
How O
can O
we O
convince O
people O
that O
non O
- O
violent O
resistance O
works O
, O
when O
we O
see O
that O
armed O
resistance O
( O
of O
Hezbollah B-ORG
) O
results O
while O
negotiations O
fail O
? O

“ O
( O
a O
) O
To O
take O
all O
necessary O
measures O
to O
ensure O
that O
all O
persons O
with O
disabilities O
have O
access O
to O
adequate O
health O
care O
, O
including O
access O
to O
safe O
drinking O
water O
and O
sanitation O
, O
and O
to O
ensure O
that O
all O
persons O
with O
disabilities O
have O
access O
to O
adequate O
health O
care O
; O

As O
for O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
Israel B-ORG
recognizes O
its O
sovereignty O
over O
all O
of O
its O
territory O
, O
but O
demands O
that O
Beirut B-ORG
guarantee O
a O
secure O
border O
and O
, O
if O
this O
is O
not O
achieved O
, O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
is O
prepared O
for O
a O
series O
of O
responses O
and O
reprisals O
. O

This O
was O
noted O
in O
the O
last O
few O
days O
by O
Israeli O
Prime O
Minister O
Ehud B-PER
Barak I-PER
, O
and O
also O
by O
Mofaz B-PER
himself O
, O
Foreign B-ORG
Minister O
David B-PER
Levy I-PER
, O
and O
other O
government O
officials O
, O
who O
held O
the O
Lebanese O
and O
Syrian O
governments B-ORG
responsible O
for O
maintaining O
calm O
at O
the O
border O
. O

In O
other O
words O
, O
if O
you O
fire O
from O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
against O
northern O
Israel B-LOC
, O
the O
Israeli O
army B-ORG
will O
immediately O
launch O
a O
crackdown O
on O
Lebanese O
, O
Syrian O
and O
even O
Iranian O
interests O
throughout O
that O
neighbouring O
Arab O
country O
. O

To O
defend O
the O
borders O
, O
the O
Israeli O
army B-ORG
decided O
to O
set O
up O
fortified O
positions O
in O
its O
own O
villages O
in O
the O
north O
of O
its O
territory O
, O
where O
its O
more O
than O
250,000 O
inhabitants O
have O
often O
been O
the O
target O
of O
attacks O
from O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
in O
particular O
from O
" O
Katiusha B-MISC
" O
rockets O
fired O
by O
Hezbollah B-ORG
. O

Military O
commentators O
today O
point O
out O
that O
the O
Israeli O
Army B-ORG
will O
have O
more O
troops O
in O
the O
south O
, O
ready O
to O
respond O
with O
new O
techniques O
, O
as O
well O
as O
with O
great O
speed O
and O
mobility O
, O
while O
maintaining O
a O
" O
low O
profile O
" O
at O
the O
border O
itself O
. O

In O
the O
face O
of O
this O
new O
situation O
, O
the O
military O
commentator O
of O
the O
prestigious O
Israeli O
daily O
Haaretz B-ORG
, O
Zeev B-PER
Schiff I-PER
, O
concludes O
that O
" O
the O
withdrawal O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
does O
not O
mean O
the O
end O
of O
the O
conflict O
" O
. O

Two O
young O
men O
, O
both O
natural O
Moroccans B-LOC
, O
face O
a O
six O
- O
year O
prison O
sentence O
for O
clamping O
a O
knife O
in O
the O
head O
of O
another O
young O
man O
, O
also O
Moroccan O
, O
to O
whom O
they O
stole O
1,500 O
pesetas O
when O
he O
was O
on O
a O
deserted O
beach O
. O

According O
to O
judicial O
sources O
, O
the O
Criminal B-ORG
Judge I-ORG
No I-ORG
. O
2 O
of O
Ceuta B-LOC
has O
today O
judged O
R. B-PER
E. I-PER
Ch I-PER
. O
and O
M. B-PER
M. I-PER
, O
for O
whom O
the O
prosecutor O
demands O
six O
years O
' O
imprisonment O
, O
two O
for O
injuries O
and O
four O
for O
theft O
. O

The O
facts O
tried O
occurred O
on O
2 O
January O
when O
allegedly O
both O
young O
men O
attacked O
a O
third O
in O
the O
vicinity O
of O
the O
beach B-LOC
of I-LOC
Ribera I-LOC
, O
and O
stole O
1,500 O
pesetas O
and O
two O
sleeping O
bags O
from O
him O
after O
stabbing O
him O
in O
the O
head O
and O
causing O
him O
to O
be O
hospitalized O
. O

The O
defence O
has O
requested O
the O
acquittal O
of O
the O
two O
young O
people O
on O
the O
grounds O
that O
there O
is O
insufficient O
evidence O
to O
determine O
the O
guilt O
of O
their O
defendants O
, O
who O
were O
recognised O
by O
the O
victim O
. O

The O
Malaysian O
band O
Digital B-ORG
21 I-ORG
wants O
to O
show O
in O
their O
debut O
album O
that O
" O
the O
digital O
and O
the O
analog O
are O
not O
tied O
" O
, O
according O
to O
explained O
today O
to O
Efe B-ORG
its O
leader O
, O
singer O
, O
composer O
and O
guitarist O
, O
Miguel B-PER
López I-PER
, O
who O
assures O
that O
his O
music O
" O
offers O
the O
contemporary O
of O
the O
machines O
and O
the O
strength O
of O
guitar O
and O
drum O
" O
. O

Paco B-PER
( O
guitar O
) O
, O
Salva B-PER
( O
battery O
) O
and O
Alberto B-PER
( O
bass O
) O
form O
, O
together O
with O
Miguel B-PER
, O
Digital B-ORG
21 I-ORG
, O
a O
band O
that O
" O
at O
the O
door O
of O
the O
21st O
century O
" O
wants O
to O
demonstrate O
that O
" O
despite O
the O
importance O
that O
computers O
and O
loops O
have O
when O
composing O
, O
traditional O
instruments O
still O
maintain O
the O
freshness O
of O
the O
music O
, O
and O
although O
sometimes O
voices O
distort O
, O
melodies O
and O
songs O
are O
the O
most O
important O
" O
. O

Groups O
such O
as O
" O
Radiohead B-ORG
" O
, O
" O
Portishead B-ORG
" O
, O
" O
Smashing B-ORG
Punpkins I-ORG
" O
and O
" O
Chemikal B-ORG
Brothers I-ORG
" O
, O
and O
the O
musician O
Beck B-PER
, O
are O
some O
of O
the O
influences O
of O
this O
Malagasy O
group O
, O
which O
although O
does O
not O
refuse O
to O
sing O
in O
Spanish O
, O
is O
of O
those O
recording O
in O
English O
. O

" O
It O
's O
not O
for O
anything O
in O
particular O
, O
we O
have O
songs O
in O
Spanish O
, O
we O
play O
live O
, O
but O
we O
think O
that O
for O
the O
disc O
it O
was O
better O
to O
do O
everything O
in O
one O
language O
" O
. O

Monday O
Friday O
the O
Madrid O
Caracol B-LOC
hall I-LOC
has O
been O
chosen O
for O
the O
official O
presentation O
of O
the O
album O
" O
Digital B-MISC
21 I-MISC
" O
, O
later O
the O
Malagasy O
formation O
travelled O
to O
Santiago B-LOC
de I-LOC
Compostela I-LOC
to O
participate O
on O
the O
13th O
of O
July O
in O
the O
Festival B-MISC
Celtirock I-MISC
and O
on O
the O
3rd O
of O
August O
will O
be O
part O
of O
the O
cartel O
" O
Benicassim B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
" O
. O

Digital B-ORG
21 I-ORG
was O
born O
not O
in O
the O
spirit O
of O
professionalisation O
, O
but O
to O
put O
on O
the O
table O
and O
stage O
their O
music O
, O
but O
after O
the O
success O
that O
they O
have O
had O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
where O
they O
have O
just O
offered O
their O
second O
tour O
of O
four O
performances O
, O
they O
decided O
why O
they O
are O
not O
going O
to O
devote O
themselves O
to O
this O
" O
. O

The O
mobile O
phone O
company O
Amena B-ORG
will O
continue O
its O
criminal O
action O
against O
Airtel B-ORG
for O
an O
alleged O
scam O
, O
which O
motivated O
the O
statement O
in O
a O
Seville B-LOC
court O
, O
as O
charged O
, O
of O
four O
Andalusian O
directors O
of O
Airtel B-ORG
, O
said O
Efe B-ORG
a O
spokesman O
for O
Amena B-ORG
. O

The O
alleged O
offences O
, O
according O
to O
Amena B-ORG
's O
complaint O
to O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Guard O
, O
took O
place O
at O
the O
end O
of O
last O
year O
, O
when O
Airtel B-ORG
purchased O
through O
intermediaries O
about O
60,000 O
mobile O
phones O
that O
Amena B-ORG
had O
put O
for O
sale O
at O
a O
lower O
price O
than O
the O
market O
to O
catch O
customers O
. O

The O
lines O
rented O
by O
Amena B-ORG
to O
Airtel B-ORG
in O
Andalusia B-LOC
would O
also O
have O
been O
manipulated O
in O
order O
to O
charge O
for O
non O
- O
existent O
use O
, O
collapse O
them O
and O
cause O
the O
loss O
of O
users O
. O

According O
to O
the O
operator O
, O
her O
complaint O
was O
aimed O
at O
clarifying O
facts O
constituting O
a O
criminally O
defined O
conduct O
of O
stealing O
and O
damages O
. O

Airtel B-ORG
has O
compensated O
Amena B-ORG
, O
according O
to O
this O
second O
operator O
, O
for O
civil O
liability O
arising O
from O
alleged O
crimes O
. O

Therefore O
, O
Amena B-ORG
has O
renounced O
the O
action O
of O
subsidiary O
civil O
liability O
that O
could O
arise O
from O
the O
criminal O
proceedings O
, O
although O
it O
trusts O
" O
fully O
" O
that O
the O
investigations O
developed O
by O
judges O
and O
courts O
of O
criminal O
law O
, O
which O
are O
currently O
under O
summary O
secrecy O
, O
clarify O
" O
fully O
" O
the O
facts O
alleged O
, O
stated O
in O
a O
statement O
. O

Fiji O
’s O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Leaders I-ORG
today O
allowed O
some O
members O
of O
the O
conspiracy O
- O
mongering O
businessman O
George B-PER
Speight I-PER
to O
participate O
in O
the O
transitional O
government O
that O
must O
form O
the O
country O
’s O
president O
, O
Kamisese B-PER
Mara I-PER
. O

This O
is O
one O
of O
the O
various O
resolutions O
adopted O
today O
by O
the O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Heads I-ORG
, O
in O
addition O
to O
calling O
for O
the O
Constitution B-MISC
to O
be O
abolished O
, O
ending O
the O
democratically O
elected O
government O
in O
last O
year O
's O
elections O
and O
recommending O
to O
the O
Head O
of O
State B-ORG
that O
he O
forgive O
all O
the O
golpistas O
. O

A O
delegation O
from O
the O
Great B-ORG
Council I-ORG
addressed O
Parliament B-ORG
after O
the O
meeting O
to O
communicate O
its O
decisions O
to O
Speight B-PER
and O
ask O
him O
to O
release O
all O
the O
hostages O
he O
has O
held O
since O
last O
Friday O
, O
including O
Prime O
Minister O
Mahendra B-PER
Chaudhry I-PER
. O

The O
three O
days O
of O
deliberations O
of O
the O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
of I-ORG
Chiefs I-ORG
have O
ended O
with O
an O
unexpected O
culprit O
, O
not O
Speight B-PER
but O
Chaudhry B-PER
, O
who O
did O
not O
have O
" O
the O
humility O
and O
political O
courage O
to O
listen O
to O
the O
growing O
popular O
dissatisfaction O
" O
, O
according O
to O
the O
resolution O
of O
the O
42 O
heads O
of O
the O
various O
ethnic O
communities O
of O
the O
country O
. O

The O
decision O
to O
amend O
the O
current O
Constitution B-MISC
, O
adopted O
in O
1997 O
, O
was O
due O
, O
according O
to O
the O
President O
of O
the O
Grand B-ORG
Council I-ORG
, O
Sitiveni B-PER
Rabuka I-PER
, O
that O
he O
has O
failed O
in O
his O
duty O
. O

" O
We O
must O
change O
the O
document O
that O
has O
brought O
us O
to O
the O
current O
situation O
. O

I O
thought O
it O
was O
a O
very O
good O
Constitution B-MISC
and O
it O
brought O
the O
unity O
of O
all O
communities O
, O
but O
the O
parties O
rejected O
it O
, O
" O
Rabuka B-PER
explained O
to O
the O
press O
in O
Suva B-LOC
. O

The O
1997 O
Magna B-MISC
Carta I-MISC
amended O
the O
1987 O
Charter O
that O
prevented O
the O
Hindu O
community O
from O
taking O
political O
office O
, O
allowing O
Chaudhry B-PER
last O
May O
to O
become O
the O
first O
member O
of O
that O
ethnic O
group O
to O
become O
Prime O
Minister O
in O
Fiyi B-LOC
's O
history O
. O

The O
decisions O
taken O
by O
the O
Fiyi B-ORG
Grand I-ORG
Council I-ORG
defy O
all O
the O
recommendations O
made O
by O
the O
UN B-ORG
and O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORG
, O
as O
well O
as O
by O
other O
countries O
, O
regarding O
respect O
for O
the O
constitutionality O
and O
the O
government O
of O
Chaudhry B-PER
, O
who O
was O
democratically O
elected O
. O

The O
resolutions O
of O
the O
great O
leaders O
were O
announced O
shortly O
after O
the O
Commonwealth B-ORG
president O
, O
the O
New O
Zealander O
Don B-PER
McKinnon I-PER
, O
left O
Suva B-LOC
with O
a O
warning O
to O
Fiyi B-ORG
not O
to O
abandon O
the O
path O
of O
democracy O
. O

Syria B-ORG
considers O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
completed O
on O
Wednesday O
, O
" O
indicates O
that O
Israel B-ORG
was O
politically O
and O
militarily O
defeated O
" O
, O
reports O
the O
Syrian O
official O
press O
today O
. O

" O
The O
day O
of O
liberation O
will O
be O
unforgettable O
for O
the O
people O
and O
the O
resistance O
of O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
as O
well O
as O
for O
all O
freedom O
fighters O
around O
the O
world O
" O
, O
says O
the O
daily O
" O
Al B-ORG
Zaura I-ORG
" O
, O
an O
organ O
of O
the O
Syrian B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
of I-ORG
Defence I-ORG
. O

Israel B-ORG
completed O
yesterday O
its O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
1,000 O
- O
square O
- O
kilometer O
fence O
it O
had O
occupied O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
since O
1978 O
. O

For O
the O
rotating O
Syrian O
, O
the O
Israeli O
reply O
, O
which O
ends O
with O
22 O
years O
of O
occupation O
, O
" O
meant O
not O
only O
a O
military O
defeat O
for O
Israel B-ORG
, O
but O
also O
a O
political O
one O
" O
. O

Another O
newspaper O
, O
" O
Tishrin B-ORG
" O
, O
an O
organ O
of O
the O
Syrian O
Government B-ORG
, O
considers O
that O
" O
the O
policy O
of O
oppression O
and O
terrorism O
practised O
by O
the O
Israelis O
in O
southern O
Lebanon B-LOC
did O
not O
guarantee O
their O
security O
or O
prevent O
the O
Lebanese O
from O
regaining O
their O
rights O
and O
liberating O
their O
land O
" O
. O

For O
its O
part O
, O
the O
daily O
" O
Baaz B-ORG
" O
, O
which O
reflects O
the O
views O
of O
the O
ruling O
party O
of O
the O
same O
name O
, O
considers O
that O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
southern O
Lebanon O
" O
does O
not O
mean O
isolation O
for O
Syria B-ORG
" O
in O
the O
peace O
negotiations O
with O
the O
Jewish O
State B-ORG
. O

Damascus B-ORG
, O
which O
has O
held O
some O
35,000 O
soldiers O
in O
Lebanon B-LOC
since O
1976 O
, O
and O
is O
considered O
the O
main O
arbiter O
of O
politics O
in O
this O
country O
, O
insisted O
on O
negotiating O
, O
together O
with O
Beirut B-ORG
, O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
southern O
Lebanon O
and O
the O
Syrian O
Golan B-LOC
, O
occupied O
since O
1967 O
. O

" O
Syria B-ORG
still O
opens O
the O
door O
to O
the O
resumption O
of O
negotiations O
" O
with O
Israel B-ORG
, O
add O
" O
Baaz B-ORG
" O
. O

Syrian O
- O
Israeli O
dialogue O
has O
been O
suspended O
since O
last O
January O
due O
to O
differences O
between O
the O
two O
sides O
over O
the O
Israeli O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
Golan B-LOC
Heights O
. O

Damascus B-ORG
insists O
that O
Israel B-ORG
commits O
to O
leaving O
the O
whole O
Golan B-LOC
before O
negotiating O
relations O
between O
the O
two O
neighbouring O
states B-ORG
, O
a O
condition O
that O
the O
Israelis O
reject O
. O

The O
Municipality B-ORG
of I-ORG
Porzuna I-ORG
( O
the O
Real B-LOC
City I-LOC
) O
has O
organized O
a O
day O
on O
education O
and O
family O
with O
the O
aim O
of O
addressing O
the O
progressive O
increase O
in O
failure O
and O
school O
drop O
- O
out O
. O

Yesterday O
's O
event O
featured O
the O
participation O
of O
parents O
and O
teachers O
of O
about O
1,000 O
students O
who O
are O
enrolled O
in O
the O
public O
school O
" O
Nuestra B-ORG
Señora I-ORG
del I-ORG
Rosario I-ORG
" O
and O
in O
the O
Institute B-ORG
of I-ORG
Secondary I-ORG
Education I-ORG
" O
Ribera B-ORG
del I-ORG
Bullaque I-ORG
" O
, O
according O
to O
EFE B-ORG
today O
, O
the O
mayor O
of O
Porzuna B-LOC
, O
Bienvenida B-PER
García I-PER
. O

The O
Director O
of O
Education B-MISC
of I-MISC
the I-MISC
Community I-MISC
Council I-MISC
, O
José B-PER
Fuentes I-PER
Pastrana I-PER
, O
was O
responsible O
for O
opening O
the O
day O
during O
which O
presentations O
, O
round O
tables O
and O
discussions O
were O
developed O
. O

Welcome B-PER
García I-PER
explained O
that O
the O
main O
aim O
he O
pursued O
was O
to O
analyse O
the O
progressive O
increase O
in O
school O
drop O
- O
outs O
occurring O
in O
the O
Institute B-ORG
of I-ORG
Secondary I-ORG
Education O
, O
with O
the O
aim O
of O
finding O
solutions O
that O
minimise O
this O
situation O
. O
