Today O
meeting O
at O
the O
Centro O
S. O
Chiara O

Breast O
milk O
, O
Pedrotti B-PER
's O
message O

Only O
60 O
% O
- O
70 O
% O
of O
mothers O
in O
Trentino O
breastfeed O
their O
children O
after O
the O
age O
of O
4 O
months O
. O

Today O
at O
5.30 O
pm O
at O
the O
Centro O
culturale O
S. O
Chiara O
we O
will O
talk O
about O
breastfeeding O
in O
Trentino B-LOC
, O
about O
mothers O
with O
many O
doubts O
, O
about O
babies O
who O
are O
not O
always O
guaranteed O
the O
right O
to O
the O
best O
nutrition O
. O

Neonatologist O
Dino B-PER
Pedrotti I-PER
will O
talk O
about O
these O
problems O
. O

First O
of O
all O
, O
I O
would O
like O
to O
have O
a O
safe O
birth O
( O
and O
all O
over O
Trentino B-LOC
this O
" O
first O
right O
" O
has O
been O
assured O
) O
; O

But O
immediately O
afterwards O
I O
would O
like O
to O
have O
many O
cuddles O
and O
a O
lot O
of O
milk O
from O
my O
mother O
. O

This O
is O
the O
problem O
that O
we O
will O
be O
discussing O
with O
politicians O
, O
health O
workers O
and O
citizens O
; O

Councillor O
Andreolli B-PER
will O
be O
present O
. O

Where O
can O
mothers O
find O
help O
in O
case O
of O
difficulty O
? O

At O
four O
months O
60 O
- O
70 O
% O
of O
mothers O
in O
Trentino O
are O
breastfeeding O
. O

In O
Scandinavia B-LOC
, O
80 O
- O
90 O
% O
of O
mothers O
breastfeed O
. O

This O
is O
the O
goal O
that O
we O
propose O
and O
that O
we O
must O
reach O
. O

To O
help O
mothers O
in O
difficulty O
, O
the O
Friends B-ORG
of I-ORG
Neonatology I-ORG
in O
Trentino O
have O
published O
a O
booklet O
with O
many O
updated O
tips O
, O
" O
The O
ABC O
of O
Breastfeeding O
. O
distributed O
at O
the O
meeting O
. O

Athenaeum B-ORG

" O
Yes O
to O
the O
research O
on O
hydrogen O
, O
but O
there O
is O
also O
room O
for O
other O
sectors O
. O

University B-ORG
, O
Cipolletta B-PER
ready O
to O
remain O

He O
has O
given O
his O
availability O
and O
the O
conditions O
for O
his O
confirmation O
are O
all O
there O
. O

Esteemed O
by O
the O
president O
of O
the O
provincial B-ORG
council I-ORG
, O
Lorenzo B-PER
Dellai I-PER
, O
in O
excellent O
relations O
with O
the O
outgoing O
rector O
, O
Massimo B-PER
Egidi I-PER
, O
he O
seems O
to O
be O
appreciated O
by O
a O
good O
part O
of O
the O
local O
academic O
world O
. O

The O
developments O
will O
be O
known O
in O
the O
next O
few O
days O
, O
since O
the O
board O
of O
directors O
has O
reached O
its O
natural O
expiration O
and O
the O
candidatures O
for O
the O
new O
council B-ORG
will O
have O
to O
be O
formalized O
by O
Tuesday O
, O
to O
then O
arrive O
at O
the O
election O
of O
the O
teachers O
on O
the O
27th O
of O
the O
month O
. O

Sixty O
- O
two O
years O
old O
, O
a O
degree O
in O
Statistical O
Sciences O
from O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Rome I-ORG
, O
he O
was O
recently O
appointed O
to O
the O
presidency O
of O
the O
" O
Sole24Ore B-ORG
Group I-ORG
" O
. O

A O
commitment O
that O
- O
he O
says O
- O
will O
not O
prevent O
him O
from O
continuing O
to O
lead O
the O
meetings O
of O
the O
Board B-ORG
of I-ORG
Directors I-ORG
of O
the O
University O
of O
Trento O
. O

He O
will O
divide O
his O
time O
between O
Rome B-LOC
, O
Milan B-LOC
and O
Trento B-LOC
. O

" O
At O
the O
Italian O
level O
, O
cuts O
make O
life O
more O
difficult O
: O

In O
Trentino B-LOC
, O
thanks O
to O
autonomy O
, O
things O
are O
much O
better O
. O

In O
his O
opinion O
, O
we O
must O
focus O
more O
and O
more O
on O
scientific O
research O
: O

" O
The O
University B-ORG
has O
its O
competences O
. O

In O
Trentino B-LOC
, O
there O
is O
talk O
of O
creating O
a O
hydrogen O
and O
renewable O
energy O
district O
. O

Is O
this O
the O
sector O
in O
which O
to O
invest O
? O

This O
is O
true O
both O
for O
the O
academic O
world O
and O
for O
the O
entrepreneurial O
one O
. O

That O
of O
renewable O
energies O
is O
a O
fundamental O
road O
, O
but O
there O
is O
also O
room O
for O
other O
sectors O
. O

When O
we O
talk O
about O
the O
University O
of O
Trento O
, O
we O
talk O
about O
the O
fundamental O
role O
played O
by O
the O
Province B-LOC
's O
funding O
. O

Then O
there O
are O
the O
national O
research O
projects O
. O

But O
in O
the O
future O
, O
will O
economic O
support O
come O
from O
private O
enterprise O
? O

" O
I O
believe O
that O
private O
companies O
will O
never O
give O
too O
much O
to O
research O
. O

Yes O
, O
contributions O
can O
and O
must O
come O
also O
from O
companies O
, O
but O
their O
role O
is O
another O
: O

They O
can O
identify O
the O
most O
promising O
areas O
, O
make O
available O
collaborators O
and O
laboratories O
for O
practical O
applications O
. O

Collio B-PER
will O
do O
the O
100 O
, O
Longo B-PER
the O
800 O
and O
Martinez B-PER
the O
triple O
. O

Berlanda B-PER
and O
Niederstätter B-PER
are O
among O
the O
regional O
champions O
. O

The O
golds O
of O
Athens O
will O
illuminate O
the O
night O

The O
favorite O
is O
the O
U.S.A. O
Joshua B-PER
Johnson I-PER
( O
10 O
" O
11 O
, O
but O
in O
2002 O
even O
9 O
" O
95 O
) O
. O

In O
the O
B B-ORG
series I-ORG
, O
watch O
out O
for O
Torrieri B-PER
( O
10 O
" O
32 O
) O
and O
Kaba B-PER
Fantoni I-PER
( O
10 O
" O
28 O
) O
. O

even O
against O
the O
Italian O
record O
of O
Fiasconaro B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
43 O
" O
7 O
in O
' O
73 O
) O
. O

The O
Belgian O
Som B-PER
is O
frightening O
( O
1 O
' O
44 O
" O
37 O
) O
but O
not O
even O
the O
Kenyans O
Wachira B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
45 O
" O
13 O
) O
and O
Yego B-PER
( O
silver O
medal O
at O
the O
World O
Junior O
Championships O
) O
and O
the O
Sudanese O
Ismail B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
45 O
" O
17 O
) O
are O
joking O
. O

In O
the O
B B-ORG
series I-ORG
, O
the O
South O
Tyroleans O
Neunhauserer B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
46 O
" O
07 O
in O
2002 O
) O
and O
Rifesser B-PER
( O
18 O
years O
old O
, O
1 O
' O
51 O
" O
18 O
) O
. O

400 O
hurdles O
/ O
The O
Panamanian O
Kamani B-PER
is O
a O
spectacle O
( O
48 O
" O
23 O
, O
5th O
in O
Athens O
and O
1st O
at O
the O
Brussels B-LOC
meeting O
) O
. O

The O
South O
Tyrolean O
Crepaz B-PER
( O
50 O
" O
68 O
) O
will O
try O
. O

5000 O
MARCH O
/ O
Catwalk O
for O
Ivano B-PER
Brugnetti I-PER
, O
Athens O
gold O
medal O
in O
the O
" O
20 O
" O
, O
who O
has O
a O
personal O
best O
of O
19 O
' O
43 O
" O
24 O
( O
2003 O
) O
. O

He O
will O
be O
crowned O
by O
all O
the O
other O
Azzurri O
. O

WEIGHT O
/ O
The O
angry O
" O
non O
- O
Olympic O
" O
Dal B-PER
Soglio I-PER
( O
20.19 O
) O
against O
the O
Belarusian O
Belov B-PER
( O
21.14 O
, O
6th O
in O
Athens O
) O
. O

Vasilevskis B-PER
( O
84.95 O
) O
is O
the O
Olympic O
silver O
medalist O
, O
and O
the O
other O
is O
Lusis B-PER
( O
82.76 O
) O
. O

TRIPLE O
/ O
Lister B-PER
( O
17.78 O
, O
2nd O
in O
the O
world O
in O
2004 O
) O
is O
the O
winner O
of O
the O
American O
Trials O
but O
at O
the O
Olympics O
he O
disappointed O
, O
as O
did O
our O
Donato B-PER
( O
16.91 O
) O
. O

Watch O
out O
for O
the O
other O
American O
Kenta B-PER
Bell I-PER
( O
17.58 O
) O
. O

In O
the O
B B-ORG
series I-ORG
there O
is O
Doris B-PER
Tomasini I-PER
from O
Rovereto O
( O
24 O
" O
12 O
, O
4th O
at O
the O
Italian O
Championships O
) O
. O

800 O
METERS O
/ O
The O
Slovenian O
Ceplak B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
55 O
" O
19 O
) O
has O
pocketed O
the O
Olympic O
bronze O
and O
is O
the O
reigning O
European O
champion O
. O

Let O
's O
see O
if O
Artuso B-PER
( O
2 O
' O
01 O
" O
04 O
) O
can O
get O
closer O
to O
2 O
minutes O
flat O
. O

1,500 O
METERS O
/ O
The O
Ukrainian O
Sidorenko B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
04 O
" O
78 O
) O
and O
the O
Kenyan O
Lagat B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
05 O
" O
32 O
) O
will O
test O
the O
Trentino O
Berlanda B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
12 O
" O
80 O
, O
Italian O
champion O
) O
and O
Dal B-PER
Ri I-PER
( O
4 O
' O
23 O
" O
84 O
) O
and O
the O
South O
Tyrolean O
Weissteiner B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
16 O
" O
6 O
manual O
) O
and O
Tschurtschenthaler B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
20 O
" O
65 O
) O
. O

400 O
Obstacles O
/ O
The O
6th O
( O
Bikert B-PER
, O
Russian O
, O
53 O
" O
72 O
) O
and O
7th O
in O
Athens O
( O
Taylor B-PER
, O
American O
, O
53 O
" O
36 O
) O
plus O
the O
2003 O
world O
silver O
( O
Glover B-PER
, O
American O
, O
53 O
" O
33 O
) O
against O
the O
South O
Tyrolean O
Niederstätter B-PER
( O
55 O
" O
52 O
, O
Italian O
record O
holder O
since O
' O
99 O
with O
55 O
" O
10 O
) O
. O

Javelin O
/ O
Arm O
wrestling O
between O
the O
Italian O
Coslovich B-PER
( O
62.66 O
) O
and O
the O
Russian O
Zabruskova B-PER
( O
63.84 O
) O
. O

But O
the O
Russian O
Polnova B-PER
( O
4.72 O
) O
, O
2nd O
in O
Brussels O
, O
can O
beat O
everyone O
. O

And O
there O
is O
also O
the O
Trentino O
Bresciani B-PER
( O
4.20 O
, O
Italian O
champion O
) O
. O

TRIPLE O
/ O
Three O
Olympic O
finalists O
: O

the O
Italian O
Martinez B-PER
( O
7th O
, O
14.85 O
, O
but O
a O
personal O
best O
of O
15.03 O
) O
, O
the O
Algerian O
Rahouli B-PER
( O
6th O
, O
14.89 O
) O
and O
the O
Russian O
Pyatykh B-PER
( O
8th O
, O
14.85 O
also O
) O
. O

On O
the O
sidelines O
the O
21 O
year O
old O
Simona B-PER
La I-PER
Mantia I-PER
( O
14.49 O
) O
. O

G. B-PER
La I-PER
. O

A O
new O
structure O
in O
the O
property O

THE O
SHAREHOLDERS O

Here O
is O
the O
new O
list O
of O
shareholders O
of O
Euregio B-ORG
Finance I-ORG
: O

It O
was O
established O
on O
October O
3 O
, O
2003 O
by O
Alpenair B-ORG
and O
the O
Dutch O
financial O
company O
Olot B-ORG
Bv I-ORG
. O

Electronic O
stock O

The O
good O
verve O
of O
Wall B-ORG
Street I-ORG
did O
not O
succeed O
in O
giving O
the O
right O
intonation O
to O
Piazza B-ORG
Affari I-ORG
which O
closed O
the O
day O
's O
trading O
in O
decline O
. O

At O
the O
end O
of O
the O
day O
, O
the O
Mibtel O
fell O
by O
0,16 O
% O
and O
the O
Mib30 O
by O
0,19 O
% O
. O

The O
Numtel O
was O
worse O
, O
down O
0.58 O
% O
. O

Exchanges O
amounted O
to O
2.263 O
billion O
euros O
. O

Day O
of O
sales O
for O
the O
credit O
institutions O
in O
Piazza B-ORG
Affari I-ORG
, O
which O
weighed O
on O
the O
whole O
list O
. O

Banca B-ORG
Intesa I-ORG
lost O
1.83 O
% O
and O
Popolare B-ORG
di I-ORG
Verona I-ORG
e I-ORG
Novara I-ORG
0.5 O
% O
. O

Capitalia B-ORG
was O
also O
weak O
, O
down O
1.65 O
% O
, O
as O
was O
Bnl B-ORG
( O
- O
1.68 O
% O
) O
, O
while O
Mps B-ORG
moved O
against O
the O
trend O
( O
+ O
0.28 O
% O
) O
. O

Antoveneta B-ORG
also O
fell O
( O
- O
1.67 O
% O
) O
, O
while O
Unicredito B-ORG
suffered O
a O
smaller O
loss O
( O
- O
0.25 O
% O
) O
. O

Insurance O
companies O
were O
in O
contrast O
: O

Generali O
closed O
with O
an O
increase O
of O
0.59 O
% O
, O
Ras O
with O
a O
drop O
of O
0.31 O
% O
. O

More O
nervousness O
for O
Alitalia B-ORG
shares O
, O
which O
closed O
unchanged O
( O
- O
0.04 O
% O
) O
after O
fluctuating O
between O
a O
fall O
of O
2.7 O
% O
and O
a O
rise O
of O
2.25 O
% O
. O

Positive O
session O
, O
instead O
, O
for O
Fiat B-ORG
, O
with O
a O
progress O
of O
0,67 O
% O
to O
6,191 O
euro O
. O

Eni O
closed O
with O
a O
fractional O
increase O
of O
0.18 O
% O
, O
while O
Edison O
registered O
an O
increase O
of O
0.14 O
% O
. O

Enel O
's O
shares O
were O
limited O
( O
- O
0,02 O
% O
) O
, O
while O
Saipem B-ORG
registered O
a O
sharp O
drop O
( O
- O
2,67 O
% O
) O
. O

Among O
the O
telecommunication O
stocks O
, O
Tim B-ORG
closed O
the O
session O
with O
a O
decrease O
of O
0,45 O
% O
. O

Well O
set O
, O
instead O
, O
the O
Telecom O
, O
up O
0.8 O
% O
. O

Among O
the O
media O
, O
Mediaset B-ORG
closed O
down O
0.65 O
% O
. O

Closing O
unchanged O
for O
Tiscali B-ORG
. O

No O
soldier O
was O
hit O
. O

The O
guerrillas O
welcome O
the O
Friuli B-ORG
Brigade I-ORG
that O
has O
just O
arrived O
in O
Iraq B-LOC
. O

ROME B-LOC
- O
Since O
August O
30 O
there O
has O
been O
no O
more O
shooting O
in O
Nassiriya B-LOC
. O

And O
yesterday O
the O
Kalashnikovs O
returned O
to O
make O
themselves O
heard O
. O

An O
hour O
of O
shooting O
, O
but O
no O
Italian O
soldier O
was O
wounded O
: O

The O
welcome O
to O
the O
Friuli B-ORG
Airborne I-ORG
Brigade I-ORG
, O
just O
arrived O
in O
Iraq B-LOC
. O

The O
attack O
took O
place O
at O
9 O
p.m. O
( O
7 O
p.m. O
in O
Italy B-LOC
) O
, O
6 O
kilometers O
northwest O
of O
Nassiriya B-LOC
. O

Against O
the O
Italian O
soldiers O
were O
fired O
numerous O
shots O
of O
automatic O
weapons O
from O
three O
directions O
, O
north O
, O
south O
and O
west O
. O

The O
soldiers O
of O
the O
Friuli B-ORG
Brigade I-ORG
immediately O
returned O
fire O
and O
, O
immediately O
afterwards O
, O
since O
the O
shooting O
continued O
, O
two O
units O
of O
the O
Rapid B-ORG
Reaction I-ORG
Force I-ORG
were O
deployed O
with O
four O
Centauro O
armored O
vehicles O
and O
eight O
other O
vehicles O
( O
6 O
tracked O
Vcc O
and O
2 O
Vm O
) O
protected O
. O

In O
flight O
also O
two O
helicopters O
to O
identify O
the O
places O
from O
where O
the O
shots O
came O
. O

The O
firefight O
lasted O
about O
an O
hour O
, O
from O
21 O
to O
22 O
, O
when O
" O
the O
situation O
- O
explain O
the O
command O
of O
the O
contingent O
- O
has O
cooled O
. O

Late O
in O
the O
evening O
everything O
was O
quiet O
. O

On O
the O
bridge O
, O
manned O
by O
Italian O
soldiers O
, O
circulation O
was O
reopened O
. O

Colonel O
Carmelo B-PER
Abisso I-PER
is O
not O
surprised O
by O
the O
" O
warm O
" O
reception O
received O
by O
the O
men O
of O
Friuli B-ORG
from O
the O
so O
- O
called O
guerrilla O
. O

Presented O
the O
2004 O
edition O
: O

" O
Journey O
in O
the O
differences O
" O
, O
the O
actress O
in O
jury O

" O
We O
want O
to O
promote O
awareness O
that O
the O
diversity O
existing O
" O
under O
one O
sky O
" O
- O
title O
and O
inspiration O
of O
the O
two O
previous O
editions O
- O
are O
a O
wealth O
and O
an O
inalienable O
heritage O
of O
mankind O
" O
, O
explained O
yesterday O
at O
the O
press O
conference O
Don O
Bosco O
. O
Massimo B-PER
Manservigi I-PER
, O
president O
of O
the O
Festival O
, O
explained O
at O
a O
press O
conference O
yesterday O
: O

The O
articulated O
occasion O
of O
confrontation O
between O
faiths O
offered O
by O
the O
Festival O
, O
which O
in O
recent O
years O
has O
achieved O
international O
visibility O
and O
consolidated O
a O
vast O
network O
of O
collaborations O
, O
is O
entrusted O
mainly O
to O
the O
language O
of O
cinema O
. O

At O
the O
center O
of O
the O
event O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
is O
the O
competition O
among O
the O
29 O
subject O
films O
, O
documentaries O
and O
short O
films O
with O
a O
religious O
theme O
selected O
from O
among O
the O
102 O
works O
sent O
in O
from O
various O
nations O
, O
competing O
for O
the O
Grand O
Prize O
" O
In O
the O
Spirit O
of O
Faith O
" O
, O
for O
supremacy O
in O
their O
respective O
categories O
. O
and O
for O
special O
awards O
established O
in O
collaboration O
with O
various O
religious O
organizations O
and O
foundations O
. O

The O
international O
jury O
is O
composed O
of O
5 O
experts O
in O
the O
fields O
of O
cinema O
, O
culture O
and O
religion O
: O

Among O
the O
29 O
films O
in O
competition O
, O
with O
an O
' O
important O
participation O
of O
the O
Orthodox O
Christian O
world O
and O
the O
Islamic O
world O
Shiite O
and O
Sunni O
, O
stands O
out O
the O
section O
of O
feature O
films O
, O
which O
boasts O
the O
presence O
of O
" O
The O
Passion O
" O
by O
Mel B-PER
Gibson I-PER
, O
in O
his O
first O
festival O
; O

Among O
the O
documentaries O
, O
" O
Not O
only O
K2 O
" O
is O
worthy O
of O
note O
. O
Renato B-PER
Morelli I-PER
's O
documentary O
on O
the O
life O
of O
the O
director O
Marco B-PER
Baldi I-PER
, O
who O
on O
the O
afternoon O
of O
Friday O
22nd O
, O
out O
of O
competition O
, O
will O
present O
his O
latest O
film O
" O
La O
perla O
nascosta O
" O
( O
The O
Hidden O
Pearl O
) O
at O
the O
Cuminetti O
Theater O
, O
a O
journey O
between O
the O
near O
and O
far O
East O
to O
discover O
the O
Aramaic O
civilization O
. O

Many O
collateral O
initiatives O
are O
also O
dedicated O
to O
art O
: O

from O
the O
exhibition O
of O
artists O
of O
the O
UCAI B-ORG
dedicated O
to O
" O
Clare O
of O
Assisi O
. O

Chiarore O
della O
luce O
perenne O
" O
( O
at O
the O
Bernardo O
Clesio O
Center O
) O
, O
to O
the O
exhibition O
of O
a O
copper O
fig O
tree O
by O
Mastro B-ORG
7 I-ORG
. O

Religion O
Today O
- O
via B-LOC
Barbacovi I-LOC
4 I-LOC
, O
38100 O
Trento B-LOC
- O
Tel O
and O
Fax O
0461 O
981853 O
( O
from O
Monday O
to O
Thursday O
9.00 O
- O
12.00 O
) O
, O
Website O
: O

www.religionfilm.com O
. O

Castles B-PER
will O
make O
De B-PER
Gasperi I-PER

Rai O
Tre O
at O
20.55 O

SLOVENIA B-ORG

Simcic B-PER

Brecko B-PER

Berko B-PER

Suler B-PER

Hadzic B-PER

Bozic B-PER

Semler B-PER

Stromajer B-PER

ITALY B-ORG

Agliardi B-PER

Power B-PER

Bovo B-PER

Mantovani B-PER

Chiellini B-PER

Rosina B-PER

Donadel B-PER

Aquilani B-PER

Lazzari B-PER

Bianchi B-PER

Pazzini B-PER

Available O
: O

SLOVENIA B-ORG
: O

Ct O
Zupan B-PER

ITALY B-ORG
: O

Berni B-PER
, O
Piccolo B-PER
, O
Zambelli B-PER
, O
Loviso B-PER
, O
Nocerino B-PER
, O
Pepe B-PER
, O
Corvia B-PER
. O

Ct O
Gentile B-PER

REFEREE O
: O

Briakos B-PER
( O
Greece B-LOC
) O

HERE O
ARCO B-ORG
/ O
The O
opinion O
of O
the O
captain O
of O
long O
course O
after O
a O
0 O
to O
0 O
all O
' O
debut O

The O
redemption O
is O
behind O
the O
corner O

Andreoli B-PER
: O

" O
In O
Salò B-LOC
you O
will O
see O
a O
different O
team O
. O

by O
GIANLUCA B-PER
DE I-PER
MASI I-PER

ARCO B-LOC
- O
In O
the O
season O
opener O
on O
Sunday O
against O
the O
freshman O
team O
from O
Ferrara O
, O
in O
which O
Arco B-ORG
was O
not O
able O
to O
go O
beyond O
a O
0 O
- O
0 O
home O
draw O
, O
the O
absence O
of O
the O
captain O
and O
charismatic O
leader O
of O
the O
group O
Giulio B-PER
Andreoli I-PER
made O
itself O
felt O
. O

L O
' O
cardinal O
element O
of O
the O
game O
arcense O
( O
great O
experience O
in O
D B-ORG
for O
having O
played O
in O
Benacense B-ORG
, O
Rovereto B-ORG
, O
in O
' O
Arzignano B-ORG
, O
Bassano B-ORG
and O
S. B-ORG
Donà I-ORG
) O
had O
to O
sit O
on O
the O
bench O
for O
a O
problem O
all O
' O
adductor O
suffered O
the O
week O
before O
and O
that O
does O
not O
allow O
him O
to O
be O
100 O
% O
. O

Nevertheless O
, O
the O
Gialloblu O
captain O
is O
confident O
: O

We O
wanted O
so O
much O
to O
do O
well O
and O
to O
get O
off O
on O
the O
right O
foot O
, O
but O
we O
must O
not O
forget O
that O
for O
many O
of O
my O
teammates O
it O
was O
the O
first O
time O
in O
this O
series O
. O

In O
spite O
of O
everything O
, O
I O
think O
we O
played O
an O
excellent O
game O
, O
putting O
in O
all O
the O
intensity O
we O
are O
capable O
of O
. O

In O
the O
early O
stages O
of O
the O
match O
we O
were O
not O
brilliant O
, O
I O
admit O
, O
but O
for O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
first O
half O
we O
tried O
to O
play O
the O
game O
and O
impose O
our O
own O
game O
and O
I O
think O
that O
for O
long O
stretches O
we O
succeeded O
quite O
well O
. O

Do O
not O
forget O
the O
goal O
ball O
on O
the O
feet O
of O
Toccoli B-PER
( O
in O
the O
picture O
the O
central O
arcense O
unhooked O
Sunday O
to O
make O
a O
surprise O
goal O
by O
finding O
the O
parade O
foot O
of O
Acts B-PER
, O
ed O
) O
, O
where O
it O
was O
good O
their O
goalkeeper O
to O
oppose O
with O
his O
feet O
, O
and O
also O
the O
goal O
canceled O
to O
Dal B-PER
Ferro I-PER
for O
a O
millimeter O
offside O
. O

In O
the O
second O
half O
the O
heat O
became O
the O
absolute O
protagonist O
. O

They O
are O
more O
minute O
and O
quicker O
players O
than O
us O
. O

Now O
we O
have O
the O
whole O
week O
in O
front O
of O
us O
to O
work O
and O
to O
get O
ready O
at O
best O
for O
the O
next O
match O
, O
correcting O
the O
mistakes O
made O
, O
but O
starting O
from O
what O
was O
good O
. O

The O
dispute O
of O
health O
care O
is O
complicated O
, O
even O
in O
view O
of O
the O
renewal O
of O
Rsu B-ORG

" O
Little O
money O
for O
the O
contract O

Cisl B-ORG
: O

immediately O
the O
balance O
of O
the O
biennial O
2002 O
- O
2003 O

On O
the O
renewal O
of O
the O
contract O
of O
the O
section O
health O
, O
it O
intervenes O
the O
Cisl B-ORG
public I-ORG
function I-ORG
. O

After O
that O
Uil B-ORG
and O
Nursing B-ORG
up I-ORG
, O
the O
two O
unions O
most O
representative O
, O
have O
abandoned O
the O
table O
with O
the O
Apran B-ORG
is O
profiled O
the O
umpteenth O
arm O
wrestling O
between O
health O
professions O
and O
non O
- O
healthcare O
. O

The O
instigation O
to O
the O
conflict O
to O
every O
level O
makes O
difficult O
the O
negotiation O
and O
disorientates O
the O
workers O
. O

We O
are O
in O
the O
midst O
of O
an O
election O
campaign O
for O
the O
renewal O
of O
the O
Rsu B-ORG
and O
the O
denigrating O
action O
of O
some O
unions O
seems O
almost O
a O
strategy O
, O
in O
view O
of O
the O
appointment O
of O
mid O
- O
November O
, O
date O
of O
the O
elections O
. O

It O
is O
necessary O
to O
find O
a O
common O
position O
. O

The O
existing O
contrast O
is O
evidenced O
by O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
five O
trade O
unions O
entitled O
to O
negotiate O
have O
presented O
five O
different O
platforms O
. O

" O
This O
is O
a O
dangerous O
anomaly O
- O
Vivian B-PER
continues O
- O
. O

The O
contract O
must O
provide O
for O
salary O
increases O
linked O
to O
inflation O
, O
as O
occurred O
at O
the O
national O
level O
. O

At O
this O
stage O
, O
in O
defense O
of O
the O
salary O
, O
we O
will O
ask O
Apran B-ORG
the O
balance O
provided O
for O
2002 O
- O
2003 O
on O
the O
salary O
in O
the O
same O
measure O
paid O
by O
the O
national O
contract O
of O
health O
, O
even O
with O
a O
partial O
agreement O
to O
be O
signed O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
, O
and O
then O
continue O
negotiations O
on O
all O
other O
matters O
. O

To O
further O
complicate O
the O
dispute O
, O
there O
is O
the O
question O
of O
the O
funds O
allocated O
, O
considered O
insufficient O
. O

" O
The O
CISL B-ORG
has O
won O
the O
appeal O
against O
the O
' O
health B-ORG
company I-ORG
that O
, O
in O
' O
decentralized O
agreement O
, O
following O
the O
provincial O
contract O
2002 O
, O
has O
used O
resources O
allocated O
to O
the O
retraining O
of O
non O
- O
healthcare O
personnel O
for O
other O
purposes O
. O

It O
is O
300,000 O
euros O
- O
recalls O
Pierachille B-PER
Dalledonne I-PER
, O
secretary O
of O
Uil B-ORG
Health I-ORG
- O
. O

But O
all O
' O
appeal O
are O
also O
missing O
1,500,000 O
euros O
. O

Toni B-PER
and O
Totti B-PER
showed O
a O
good O
understanding O
in O
the O
friendly O
match O
with O
the O
U18 B-ORG
team O

FLORENCE B-LOC
- O
It O
ended O
5 O
- O
2 O
the O
friendly O
match O
that O
Italy B-ORG
played O
against O
the O
Under B-ORG
18 I-ORG
at O
Coverciano B-LOC
. O

Two O
times O
of O
50 O
' O
, O
which O
did O
not O
take O
part O
Gattuso B-PER
and O
Nesta B-PER
, O
who O
remained O
to O
train O
on O
an O
adjacent O
field O
. O

With O
them O
, O
at O
the O
beginning O
, O
also O
Zambrotta B-PER
, O
that O
Lippi B-PER
entered O
at O
26 O
' O
of O
the O
second O
half O
in O
place O
of O
Pancaro B-PER
. O

The O
coach O
tried O
at O
the O
beginning O
a O
4 O
- O
2 O
- O
3 O
- O
1 O
with O
Toni B-PER
as O
central O
point O
, O
Totti B-PER
as O
support O
, O
Esposito B-PER
on O
the O
left O
and O
De B-PER
Rossi I-PER
- O
Blasi B-PER
as O
central O
couple O
of O
midfield O
. O

In O
the O
first O
half O
the O
best O
was O
just O
De B-PER
Rossi I-PER
, O
who O
took O
immediately O
a O
crossbar O
header O
and O
who O
was O
always O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
game O
, O
both O
in O
front O
of O
the O
defense O
to O
start O
the O
action O
, O
both O
in O
the O
final O
phase O
. O

Bad O
, O
however O
, O
Esposito B-PER
, O
perhaps O
blocked O
by O
emotion O
, O
who O
has O
failed O
two O
sensational O
goals O
and O
did O
not O
seem O
lively O
as O
with O
Cagliari B-ORG
. O

In O
crescendo O
the O
game O
of O
Totti B-PER
, O
the O
first O
in O
blue O
after O
the O
European O
Championship O
. O

His O
assist O
to O
14 O
' O
for O
the O
first O
goal O
of O
Toni B-PER
( O
right O
cross O
under O
the O
crossbar O
) O
and O
his O
26 O
' O
shot O
from O
outside O
then O
deflected O
by O
Castroni B-PER
behind O
Consigli B-PER
. O

For O
the O
Under B-ORG
18 I-ORG
team O
, O
Acquafresca B-PER
's O
goal O
in O
the O
28th O
minute O
with O
a O
great O
shot O
from O
inside O
the O
area O
. O

In O
the O
second O
half O
Lippi B-PER
passed O
to O
4 O
- O
4 O
- O
2 O
, O
with O
Di B-PER
Vaio I-PER
wide O
on O
the O
left O
and O
Corradi B-PER
- O
Gilardino B-PER
in O
front O
. O

Perrotta B-PER
played O
well O
, O
who O
yesterday O
for O
the O
first O
time O
got O
confident O
with O
the O
ball O
and O
who O
also O
scored O
. O

Before O
him O
, O
however O
, O
it O
was O
Di B-PER
Vaio I-PER
to O
open O
the O
scoring O
in O
the O
second O
half O
with O
a O
diagonal O
left O
, O
while O
after O
the O
4 O
- O
2 O
of O
Momentè B-PER
was O
Zambrotta B-PER
to O
fix O
the O
final O
5 O
- O
2 O
with O
a O
powerful O
right O
after O
a O
great O
number O
on O
the O
left O
side O
. O

This O
is O
the O
scoreboard O
of O
the O
friendly O
match O
: O

RETIREES O
: O

ITALY B-ORG
pt O
( O
4 O
- O
2 O
- O
3 O
- O
1 O
) O
: O

Buffon B-PER
; O

Bonera B-PER
, O
Cannavaro B-PER
, O
Materazzi B-PER
, O
Pancaro B-PER
; O

Blasi B-PER
, O
De B-PER
Rossi I-PER
; O

Camoranesi B-PER
, O
Totti B-PER
, O
Esposito B-PER
; O

Toni B-PER
. O

Ct O
Lippi B-PER

ITALY B-ORG
st O
( O
4 O
- O
4 O
- O
2 O
) O
: O

Pelizzoli B-PER
; O

Diana B-PER
, O
Perrotta B-PER
, O
Fiore B-PER
, O
Di B-PER
Vaio I-PER
; O

Corradi B-PER
, O
Gilardino B-PER
. O

Ct O
Lippi B-PER

REFEREE O
: O

Tagliavento B-PER
of O
Terni B-LOC

The O
courses O
start O

Oriental O
Dance O

There O
is O
also O
a O
course O
for O
girls O
aged O
9 O
to O
15 O
years O
( O
from O
18.30 O
to O
19.30 O
) O
, O
as O
well O
as O
monthly O
workshops O
in O
styles O
baladi O
- O
sharqi O
- O
saidi O
- O
rhythmic O
music O
- O
choreography O
. O

Info O
: O

0464 O
555104 O
; O

cell O
. O
347 O
/ O
4285696 O
- O
e O
- O
mail O
cc.margarit O
@ O
tin.it O
; O

www.ccmargarita.com O

University O

The O
outgoing O
rector O
is O
being O
courted O
in O
Rome B-LOC
, O
where O
he O
would O
be O
responsible O
for O
the O
reform O
of O
Italian O
universities O
. O

Moratti B-PER
wants O
Egidi B-PER
at O
his O
side O

Candidate O
to O
the O
guide O
of O
the O
commission O

He O
could O
take O
the O
place O
of O
De B-PER
Maio I-PER

He O
has O
not O
yet O
left O
the O
office O
of O
via B-LOC
Belenzani I-LOC
- O
where O
he O
worked O
for O
8 O
years O
- O
and O
already O
the O
" O
job O
offers O
" O
are O
flowing O
in O
. O

After O
two O
mandates O
in O
the O
cabin O
of O
command O
of O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Trento I-ORG
, O
where O
it O
is O
made O
to O
appreciate O
, O
now O
it O
does O
not O
have O
that O
the O
embarrassment O
of O
the O
choice O
. O

Various O
proposals O
have O
been O
made O
to O
him O
: O

Massimo O
Egidi O
, O
outgoing O
rector O
, O
in O
a O
few O
weeks O
will O
leave O
the O
place O
to O
the O
newly O
elected O
Davide B-PER
Bassi I-PER
, O
but O
for O
sure O
he O
will O
not O
have O
problems O
of O
" O
placement O
" O
. O

In O
recent O
days O
he O
has O
been O
painted O
as O
the O
ideal O
candidate O
for O
the O
presidency O
of O
the O
Itc B-ORG
, O
the O
future O
Kessler B-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
, O
after O
the O
" O
Bonvicini O
era O
. O

A O
voice O
, O
this O
one O
, O
that O
for O
a O
long O
time O
has O
been O
circulating O
in O
the O
corridors O
of O
the O
university O
and O
that O
now O
could O
become O
concrete O
. O

Adriano B-PER
De I-PER
Maio I-PER
has O
left O
the O
position O
and O
his O
ideal O
successor O
seems O
to O
be O
just O
the O
tenant O
of O
the O
rectorate O
of O
Trento B-LOC
. O

The O
possible O
waltz O
of O
chairs O
is O
given O
as O
more O
than O
probable O
by O
Il B-ORG
Mondo I-ORG
, O
the O
economic O
magazine O
that O
pays O
particular O
attention O
to O
the O
universe O
of O
the O
academy O
in O
Italy B-LOC
. O

At O
the O
end O
of O
July O
Adriano B-PER
De I-PER
Maio I-PER
has O
abandoned O
the O
ministerial O
commission O
committed O
to O
renew O
the O
legal O
framework O
of O
teachers O
and O
the O
new O
classes O
of O
degrees O
. O

" O
Just O
on O
this O
issue O
- O
we O
read O
in O
the O
column O
" O
In O
cattedra O
" O
- O
the O
proposals O
formulated O
by O
De B-PER
Maio I-PER
( O
such O
as O
the O
' O
unification O
of O
degree O
classes O
) O
have O
ended O
up O
in O
the O
drawer O
: O

they O
did O
not O
like O
to O
professional O
orders O
and O
to O
the O
undersecretary O
Maria B-PER
Grazia I-PER
Siliquini I-PER
" O
. O

It O
seems O
that O
the O
breakup O
is O
due O
to O
the O
lacked O
appointment O
of O
De B-PER
Maio I-PER
to O
the O
presidency O
of O
the O
CNR B-ORG
. O

In O
this O
phase O
Massimo B-PER
Egidi I-PER
enters O
therefore O
in O
game O
. O

Letizia B-PER
Moratti I-PER
could O
bet O
on O
the O
outgoing O
rector O
, O
who O
would O
work O
in O
committee O
together O
with O
Francesco B-PER
Alberoni I-PER
and O
Fabio B-PER
Roversi I-PER
Monaco I-PER
. O

A O
few O
days O
from O
the O
end O
of O
his O
second O
mandate O
, O
Egidi B-PER
has O
two O
roads O
to O
choose O
from O
: O

Both O
in O
Trentino B-LOC
and O
in O
the O
capital O
he O
enjoys O
great O
esteem O
. O

A.Tom B-PER
. O

The O
top O
management O
of O
Viale B-ORG
Mazzini I-ORG
is O
confirmed O
. O

The O
opposition O
accuses O
: O

What O
a O
turnaround O

Rai B-ORG
, O
the O
Udc B-ORG
changes O
its O
mind O
. O

Forward O
like O
this O

ROME B-LOC
- O
The O
Rai B-ORG
Board I-ORG
of O
Directors O
can O
remain O
in O
the O
saddle O
until O
June O
2005 O
. O

Not O
even O
the O
draft O
opinion O
drawn O
up O
by O
President O
Petruccioli B-PER
is O
put O
to O
the O
vote O
with O
the O
no O
to O
the O
extension O
of O
the O
council B-ORG
, O
branded O
by O
the O
same O
centrists O
as O
delegitimized O
. O

The O
opposition O
cries O
out O
to O
the O
" O
about O
- O
turn O
" O
and O
to O
the O
" O
hidden O
pact O
" O
in O
the O
majority O
in O
exchange O
for O
who O
knows O
what O
quid O
pro O
quo O
, O
the O
Udc B-ORG
replies O
by O
talking O
about O
a O
" O
managerial O
choice O
" O
, O
dictated O
by O
the O
need O
not O
to O
block O
the O
extension O
of O
the O
council O
. O
dictated O
by O
the O
need O
not O
to O
block O
the O
process O
of O
the O
new O
Rai B-ORG
. O

Those O
who O
imagined O
that O
yesterday O
at O
Palazzo O
San O
Macuto O
the O
transversal O
array O
was O
repeated O
, O
which O
in O
July O
was O
expressed O
in O
the O
ultimatum O
to O
the O
Board O
of O
Directors O
- O
at O
home O
by O
September O
30 O
- O
is O
immediately O
denied O
by O
the O
Udc B-ORG
group O
leader O
. O

At O
the O
opening O
of O
the O
session O
, O
Iervolino B-PER
announced O
the O
favorable O
opinion O
to O
the O
document O
of O
Forza B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
, O
An B-ORG
and O
Lega B-ORG
Nord I-ORG
for O
the O
yes O
to O
the O
statute O
as O
well O
as O
' O
was O
approved O
by O
the O
assembly O
of O
Rai B-ORG
Spa I-ORG
and O
Rai B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
. O

We O
need O
that O
the O
Rai B-ORG
starts O
, O
albeit O
with O
a O
politically O
delegitimized O
top O
. O

Result O
, O
19 O
yes O
against O
17 O
no O
. O

It O
does O
n't O
succeed O
neither O
to O
the O
group O
leader O
of O
the O
Margherita B-ORG
Gentiloni B-PER
the O
attempt O
to O
insert O
, O
under O
form O
of O
subamendment O
to O
the O
document O
, O
the O
appeal O
to O
the O
council B-ORG
to O
resign O
as O
soon O
as O
concluded O
the O
fusion O
: O

Also O
in O
this O
case O
the O
Cdl B-ORG
is O
compact O
and O
the O
no O
votes O
are O
19 O
against O
18 O
yes O
. O

The O
president O
of O
the O
Greens B-ORG
, O
Pecoraro B-PER
Scanio I-PER
, O
reacted O
immediately O
from O
the O
opposition O
and O
spoke O
of O
an O
" O
incredible O
turncoat O
of O
the O
Udc B-ORG
" O
and O
wondered O
if O
" O
hidden O
pacts O
had O
been O
signed O
on O
the O
skin O
of O
the O
company O
" O
. O

From O
the O
Ds B-ORG
, O
Giulietti B-PER
brands O
the O
vote O
of O
the O
Vigilance O
as O
" O
very O
serious O
" O
and O
sees O
the O
risk O
that O
we O
go O
" O
towards O
a O
presidential O
republic O
to O
unified O
networks O
. O

More O
cautious O
Gentiloni B-PER
, O
that O
however O
notes O
like O
the O
norm O
that O
concurs O
to O
the O
cda B-ORG
to O
remain O
in O
saddle O
until O
june O
2005 O
( O
that O
is O
until O
all O
' O
approval O
of O
the O
budget O
2004 O
) O
" O
it O
will O
render O
the O
business O
apex O
still O
more O
unstable O
and O
it O
will O
open O
one O
new O
season O
of O
legal O
controversies O
" O
. O

For O
the O
Italian B-ORG
Communists I-ORG
, O
Sgobio B-PER
speaks O
of O
a O
" O
tacit O
pact O
in O
the O
majority O
with O
the O
objective O
of O
destructuring O
the O
company O
" O
. O

in O
Brief O

Appeal O
to O
the O
Consulta B-ORG

University B-ORG
, O
funds O
to O
' O
Opera B-ORG

For O
operating O
expenses O
in O
2004 O
, O
5,558,955 O
euros O
have O
been O
allocated O
to O
the O
Trento B-ORG
University I-ORG
Opera I-ORG
, O
plus O
another O
2,500,000 O
euros O
for O
investment O
expenses O
. O

Eight O
million O
for O
research O

8,870,000 O
euros O
were O
allocated O
to O
institutional O
research O
activities O
for O
2004 O
at O
the O
Agricultural B-ORG
Institute I-ORG
of I-ORG
San I-ORG
Michele I-ORG
. O

Minorities O
in O
party O

TRENTO B-LOC
- O
Today O
the O
kermesse O
" O
Mi.no.ran.Zè.ro O
" O
starts O
in O
Pergine B-LOC
Valsugana I-LOC
. O
a O
play O
on O
words O
to O
reflect O
on O
the O
" O
state O
of O
the O
art O
" O
of O
ethnic O
and O
linguistic O
minorities O
, O
between O
globalization O
, O
contamination O
and O
protection O
of O
identities O
. O

A O
" O
shortsightedness O
" O
to O
wonder O
about O
the O
others O
, O
the O
different O
, O
the O
boundaries O
that O
break O
and O
move O
, O
even O
distant O
minorities O
that O
become O
close O
and O
daily O
presences O
. O

Reanto B-PER
Morelli I-PER
, O
organizer O
of O
the O
event O
, O
argues O
: O

The O
concept O
of O
the O
` O
` O
universal O
mixture O
'' O
of O
the O
Nobel O
Prize O
winner O
, O
Derek B-PER
Walcott I-PER
, O
explains O
that O
all O
over O
the O
world O
the O
mixture O
of O
languages O
, O
peoples O
and O
cultures O
is O
an O
unavoidable O
fact O
. O

Gigi B-PER
Zoppello I-PER
presents O
" O
La O
festa O
del O
ritorno O
" O
by O
Carmine B-PER
Abate I-PER
; O

9 O
p.m. O
- O
concert O
in O
the O
Church O
of O
S. O
Giorgio O
Serso O
by O
the O
Cantori B-ORG
di I-ORG
Castelsardo I-ORG
and I-ORG
Sessa I-ORG
Aurunca I-ORG
. O

9 O
p.m. O
- O
concert O
of O
the O
" O
Boghes B-ORG
and I-ORG
Voices I-ORG
" O
in O
the O
Archpriest O
's O
Church O
of O
Pergine O
; O

Friday O
: O

5:00 O
p.m. O
- O
11:00 O
p.m. O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruet I-LOC
" O
In O
search O
of O
the O
gold O
of O
the O
Fersina O
" O
; O

8.30 O
p.m. O
- O
dance O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Municipio I-LOC
with O
the O
Gruppo B-ORG
Folkloristico I-ORG
Canazei I-ORG
and O
the O
Gruppo B-ORG
Folk I-ORG
of I-ORG
Palù I-ORG
del I-ORG
Fersina I-ORG
; O

from O
7 O
p.m. O
to O
11 O
p.m. O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruet I-LOC
" O
Minorities O
in O
the O
pot O
" O
; O

Saturday O
: O

5 O
p.m. O
- O
11 O
p.m. O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruet I-LOC
" O
In O
search O
of O
the O
gold O
of O
the O
Fersina O
" O
; O

9.30 O
p.m. O
- O
Concert O
of O
the O
Choir O
" O
Marco B-ORG
Garbin I-ORG
" O
in O
Piazza O
Municipio O
; O

from O
7 O
p.m. O
to O
11 O
p.m. O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruet I-LOC
" O
Minorities O
in O
the O
pot O
" O
; O

Sunday O
: O

10 O
a.m. O
- O
12 O
p.m. O
and O
5 O
p.m. O
- O
11 O
p.m. O
in O
Piazza O
E. O
Fruet O
" O
In O
search O
of O
the O
gold O
of O
the O
Fersina O
" O
. O

PROMOTION B-ORG
/ O
The O
first O
day O
of O
the O
championship O
smiles O
all O
' O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
, O
victorious O
in O
the O
big O
match O
with O
the O
Condinese B-ORG

Riva B-ORG
del I-ORG
Garda I-ORG
, O
departure O
with O
a O
bang O

Rudy B-PER
Prandi I-PER
's O
team O
scores O
four O
goals O
against O
Calcio B-ORG
Bleggio I-ORG

TRENTO B-LOC
- O
First O
day O
of O
the O
Promozione B-ORG
championship O
without O
any O
big O
surprises O
. O

The O
two O
favorites O
of O
the O
eve O
, O
Riva B-ORG
del I-ORG
Garda I-ORG
and O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
have O
debuted O
by O
winning O
the O
three O
points O
; O

Net O
the O
affirmation O
of O
the O
eleven O
of O
Prandi B-PER
, O
victorious O
four O
to O
zero O
on O
the O
field O
of O
Cavrasto B-LOC
, O
more O
suffered O
the O
success O
of O
the O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
that O
had O
to O
deal O
with O
a O
team O
very O
quoted O
as O
the O
Condinese B-ORG
. O

Net O
victory O
for O
the O
Villazzano B-ORG
of O
Alberto B-PER
Betta I-PER
that O
in O
Gabbiolo O
takes O
little O
more O
than O
ten O
minutes O
to O
archive O
the O
practice O
La B-ORG
Rovere I-ORG
. O

The O
two O
goals O
from O
the O
distance O
of O
Fontana B-PER
and O
the O
' O
framed O
Floriani B-PER
have O
left O
no O
escape O
to O
Bevilacqua B-PER
. O

The O
newly O
promoted O
Azzurra B-ORG
starts O
well O
and O
thanks O
to O
Flores B-PER
and O
Fabbri B-PER
's O
goals O
, O
it O
scores O
in O
Cavalese B-LOC
what O
can O
perhaps O
be O
considered O
as O
the O
main O
surprise O
of O
the O
day O
. O

Too O
heavy O
( O
as O
it O
happened O
in O
the O
past O
season O
) O
for O
Fiemme B-ORG
the O
absence O
of O
Luca B-PER
Giunchi I-PER
in O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
field O
. O

The O
brand O
new O
Aldeno B-ORG
of O
the O
ds O
Kaisermann B-PER
makes O
a O
great O
debut O
conquering O
the O
whole O
stake O
in O
the O
external O
match O
on O
the O
difficult O
field O
of O
Calcio B-ORG
Chiese I-ORG
. O

Borghesi B-PER
and O
Fante B-PER
are O
the O
scorers O
for O
the O
giallorossi O
. O

Half O
a O
false O
step O
of O
Levico B-ORG
Terme I-ORG
, O
stopped O
on O
the O
draw O
by O
Monte B-ORG
Baldo I-ORG
. O

Agostini B-PER
's O
goal O
, O
Brusco B-PER
's O
tie O
. O

In O
the O
advance O
success O
for O
Rotaliana B-ORG
on O
Dro B-ORG
. O

In O
Taio B-LOC
the O
hosts O
of O
Predaia B-ORG
have O
been O
reached O
in O
the O
recovery O
from O
the O
goal O
of O
Campo B-PER
( O
author O
of O
a O
double O
) O
. O

Two O
to O
two O
the O
final O
result O
. O

Franco B-PER
Pistolato I-PER
, O
coach O
of O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
, O
is O
satisfied O
for O
the O
important O
success O
obtained O
against O
Condinese B-ORG
. O

" O
I O
'm O
happy O
for O
the O
result O
. O

The O
game O
on O
Sunday O
confirmed O
that O
we O
still O
have O
to O
work O
hard O
. O

What O
ideas O
did O
the O
game O
offer O
on O
Sunday O
? O

Where O
should O
your O
team O
grow O
the O
most O
? O

" O
Surely O
we O
have O
some O
little O
problems O
that O
we O
must O
try O
to O
solve O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
. O

Especially O
in O
the O
offensive O
phase O
we O
have O
to O
grow O
a O
lot O
. O

Who O
do O
you O
fear O
more O
for O
the O
final O
success O
? O

" O
Condinese B-ORG
gave O
me O
a O
very O
good O
impression O
and O
I O
'm O
sure O
they O
will O
play O
a O
leading O
role O
. O

We O
aim O
to O
find O
a O
good O
balance O
and O
to O
play O
a O
good O
championship O
. O

Are O
the O
forecasts O
respected O
or O
is O
there O
some O
result O
that O
you O
did O
n't O
expect O
in O
this O
first O
day O
? O

" O
Broadly O
speaking O
, O
there O
were O
no O
big O
surprises O
. O

I O
did O
n't O
expect O
Calcio B-ORG
Bleggio I-ORG
to O
score O
four O
goals O
at O
home O
, O
but O
obviously O
they O
paid O
for O
some O
absence O
too O
. O

Cooperatives O
called O
to O
vote O

The O
cooperatives O
registered O
in O
the O
provincial O
register O
are O
called O
to O
elect O
representatives O
( O
two O
members O
and O
one O
alternate O
) O
in O
the O
Regional B-ORG
Commission I-ORG
for I-ORG
cooperation I-ORG
and O
in O
the O
Commission B-ORG
for I-ORG
cooperatives I-ORG
in O
the O
province B-LOC
of I-LOC
Trento I-LOC
. O

The O
elections O
will O
be O
held O
from O
September O
8 O
to O
27 O
. O

The O
following O
day O
, O
at O
10 O
a.m. O
, O
the O
public O
counting O
of O
ballots O
will O
begin O
at O
the O
headquarters O
of O
the O
Cooperative O
Service O
, O
in O
via B-LOC
Brennero I-LOC
136 I-LOC
. O

Each O
cooperative O
may O
vote O
for O
one O
full O
member O
and O
one O
alternate O
member O
, O

The O
sector O
has O
been O
suffering O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

At O
Saie O
13 O
exhibitors O

Purchases O
down O
by O
40 O
% O

TRENTO B-LOC
- O
In O
Trentino B-LOC
, O
the O
woodworking O
industry O
includes O
1,400 O
companies O
and O
a O
total O
of O
about O
5,000 O
employees O
. O

56 O
% O
of O
the O
provincial O
territory O
is O
covered O
by O
woods O
and O
forests O
, O
70 O
% O
of O
which O
are O
public O
property O
( O
Province B-LOC
, O
Municipalities O
and O
so O
on O
) O
. O

The O
raw O
material O
suffers O
the O
competition O
of O
other O
materials O
considered O
more O
convenient O
. O

Quality O
wood O
, O
such O
as O
certified O
Trentino O
wood O
, O
is O
having O
difficulty O
in O
finding O
a O
place O
due O
to O
higher O
prices O
. O

90 O
thousand O
square O
meters O
in O
total O
. O

The O
average O
value O
per O
metrocube O
was O
just O
over O
69 O
euro O
. O

The O
total O
value O
of O
the O
sales O
exceeded O
4 O
million O
euros O
. O

In O
the O
meantime O
, O
there O
will O
be O
13 O
exhibitors O
from O
Trentino O
( O
9 O
last O
year O
) O
out O
of O
the O
1,800 O
present O
at O
the O
2004 O
edition O
of O
Saie O
, O
the O
Building O
Industry O
Exhibition O
( O
October O
13 O
- O
17 O
) O
in O
Bologna B-LOC
, O
which O
boasts O
170 O
thousand O
visitors O
. O

The O
Chamber B-ORG
of I-ORG
Commerce I-ORG
, O
which O
coordinates O
the O
operation O
, O
has O
confirmed O
a O
part O
of O
the O
stand O
that O
had O
obtained O
a O
high O
level O
of O
appreciation O
in O
2003 O
( O
70 O
thousand O
presences O
estimated O
) O
. O

M. B-PER
E. I-PER

CRAC O
SICA B-ORG

Dissegna B-PER
investigated O
for O
receiving O
stolen O
goods O

Paolo B-PER
Postai I-PER
drags O
with O
him O
also O
all O
the O
purchasers O
of O
the O
goods O
of O
Sica B-ORG
srl I-ORG
. O

The O
public O
prosecutor O
, O
Alessandra B-PER
Liverani I-PER
, O
is O
investigating O
for O
receiving O
stolen O
goods O
Gianluca B-PER
Dissegna I-PER
who O
would O
have O
bought O
a O
silver O
Audi O
A4 O
Avant O
from O
Sica B-ORG
. O

The O
car O
was O
not O
owned O
by O
Sica B-ORG
, O
but O
had O
been O
leased O
. O

According O
to O
the O
prosecution O
Dissegna B-PER
would O
have O
even O
falsified O
the O
report O
of O
loss O
of O
documents O
of O
the O
car O
. O

The O
car O
was O
seized O
yesterday O
morning O
by O
the O
Guardia B-ORG
di I-ORG
Finanza I-ORG
. O

Sica B-ORG
went O
bankrupt O
because O
of O
a O
serious O
financial O
failure O
that O
caused O
its O
collapse O
; O

Ten O
families O
were O
the O
ones O
who O
had O
to O
bear O
the O
costs O
, O
as O
they O
had O
faced O
huge O
expenses O
to O
buy O
an O
apartment O
. O

Now O
there O
are O
still O
missing O
assets O
of O
Sica B-ORG
for O
a O
value O
of O
hundreds O
of O
thousands O
of O
euros O
. O

Among O
these O
a O
mechanical O
lathe O
of O
the O
value O
of O
200 O
thousand O
euros O
and O
a O
Porsche O
Carrera O
convertible O
. O

Tests O
say O
that O
the O
man O
arrested O
is O
not O
Saddam B-PER
's O
deputy O
. O

Kidnappers O
: O

" O
Give O
us O
5 O
million O
dollars O
" O

To O
free O
the O
two O
journalists O

Raffarin B-PER
: O

" O
We O
are O
not O
convinced O
" O
. O

the O
liberation O
of O
the O
two O
hostages O
, O
which O
seemed O
a O
done O
deal O
. O

For O
France B-LOC
it O
would O
obviously O
be O
a O
big O
snub O
if O
the O
communiqué O
is O
authentic O
: O

President O
Jacques B-PER
Chirac I-PER
defused O
, O
thanks O
to O
the O
extraordinary O
solidarity O
of O
the O
Arab O
world O
, O
the O
kidnappers O
' O
insidious O
blackmail O
on O
the O
anti O
- O
Islamic O
veil O
law O
at O
school O
( O
" O
Either O
you O
repeal O
it O
or O
we O
kill O
the O
two O
journalists O
" O
) O
. O

The O
skepticism O
expressed O
by O
Raffarin B-PER
on O
the O
authenticity O
of O
the O
document O
is O
based O
on O
several O
considerations O
. O

The O
warning O
to O
the O
French O
not O
to O
attack O
" O
as O
you O
did O
in O
Latifiya B-LOC
, O
the O
day O
we O
would O
have O
wanted O
to O
hand O
over O
" O
the O
hostages O
is O
also O
unbalanced O
. O

in O
Brief O

More O
works O
on O
Valsugana O

In O
order O
to O
allow O
extraordinary O
maintenance O
works O
of O
milling O
and O
bitumening O
, O
along O
the O
state O
road O
47 O
of O
Valsugana O
in O
the O
section O
between O
Marter B-LOC
and O
Trento B-LOC
, O
and O
precisely O
in O
the O
sections O
between O
km O
. O
100,5 O
and O
106 O
and O
km O
. O
118,3 O
and O
126,8 O
, O
a O
narrowing O
of O
the O
carriageway O
is O
established O
with O
reduction O
from O
two O
to O
one O
lane O
and O
the O
narrowing O
of O
lanes O
in O
the O
remaining O
sections O
with O
two O
lanes O
. O

The O
work O
must O
be O
completed O
by O
October O
14 O
. O

Last O
Monday O
the O
boys O
of O
the O
New O
Casa O
Serena O
, O
residential O
center O
Anffas B-ORG
Trentino I-ORG
onlus I-ORG
, O
had O
the O
pleasure O
to O
attend O
a O
beautiful O
demonstration O
of O
the O
State B-ORG
Police I-ORG
with O
a O
group O
of O
dogs O
, O
motorcycles O
, O
cars O
and O
minibus O
has O
animated O
and O
enlivened O
the O
morning O
of O
late O
summer O
. O

All O
the O
children O
present O
( O
several O
of O
them O
arrived O
for O
the O
occasion O
also O
from O
day O
care O
centers O
of O
Anffas B-ORG
of O
Trento B-LOC
) O
have O
appreciated O
in O
a O
particular O
way O
, O
responding O
with O
enthusiasm O
and O
great O
emotion O
. O

The O
profound O
sensitivity O
shown O
to O
the O
young O
people O
was O
striking O
, O
as O
they O
climbed O
on O
the O
motorcycles O
, O
activated O
the O
sirens O
or O
talked O
on O
the O
radio O
from O
the O
car O
, O
they O
felt O
like O
important O
actors O
, O
valued O
and O
welcomed O
with O
great O
warmth O
by O
the O
operators O
of O
the O
State B-ORG
Police I-ORG
. O

A O
warm O
thank O
you O
to O
all O
the O
operators O
of O
the O
State B-ORG
Police I-ORG
: O

to O
the O
Dog B-ORG
Training I-ORG
Center I-ORG
of O
Moena B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
Traffic B-ORG
Police O
of O
Trento B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
staff O
of O
the O
Police O
Headquarters B-ORG
, O
to O
the O
neighborhood O
police O
, O
to O
the O
Artificieri B-ORG
Department I-ORG
, O
to O
Dr. O
Morelli B-PER
, O
to O
Dr. O
Spirali B-PER
, O
to O
the O
Chief O
of O
Police O
of O
Trento B-LOC
for O
their O
availability O
and O
participation O
. O

The O
Crash O

The O
building O
contractor O
feels O
cheated O
by O
the O
accountant O
of O
Parma B-LOC
who O
had O
to O
save O
his O
company O

Chini B-PER
denounces O
Signifredi B-PER
for O
fraud O

L O
' O
buyer O
of O
the O
enterprise O
has O
not O
even O
paid O
the O
thousand O
euros O
agreed O
upon O

Chini B-PER
feels O
cheated O
by O
Paolo B-PER
Signifredi I-PER
. O

For O
this O
reason O
the O
' O
building O
contractor O
has O
filed O
a O
complaint O
against O
the O
accountant O
of O
Parma B-LOC
who O
had O
purchased O
the O
Chini B-ORG
construction I-ORG
for O
one O
thousand O
euros O
, O
money O
that O
, O
among O
other O
things O
, O
Signifredi B-PER
has O
never O
paid O
. O

Signifredi B-PER
a O
few O
days O
after O
the O
' O
purchase O
of O
Chini B-ORG
was O
arrested O
by O
the O
Guardia O
di O
Finanza O
because O
he O
had O
to O
serve O
a O
sentence O
of O
three O
years O
for O
receiving O
stolen O
goods O
and O
recycling O
of O
a O
' O
car O
. O

The O
arrest O
of O
Signifredi B-PER
precipitated O
the O
situation O
and O
in O
a O
few O
days O
the O
Court B-ORG
of I-ORG
Trento I-ORG
declared O
the O
bankruptcy O
of O
Chini B-ORG
. O

Subsequently O
Chini B-PER
decided O
to O
denounce O
Signifredi B-PER
. O

But O
the O
complaint O
for O
fraud O
is O
probably O
linked O
to O
a O
series O
of O
agreements O
that O
the O
two O
entrepreneurs O
had O
made O
. O

Chini B-PER
reproached O
Signifredi B-PER
for O
not O
having O
kept O
faith O
with O
the O
commitments O
, O
for O
having O
deceived O
him O
about O
the O
seriousness O
of O
his O
intentions O
. O

These O
were O
deals O
that O
would O
have O
definitively O
restored O
the O
Chini B-ORG
coffers O
. O

Businesses O
that O
could O
not O
be O
concluded O
due O
to O
bankruptcy O
. O

Now O
it O
is O
the O
curatorship O
that O
tries O
to O
draw O
the O
sums O
. O

Naturally O
, O
the O
revenues O
are O
likely O
to O
be O
much O
lower O
than O
in O
a O
normal O
management O
. O

L O
' O
arrest O
of O
the O
accountant O
, O
however O
, O
has O
blown O
up O
everything O
. O

For O
this O
reason O
Chini B-PER
felt O
cheated O
and O
decided O
to O
file O
a O
complaint O
. O

This O
would O
have O
, O
of O
course O
, O
also O
safeguarded O
the O
position O
of O
the O
same O
Chini B-PER
who O
later O
ended O
up O
under O
house O
arrest O
and O
is O
now O
still O
under O
investigation O
with O
his O
son O
with O
the O
charge O
of O
fraudulent O
bankruptcy O
. O

Chini B-PER
even O
risks O
to O
lose O
his O
house O
, O
since O
it O
is O
registered O
to O
his O
former O
company O
and O
now O
it O
could O
be O
sold O
at O
auction O
by O
the O
curator O
. O

The O
court B-ORG
of I-ORG
re I-ORG
- O
examination O
annulled O
the O
orders O
against O
Spagnolo B-PER
and O
Trentini B-PER
. O

Shot O
by O
Dusevich B-PER
, O
two O
released O

Gianfranco B-PER
Spagnolo I-PER
and O
Fulvio B-PER
Trentini I-PER
have O
been O
exonerated O
by O
the O
re O
- O
examination B-ORG
court I-ORG
for O
the O
hit O
in O
the O
Dusevich B-PER
house O
. O

The O
two O
are O
accused O
by O
the O
Carabinieri B-ORG
of O
having O
participated O
in O
the O
heist O
together O
with O
Walter B-PER
Zanetti I-PER
and O
Paul B-PER
John I-PER
Pallaoro I-PER
. O

According O
to O
what O
is O
contested O
by O
the O
Prosecutor B-ORG
's I-ORG
Office I-ORG
, O
the O
two O
would O
only O
have O
organized O
the O
hit O
, O
which O
would O
then O
have O
been O
carried O
out O
by O
the O
two O
accomplices O
, O
who O
have O
been O
recognized O
by O
two O
people O
. O

The O
witnesses O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
claimed O
that O
the O
two O
robbers O
moved O
inside O
their O
house O
with O
perfect O
knowledge O
of O
the O
places O
, O
so O
much O
so O
that O
they O
knew O
where O
the O
safe O
was O
. O

Therefore O
, O
he O
could O
not O
have O
participated O
in O
the O
renovation O
work O
in O
the O
Dusevich B-PER
house O
in O
recent O
times O
. O

He O
himself O
told O
the O
judge O
that O
he O
had O
done O
the O
work O
in O
1992 O
. O

Given O
the O
time O
elapsed O
, O
the O
judges O
doubt O
that O
Trentini B-PER
can O
be O
the O
source O
of O
information O
so O
detailed O
as O
to O
allow O
the O
robbers O
to O
move O
perfectly O
at O
ease O
in O
the O
Dusevich B-PER
house O
. O

Today O
at O
the O
Cinema O

" O
La O
mala O
educacion O
" O
( O
The O
Bad O
Education O
) O
is O
the O
story O
of O
a O
director O
who O
investigates O
pedophile O
behavior O
and O
sexual O
violence O
that O
he O
suffered O
from O
a O
priest O
in O
the O
college O
where O
he O
grew O
up O
as O
a O
child O
. O

Bitter O
film O
, O
cruel O
and O
raw O
, O
set O
in O
a O
Francoist O
and O
ultra O
- O
Catholic O
Spain B-LOC
of O
the O
sixties O
, O
according O
to O
the O
director O
is O
, O
however O
, O
only O
" O
a O
film O
about O
homosexuality O
. O

( O
in O
the O
photo O
, O
a O
scene O
from O
the O
film O
) O
. O

The O
life O
I O
want O

by O
Giuseppe B-PER
Piccioni I-PER
, O
with O
Luigi B-PER
Lo I-PER
Cascio I-PER
and O
Sandra B-PER
Ceccarelli I-PER
who O
live O
a O
love O
story O
inside O
the O
set O
of O
a O
costume O
film O
and O
in O
real O
life O
. O

A O
film O
about O
making O
films O
, O
quoting O
Truffaut B-PER
. O

Rediscovered O
Love O

The O
story O
: O

Garfield O
's O
owner O
brings O
home O
an O
adorable O
puppy O
dog O
named O
Odie O
. O

At O
first O
Garfield O
does O
not O
agree O
with O
the O
entry O
of O
a O
new O
tenant O
in O
the O
house O
, O
but O
when O
little O
Odie O
is O
kidnapped O
, O
he O
will O
do O
anything O
to O
find O
him O
. O

For O
kids O
. O

Who O
questions O
himself O
about O
his O
mission O
. O

But O
there O
is O
no O
shortage O
of O
special O
effects O
. O

First B-ORG
Category I-ORG

THE O
PEOPLE O
/ O
" O
The O
company O
aims O
to O
jump O
category O
: O

It O
has O
invested O
a O
lot O
and O
does O
not O
make O
us O
miss O
anything O
. O

Ceraso B-PER
, O
the O
great O
challenge O
: O

" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion B-ORG

L O
' O
ambitious O
Torbole B-ORG
entrusts O
its O
bench O
to O
a O
luxury O
rookie O

For O
Massimiliano B-PER
Ceraso I-PER
( O
pictured O
) O
, O
bomber O
race O
with O
a O
past O
of O
all O
respect O
between O
the O
ranks O
of O
Benacense B-ORG
, O
Arco B-ORG
, O
Rovereto B-ORG
and O
Borgo B-ORG
has O
begun O
a O
new O
career O
. O

That O
of O
coach O
, O
with O
a O
very O
precise O
task O
: O

To O
bring O
the O
Torbole B-ORG
in O
Promozione B-ORG
. O

After O
three O
second O
places O
in O
a O
row O
( O
behind O
Calcio B-ORG
Bleggio I-ORG
in O
2002 O
, O
Dro B-ORG
in O
2003 O
and O
Monte B-ORG
Baldo I-ORG
in O
2004 O
) O
the O
association O
presided O
over O
by O
Pietro B-PER
Addeo I-PER
is O
in O
fact O
the O
logical O
favorite O
to O
win O
the O
first O
place O
. O

" O
It O
's O
an O
exciting O
adventure O
, O
we O
are O
aware O
that O
the O
company O
aims O
to O
jump O
category O
. O

He O
has O
invested O
a O
lot O
and O
we O
do O
not O
miss O
anything O
. O

" O
Passing O
in O
a O
couple O
of O
months O
from O
the O
field O
to O
the O
bench O
requires O
a O
considerable O
change O
of O
mentality O
. O

Fortunately O
, O
things O
went O
well O
in O
the O
pre O
- O
season O
and O
that O
made O
my O
job O
easier O
. O

Which O
are O
the O
teams O
you O
fear O
the O
most O
? O

" O
Pieve B-ORG
di I-ORG
Bono I-ORG
is O
surely O
a O
very O
good O
team O
, O
that O
runs O
a O
lot O
and O
with O
technically O
valid O
players O
. O

Calavino B-ORG
and O
Isera B-ORG
have O
all O
the O
potential O
to O
do O
well O
, O
then O
there O
is O
Pinzolo B-ORG
Campiglio I-ORG
which O
is O
a O
bit O
of O
a O
loose O
cannon O
. O

What O
are O
the O
problems O
that O
you O
are O
encountering O
as O
a O
coach O
? O

" O
The O
problems O
will O
begin O
to O
come O
when O
the O
results O
do O
not O
arrive O
. O

So O
far O
there O
have O
been O
no O
hiccups O
. O

However O
, O
it O
is O
in O
times O
of O
difficulty O
that O
you O
can O
see O
the O
quality O
of O
a O
team O
and O
consequently O
of O
its O
coach O
. O

61st O
INTERNATIONAL O
CINEMA O
SHOW O
IN O
VENICE O

Religion O
at O
the O
Venice O
Film O
Festival O

A O
new O
film O
taken O
from O
the O
archives O
of O
the O
Istituto B-ORG
Luce I-ORG
and O
the O
Biennale B-ORG
" O
to O
document O
the O
folly O
of O
religious O
wars O
and O
indicate O
the O
path O
to O
follow O
, O
which O
is O
that O
of O
coexistence O
among O
different O
religions O
. O

This O
is O
what O
the O
Minister O
of O
Cultural O
Heritage O
Giuliano B-PER
Urbani I-PER
proposes O
to O
suggest O
in O
light O
of O
the O
tragic O
events O
of O
recent O
days O
in O
Ossetia B-LOC
. O

Nicole B-PER
's O
scandal O

Here O
comes O
" O
Birth O
" O
, O
the O
long O
- O
awaited O
film O
by O
Jonathan B-PER
Glazer I-PER
with O
the O
superdiva O
Nicole B-PER
Kidman I-PER
in O
odor O
of O
scandal O
, O
but O
the O
incriminated O
scene O
, O
the O
one O
that O
sees O
the O
Oscar O
- O
winning O
actress O
naked O
in O
the O
bathtub O
with O
a O
child O
of O
10 O
years O
, O
in O
the O
end O
, O
despite O
everything O
, O
is O
not O
really O
scandalous O
: O

the O
little O
one O
enters O
the O
room O
with O
already O
Kidman B-PER
( O
Anna B-PER
) O
in O
the O
water O
, O
stops O
a O
meter O
from O
the O
tub O
, O
gets O
undressed O
, O
but O
then O
everything O
fades O
. O

For O
ordinary O
mortals O
, O
we O
will O
have O
to O
wait O
for O
the O
release O
in O
February O
. O

No O
Clooney B-PER
No O
party O

George B-PER
Clooney I-PER
will O
not O
be O
attending O
the O
Festival O
. O

Briatore B-PER
's O
favorite O
movies O

Flavio B-PER
Briatore I-PER
, O
the O
Formula B-ORG
1 I-ORG
manager O
who O
is O
better O
known O
for O
his O
collection O
of O
women O
than O
for O
his O
collection O
of O
grand O
prix O
victories O
, O
talks O
about O
cinema O
in O
this O
way O
: O

" O
I O
love O
films O
that O
I O
understand O
, O
those O
that O
make O
me O
laugh O
or O
adventure O
films O
or O
documentaries O
. O

I O
do O
n't O
like O
dramas O
where O
the O
children O
are O
sick O
or O
the O
wives O
are O
handicapped O
. O

NORDIC O
SKIING O
/ O
The O
Marcialonga O
, O
even O
if O
4 O
months O
are O
missing O
, O
has O
already O
1500 O
subscribers O

Paruzzi B-PER
godmother O
, O
Giorgio B-PER
Di I-PER
Centa I-PER
to O
win O

It O
's O
already O
time O
to O
dust O
off O
your O
skis O
, O
prepare O
your O
wax O
and O
? O

register O
for O
the O
Marcialonga O
. O

1.500 O
people O
have O
already O
done O
so O
when O
there O
are O
less O
than O
4 O
months O
to O
January O
30 O
, O
2005 O
. O

Last O
year O
, O
for O
the O
first O
time O
as O
a O
World O
Cup O
race O
, O
the O
Marcialonga O
gathered O
3.733 O
classified O
athletes O
at O
the O
finishing O
line O
, O
but O
in O
total O
the O
number O
of O
registered O
athletes O
amounted O
to O
4.378 O
. O

The O
32nd O
edition O
will O
be O
marked O
by O
Gabriella B-PER
Paruzzi I-PER
, O
the O
winner O
of O
the O
2004 O
World O
Cup O
who O
, O
thanks O
to O
the O
victory O
of O
the O
last O
Marcialonga O
, O
has O
had O
the O
incentive O
to O
aim O
at O
a O
great O
result O
in O
the O
Cup O
. O

The O
champion O
from O
Tarvisio O
has O
become O
, O
and O
it O
could O
not O
be O
otherwise O
, O
the O
testimonial O
and O
the O
ambassador O
of O
the O
granfondo O
on O
skis O
that O
has O
made O
the O
history O
of O
Italian O
cross O
- O
country O
skiing O
. O

In O
all O
likelihood O
there O
will O
be O
also O
Giorgio B-PER
Di I-PER
Centa I-PER
, O
second O
last O
January O
" O
trapped O
" O
between O
the O
two O
Aukland B-PER
brothers O
. O

" O
D O
' O
agreement O
with O
the O
trainer O
Chenetti B-PER
I O
put O
in O
calendar O
the O
Marcialonga O
. O

This O
year O
I O
want O
to O
win O
it O
, O
it O
's O
a O
race O
too O
important O
for O
me O
" O
, O
declared O
the O
Friulian O
. O

SOCIETY O
& O
CULTURE O

Trento B-LOC
: O

Popular B-ORG
University I-ORG
exhibition O

Sixty O
years O
ago O
, O
the O
Popular B-ORG
University I-ORG
of O
Trento O
was O
born O
in O
Trento O
. O

In O
these O
days O
is O
open O
, O
at O
the O
Palazzo O
della O
Regione O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Dante I-LOC
, O
the O
" O
Painting O
Exhibition O
" O
of O
the O
students O
of O
yesterday O
and O
today O
of O
Prof. O
Perilli B-PER
. O

It O
closes O
tomorrow O
, O
Saturday O
, O
October O
9 O
, O
at O
12 O
noon O
. O

Riva B-LOC
del I-LOC
Garda I-LOC
: O

third O
age O

" O
5th O
Gold O
Age O
" O
. O
International O
Forum O
of O
the O
Third O
Age O
. O

Until O
Monday O
, O
October O
11 O
at O
Palacongressi O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

flavors O
, O
9 O
am O
- O
8 O
pm O

The O
traditional O
" O
Piazza O
dei O
Sapori O
" O
returns O
, O
stands O
of O
typical O
regional O
products O
. O

Until O
Sunday O
from O
9 O
am O
to O
8 O
pm O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Fiera I-LOC
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

Ecumenism O
, O
9.30 O
am O

It O
will O
continue O
tomorrow O
morning O
at O
9.30 O
am O
at O
the O
Istituto O
Trentino O
di O
Cultura O
, O
in O
via B-LOC
S. I-LOC
Croce I-LOC
77 I-LOC
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

Developmental O
Age O
, O
9.30 O
am O

Conference O
of O
the O
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Cognitive I-ORG
and I-ORG
Educational I-ORG
Sciences I-ORG
on O
" O
The O
forms O
of O
discomfort O
. O

Stress O
: O

Causes O
and O
manifestations O
in O
developmental O
age O
" O
. O

Via B-LOC
Matteo I-LOC
del I-LOC
Ben I-LOC
, O
Room O
1 O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

Mental O
Health O
, O
2 O
p.m. O

Comparing O
experiences O
" O
. O

Today O
, O
Giuseppe B-PER
Lumia I-PER
( O
rapporteur O
of O
a O
draft O
law O
on O
mental O
health O
) O
and O
contributions O
to O
several O
voices O
on O
" O
doing O
together O
" O
. O

At O
9 O
p.m. O
, O
expressive O
, O
theatrical O
and O
singing O
proposals O
from O
groups O
, O
associations O
, O
centers O
, O
cooperatives O
. O

The O
work O
continues O
tomorrow O
morning O
at O
9 O
am O
. O

At O
the O
Sala O
della O
Cooperazione O
in O
Via B-LOC
Segantini I-LOC
10 I-LOC
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

The O
show O
, O
3 O
pm O

The O
interregional B-ORG
delegation I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Tre O
Venezie O
of O
the O
Associazione B-ORG
Generale I-ORG
Italiana I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Spettacolo I-ORG
( O
Agis B-ORG
) O
proposes O
the O
seminar O
" O
For O
a O
new O
entertainment O
policy O
" O
. O

The O
seminar O
will O
be O
chaired O
by O
Carlo O
Fait O
, O
president O
of O
the O
Centro B-ORG
S. I-ORG
Chiara I-ORG
. O

With O
Lorenzo B-PER
Dellai I-PER
and O
Alberto B-PER
Pacher I-PER
, O
the O
Councillor O
for O
Culture O
Margherita B-PER
Cogo I-PER
will O
introduce O
the O
seminar O
. O

Followed O
by O
speeches O
by O
superintendents O
, O
regional O
and O
municipal O
councillors O
, O
politicians O
, O
artists O
. O

Among O
them O
, O
the O
superintendent O
of O
the O
Rome B-ORG
Opera I-ORG
Francesco B-PER
Ernani I-PER
and O
the O
director O
of O
" O
Opera B-ORG
Europa I-ORG
" O
, O
Nicholas B-PER
Payne I-PER
. O
Nicholas O
Payne O
. O

The O
director O
Mario B-PER
Martone I-PER
will O
also O
take O
part O
in O
the O
debate O
. O

Arco B-LOC
: O

Astra O
, O
3 O
pm O

Returning O
for O
the O
25th O
time O
, O
" O
Astra O
" O
, O
the O
international O
astrology O
conference O
. O
International O
conference O
of O
astrology O
on O
the O
theme O
" O
Actuality O
of O
ancient O
mysteries O
" O
. O

At O
the O
Casino O
. O

Arco B-LOC
: O

Quisisana O
, O
5 O
pm O

" O
The O
changing O
city O
. O

At O
Palazzo O
dei O
Panni O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

Tales O
, O
5 O
p.m. O

Paolo B-PER
Tognolatti I-PER
presents O
the O
volume O
of O
short O
stories O
" O
Bagliori O
" O
by O
Giovanni B-PER
Duca I-PER
( O
Ed B-ORG
. O

Arca B-ORG
- O
Trento B-LOC
2004 O
) O
. O

Voice O
of O
Giliola B-PER
Galvagni I-PER
. O

At O
the O
" O
Rosmini O
" O
Center O
in O
via B-LOC
Dordi I-LOC
8 I-LOC
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

The O
paintings O
of O
Debiasi B-PER
, O
5.30 O
pm O

Appointment O
at O
17.30 O

Trento B-LOC
: O

Morando B-PER
, O
at O
18 O

Meeting O
with O
the O
senator O
Ds B-ORG
Enrico B-PER
Morando I-PER
on O
the O
theme O
" O
The O
proposals O
of O
the O
Riformisti O
for O
the O
Federation O
and O
the O
reforms O
" O
. O

Hotel O
America O
, O
via B-LOC
Torre I-LOC
Verde I-LOC
52 I-LOC
. O

Villa B-LOC
Lagarina I-LOC
: O

party O
, O
hours O
19 O
- O
23 O

For O
three O
days O
, O
in O
the O
squares O
, O
in O
the O
courtyards O
, O
in O
the O
vaults O
, O
shows O
, O
food O
and O
wine O
, O
guided O
tours O
for O
the O
" O
Festa O
del O
Borgoantico O
" O
. O

Trent B-LOC
: O

prayer O
, O
19.30 O

" O
Universal O
Life O
" O
proposes O
the O
meeting O
" O
Inner O
prayer O
: O

A O
force O
to O
radiate O
positive O
energies O
on O
earth O
. O

Hotel O
Everest O
in O
Corso B-LOC
Alpini I-LOC
16 I-LOC
. O

Gardolo B-LOC
: O

party O
at O
the O
oratory O
, O
8 O
pm O

The O
three O
days O
of O
the O
" O
Festa O
dell O
' O
oratorio O
" O
begin O
today O
in O
Gardolo B-LOC
. O

It O
begins O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
with O
the O
Holy O
Rosary O
. O

At O
the O
end O
, O
at O
9 O
p.m. O
, O
distribution O
of O
pasta O
, O
followed O
by O
music O
and O
dancing O
. O

Tomorrow O
afternoon O
, O
at O
15 O
, O
the O
non O
- O
competitive O
march O
" O
Up O
and O
zo O
for O
Gardol O
" O
The O
festival O
will O
continue O
throughout O
the O
afternoon O
. O

Trent B-LOC
: O

Parents O
, O
Solteri B-LOC
, O
8.15 O
p.m. O

Meeting O
of O
the O
Parents B-ORG
' I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
of O
the B-ORG
Solteri I-ORG
elementary I-ORG
school I-ORG
on O
: O

activities O
, O
canteen O
commission O
, O
school B-ORG
council I-ORG
elections O
. O

Elementary O
School O
main O
hall O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

Prano O
, O
8.30 O
p.m. O

Information O
: O

328.7065165 O
- O
348.2399999 O
( O
Luisa B-PER
Piccolroaz I-PER
0464.434209 O
) O
. O

Sopramonte B-LOC
: O

the O
Vela B-LOC
, O
8.30 O
p.m. O

Inauguration O
of O
the O
exhibition O
" O
Lungo O
il O
torrente O
Vela O
" O
, O
photographs O
of O
the O
group O
" O
La B-ORG
Regola I-ORG
" O
of O
Cadine B-LOC
. O

Until O
Sunday O
, O
October O
17 O
, O
every O
weekend O
: O

Saturday O
9 O
and O
16 O
, O
6 O
- O
9.30 O
p.m. O
, O
Sunday O
10 O
and O
17 O
, O
10 O
- O
12 O
a.m. O
and O
3 O
- O
7 O
p.m. O
. O

Next O
Friday O
, O
October O
15 O
, O
18 O
- O
21.30 O
hours O
. O

At O
the O
multipurpose O
room O
of O
the O
Oratory O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

Diabetes O
, O
8.30 O
p.m. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

Critical O
consumption O
, O
8.30 O
pm O

Screening O
of O
the O
film O
" O
Forest O
medicine O
: O

Tiziana B-PER
Andretti I-PER
will O
illustrate O
the O
" O
didactic O
gardens O
" O
. O

At O
the O
Sala O
della O
Roggia O
. O
