Today O
meeting O
at O
the O
Centro O
S. O
Chiara O

Breast O
milk O
, O
sos O
di O
Pedrotti B-PER

Only O
60 O
% O
to O
70 O
% O
of O
Trentino O
mothers O
breast O
- O
feed O
their O
children O
after O
4 O
months O
of O
age O
. O

The O
first O
week O
of O
October O
was O
declared O
an O
international O
week O
of O
breast O
- O
feeding O
. O

Today O
at O
5.30 O
p.m. O
at O
the O
Cultural O
Center O
S. O
Chiara O
we O
will O
talk O
about O
breastfeeding O
in O
Trentino B-LOC
, O
moms O
with O
many O
doubts O
, O
babies O
who O
are O
not O
always O
guaranteed O
the O
right O
to O
better O
nutrition O
. O

Dino B-PER
Pedrotti I-PER
will O
talk O
about O
these O
problems O
. O

But O
soon O
after O
I O
wish O
I O
had O
so O
many O
cuddles O
and O
a O
lot O
of O
mom O
's O
milk O
. O

Alderman O
Andreolli B-PER
will O
be O
present O
. O

Where O
can O
mothers O
find O
help O
in O
case O
of O
difficulty O
? O

At O
four O
months O
60 O
to O
70 O
% O
of O
Trentino O
mothers O
breast O
- O
feeding O
. O

In O
Scandinavia B-LOC
breast O
- O
feeding O
mothers O
at O
80 O
to O
90 O
% O
. O

This O
is O
the O
objective O
we O
are O
aiming O
for O
and O
which O
we O
must O
achieve O
. O

In O
order O
to O
help O
mothers O
in O
difficulty O
, O
the O
Friends B-ORG
of I-ORG
Trentino I-ORG
Neonatology I-ORG
published O
a O
brochure O
with O
many O
updated O
advices O
, O
" O
The O
ABC O
of O
Mother O
's O
Nursing O
" O
, O
distributed O
on O
the O
occasion O
of O
the O
meeting O
. O

University B-ORG

The O
President O
shall O
: O

♪ O
As O
long O
as O
they O
want O
me O
I O
'm O
there O
♪ O

OF O
ANDREA B-PER
TOMASI I-PER

As O
long O
as O
they O
want O
me O
, O
I O
'm O
there O
. O

He O
gave O
his O
own O
availability O
and O
the O
premises O
for O
his O
confirmation O
are O
all O
there O
. O

Estimated O
by O
the O
president O
of O
the O
provincial B-ORG
council I-ORG
Lorenzo B-PER
Dellai I-PER
, O
in O
excellent O
relations O
with O
the O
outgoing O
rector O
Massimo B-PER
Egidi I-PER
, O
seems O
to O
be O
appreciated O
by O
a O
good O
part O
of O
the O
local O
academic O
world O
. O

The O
developments O
will O
be O
known O
in O
the O
next O
few O
days O
, O
since O
the O
cda B-ORG
has O
reached O
its O
natural O
deadline O
and O
the O
nominations O
to O
the O
new O
council B-ORG
will O
have O
to O
be O
formalized O
by O
Tuesday O
, O
and O
then O
arrive O
at O
the O
election O
of O
the O
teachers O
on O
the O
27th O
of O
the O
month O
. O

Inside O
the O
university O
there O
are O
those O
who O
think O
that O
Onions B-PER
can O
be O
the O
right O
person O
for O
that O
charge O
, O
given O
its O
history O
and O
strong O
ties O
with O
the O
world O
of O
Italian O
industry O
. O

62 O
years O
old O
, O
a O
degree O
in O
statistical O
science O
at O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Rome I-ORG
, O
was O
recently O
appointed O
to O
the O
presidency O
of O
the O
Sole24Ore B-ORG
Group I-ORG
. O

A O
commitment O
that O
- O
he O
says O
- O
will O
not O
prevent O
him O
from O
continuing O
to O
lead O
the O
sessions O
of O
the O
cda B-ORG
of O
the O
University O
of O
Trentino O
. O

This O
new O
assignment O
- O
he O
explains O
- O
absorbs O
much O
of O
my O
time O
, O
but O
time O
is O
elastic O
and O
I O
am O
willing O
to O
continue O
the O
collaboration O
with O
the O
university O
, O
assuming O
that O
they O
want O
me O
. O

It O
will O
divide O
between O
Rome B-LOC
, O
Milan B-LOC
and O
Trento B-LOC
. O

At O
the O
Italian O
level O
the O
cuts O
make O
life O
more O
difficult O
: O

There O
are O
rules O
that O
are O
too O
strict O
. O

In O
Trentino B-LOC
, O
thanks O
to O
autonomy O
, O
things O
are O
much O
better O
. O

In O
his O
view O
, O
more O
and O
more O
emphasis O
should O
be O
placed O
on O
scientific O
research O
: O

The O
University B-ORG
has O
its O
own O
expertise O
. O

In O
Trentino B-LOC
we O
talk O
about O
the O
construction O
of O
a O
district O
of O
hydrogen O
and O
renewable O
energy O
. O

Is O
this O
the O
sector O
to O
be O
invested O
in O
? O

The O
issue O
is O
complex O
. O

The O
speech O
applies O
both O
to O
academia O
and O
business O
. O

Renewable O
energy O
is O
a O
key O
road O
, O
but O
there O
is O
also O
room O
for O
other O
sectors O
. O

When O
we O
talk O
about O
the O
University O
of O
Trentino O
we O
talk O
about O
the O
fundamental O
role O
that O
have O
had O
the O
funding O
of O
the O
Province B-LOC
. O

Then O
there O
are O
research O
projects O
at O
national O
level O
. O

But O
can O
economic O
support O
come O
from O
private O
enterprise O
in O
the O
future O
? O

I O
believe O
that O
private O
individuals O
will O
never O
give O
too O
much O
to O
research O
. O

Yes O
, O
they O
can O
come O
and O
they O
must O
come O
contributions O
also O
from O
companies O
, O
but O
their O
role O
is O
another O
: O

Collio B-PER
will O
make O
the O
100 O
, O
Longo B-PER
the O
800 O
and O
Martinez B-PER
the O
triple O
. O

Among O
the O
regional O
, O
Berlanda B-PER
and O
Niederstätter B-PER

The O
golds O
of O
Athens O
will O
illuminate O
the O
night O

Devonish B-PER
, O
Bailey B-PER
and O
all O
the O
protagonists O
race O
for O
race O

The O
Kenyan O
Sambu B-PER
is O
a O
nice O
little O
guy O
( O
45 O
" O
33 O
" O
) O
. O

Andrea B-PER
Barberi I-PER
( O
45 O
" O
98 O
) O
is O
the O
best O
of O
ours O
. O

800 O
METRES O
/ O
The O
Olympic O
semifinalist O
Andrea B-PER
Longo I-PER
( O
1 O
' O
44 O
" O
42 O
season O
, O
1 O
' O
43 O
" O
74 O
in O
2000 O
) O
against O
all O
; O

The O
Belgian O
Som B-PER
is O
scary O
( O
1 O
' O
44 O
" O
37 O
) O
but O
they O
do O
n't O
even O
joke O
the O
Kenyans O
Wachira B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
45 O
" O
13 O
) O
and O
Yego B-PER
( O
silver O
at O
the O
junior O
World O
Championships O
) O
and O
Sudanese O
Ismail B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
45 O
" O
17 O
) O
. O

In O
the O
B B-ORG
series I-ORG
, O
the O
South O
Tyrolean O
Neunhauserer B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
46 O
" O
07 O
in O
2002 O
) O
and O
Rifesser B-PER
( O
18 O
years O
, O
1 O
' O
51 O
" O
18 O
) O
. O

The O
South O
Tyrolean O
Crepaz B-PER
( O
50 O
" O
68 O
) O
will O
try O
. O

5.000 O
MACHINE O
/ O
Passerella O
for O
Ivano B-PER
Brugnetti I-PER
, O
Athens O
gold O
in O
the O
20th O
, O
which O
on O
this O
distance O
has O
a O
staff O
of O
19 O
' O
43 O
" O
24 O
( O
2003 O
) O
. O

They O
'll O
crown O
him O
with O
all O
the O
other O
blues O
. O

WEIGHT O
/ O
The O
angry O
non O
- O
Olympic O
from B-PER
the I-PER
Sun I-PER
( O
20.19 O
) O
against O
the O
Belarusian O
Belov B-PER
( O
21.14 O
, O
6th O
in O
Athens O
) O
. O

GIAVELLOT O
/ O
Two O
Lithuanians O
on O
the O
cover O
: O

Watch O
out O
for O
the O
other O
American O
Kenta B-PER
Bell I-PER
( O
17.58 O
) O
. O

In O
the O
B B-ORG
series I-ORG
there O
is O
Doris B-PER
Tomasini I-PER
oak O
( O
24 O
" O
12 O
, O
4 O
a O
alle O
Italiani O
) O
. O

800 O
METRI O
/ O
Slovenian O
Ceplak B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
55 O
" O
19 O
) O
pocketed O
the O
Olympic O
bronze O
and O
is O
the O
current O
European O
champion O
. O

1,500 O
METERS O
/ O
The O
Ukrainian O
Sidorenko B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
04 O
" O
78 O
) O
and O
the O
kenian O
Lagat B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
05 O
" O
32 O
) O
will O
take O
the O
exam O
at O
the O
Trentino O
Berlanda B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
12 O
" O
80 O
, O
Italian O
champion O
) O
and O
Dal B-PER
Ri I-PER
( O
4 O
' O
23 O
" O
84 O
) O
and O
the O
South O
Tyrolean O
Weissteiner B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
16 O
" O
6 O
manual O
) O
and O
Tschurtschenthaler B-PER
( O
4 O
' O
20 O
" O
65 O
) O
. O

400 O
OSTACOLI O
/ O
La O
6 O
a O
( O
Bikert B-PER
, O
Russian O
, O
53 O
" O
72 O
) O
and O
the O
7 O
a O
of O
Athens O
( O
Taylor B-PER
, O
US O
, O
53 O
" O
36 O
) O
plus O
the O
World O
Silver O
2003 O
( O
Glover B-PER
, O
US O
, O
53 O
" O
33 O
) O
against O
the O
South O
Tyrolean O
Niederstätter B-PER
( O
55 O
" O
52 O
, O
Italian O
primatist O
since O
' O
99 O
with O
55 O
" O
10 O
) O
. O

ASTA O
/ O
Olympic O
rematch O
between O
the O
3rd O
in O
Athens O
( O
the O
Polish O
Anna B-PER
Rogowska I-PER
, O
4.71 O
) O
, O
the O
4th O
in O
( O
the O
other O
Polish O
Pirek B-PER
, O
4.72 O
) O
and O
the O
5th O
in O
( O
the O
Icelandic O
Elisdottir B-PER
, O
4.60 O
) O
. O

And O
there O
is O
also O
the O
Trentino O
Bresciani B-PER
( O
4.20 O
, O
Italian O
champion O
) O
. O

the O
blue O
Martinez B-PER
( O
7 O
to O
, O
14.85 O
, O
but O
a O
staff O
of O
15.03 O
) O
, O
the O
Algerian O
Rahouli B-PER
( O
6 O
to O
, O
14.89 O
) O
and O
the O
Russian O
Pyatykh B-PER
( O
8 O
to O
, O
14.85 O
also O
her O
) O
. O

Outside O
the O
21 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Simona B-PER
La I-PER
Mantia I-PER
( O
14.49 O
) O
. O

G. B-PER
La. I-PER

A O
new O
layout O
in O
the O
property O

THE O
ACTIONISTS O

Here O
is O
the O
new O
list O
of O
shareholders O
of O
Euregio B-ORG
Finance I-ORG
: O

It O
was O
established O
on O
3 O
October O
2003 O
by O
Alpenair B-ORG
and O
Dutch O
finance O
Olot B-ORG
Bv I-ORG
. O

Telematics O
stock O
exchange O

The O
good O
verve O
of O
Wall B-ORG
Street I-ORG
failed O
to O
give O
the O
right O
pitch O
to O
Piazza B-ORG
Affari I-ORG
that O
stores O
the O
day O
of O
negotiations O
in O
decline O
. O

At O
the O
end O
, O
the O
Mibtel O
fell O
by O
0.16 O
% O
and O
the O
Mib30 O
by O
0.19 O
% O
. O

It O
makes O
worse O
the O
Numtel O
, O
in O
bending O
of O
0,58 O
% O
. O

Trade O
amounted O
to O
EUR O
2,263 O
billion O
. O

Day O
of O
sales O
for O
credit O
institutions O
in O
Piazza B-ORG
Affari I-ORG
, O
which O
weighed O
on O
the O
whole O
list O
. O

Banca B-ORG
Intesa I-ORG
sold O
1,83 O
% O
and O
the O
People B-ORG
of I-ORG
Verona I-ORG
and I-ORG
Novara I-ORG
0.5 O
% O
. O

Also O
weak O
Capitalia B-ORG
, O
in O
bending O
of O
1,65 O
% O
, O
as O
well O
as O
Bnl B-ORG
( O
- O
1,68 O
% O
) O
, O
while O
it O
moved O
in O
countertrend O
Mps B-ORG
( O
+ O
0,28 O
% O
) O
. O

Down O
also O
Antoveneta B-ORG
( O
- O
1.67 O
% O
) O
, O
lower O
loss O
for O
Unicredito B-ORG
( O
- O
0.25 O
% O
) O
. O

Contrast O
insurance O
: O

Generals O
closed O
with O
a O
rise O
of O
0.59 O
% O
, O
Ras O
with O
a O
decrease O
of O
0.31 O
% O
. O

Still O
nervous O
for O
the O
Alitalia B-ORG
securities O
, O
which O
closed O
unchanged O
( O
- O
0.04 O
% O
) O
after O
having O
fluctuated O
between O
a O
decrease O
of O
2.7 O
% O
and O
a O
rise O
of O
2.25 O
% O
. O

Positive O
sitting O
, O
on O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
for O
Fiat B-ORG
, O
with O
a O
progress O
of O
0.67 O
% O
at O
6,191 O
euros O
. O

Limate O
the O
Enels O
( O
- O
0.02 O
% O
) O
, O
decided O
to O
decrease O
for O
Saipem B-ORG
( O
- O
2.67 O
% O
) O
. O

Among O
the O
titles O
of O
telecommunications O
, O
Tim B-ORG
closed O
the O
session O
with O
a O
fall O
of O
0.45 O
% O
. O

Well O
set O
, O
instead O
, O
the O
Telecoms O
, O
up O
by O
0.8 O
% O
. O

ROME B-LOC
- O
It O
has O
been O
since O
August O
30 O
that O
was O
no O
longer O
shot O
in O
Nassiriya B-LOC
. O

And O
yesterday O
the O
Kalashnikovs O
came O
back O
to O
be O
heard O
. O

An O
hour O
of O
shooting O
, O
but O
no O
Italian O
military O
was O
injured O
: O

The O
attack O
took O
place O
at O
21 O
( O
at O
19 O
in O
Italy B-LOC
) O
, O
6 O
kilometers O
north O
- O
west O
of O
Nassiriya B-LOC
. O

Against O
the O
Italian O
military O
were O
fired O
numerous O
shots O
of O
automatic O
weapons O
coming O
from O
three O
directions O
, O
north O
, O
south O
and O
west O
. O

The O
soldiers O
of O
the O
Friuli B-ORG
Brigade I-ORG
immediately O
responded O
to O
the O
fire O
and O
, O
immediately O
after O
, O
since O
the O
shooting O
continued O
, O
two O
rates O
of O
the O
Rapid B-ORG
Reaction I-ORG
Force I-ORG
were O
brought O
in O
with O
four O
blind O
Centauro O
and O
eight O
other O
means O
( O
6 O
Vcc O
and O
2 O
Vm O
tracks O
) O
protected O
. O

In O
flight O
also O
two O
helicopters O
to O
identify O
the O
places O
where O
the O
shots O
came O
from O
. O

Late O
in O
the O
evening O
everything O
was O
quiet O
. O

On O
the O
bridge O
, O
guarded O
by O
Italian O
soldiers O
, O
the O
circulation O
has O
been O
reopened O
. O

Colonel O
Carmelo B-PER
Abysso I-PER
is O
not O
surprised O
at O
the O
warm O
welcome O
received O
from O
the O
men O
of O
Friuli B-ORG
by O
the O
so O
- O
called O
guerrilla O
. O

Presented O
the O
2004 O
edition O
: O

" O
Journey O
in O
differences O
" O
, O
the O
actress O
on O
the O
jury O

" O
We O
want O
to O
promote O
the O
awareness O
that O
the O
existing O
differences O
" O
under O
one O
sky O
" O
- O
title O
and O
inspiration O
of O
the O
two O
previous O
editions O
- O
are O
a O
richness O
and O
an O
indispensable O
heritage O
of O
the O
human O
race O
, O
" O
explained O
yesterday O
in O
press O
conference O
Fr O
Massimo B-PER
Manservigi I-PER
, O
president O
of O
the O
Festival O
: O

Only O
after O
having O
determined O
exactly O
its O
identity O
and O
that O
of O
its O
interlocutors O
can O
we O
find O
a O
real O
way O
to O
understanding O
and O
dialogue O
. O

At O
the O
center O
of O
the O
event O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
is O
the O
competition O
among O
the O
29 O
films O
on O
topic O
, O
documentaries O
and O
short O
films O
on O
religious O
theme O
selected O
from O
among O
the O
102 O
works O
sent O
by O
various O
nations O
, O
in O
competition O
for O
the O
Grand O
Prix O
" O
In O
the O
Spirit O
of O
the O
Faith O
, O
" O
for O
the O
primacy O
in O
the O
respective O
sections O
and O
for O
the O
special O
awards O
instituted O
in O
concert O
with O
various O
bodies O
and O
religious O
foundations O
. O

The O
international O
jury O
consists O
of O
5 O
experts O
in O
cinema O
, O
cultures O
and O
religions O
: O

Among O
the O
29 O
films O
in O
competition O
, O
with O
an O
important O
participation O
of O
the O
Orthodox O
Christian O
world O
and O
the O
Shiite O
and O
Sunni O
Islamic O
world O
, O
stands O
the O
section O
of O
the O
subject O
films O
, O
which O
boasts O
the O
presence O
of O
" O
The O
Passion O
" O
by O
Mel B-PER
Gibson I-PER
, O
at O
his O
first O
festival O
; O

There O
are O
many O
side O
initiatives O
dedicated O
to O
art O
as O
well O
: O

from O
the O
exhibition O
of O
Ucai B-ORG
artists O
dedicated O
to O
" O
Chiara O
d'Assisi O
. O

Light O
of O
the O
perennial O
light O
" O
( O
at O
the O
Centro O
Bernardo O
Clesio O
) O
, O
at O
the O
exposition O
of O
a O
copper O
fig O
of O
Mastro B-ORG
7 I-ORG
. O

Religion O
Today O
- O
via B-LOC
Barbacovi I-LOC
4 I-LOC
, O
38100 O
Trento B-LOC
- O
Tel O
and O
Fax O
0461 O
981853 O
( O
Monday O
to O
Thursday O
9.00 O
- O
12.00 O
) O
, O
Website O
: O

www.religionfilm.com O
. O

Castles B-PER
will O
make O
De B-PER
Gasperi I-PER

Rai O
Three O
hours O
20.55 O

SLOVENIA B-ORG

Simcic B-PER

Brecko B-PER

Berko B-PER

Suler B-PER

Hadzic B-PER

Bozic B-PER

Semler B-PER

Stromajer B-PER

ITALY B-ORG

Agliardi B-PER

Power B-PER

Bovo B-PER

Mantovani B-PER

Chiellini B-PER

Rosina B-PER

Donadel B-PER

Aquilanes B-PER

Lazzars B-PER

White B-PER

Pazzini B-PER

Available O
: O

SLOVENIA B-ORG
: O

Ct O
Zupan B-PER

ITALY B-ORG
: O

Berni B-PER
, O
Piccolo B-PER
, O
Zambelli B-PER
, O
Loviso B-PER
, O
Nocerino B-PER
, O
Pepe B-PER
, O
Corvia B-PER
. O

Ct O
Gentile B-PER

ARBITRO O
: O

Briakos B-PER
( O
Greece B-LOC
) O

HERE O
ARCO B-ORG
/ O
The O
opinion O
of O
the O
captain O
of O
long O
course O
after O
one O
the O
0 O
to O
0 O
at O
the O
beginning O

The O
ransom O
's O
around O
the O
corner O
. O

Andreoli B-PER
: O

You O
'll O
see O
a O
different O
team O
at O
Salò B-LOC
. O

by O
GIANLUCA B-PER
DE I-PER
MASI I-PER

ARCO B-LOC
- O
In O
the O
seasonal O
debut O
on O
Sunday O
against O
the O
freshman O
Ferrara O
, O
in O
which O
the O
Arco B-ORG
failed O
to O
go O
beyond O
a O
domestic O
tie O
to O
inviolate O
nets O
, O
it O
was O
felt O
, O
and O
not O
a O
little O
, O
the O
absence O
of O
the O
captain O
and O
charismatic O
leader O
of O
the O
group O
Giulio B-PER
Andreoli I-PER
. O

Nevertheless O
, O
the O
yellow O
- O
blue O
captain O
declares O
himself O
confident O
: O

As O
far O
as O
my O
physical O
condition O
is O
concerned O
, O
I O
do O
not O
feel O
that O
I O
am O
unbalanced O
at O
the O
moment O
. O

Analyzing O
yesterday O
's O
match O
, O
I O
think O
we O
paid O
dearly O
for O
the O
emotion O
of O
the O
debut O
in O
front O
of O
our O
audience O
. O

Despite O
everything O
, O
I O
think O
we O
have O
played O
a O
great O
game O
, O
putting O
in O
the O
field O
all O
the O
intensity O
we O
are O
capable O
of O
. O

Let O
's O
not O
forget O
the O
goal O
ball O
on O
Toccoli B-PER
's O
feet O
( O
in O
the O
photo O
the O
Central O
Arcenese O
dropped O
Sunday O
to O
make O
surprise O
goals O
finding O
the O
parade O
of O
Atti B-PER
's O
foot O
, O
ed O
) O
, O
where O
their O
goalkeeper O
was O
good O
to O
oppose O
with O
the O
feet O
, O
and O
also O
the O
goal O
canceled O
at O
Dal B-PER
Ferro I-PER
for O
a O
millimeter O
outgame O
. O

In O
the O
second O
half O
the O
heat O
became O
the O
absolute O
protagonist O
. O

They O
are O
players O
more O
minutes O
and O
faster O
than O
we O
are O
. O

I O
hope O
to O
return O
to O
the O
coach O
's O
disposal O
and O
I O
am O
confident O
, O
especially O
in O
the O
light O
of O
the O
fact O
that O
next O
week O
we O
will O
have O
a O
better O
basic O
physical O
condition O
than O
the O
one O
against O
the O
Rhine B-ORG
Centese I-ORG
. O

The O
health O
dispute O
is O
complicated O
, O
also O
with O
a O
view O
to O
the O
renewal O
of O
the O
Rsu B-ORG

• O
Few O
money O
for O
the O
contract O
• O
.................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................... O

On O
the O
renewal O
of O
the O
contract O
of O
the O
health O
sector O
, O
the O
CISL B-ORG
civil I-ORG
service I-ORG
intervenes O
. O

After O
Uil B-ORG
and O
Nursing B-ORG
up I-ORG
, O
the O
two O
most O
representative O
unions O
, O
have O
abandoned O
the O
table O
with O
the O
Apran B-ORG
, O
there O
is O
yet O
another O
arm O
wrestling O
between O
healthcare O
and O
non O
- O
health O
professions O
. O

We O
are O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
an O
electoral O
campaign O
for O
the O
renewal O
of O
the O
Rsu B-ORG
and O
the O
denial O
of O
certain O
trade O
union O
acronyms O
appears O
almost O
a O
strategy O
, O
with O
a O
view O
to O
the O
appointment O
of O
mid O
- O
November O
, O
the O
date O
of O
the O
elections O
. O

A O
common O
position O
must O
be O
found O
. O

The O
existing O
opposition O
is O
evidenced O
by O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
five O
trade O
union O
organizations O
titled O
to O
the O
negotiation O
have O
presented O
five O
different O
platforms O
. O

The O
contract O
must O
provide O
for O
wage O
increases O
linked O
to O
inflation O
, O
as O
was O
the O
case O
at O
national O
level O
. O

To O
further O
complicate O
the O
dispute O
there O
is O
the O
question O
of O
the O
funds O
allocated O
, O
which O
are O
considered O
insufficient O
. O

CISL B-ORG
has O
won O
the O
appeal O
against O
the O
Health B-ORG
Company I-ORG
which O
, O
in O
the O
decentralised O
agreement O
, O
following O
the O
2002 O
provincial O
contract O
, O
used O
resources O
to O
retrain O
non O
- O
health O
staff O
for O
other O
purposes O
. O

It O
is O
300 O
thousand O
euros O
- O
recalls O
Pierachille B-PER
Dalledonne I-PER
, O
secretary O
Uil B-ORG
sanità I-ORG
- O
. O

But O
the O
appeal O
also O
lacks O
1,500,000 O
euros O
. O

Toni B-PER
and O
Totti B-PER
showed O
a O
good O
understanding O
in O
the O
friendly O
with O
the O
U18 B-ORG

FIRENZE B-LOC
- O
It O
ended O
5 O
- O
2 O
the O
friendly O
that O
Italy B-ORG
played O
against O
the O
Under B-ORG
18 I-ORG
in O
Coverciano B-LOC
. O

Two O
times O
of O
50 O
' O
, O
to O
which O
Gattuso B-PER
and O
Nesta B-PER
did O
not O
take O
part O
, O
who O
remained O
to O
train O
on O
an O
adjacent O
field O
. O

With O
them O
at O
the O
beginning O
also O
Zambrotta B-PER
, O
which O
Lippi B-PER
then O
made O
enter O
the O
26 O
' O
of O
the O
second O
half O
in O
place O
of O
Pancaro B-PER
. O

The O
ct O
tried O
at O
the O
beginning O
a O
4 O
- O
2 O
- O
3 O
- O
1 O
with O
Toni B-PER
central O
tip O
, O
Totti B-PER
support O
, O
Esposito B-PER
left O
and O
De B-PER
Rossi I-PER
- O
Blasi B-PER
central O
pair O
of O
midfield O
. O

Bad O
, O
however O
, O
Esposito B-PER
, O
perhaps O
blocked O
by O
the O
emotion O
, O
who O
failed O
two O
resounding O
goals O
and O
did O
not O
seem O
as O
lively O
as O
with O
Cagliari B-ORG
. O

His O
assist O
at O
14 O
' O
for O
the O
first O
goal O
of O
Toni B-PER
( O
right O
to O
cross O
under O
the O
cross O
) O
and O
his O
at O
26 O
' O
the O
shot O
from O
outside O
then O
deviated O
from O
Castroni B-PER
behind O
Tips O
. O

For O
the O
Under B-ORG
18 I-ORG
goals O
at O
28 O
' O
of O
Acquafresca B-PER
who O
put O
Buffon B-PER
with O
a O
big O
shot O
from O
inside O
the O
area O
. O

In O
the O
second O
half O
Lippi B-PER
passed O
to O
the O
4 O
- O
4 O
- O
2 O
, O
with O
Di B-PER
Vaio I-PER
wide O
on O
the O
left O
and O
Corradi B-PER
- O
Gilardino B-PER
in O
front O
. O

He O
played O
Perrotta B-PER
well O
, O
who O
yesterday O
for O
the O
first O
time O
became O
familiar O
with O
the O
ball O
and O
who O
also O
scored O
. O

Before O
him O
, O
however O
, O
it O
was O
Di B-PER
Vaio I-PER
who O
opened O
the O
markings O
in O
the O
shot O
with O
a O
diagonal O
left O
, O
while O
after O
the O
4 O
- O
2 O
of O
Momentè B-PER
it O
was O
Zambrotta B-PER
who O
fixed O
the O
definitive O
5 O
- O
2 O
with O
a O
powerful O
right O
after O
a O
large O
number O
on O
the O
left O
band O
. O

This O
is O
the O
friendly O
board O
: O

NETWORKS O
: O

ITALY B-ORG
pt O
( O
4 O
- O
2 O
- O
3 O
- O
1 O
) O

Buffon B-PER
; O

Bonera B-PER
, O
Cannavaro B-PER
, O
Materazzi B-PER
, O
Pancaro B-PER
; O

Blasi B-PER
, O
De B-PER
Rossi I-PER
; O

Camoranesi B-PER
, O
Totti B-PER
, O
Esposito B-PER
; O

Toni B-PER
. O

Ct O
Lippi B-PER

ITALY B-ORG
st O
( O
4 O
- O
4 O
- O
2 O
) O

Pelizzoli B-PER
; O

Diana B-PER
, O
Perrotta B-PER
, O
Flower O
, O
Di B-PER
Vaio I-PER
; O

Corradi B-PER
, O
Gilardino B-PER
. O

Ct O
Lippi B-PER

ARBITRO O
: O

Wind B-PER
cutter I-PER
of O
Terni B-LOC

Courses O
at O
the O
start O

A O
course O
for O
girls O
from O
9 O
to O
15 O
years O
( O
from O
6.30 O
p.m. O
to O
7.30 O
p.m. O
) O
as O
well O
as O
monthly O
improvement O
in O
balad O
styles O
- O
sharqi O
- O
sadis O
- O
musical O
rhythmic O
- O
choreography O
has O
also O
been O
activated O
. O

Info O
: O

0464 O
555104 O
; O

cell O
. O
347 O
/ O
4285696 O
- O
email O
cc.margarit O
@ O
tin.it O
; O

www.ccmargarita.com O

Universities O

The O
outgoing O
rector O
courted O
in O
Rome B-LOC
, O
where O
he O
would O
deal O
with O
the O
reform O
of O
Italian O
universities O

After O
two O
mandates O
in O
the O
command O
booth O
of O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Trento I-ORG
, O
where O
he O
got O
appreciated O
, O
he O
now O
has O
only O
the O
embarrassment O
of O
choice O
. O

Several O
proposals O
have O
been O
made O
to O
him O
: O

Massimo O
Egidi O
, O
outgoing O
rector O
, O
in O
a O
few O
weeks O
will O
give O
way O
to O
the O
newly O
elected O
Davide B-PER
Bassi I-PER
, O
but O
for O
sure O
he O
will O
not O
have O
problems O
with O
" O
placement O
" O
. O

Adriano B-PER
De I-PER
Maio I-PER
left O
office O
and O
his O
ideal O
successor O
seems O
to O
be O
just O
the O
tenant O
of O
the O
rectorate O
of O
Trento B-LOC
. O

At O
the O
end O
of O
July O
Adriano B-PER
De I-PER
Maio I-PER
abandoned O
the O
ministerial O
commission O
committed O
to O
renew O
the O
legal O
framework O
of O
the O
teachers O
and O
the O
new O
degree O
classes O
. O

On O
this O
very O
subject O
- O
we O
can O
read O
in O
the O
section O
" O
In O
chair O
" O
- O
the O
proposals O
made O
by O
De B-PER
Maio I-PER
( O
such O
as O
the O
amalgamation O
of O
the O
graduation O
classes O
) O
have O
ended O
up O
in O
the O
drawer O
: O

The O
professional O
orders O
and O
the O
Undersecretary O
Maria B-PER
Grazia I-PER
Siliquini I-PER
did O
n't O
like O
them O
. O

It O
seems O
that O
the O
break O
was O
due O
to O
De B-PER
Maio I-PER
's O
failure O
to O
appoint O
as O
president O
of O
the O
CNR B-ORG
. O

Massimo B-PER
Egidi I-PER
comes O
into O
play O
in O
this O
phase O
. O

Both O
in O
Trentino B-LOC
and O
in O
the O
capital O
enjoys O
great O
esteem O
. O

A.Tom B-PER
. O

The O
opposition O
accuses O
: O

What O
's O
going O
on O
? O

Rai B-ORG
, O
the O
UoC B-ORG
changes O
its O
mind O
. O

Come O
on O
. O

ROME B-LOC
- O
The O
Rai B-ORG
cda I-ORG
can O
remain O
in O
the O
saddle O
until O
June O
2005 O
. O

Not O
even O
the O
draft O
opinion O
drawn O
up O
by O
President O
Petruccioli B-PER
with O
the O
extension O
of O
the O
Council B-ORG
, O
marked O
by O
the O
centrists O
themselves O
as O
delegitimized O
, O
is O
put O
to O
the O
vote O
. O

The O
opposition O
shouts O
at O
the O
turn O
- O
of O
- O
the O
- O
face O
and O
the O
occult O
pact O
in O
the O
majority O
in O
exchange O
for O
who O
knows O
as O
counterpart O
, O
the O
UoC B-ORG
replica O
talking O
about O
" O
management O
choice O
" O
, O
dictated O
by O
the O
need O
not O
to O
block O
the O
iter O
of O
the O
new O
Rai B-ORG
. O

Who O
imagined O
that O
yesterday O
was O
repeated O
at O
Palazzo O
San O
Macuto O
the O
cross O
- O
section O
that O
in O
July O
expressed O
itself O
in O
the O
ultimatum O
at O
the O
cda B-ORG
- O
at O
home O
by O
30 O
September O
- O
is O
denied O
immediately O
by O
the O
parent O
Udc B-ORG
. O

" O
We O
have O
not O
signed O
the O
document O
to O
mark O
a O
distinction O
that O
sees O
us O
in O
total O
dissension O
with O
respect O
to O
the O
problems O
of O
the O
cda B-ORG
" O
, O
explains O
Iervolino B-PER
, O
" O
but O
the O
iter O
should O
not O
be O
blocked O
: O

We O
need O
the O
Rai B-ORG
to O
leave O
, O
albeit O
with O
a O
politically O
delegitimized O
summit O
. O

Result O
, O
19 O
yes O
versus O
17 O
no O
. O

Nor O
can O
the O
leader O
of O
Margherita B-ORG
Gentiloni B-PER
attempt O
to O
include O
, O
in O
the O
form O
of O
a O
sub O
- O
amendment O
to O
the O
document O
, O
the O
appeal O
to O
the O
council B-ORG
to O
resign O
as O
soon O
as O
the O
merger O
is O
completed O
: O

Also O
in O
this O
case O
the O
Cdl B-ORG
is O
compact O
and O
the O
no O
are O
19 O
, O
versus O
18 O
yes O
. O

The O
President O
of O
the O
Verdi B-ORG
Pecoraro B-PER
Scanio I-PER
reacts O
immediately O
from O
the O
opposition O
, O
who O
speaks O
of O
" O
the O
incredible O
turn O
of O
the O
Udc B-ORG
" O
and O
wonders O
if O
there O
have O
been O
no O
secret O
pacts O
on O
the O
skin O
of O
the O
company O
" O
. O

From O
the O
Ds B-ORG
, O
Juliet B-PER
bullied O
the O
Vigilance O
vote O
as O
" O
very O
serious O
" O
and O
glimpsed O
the O
risk O
that O
one O
would O
go O
towards O
a O
presidential O
republic O
to O
unified O
networks O
" O
. O

More O
cautious O
Gentiloni B-PER
, O
which O
, O
however O
, O
is O
known O
as O
the O
rule O
allowing O
the O
Board B-ORG
to O
remain O
in O
the O
saddle O
until O
June O
2005 O
( O
i.e. O
until O
the O
2004 O
budget O
is O
approved O
) O
will O
make O
the O
business O
summit O
even O
more O
unstable O
and O
open O
a O
new O
season O
of O
legal O
disputes O
. O

For O
Italian B-ORG
Communists I-ORG
, O
Sgobio B-PER
speaks O
of O
a O
tacit O
pact O
in O
the O
majority O
with O
the O
aim O
of O
deconstructing O
the O
company O
. O

In O
Brief O

Use O
of O
the O
Consultative B-ORG
Committee O

Two O
million O
at O
Appa B-ORG

Assigned O
to O
the O
Provincial B-ORG
Agency I-ORG
for I-ORG
the I-ORG
Protection I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Environment O
, O
the O
budget O
appropriations O
for O
2004 O
amounted O
to O
EUR O
2,282,900 O
, O
of O
which O
EUR O
1,187,500 O
for O
current O
expenditure O
, O
398,000 O
for O
investment O
expenditure O
and O
EUR O
696,600 O
for O
the O
implementation O
of O
operations O
. O

For O
the O
2004 O
operating O
expenditure O
, O
EUR O
5.558.955 O
was O
allocated O
to O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Trento I-ORG
, O
plus O
EUR O
2.500,000 O
for O
investment O
expenditure O
. O

" O
A O
first O
outcome O
of O
this O
game O
could O
be O
" O
zero O
minorities O
' O
, O
which O
( O
in O
addition O
to O
the O
" O
zero O
number O
' O
of O
this O
first O
experimental O
edition O
) O
sums O
up O
a O
way O
to O
say O
that O
minorities O
exist O
and O
do O
not O
exist O
, O
as O
we O
are O
all O
minority O
of O
someone O
else O
: O

The O
concept O
of O
the O
Nobel O
Prize O
winner O
, O
Derek B-PER
Walcott I-PER
, O
" O
Universal O
Meticciate O
" O
explains O
to O
us O
that O
all O
over O
the O
world O
the O
mixture O
of O
languages O
, O
peoples O
and O
cultures O
is O
now O
an O
essential O
fact O
. O

21 O
o'clock O
- O
concert O
in O
the O
Church O
of O
S. O
Giorgio O
Serso O
dei O
Cantori B-ORG
of I-ORG
Castelsardo I-ORG
and I-ORG
Sessa I-ORG
Aurunca I-ORG
. O

Thursday O
: O

Gianni B-PER
Gentilini I-PER
presents O
" O
Travel O
in O
the O
Occitan O
valleys O
of O
Piedmont O
" O
by O
Fredo B-PER
Valla I-PER
; O

Friday O
: O

17 O
- O
23 O
p.m. O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruit I-LOC
" O
In O
search O
of O
the O
gold O
of O
the O
Fersina O
" O
; O

8.30 O
pm O
- O
dance O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Municipio I-LOC
with O
the O
Folkloristic B-ORG
Group I-ORG
Canazei I-ORG
and O
the O
Folk B-ORG
Group I-ORG
of I-ORG
Palù I-ORG
del I-ORG
Fersina I-ORG
; O

from O
7 O
p.m. O
to O
11 O
p.m. O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruit I-LOC
( O
Piazza O
E. O
Fruit O
) O

Saturday O
: O

17 O
- O
23 O
p.m. O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruit I-LOC
" O
In O
search O
of O
the O
gold O
of O
the O
Fersina O
" O
; O

8.30 O
p.m. O
- O
multimedia O
show O
at O
the O
Teatro O
Tent O
• O
Yol O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
• O
Teatro O
Tent O
• O
• O
Teatro O
Tent O
• O
• O
Yol O
• O
• O
• O
Teatro O
Tent O
• O
• O
Yol O
• O
• O

9.30 O
p.m. O
- O
Concert O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Municipio I-LOC
del O
Coro B-ORG
Marco I-ORG
Garbin I-ORG
; O

from O
7 O
p.m. O
to O
11 O
p.m. O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruit I-LOC
( O
Piazza O
E. O
Fruit O
) O

Sunday O
: O

10 O
am O
- O
12 O
pm O
and O
17pm O
- O
23pm O
in O
Piazza O
E. O
Fruet O
" O
In O
search O
of O
the O
gold O
of O
the O
Fersina O
" O
. O

Riva B-ORG
del I-ORG
Garda I-ORG
, O
start O
with O
the O
bang O

Rudy B-PER
Prandi I-PER
's O
training O
draws O
four O
goals O
at O
Bleggio B-ORG
Football I-ORG

TRENTO B-LOC
- O
First O
day O
of O
the O
Championship O
of O
Promotion B-ORG
without O
huge O
surprises O
. O

The O
two O
favourites O
on O
the O
eve O
, O
Riva B-ORG
del I-ORG
Garda I-ORG
and O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
have O
debuted O
winning O
the O
three O
points O
; O

net O
the O
affirmation O
of O
the O
eleven O
of O
Prandi B-PER
, O
victorious O
four O
to O
zero O
on O
the O
field O
of O
Cavrasto B-LOC
, O
more O
suffered O
the O
success O
of'Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
that O
had O
to O
face O
but O
with O
a O
team O
much O
quoted O
like O
the O
Condinese B-ORG
. O

Net O
victory O
for O
Alberto B-PER
Betta I-PER
's O
Villazzano O
which O
in O
Gabbiolo O
takes O
just O
over O
ten O
minutes O
to O
archive O
the O
practice O
La B-ORG
Rovere I-ORG
. O

The O
two O
nets O
from O
the O
distance O
to O
Fontana B-PER
and O
Floriani B-PER
's O
crown O
left O
no O
escape O
to O
Bevilacqua B-PER
. O

The O
newly O
promoted O
Azzurra B-ORG
starts O
well O
, O
thanks O
to O
the O
markings O
of O
Flores B-PER
and O
Fabbri B-PER
puts O
to O
mark O
Cavalese B-LOC
what O
can O
perhaps O
be O
considered O
as O
the O
main O
surprise O
of O
the O
day O
. O

Too O
heavy O
( O
as O
happened O
in O
the O
past O
season O
) O
for O
the O
Fiemme B-ORG
the O
absence O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
camp O
of O
Luca B-PER
Giunchi I-PER
. O

The O
new O
Aldeno B-ORG
of O
the O
ds O
Kaisermann B-PER
debuts O
to O
the O
great O
conquering O
the O
entire O
stakes O
in O
the O
external O
match O
on O
the O
difficult O
field O
of O
the O
Chiese B-ORG
Soccer I-ORG
. O

Borghesi B-PER
and O
Knave B-PER
the O
markers O
for O
the O
Giallorossi O
. O

Half O
- O
step O
fake O
Levico B-ORG
Terme I-ORG
, O
stopped O
on O
the O
draw O
by O
Monte B-ORG
Baldo I-ORG
. O

Advantage O
of O
Agostini B-PER
, O
draw O
by O
Brusco B-PER
. O

In O
early O
measurement O
success O
for O
the O
Rotaliana B-ORG
on O
the O
Dro B-ORG
. O

Two O
by O
two O
the O
final O
result O
. O

Franco B-PER
Pistolato I-PER
, O
coach O
of O
the O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
, O
is O
satisfied O
with O
the O
important O
success O
achieved O
against O
the O
Condinese B-ORG
. O

I O
'm O
happy O
for O
the O
result O
. O

The O
game O
on O
Sunday O
confirmed O
that O
we O
still O
have O
a O
lot O
of O
work O
to O
do O
. O

What O
ideas O
did O
the O
game O
on O
Sunday O
offer O
you O
? O

Where O
does O
your O
team O
have O
to O
grow O
more O
? O

We O
certainly O
have O
some O
small O
problems O
that O
we O
will O
have O
to O
try O
to O
solve O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
. O

Especially O
in O
the O
offensive O
phase O
we O
have O
to O
grow O
a O
lot O
. O

Who O
fears O
most O
for O
the O
final O
success O
? O

" O
La O
Condinese B-ORG
has O
given O
me O
a O
very O
good O
impression O
and O
I O
'm O
sure O
it O
will O
play O
a O
leading O
role O
. O
" O

We O
aim O
to O
find O
a O
good O
balance O
and O
to O
play O
a O
good O
championship O
. O

Expected O
predictions O
or O
is O
there O
any O
result O
you O
did O
n't O
expect O
on O
this O
first O
day O
? O

In O
broad O
lines O
there O
were O
no O
big O
surprises O
. O

I O
did O
n't O
expect O
the O
Bleggio B-ORG
Soccer I-ORG
to O
score O
four O
goals O
in O
the O
house O
, O
but O
apparently O
they O
paid O
for O
some O
lack O
of O
too O
much O
. O

Co O
- O
operatives O
called O
to O
vote O

Cooperatives O
registered O
in O
the O
provincial O
register O
shall O
be O
called O
upon O
to O
elect O
representatives O
( O
two O
actual O
members O
and O
one O
alternate O
) O
from O
the O
Regional B-ORG
Commission I-ORG
for I-ORG
Cooperation I-ORG
and O
the O
Commission B-ORG
for I-ORG
Cooperatives I-ORG
of O
the O
province B-LOC
of I-LOC
Trento I-LOC
. O

The O
elections O
are O
held O
from O
8 O
to O
27 O
September O
. O

The O
following O
day O
, O
at O
10 O
a.m. O
, O
the O
public O
check O
- O
out O
will O
begin O
at O
the O
headquarters O
of O
the O
Cooperation O
Service O
, O
in O
via B-LOC
Brennero I-LOC
136 I-LOC
. O

Each O
cooperative O
may O
vote O
on O
an O
effective O
member O
and O
an O
alternate O
, O

The O
sector O
has O
been O
suffering O
for O
some O
time O
. O

Al O
Saie O
13 O
exhibitors O

Purchases O
in O
decrease O
of O
40 O
% O

TRENTO B-LOC
- O
The O
wood O
supply O
chain O
counts O
in O
Trentino B-LOC
1,400 O
companies O
for O
a O
total O
of O
about O
5,000 O
employees O
. O

56 O
% O
of O
the O
provincial O
territory O
is O
covered O
by O
woods O
and O
forests O
which O
, O
for O
70 O
% O
are O
public O
property O
( O
Province B-LOC
, O
Municipalities O
and O
so O
on O
) O
. O

Quality O
wood O
such O
as O
the O
certified O
Trentino O
wood O
, O
discounted O
difficulty O
of O
placement O
due O
to O
higher O
prices O
. O

The O
average O
value O
per O
metrocube O
was O
just O
over O
€ O
69 O
. O

The O
total O
sales O
value O
exceeded O
EUR O
4 O
million O
. O

Meanwhile O
, O
there O
will O
be O
13 O
exhibitors O
from O
Trentino O
( O
9 O
last O
year O
) O
on O
the O
1,800 O
present O
at O
the O
2004 O
edition O
of O
the O
Saie O
, O
the O
Exhibition O
of O
Industrialization O
Building O
( O
13 O
- O
17 O
October O
) O
in O
Bologna B-LOC
that O
boasts O
170 O
thousand O
visitors O
. O

In O
addition O
to O
industrial O
and O
artisan O
companies O
and O
the O
Magnificent B-ORG
Community I-ORG
, O
in O
Bologna B-LOC
there O
will O
also O
be O
the O
CNR B-ORG
of O
St. B-LOC
Michael I-LOC
, O
the O
University B-ORG
and O
the O
Forest B-ORG
and I-ORG
Fauna I-ORG
Service I-ORG
. O

The O
cost O
of O
the O
operation O
exceeds O
EUR O
150 O
thousand O
, O
without O
considering O
the O
share O
borne O
by O
the O
companies O
. O

M. B-PER
E. I-PER

CRAC O
SICA B-ORG

Dissegne B-PER
intrigoto O
per O
recitazione O

Paolo B-PER
Postai I-PER
also O
drags O
with O
him O
all O
the O
buyers O
of O
the O
assets O
of O
Sica B-ORG
srl I-ORG
. O

The O
car O
was O
not O
owned O
by O
Sica B-ORG
, O
but O
had O
been O
leased O
. O

According O
to O
the O
accusation O
Dissigna B-PER
had O
even O
falsified O
to O
the O
denunciation O
of O
the O
loss O
of O
the O
documents O
of O
the O
car O
. O

The O
car O
was O
seized O
yesterday O
morning O
by O
the O
Guardia B-ORG
di I-ORG
Finanza I-ORG
. O

The O
Sica B-ORG
failed O
because O
of O
a O
serious O
financial O
breakdown O
that O
caused O
its O
collapse O
; O

The O
cost O
of O
this O
was O
ten O
families O
, O
who O
had O
faced O
huge O
expenses O
to O
buy O
an O
apartment O
. O

Now O
there O
is O
still O
a O
lack O
of O
Sica B-ORG
assets O
for O
a O
value O
of O
hundreds O
of O
thousands O
of O
euros O
. O

Iraq B-LOC

A O
car O
bomb O
in O
Fallujah B-LOC
kills O
seven O
American O
soldiers O
. O

Tests O
say O
the O
arrested O
man O
is O
n't O
Saddam B-PER
's O
deputy O
. O

The O
kidnappers O
: O

" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O
" O
Give O
us O
$ O
5 O
million O
" O

To O
free O
the O
two O
journalists O

Raffarin B-PER
: O

It O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
, O
it O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
. O

Within O
48 O
hours O
the O
two O
French O
journalists O
held O
hostage O
from O
August O
20 O
in O
Iraq B-LOC
, O
Christian B-PER
Chesnot I-PER
and O
Georges B-PER
Malbrunot I-PER
, O
may O
be O
free O
if O
: O

( O
a O
) O
five O
million O
dollars O
will O
be O
paid O
, O
( O
b O
) O
a O
truce O
will O
be O
accepted O
with O
the O
" O
sheikh O
Osama B-PER
Bin I-PER
Laden I-PER
, O
" O
( O
c O
) O
a O
truce O
will O
be O
avoided O
from O
commercial O
and O
military O
relations O
with O
Iraq B-LOC
. O

This O
is O
the O
last O
message O
released O
on O
the O
Internet O
by O
the O
group O
of O
alleged O
journalists O
' O
kidnappers O
, O
the O
Islamic B-ORG
Army I-ORG
in I-ORG
Iraq I-ORG
. O

Although O
, O
from O
Pristina B-LOC
, O
the O
Foreign O
Minister O
Michel B-PER
Barnier I-PER
said O
he O
believed O
that O
there O
is O
a O
possibility O
of O
positive O
evolution O
of O
the O
affair O
. O

For O
France B-LOC
it O
would O
obviously O
be O
a O
big O
blow O
if O
the O
statement O
were O
authentic O
: O

The O
warning O
then O
appears O
to O
the O
French O
that O
they O
do O
n't O
attack O
as O
you O
did O
to O
Latifiya B-LOC
, O
the O
day O
we O
wanted O
to O
give O
you O
the O
hostages O
. O

Witnesses O
have O
stated O
that O
in O
the O
attack O
on O
American O
forces O
- O
in O
the O
village O
of O
Saqlawiya B-LOC
, O
northern O
suburb O
of O
Falluja B-LOC
- O
at O
least O
seven O
marines O
were O
killed O
on O
board O
a O
convoy O
vehicle O
. O

The O
work O
must O
be O
completed O
by O
14 O
October O
. O

Lot O
, O
won O
404 O
thousand O
euros O

In O
Trentino B-LOC
last O
Wednesday O
at O
Lotto O
5,363 O
wins O
were O
made O
for O
a O
total O
of O
404,991,23 O
euros O
. O

The O
meeting O

Last O
Monday O
the O
boys O
of O
the O
New O
Serena O
House O
, O
residential O
center O
Anffas B-ORG
Trentino I-ORG
onlus I-ORG
, O
had O
the O
pleasure O
to O
attend O
a O
beautiful O
manifestation O
of O
the O
State B-ORG
Police I-ORG
that O
with O
a O
dog O
group O
, O
motorbikes O
, O
cars O
and O
van O
animated O
and O
enlivened O
the O
morning O
of O
late O
summer O
. O

All O
the O
boys O
present O
( O
several O
of O
them O
arrived O
for O
the O
occasion O
also O
from O
day O
centers O
of O
the O
Anffas B-ORG
of O
Trento B-LOC
) O
appreciated O
in O
a O
particular O
way O
, O
responding O
with O
enthusiasm O
and O
great O
emotion O
. O

It O
struck O
the O
deep O
sensitivity O
shown O
towards O
the O
boys O
who O
, O
climbing O
the O
bikes O
, O
operating O
the O
sirens O
or O
speaking O
on O
the O
radio O
from O
the O
car O
, O
felt O
important O
actors O
, O
valued O
and O
greeted O
with O
great O
warmth O
by O
the O
operators O
of O
the O
State B-ORG
Police I-ORG
. O

There O
were O
different O
people O
looking O
out O
at O
the O
windows O
who O
were O
able O
to O
catch O
this O
extraordinary O
moment O
of O
celebration O
. O

A O
warm O
thanks O
goes O
to O
all O
the O
operators O
present O
of O
the O
State B-ORG
Police I-ORG
: O

to O
the O
Cinofilo B-ORG
Training I-ORG
Centre I-ORG
in O
Moena B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
Trento B-LOC
Road O
Police O
, O
to O
the O
staff O
of O
the O
police O
station B-ORG
, O
to O
the O
neighborhood O
police O
, O
to O
the O
Artificial B-ORG
Department I-ORG
, O
to O
Dr. O
Morelli B-PER
, O
to O
Dr. O
Spirali B-PER
, O
to O
the O
quaestor O
of O
Trento B-LOC
for O
their O
availability O
and O
participation O
. O

The O
Crac O

The O
construction O
contractor O
feels O
deceived O
by O
Parma B-LOC
's O
accountant O
who O
had O
to O
save O
his O
company O

Chini B-PER
complaint O
for O
Scam O
Signifredi B-PER

The O
buyer O
of O
the O
company O
has O
not O
even O
paid O
the O
thousand O
euros O
agreed O

Chini B-PER
feels O
cheated O
by O
Paolo B-PER
Signifredi I-PER
. O

For O
this O
reason O
the O
construction O
contractor O
filed O
a O
complaint O
against O
the O
accountant O
of O
Parma B-LOC
who O
had O
purchased O
the O
Chini B-ORG
constructions I-ORG
for O
a O
thousand O
euros O
, O
money O
that O
, O
among O
other O
things O
, O
Signifredi B-PER
never O
paid O
. O

Signifredi B-PER
a O
few O
days O
after O
the O
purchase O
of O
Chini B-ORG
was O
arrested O
by O
the O
Finance O
Guard O
because O
he O
had O
to O
serve O
a O
three O
- O
year O
sentence O
for O
the O
recuperation O
and O
recycling O
of O
a O
car O
. O

A O
month O
later O
the O
Public O
Prosecutor B-ORG
asked O
for O
the O
arrests O
for O
Chini B-PER
and O
his O
son O
Gianluca B-PER
, O
investigated O
for O
fraudulent O
bankruptcy O
. O

Chini B-PER
subsequently O
decided O
to O
denounce O
Signifredi B-PER
. O

The O
accountant O
had O
to O
be O
the O
white O
knight O
called O
to O
save O
the O
Chini B-ORG
and O
, O
instead O
, O
it O
was O
the O
one O
who O
buried O
it O
. O

But O
the O
complaint O
for O
fraud O
is O
probably O
linked O
to O
a O
series O
of O
agreements O
that O
the O
two O
entrepreneurs O
had O
made O
. O

Chini B-PER
reproaches O
Signifredi B-PER
for O
not O
fulfilling O
his O
commitments O
, O
for O
having O
deceived O
him O
on O
the O
seriousness O
of O
his O
intentions O
. O

It O
was O
business O
that O
would O
permanently O
cleanse O
the O
Chini B-ORG
coffers O
. O

Business O
that O
could O
not O
be O
concluded O
due O
to O
bankruptcy O
. O

Now O
it O
is O
the O
cure O
that O
tries O
to O
throw O
the O
sums O
. O

Of O
course O
, O
revenue O
is O
likely O
to O
be O
much O
lower O
than O
normal O
management O
. O

The O
arrest O
of O
the O
accountant O
, O
however O
, O
blew O
up O
everything O
. O

That O
's O
why O
Chini B-PER
felt O
deceived O
and O
decided O
to O
file O
a O
complaint O
. O

The O
entrepreneur O
feels O
the O
victim O
of O
a O
scam O
because O
in O
his O
view O
Signifredi B-PER
had O
at O
his O
disposal O
all O
the O
means O
to O
save O
the O
company O
. O

Chini B-PER
even O
risks O
losing O
the O
house O
, O
since O
it O
is O
registered O
to O
its O
former O
company O
and O
could O
now O
be O
sold O
to O
the O
auction O
by O
the O
curator O
. O

Shot O
by O
the O
Dusevichs B-PER
, O
two O
released O

Gianfranco B-PER
Spagnolo I-PER
and O
Fulvio B-PER
Trentini I-PER
were O
exonerated O
by O
the O
review B-ORG
court I-ORG
for O
the O
blow O
in O
the O
house O
Dusevich B-PER
. O

According O
to O
what O
was O
contested O
by O
the O
Public O
Prosecutor B-ORG
's I-ORG
Office I-ORG
, O
the O
two O
would O
only O
organize O
the O
coup O
, O
which O
would O
then O
be O
executed O
by O
the O
two O
accomplices O
, O
who O
were O
recognized O
by O
two O
persons O
. O

The O
witnesses O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
claimed O
that O
the O
two O
robbers O
moved O
inside O
their O
house O
with O
perfect O
knowledge O
of O
the O
places O
, O
so O
much O
so O
that O
they O
knew O
where O
the O
safe O
was O
. O

Moreover O
, O
the O
judges O
observe O
that O
Trentini B-PER
remained O
in O
prison O
from O
1999 O
to O
2003 O
. O

Therefore O
he O
may O
not O
have O
participated O
in O
the O
renovation O
work O
in O
Dusevich B-PER
house O
in O
recent O
times O
. O

He O
himself O
told O
the O
gip O
that O
he O
had O
done O
those O
jobs O
in O
1992 O
. O

Given O
the O
time O
spent O
, O
the O
judges O
doubt O
that O
Trentini B-PER
can O
be O
the O
source O
of O
information O
so O
detailed O
that O
they O
allow O
the O
robbers O
to O
move O
perfectly O
at O
ease O
in O
the O
house O
Dusevich B-PER
. O

Today O
at O
the O
Cinema O

The O
evil O
education O
is O
the O
story O
of O
a O
director O
who O
investigates O
paedophile O
behavior O
and O
sexual O
violence O
suffered O
by O
a O
priest O
in O
the O
college O
where O
he O
grew O
up O
as O
a O
child O
. O

A O
bitter O
, O
cruel O
and O
raw O
film O
, O
set O
in O
a O
Franco O
- O
speaking O
and O
ultra O
- O
Catholic O
Spain B-LOC
of O
the O
1960s O
, O
according O
to O
the O
director O
is O
however O
only O
a O
film O
about O
homosexuality O
. O

( O
in O
the O
picture O
, O
a O
scene O
of O
the O
movie O
) O

The O
life O
I O
'd O
like O

by O
Giuseppe B-PER
Piccioni I-PER
, O
with O
Luigi B-PER
Lo I-PER
Cascio I-PER
and O
Sandra B-PER
Ceccarelli I-PER
living O
a O
love O
story O
inside O
the O
set O
of O
a O
movie O
in O
costume O
and O
in O
real O
life O
. O

A O
movie O
about O
making O
movies O
, O
quoting O
Truffaut B-PER
. O

Love O
Found O

Garfield O
: O

the O
film O

Electronic O
animation O
film O
, O
starring O
the O
irreverent O
Garfield O
cat O
of O
the O
American O
comic O
book O
. O

The O
story O
: O

Garfield O
's O
owner O
brings O
home O
a O
lovely O
dog O
puppy O
named O
Odie O
. O

Who O
wonders O
about O
his O
mission O
. O

But O
there O
is O
no O
shortage O
of O
special O
effects O
. O

First B-ORG
Category I-ORG

THE O
PERSONALITY O
/ O
The O
company O
aims O
at O
the O
jump O
of O
category O
: O

has O
invested O
a O
lot O
and O
does O
n't O
make O
us O
miss O
anything O
at O
all O

Ceraso B-PER
, O
the O
great O
challenge O
: O

" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion B-ORG
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O
" O
We O
want O
the O
promotion O
" O

The O
ambitious O
Torbole B-ORG
entrusts O
its O
bench O
to O
a O
luxury O
beginner O

That O
of O
a O
coach O
, O
with O
a O
precise O
task O
: O

bring O
the O
Torbole B-ORG
to O
Promotion B-ORG
. O

After O
three O
consecutive O
second O
places O
( O
backwards O
of O
Calcio B-ORG
Bleggio I-ORG
in O
2002 O
, O
Dro B-ORG
in O
2003 O
and O
Monte B-ORG
Baldo I-ORG
in O
2004 O
) O
the O
partnership O
chaired O
by O
Pietro B-PER
Addeo I-PER
is O
in O
fact O
the O
preferred O
logic O
to O
win O
first O
place O
. O

It O
is O
a O
challenging O
adventure O
, O
we O
are O
aware O
that O
the O
company O
points O
to O
the O
category O
jump O
. O

He O
's O
invested O
a O
lot O
and O
we O
do O
n't O
miss O
anything O
at O
all O
. O

How O
do O
you O
find O
yourself O
at O
your O
first O
bench O
experience O
after O
a O
life O
spent O
in O
the O
field O
? O

Moving O
within O
a O
couple O
of O
months O
from O
the O
field O
to O
the O
bench O
requires O
a O
considerable O
change O
of O
mindset O
. O

Luckily O
things O
in O
the O
pre O
- O
season O
have O
flown O
in O
the O
best O
way O
and O
this O
has O
facilitated O
my O
work O
. O

What O
are O
the O
teams O
that O
fear O
the O
most O
? O

The O
Pieve B-ORG
di I-ORG
Bono I-ORG
is O
definitely O
an O
excellent O
team O
, O
which O
runs O
a O
lot O
and O
with O
technically O
valid O
players O
. O

Calavino B-ORG
and O
Isera B-ORG
have O
all O
the O
potential O
to O
do O
well O
, O
then O
there O
is O
Pinzolo B-ORG
Campiglio I-ORG
which O
is O
a O
bit O
of O
a O
loose O
cannon O
. O

What O
are O
the O
problems O
you O
're O
encountering O
as O
a O
coach O
? O

" O
The O
problems O
will O
begin O
to O
come O
when O
the O
results O
do O
not O
arrive O
. O
" O

So O
far O
there O
have O
been O
no O
hiccups O
. O

61st O
INTERNATIONAL O
EXHIBITION O
OF O
VENICE O
CINEMA O

A O
new O
film O
taken O
from O
the O
archive O
materials O
of O
the O
Istituto B-ORG
Luce I-ORG
and O
the O
Biennale B-ORG
to O
document O
the O
madness O
of O
the O
wars O
of O
religions O
and O
indicate O
the O
path O
to O
follow O
, O
which O
is O
that O
of O
coexistence O
between O
different O
religions O
. O

What O
stress O
to O
be O
Placid B-PER

Daughter O
of O
art O
, O
she O
began O
very O
young O
: O

now O
Violante B-PER
Placido I-PER
tackles O
the O
profession O
of O
actress O
directed O
by O
his O
father O
Michele B-PER
, O
female O
co O
- O
star O
with O
Barbora B-PER
Bobulova I-PER
of O
" O
Everywhere O
you O
are O
" O
: O

" O
It O
was O
hard O
, O
I O
suffered O
, O
but O
today O
I O
'm O
satisfied O
, O
" O
he O
says O
. O

Nicole B-PER
's O
scandal O

Here O
comes O
" O
Birth O
" O
, O
Jonathan B-PER
Glazer I-PER
's O
anticipated O
film O
with O
the O
superdiva O
Nicole B-PER
Kidman I-PER
in O
scandal O
smell O
, O
but O
the O
indicted O
scene O
, O
the O
one O
that O
sees O
the O
actress O
award O
Oscar O
naked O
in O
the O
bathtub O
with O
a O
10 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
, O
in O
the O
end O
, O
despite O
everything O
, O
is O
not O
really O
scandalous O
: O

the O
little O
one O
enters O
the O
room O
with O
already O
the O
Kidman B-PER
( O
Anna B-PER
) O
in O
the O
water O
, O
stops O
one O
meter O
from O
the O
bathtub O
, O
undresses O
, O
but O
then O
everything O
fades O
. O

For O
ordinary O
mortals O
, O
it O
will O
be O
necessary O
to O
wait O
until O
February O
. O

No O
Clooney B-PER
No O
party O

George B-PER
Clooney I-PER
's O
Forfait O
at O
the O
Exhibition O
. O

Briatore B-PER
's O
favorite O
movies O

Flavio B-PER
Briatore I-PER
, O
the O
manager O
of O
Formula B-ORG
1 I-ORG
better O
known O
for O
the O
collection O
of O
women O
than O
for O
that O
of O
victories O
in O
the O
grand O
prizes O
, O
talks O
about O
cinema O
: O

NORDIC O
SCI O
/ O
The O
Marcialonga O
, O
although O
4 O
months O
away O
, O
already O
has O
1500 O
members O

Paruzzi B-PER
godmother O
, O
Giorgio B-PER
Di I-PER
Centa I-PER
to O
win O

It O
's O
already O
time O
to O
dust O
the O
skis O
, O
prepare O
the O
silly O
and O
? O

They O
have O
already O
done O
so O
in O
1,500 O
when O
they O
are O
less O
than O
4 O
months O
away O
from O
30 O
January O
2005 O
. O

Last O
year O
, O
for O
the O
first O
time O
World O
Cup O
race O
, O
the O
Marcialonga O
gathered O
on O
the O
finish O
line O
as O
many O
as O
3,733 O
classified O
, O
but O
in O
total O
the O
entries O
amounted O
to O
4,378 O
. O

The O
32nd O
edition O
will O
be O
at O
the O
sign O
of O
Gabriella B-PER
Paruzzi I-PER
, O
the O
winner O
of O
the O
2004 O
World O
Cup O
who O
, O
thanks O
to O
the O
victory O
of O
the O
last O
Marcialonga O
, O
had O
the O
stimuli O
to O
aim O
for O
the O
great O
result O
in O
the O
Cup O
. O

The O
Tarvisian O
champion O
became O
, O
and O
could O
not O
be O
otherwise O
, O
the O
testimonial O
and O
the O
ambassador O
of O
the O
grandfund O
on O
skis O
that O
made O
the O
history O
of O
Italian O
cross O
- O
countryism O
. O

And O
so O
the O
Marcialonga O
of O
the O
Valleys O
of O
Fiemme O
and O
Fassa O
is O
proposed O
for O
the O
third O
consecutive O
time O
in O
classic O
style O
and O
, O
after O
the O
parenthesis O
last O
year O
, O
returns O
valid O
as O
a O
stage O
of O
the O
FIS O
Marathon O
Cup O
. O

In O
agreement O
with O
Coach O
Chenetti B-PER
I O
have O
scheduled O
the O
Marcialonga O
. O

This O
year O
I O
want O
to O
win O
it O
, O
it O
's O
a O
race O
too O
important O
for O
me O
, O
said O
the O
Friulian O
. O

& O
CULTURE O
COMPANY O

Trento B-LOC
: O

exhibition O
Popular B-ORG
University I-ORG

Sixty O
years O
ago O
the O
Trentino O
Popular B-ORG
University I-ORG
was O
born O
in O
Trento O
. O

In O
these O
days O
it O
is O
open O
, O
at O
the O
Palazzo O
della O
Regione O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Dante I-LOC
the O
exhibition O
of O
painting O
of O
the O
students O
of O
yesterday O
and O
today O
Prof. O
Perilli B-PER
. O

Closes O
tomorrow O
, O
Saturday O
9 O
October O
, O
at O
12 O
noon O
. O

Riva B-LOC
del I-LOC
Garda I-LOC
: O

old O
age O

" O
5th O
Gold O
Age O
" O
, O
international O
forum O
of O
the O
elderly O
. O

Until O
Monday O
, O
October O
11th O
at O
the O
Palacongressi O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

flavors O
, O
9 O
- O
20 O
o'clock O

The O
traditional O
Piazza O
dei O
Sapori O
( O
Piazza O
dei O
Sapori O
) O
, O
stand O
of O
typical O
regional O
products O
, O
returns O
. O

Until O
Sunday O
from O
9 O
am O
to O
8 O
pm O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Fiera I-LOC
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

Ecumenism O
, O
9.30 O
a.m. O

It O
continues O
tomorrow O
morning O
at O
9.30 O
am O
at O
the O
Istituto O
Trentino O
di O
Cultura O
, O
in O
via B-LOC
S. I-LOC
Croce I-LOC
77 I-LOC
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

evolutionary O
age O
, O
9.30 O
a.m. O

Conference O
of O
the O
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Science I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Cognition O
and O
Formation O
on O
the O
theme O
" O
The O
forms O
of O
discomfort O
. O
" O

Stress O
: O

Causes O
and O
manifestations O
of O
evolutionary O
age O
. O

In O
via B-LOC
Matteo I-LOC
del I-LOC
Ben I-LOC
, O
Hall O
1 O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

mental O
health O
, O
14 O
o'clock O

The O
Provincial B-ORG
Mental I-ORG
Health I-ORG
Service I-ORG
proposes O
the O
three O
- O
day O
conference O
" O
The O
rediscovered O
words O
" O
( O
5th O
National O
Meeting O
) O
" O
, O
i.e. O
, O
" O
Culture O
and O
practices O
of O
consivision O
in O
menathle O
health O
policies O
. O

Experiences O
compared O
to O
each O
other O
. O

Today O
the O
speeches O
of O
Giuseppe B-PER
Lumia I-PER
( O
rapporteur O
of O
a O
draft O
law O
on O
mental O
health O
) O
and O
contributions O
to O
several O
voices O
on O
the O
" O
do O
together O
" O
. O

At O
21 O
, O
expressive O
proposals O
, O
theatrical O
and O
singing O
of O
groups O
, O
associations O
, O
centers O
, O
cooperatives O
. O

The O
work O
continues O
tomorrow O
morning O
at O
9 O
a.m. O

To O
the O
Cooperation O
Room O
in O
Via B-LOC
Segantini I-LOC
10 I-LOC
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

the O
show O
, O
15 O
o'clock O

The O
Interregional B-ORG
Delegation I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Three O
Venezies O
of O
the O
Associazione B-ORG
Generale I-ORG
Italiana I-ORG
dello I-ORG
Spettacolo I-ORG
( O
Agis B-ORG
) O
proposes O
the O
seminar O
" O
Per O
una O
nuova O
politica O
dello O
spettacolo O
" O
. O

He O
will O
chair O
the O
president O
of O
the O
Centro B-ORG
S. I-ORG
Chiara I-ORG
, O
Carlo B-PER
Fait I-PER
. O

Interventions O
by O
supervisors O
, O
regional O
and O
municipal O
councillors O
, O
politicians O
, O
artists O
will O
follow O
. O

Among O
these O
, O
the O
superintendent O
of O
the O
Opera B-ORG
di I-ORG
Roma I-ORG
Francesco B-PER
Ernani I-PER
and O
the O
director O
of O
" O
Opera B-ORG
Europa I-ORG
" O
, O
Nicholas B-PER
Payne I-PER
. O

For O
the O
Trentino B-LOC
, O
Micaela B-PER
Bertoldi I-PER
, O
city O
councilwoman O
, O
Marco B-PER
Bernardi I-PER
, O
director O
of O
the O
Teatro B-ORG
Stabile I-ORG
of I-ORG
Bolzano I-ORG
, O
Franz B-PER
Von I-PER
Walther I-PER
, O
president O
of O
the O
Orchestra B-ORG
Haydn I-ORG
of O
Bolzano B-LOC
and O
Trento B-LOC
. O

In O
the O
debate O
will O
also O
be O
the O
director O
Mario B-PER
Martone I-PER
. O

Arco B-LOC
: O

Astra O
, O
3 O
p.m. O

Return O
, O
for O
the O
25th O
appointment O
, O
" O
Astra O
" O
, O
international O
conference O
of O
astrology O
on O
the O
theme O
" O
News O
of O
ancient O
mysteries O
" O
. O

At O
the O
Casino O
. O

Arco B-LOC
: O

Quisisana O
, O
5:00 O
p.m. O

The O
city O
that O
changes O
. O

At O
the O
Palazzo O
dei O
Panni O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

stories O
, O
5 O
p.m. O

Paolo B-PER
Tognolatti I-PER
presents O
the O
volume O
of O
stories O
" O
Gagliori O
" O
by O
Giovanni B-PER
Duca I-PER
( O
Ed B-ORG
. O

Arca B-ORG
- O
Trento B-LOC
2004 O
) O
. O

Appointment O
at O
5.30 O
p.m. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

Dead B-PER
, O
6:00 O
p.m. O

Meeting O
with O
Senator O
Ds B-ORG
Enrico B-PER
Morando I-PER
on O
the O
theme O
" O
The O
proposals O
of O
the O
Reformists O
for O
the O
Federation O
and O
the O
reforms O
" O
. O

Hotel O
America O
, O
via B-LOC
Torre I-LOC
Verde I-LOC
52 I-LOC
. O

Villa B-LOC
Lagarina I-LOC
: O

party O
, O
7 O
p.m. O
- O
23 O
p.m. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

prayer O
, O
7.30 O
p.m. O

" O
Universal O
Life O
" O
proposes O
the O
meeting O
" O
Inner O
Prayer O
" O
: O

It O
starts O
at O
8 O
p.m. O
, O
with O
the O
Holy O
Rosary O
. O

At O
the O
end O
, O
at O
21 O
, O
distribution O
of O
pasta O
, O
followed O
by O
music O
and O
dances O
. O

Tomorrow O
afternoon O
, O
at O
3:00 O
pm O
, O
the O
non O
- O
competitive O
march O
" O
Up O
and O
Zo O
for O
Gardol O
" O
The O
party O
will O
continue O
then O
all O
afternoon O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

parents O
, O
Solteri B-LOC
, O
8.15 O
p.m. O

Assembly O
of O
the O
Parents B-ORG
Committee I-ORG
of O
the O
Primary B-ORG
School I-ORG
of I-ORG
Solter I-ORG
on O
: O

activities O
carried O
out O
, O
cafeteria O
commission O
, O
elections O
of O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
Institute I-ORG
. O

Aula O
Magna O
elementary O
school O
. O

Trento B-LOC
: O

prano O
, O
8.30 O
p.m. O

The O
Pranic B-ORG
Healing I-ORG
Association I-ORG
( O
based O
in O
Via B-LOC
Perini I-LOC
43 I-LOC
) O
presents O
its O
activities O
to O
the O
public O
( O
meditation O
and O
breathing O
techniques O
) O
. O

Information O
: O

328,7065165 O
- O
348,2399999 O
( O
Luisa B-PER
Piccolroaz I-PER
0464,434209 O
) O
. O

Abovemonte B-LOC
: O

on O
the O
Sailing B-LOC
, O
8.30 O
p.m. O

Inauguration O
of O
the O
exhibition O
" O
Along O
the O
stream O
Vela O
" O
, O
photographs O
of O
the O
Group O
" O
La B-ORG
Regola I-ORG
" O
of O
Cadine B-LOC
. O
