Today O
, O
I O
meet O
at O
the O
S. O
Chiara O
Center O
. O

Breast O
milk O
, O
Pedrotti B-PER
's O
sos O

Only O
60 O
to O
70 O
percent O
of O
30 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
mothers O
breastfeed O
their O
children O
after O
they O
're O
four O
months O
old O
. O

The O
first O
week O
of O
October O
was O
declared O
International O
Motherhood O
Week O
. O

At O
5.30 O
p.m. O
today O
at O
the O
S. O
Chiara O
Cultural O
Center O
, O
we O
're O
going O
to O
talk O
about O
breastfeeding O
in O
Trenton B-LOC
, O
about O
mothers O
with O
lots O
of O
doubts O
, O
about O
babies O
who O
do O
n't O
always O
have O
the O
right O
to O
the O
best O
nutrition O
. O

The O
neurologist O
Dino B-PER
Pedrotti I-PER
will O
be O
talking O
about O
these O
problems O
. O

" O
If O
I O
were O
a O
baby O
, O
" O
writes O
Dino B-PER
Pedrotti I-PER
, O
" O
I O
'd O
like O
to O
find O
a O
world O
that O
welcomes O
me O
and O
helps O
me O
realize O
myself O
. O

First O
of O
all O
, O
I O
want O
to O
have O
a O
safe O
birth O
. O

but O
right O
after O
that O
I O
'd O
like O
a O
lot O
of O
chocolate O
and O
a O
lot O
of O
milk O
from O
my O
mom O
. O

Here O
's O
the O
problem O
that O
we O
're O
going O
to O
discuss O
with O
politicians O
, O
with O
health O
workers O
, O
with O
citizens O
. O

there O
will O
be O
an O
advisor O
, O
Andreolli B-PER
. O
" O

Where O
can O
mothers O
find O
help O
in O
times O
of O
need O
? O

Every O
month O
, O
10 O
percent O
of O
our O
mothers O
lose O
their O
milk O
. O

At O
four O
months O
of O
age O
, O
60 O
to O
70 O
percent O
of O
thirty O
- O
year O
- O
old O
mothers O
breastfeed O
. O

In O
Scandinavia B-LOC
, O
mothers O
give O
birth O
at O
80 O
to O
90 O
percent O
. O

That O
's O
the O
goal O
that O
we O
're O
proposing O
and O
we O
need O
to O
achieve O
. O

To O
help O
mothers O
in O
difficulty O
, O
the O
Friends B-ORG
of I-ORG
Neonatology I-ORG
Thirty I-ORG
published O
a O
pamphlet O
with O
lots O
of O
updated O
advice O
, O
" O
The O
ABC O
's O
of O
Breastfeeding O
, O
" O
distributed O
at O
the O
meeting O
. O

Athens B-ORG

" O
Yes O
to O
hydrogen O
research O
, O
but O
there O
's O
room O
for O
other O
sectors O
as O
well O
. O
" O
The O
new O
role O
of O
industry O

The O
president O
: O

By O
ANDREA B-PER
TOMASI I-PER

" O
As O
long O
as O
they O
want O
me O
, O
I O
'm O
there O
. O
" O

Innocence B-PER
Cipolletta I-PER
could O
be O
sitting O
on O
the O
chair O
of O
the O
university B-ORG
's O
board I-ORG
of I-ORG
directors I-ORG
. O

He O
has O
given O
his O
willingness O
, O
and O
the O
prerequisites O
for O
his O
acceptance O
are O
all O
there O
. O

Supported O
by O
the O
chairman O
of O
the O
provincial B-ORG
council I-ORG
, O
Lorenzo B-PER
Dellai I-PER
, O
in O
excellent O
relations O
with O
the O
outgoing O
president O
, O
Massimo B-PER
Egidi I-PER
, O
seems O
to O
be O
appreciated O
by O
much O
of O
the O
local O
academic O
world O
. O

And O
we O
'll O
see O
the O
progress O
in O
the O
next O
few O
days O
, O
because O
the O
board O
has O
now O
reached O
its O
natural O
deadline O
, O
and O
the O
nominations O
for O
the O
new O
board B-ORG
will O
have O
to O
be O
formalized O
by O
Tuesday O
, O
and O
then O
the O
teachers O
' O
election O
will O
be O
held O
on O
the O
27th O
of O
the O
month O
. O

When O
all O
the O
members O
are O
then O
appointed O
, O
along O
with O
the O
representatives O
of O
the O
staff O
and O
the O
various O
outside O
faculties O
of O
the O
academy O
, O
the O
new O
president O
will O
be O
elected O
by O
the O
secular O
elite O
. O

Inside O
the O
Athenian O
, O
there O
are O
people O
who O
think O
that O
maybe O
Cipolletta B-PER
is O
the O
right O
person O
for O
that O
job O
, O
given O
her O
history O
and O
her O
strong O
connections O
with O
the O
Italian O
industry O
. O

62 O
years O
old O
, O
a O
graduate O
of O
statistics O
at O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Rome I-ORG
, O
he O
was O
recently O
appointed O
president O
of O
the O
Sole24Ore B-ORG
Group I-ORG
. O

A O
commitment O
that O
, O
he O
says O
, O
will O
not O
prevent O
him O
from O
continuing O
to O
drive O
the O
steering O
wheels O
of O
the O
Trojan O
horse O
. O

" O
This O
new O
assignment O
, O
" O
he O
explains O
, O
" O
is O
taking O
up O
a O
lot O
of O
my O
time O
, O
but O
time O
is O
elastic O
, O
and O
I O
'm O
willing O
to O
continue O
working O
with O
the O
Athenian O
, O
if O
they O
want O
to O
. O
" O

It O
will O
be O
divided O
into O
Rome B-LOC
, O
Milan B-LOC
and O
Trento B-LOC
. O

" O
On O
the O
Italian O
level O
, O
cuts O
make O
life O
harder O
. O

there O
are O
too O
many O
rigid O
rules O
. O

In O
Trentino B-LOC
, O
with O
autonomy O
, O
things O
are O
going O
so O
much O
better O
. O
" O

In O
his O
opinion O
, O
we O
need O
to O
focus O
more O
and O
more O
on O
scientific O
research O
. O

" O
The O
university B-ORG
has O
its O
expertise O
. O

Often O
the O
research O
does O
n't O
bring O
immediate O
results O
. O

It O
's O
long O
- O
term O
investment O
, O
and O
sometimes O
it O
's O
going O
to O
be O
unthinkable O
. O
" O

Trentino B-LOC
is O
talking O
about O
building O
a O
hydrogen O
and O
renewable O
energy O
district O
. O

Is O
this O
the O
kind O
of O
sector O
you O
want O
to O
invest O
in O
? O

" O
The O
question O
is O
complex O
. O

Surely O
Thirty B-LOC
ca O
n't O
miss O
an O
opportunity O
to O
invest O
in O
clean O
energy O
like O
hydrogen O
. O

It O
's O
true O
for O
the O
academic O
world O
as O
well O
as O
for O
the O
business O
world O
. O

The O
university B-ORG
will O
have O
a O
new O
president O
and O
the O
opportunity O
to O
program O
investments O
. O

Renewable O
energy O
is O
a O
fundamental O
way O
forward O
, O
but O
there O
's O
room O
for O
other O
sectors O
as O
well O
. O

Then O
you O
should O
n't O
underestimate O
the O
evolution O
of O
the O
cognitive B-ORG
sciences I-ORG
faculty I-ORG
, O
which O
has O
great O
potential O
. O
" O

When O
you O
talk O
about O
the O
Trenton O
Atene O
, O
you O
talk O
about O
the O
pivotal O
role O
that O
the O
province B-LOC
's O
funding O
played O
. O

And O
then O
there O
's O
the O
national O
research O
projects O
. O

But O
will O
economic O
support O
come O
from O
the O
private O
sector O
in O
the O
future O
? O

" O
I O
do O
n't O
think O
the O
private O
sector O
is O
going O
to O
do O
too O
much O
research O
. O

Collio B-PER
's O
going O
to O
be O
100 O
, O
Longo B-PER
's O
going O
to O
be O
800 O
, O
and O
Martinez B-PER
's O
going O
to O
be O
three O
. O

Among O
the O
regionals O
, O
Berland B-PER
and O
Niederstätter B-PER
. O

The O
streets O
of O
Athens O
will O
light O
up O
at O
night O

Devonish B-PER
, O
Bailey B-PER
and O
all O
the O
protagonists O
compete O
. O

LONDON O
-- O
100 O
METERS O
/ O
This O
year O
, O
the O
British O
Marlon B-PER
Devonish I-PER
, O
Olympic O
gold O
medalist O
in O
the O
4x100 O
, O
has O
a O
10 O
- O
inch O
, O
32 O
- O
inch O
record O
, O
but O
a O
10 O
- O
inch O
, O
13 O
- O
inch O
record O
. O

My O
favorite O
is O
Joshua B-PER
Johnson I-PER
from O
the O
U.S. O
-- O
he O
's O
11 O
inches O
, O
but O
in O
2002 O
, O
he O
was O
9.95 O
inches O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
Simone B-PER
Collio I-PER
( O
10 O
" O
20 O
) O
, O
Slovenian O
Osovnikar B-PER
( O
10 O
" O
15 O
) O
and O
American O
Streete B-PER
- I-PER
Thompson I-PER
( O
10 O
" O
15 O
) O
. O

In O
series B-ORG
B I-ORG
, O
an O
eye O
for O
Torrieri B-PER
( O
10 O
" O
32 O
) O
and O
Kaba B-PER
Fantoni I-PER
( O
10 O
" O
28 O
) O
. O

The O
Kenyan O
Sambu B-PER
is O
a O
very O
nice O
guy O
. O

Andrea B-PER
Barberi I-PER
is O
our O
best O
. O

800 O
metric O
yards O
-- O
Olympic O
semi O
- O
finalist O
Andrea B-PER
Longo I-PER
( O
1'44 O
" O
42 O
season O
, O
1'43 O
" O
74 O
in O
2000 O
) O
versus O
everyone O
else O
. O

even O
against O
the O
Italian O
record O
of O
Fiasconaro B-PER
( O
1,43 O
" O
7 O
in O
' O
73 O
) O
. O

The O
beautiful O
Som B-PER
is O
terrified O
, O
but O
the O
Kenyans O
Wachira B-PER
and O
Yego B-PER
and O
the O
Sudanese O
Ismail B-PER
are O
not O
even O
laughing O
. O

In O
series B-ORG
B I-ORG
are O
the O
high O
school O
students O
Neunhauserer B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
46 O
" O
in O
2002 O
) O
and O
Rifesser B-PER
( O
18 O
years O
old O
, O
1 O
' O
51 O
" O
18 O
in O
2002 O
) O
. O

400 O
OSTACOLI O
/ O
The O
Kamani B-PER
Pancake O
is O
a O
show O
. O

The O
octopus O
Crepaz B-PER
is O
going O
to O
try O
it O
. O

5,000 O
RMB O
/ O
Passenger O
for O
Ivano B-PER
Brugnetti I-PER
, O
Athens O
gold O
in O
the O
" O
20 O
, O
" O
which O
on O
this O
distance O
has O
a O
crew O
of O
19 O
' O
43 O
" O
24 O
( O
2003 O
) O
. O

He O
's O
going O
to O
be O
crowned O
with O
all O
the O
other O
blue O
guys O
. O

PESO O
/ O
The O
angry O
" O
non O
- O
Olympic O
" O
from B-PER
Soglio I-PER
( O
20:19 O
) O
vs. O
Belarusian O
Belov B-PER
( O
21:14 O
, O
6 O
° O
in O
Athens O
) O
. O

GIAVELLOTTO O
/ O
Two O
Lithuanians O
on O
a O
cover O
: O

Vasilevskis B-PER
, O
84.95 O
, O
is O
the O
Olympic O
silver O
, O
and O
Lusis B-PER
, O
82.76 O
. O

ALTO O
/ O
The O
American O
Nieto B-PER
( O
2.34 O
, O
4 O
° O
in O
Athens O
) O
versus O
the O
Swedish O
Strand B-PER
( O
2.30 O
) O
and O
the O
twins O
Nicola B-PER
( O
2.30 O
) O
and O
Julius B-PER
Ciotti I-PER
( O
2.26 O
) O
. O

TRIPLO O
/ O
Lister B-PER
( O
17.78 O
, O
2 O
° O
C O
in O
the O
world O
in O
2004 O
) O
is O
the O
winner O
of O
the O
U.S. O
Trials O
, O
but O
he O
failed O
at O
the O
Olympics O
, O
as O
did O
our O
donor B-PER
( O
16.91 O
) O
. O

Watch O
out O
for O
the O
other O
American O
, O
Kenta B-PER
Bell I-PER
( O
17.58 O
) O
. O

WOMAN O
-- O
200 O
METERS O
/ O
Jamaican O
Bailey B-PER
, O
22 O
, O
won O
the O
Olympic O
gold O
in O
the O
4x100 O
. O

In O
series B-ORG
B I-ORG
, O
there O
's O
Doris B-PER
Tomasini I-PER
, O
a O
24 O
- O
inch O
, O
four O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Italian O
. O

800 O
METHR O
. O
Slovenia O
's O
Ceplak B-PER
( O
1 O
' O
55 O
" O
19 O
" O
) O
won O
the O
Olympic O
bronze O
and O
is O
the O
current O
European O
champion O
. O

Let O
's O
see O
if O
Artuso B-PER
gets O
closer O
to O
the O
two O
minutes O
. O

1,500 O
METRI O
/ O
Ukraine O
's O
Sidorenko B-PER
( O
4'04 O
" O
78 O
" O
) O
and O
Kenya O
's O
Lagat B-PER
( O
4'05 O
" O
32 O
" O
) O
will O
take O
the O
test O
in O
the O
trenches O
of O
Berlanda B-PER
( O
4'12 O
" O
80 O
, O
Italian O
champion O
) O
and O
Dal B-PER
Ri I-PER
( O
4'23 O
" O
84 O
) O
and O
Weissteiner B-PER
( O
4'16 O
" O
6 O
manual O
) O
and O
Tschurtschenthaler B-PER
( O
4'20 O
" O
65 O
) O
. O

400 O
OSTACOLI O
/ O
The O
6 O
a O
( O
Bikert B-PER
, O
Russia O
, O
53 O
" O
72 O
) O
and O
the O
7 O
a O
of O
Athens O
( O
Taylor B-PER
, O
USA O
, O
53 O
" O
36 O
) O
plus O
the O
2003 O
world O
silver O
( O
Glover B-PER
, O
USA O
, O
53 O
" O
33 O
) O
against O
the O
high O
- O
achieving O
Niederstätter B-PER
( O
55 O
" O
52 O
, O
99 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Italian O
champion O
with O
55 O
" O
10 O
) O
. O

ASTA O
/ O
Olympic O
rivalry O
between O
Athens O
' O
3a O
( O
Polish O
Anna B-PER
Rogowska I-PER
, O
4.71 O
) O
, O
4a O
( O
Another O
Polish O
Pirek B-PER
, O
4.72 O
) O
and O
5a O
( O
Iceland O
's O
Elisdottir B-PER
, O
4.60 O
) O
. O

But O
the O
Russians O
, O
Polnova B-PER
( O
4.72 O
) O
, O
two O
in O
Brussels O
, O
can O
beat O
everybody O
. O

And O
there O
's O
also O
30 O
Britons B-PER
( O
4.20 O
, O
Italian O
champion O
) O
. O

the O
blue O
Martinez B-PER
( O
a O
7 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
, O
14.85 O
, O
but O
a O
15 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
) O
, O
the O
Algerian O
Rahouli B-PER
( O
a O
6 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
, O
14.89 O
) O
, O
and O
the O
Russian O
Pyatykh B-PER
( O
a O
8 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
, O
14.85 O
too O
) O
. O

Outlined O
by O
21 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Simona B-PER
La I-PER
Mantia I-PER
( O
14.49 O
) O
. O

G. B-PER
The I-PER
. O

A O
new O
ownership O
dimension O

GLI O
Azionisti O

Here O
's O
the O
new O
list O
of O
shareholders O
of O
Euregio B-ORG
Finance I-ORG
. O

It O
was O
formed O
on O
October O
3 O
, O
2003 O
, O
by O
Alpenair B-ORG
and O
the O
Dutch O
financial O
firm O
Olot B-ORG
Bv I-ORG
. O

Telematics O
dictionary O

Wall B-ORG
Street I-ORG
's O
good O
fortune O
has O
n't O
been O
able O
to O
get O
the O
timing O
right O
for O
Business B-ORG
Square I-ORG
, O
which O
archives O
the O
day O
of O
the O
decline O
in O
contracts O
. O

In O
the O
end O
, O
the O
Mibtel O
dropped O
0.16 O
percent O
, O
and O
the O
Mib30 O
dropped O
0.19 O
percent O
. O

It O
worsens O
the O
Numtel O
, O
which O
is O
0.58 O
percent O
. O

The O
trades O
amounted O
to O
2.263 O
billion O
euros O
. O

It O
's O
a O
day O
of O
auctions O
for O
the O
credit O
institutions O
in O
Piazza B-ORG
Affari I-ORG
, O
and O
they O
've O
weighed O
all O
the O
billboard O
. O

Intesa B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
dropped O
1.83 O
percent O
, O
and O
the O
People B-ORG
of I-ORG
Verona I-ORG
and I-ORG
Novara I-ORG
dropped O
0.5 O
percent O
. O

Weak O
also O
Capitalia B-ORG
, O
at O
a O
rate O
of O
1.65 O
percent O
, O
as O
well O
as O
Bnl B-ORG
-- O
1.68 O
percent O
, O
as O
it O
moved O
in O
opposition O
to O
Mps B-ORG
-- O
0.28 O
percent O
. O

And O
down O
, O
Antoveneta B-ORG
-- O
1.67 O
% O
, O
lower O
than O
Unicredit B-ORG
-- O
0.25 O
percent O
. O

Contrast O
insurance O
. O

The O
Generals O
closed O
with O
a.59 O
percent O
increase O
, O
the O
Ras O
with O
a O
0.31 O
percent O
decrease O
. O

There O
's O
still O
some O
nervousness O
about O
the O
headlines O
of O
Alitalia B-ORG
, O
which O
closed O
in O
reverse O
-- O
0.04 O
percent O
-- O
after O
hovering O
between O
a O
2.7 O
percent O
decline O
and O
a O
2.25 O
percent O
rise O
. O

On O
the O
positive O
side O
, O
for O
Fiat B-ORG
, O
with O
an O
increase O
of O
0.67 O
% O
to O
6,191 O
euros O
. O

The O
Eni O
closed O
with O
a O
fractional O
0.8 O
percent O
, O
whereas O
the O
Edison O
closed O
with O
a O
0.4 O
percent O
. O

Take O
Enel O
--.02 O
percent O
-- O
take O
Saipem B-ORG
--.67 O
percent O
. O

Among O
the O
telecommunications O
headlines O
, O
Tim B-ORG
closed O
the O
session O
with O
a O
0.45 O
% O
spike O
. O

Well O
, O
put O
Telecom O
up O
by O
0.8 O
percent O
. O

In O
the O
media O
, O
it O
closed O
down O
at.65 O
percent O
Mediaset B-ORG
. O

On O
the O
New O
Market O
, O
sales O
for O
e. B-ORG
Biscom I-ORG
( O
-1.67 O
% O
) O
, O
Euphon B-ORG
( O
-1.11 O
% O
) O
and O
even O
Inferentia B-ORG
, O
down O
2.02 O
% O
. O

Fixed O
lock O
for O
tiles B-ORG
. O

None O
of O
the O
soldiers O
were O
hurt O
. O

It O
's O
a O
welcome O
from O
the O
Friuli B-ORG
Brigade I-ORG
, O
just O
arriving O
in O
Iraq B-LOC
. O

Nassiriya B-LOC
, O
a O
firefight O
against O
Italians O

ROMA B-LOC
-- O
On O
August O
30th O
, O
there O
was O
no O
shooting O
in O
Nassiriya B-LOC
. O

And O
yesterday O
the O
Kalashnikovs O
came O
back O
to O
make O
their O
voices O
heard O
. O

welcome O
to O
the O
Friuli B-ORG
Flying I-ORG
Brigade I-ORG
, O
just O
arriving O
in O
Iraq B-LOC
. O

The O
attack O
happened O
at O
21 O
o'clock O
, O
19 O
o'clock O
in O
Italy B-LOC
, O
six O
kilometers O
northwest O
of O
Nasiriyah B-LOC
. O

Numerous O
automatic O
weapons O
were O
fired O
at O
Italian O
soldiers O
from O
three O
directions O
: O
north O
, O
south O
and O
west O
. O

Soldiers O
from O
the O
Friulian B-ORG
Brigade I-ORG
responded O
immediately O
to O
the O
fire O
, O
and O
immediately O
afterwards O
, O
as O
the O
shooting O
continued O
, O
two O
portions O
of O
the O
Rapid B-ORG
Reaction I-ORG
Force I-ORG
were O
deployed O
with O
four O
hundred O
- O
pound O
tanks O
and O
eight O
other O
protected O
vehicles O
. O

Two O
helicopters O
also O
flew O
in O
to O
find O
out O
where O
the O
bombs O
were O
coming O
from O
. O

By O
late O
at O
night O
everything O
was O
quiet O
. O

On O
the O
bridge O
, O
presided O
over O
by O
Italian O
soldiers O
, O
circulation O
was O
restored O
. O

Presentation O
of O
the O
2004 O
edition O
: O

" O
Travel O
in O
Differences O
, O
" O
the O
jury O
actress O

Religion O
Today O
, O
there O
's O
also O
Koll B-PER
. O

From O
sweetheart O
Kathy B-PER
. O

" O
We O
want O
to O
promote O
the O
awareness O
that O
the O
diversity O
that O
exists O
" O
under O
a O
single O
sky O
" O
-- O
the O
title O
and O
inspiration O
of O
the O
two O
previous O
editions O
-- O
is O
an O
inalienable O
wealth O
and O
heritage O
of O
humankind O
, O
" O
said O
Don O
Massimo B-PER
Manservigi I-PER
, O
president O
of O
the O
Festival O
, O
at O
a O
press O
conference O
yesterday O
. O

only O
after O
you O
've O
identified O
exactly O
who O
you O
are O
and O
who O
your O
interlocutors O
are O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
you O
can O
find O
a O
real O
path O
to O
understanding O
and O
dialogue O
. O

At O
the O
center O
of O
the O
demonstration O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
is O
a O
competition O
of O
29 O
feature O
films O
, O
documentaries O
and O
short O
films O
on O
religious O
themes O
selected O
from O
102 O
works O
submitted O
by O
different O
nations O
, O
in O
competition O
for O
the O
Grand O
Prix O
" O
In O
the O
Spirit O
of O
the O
Father O
, O
" O
for O
the O
first O
prize O
in O
consecutive O
sections O
and O
for O
the O
special O
recognitions O
established O
by O
concerts O
with O
various O
religious O
entities O
and O
foundations O
. O

The O
international O
jury O
consists O
of O
five O
film O
, O
culture O
and O
religion O
experts O
. O

" O
Her O
presence O
-- O
says O
Lia B-PER
G. I-PER
Beltrami I-PER
, O
the O
festival O
's O
artistic O
director O
-- O
is O
very O
welcome O
, O
because O
she O
will O
be O
able O
to O
tell O
the O
story O
of O
the O
inner O
journey O
that O
, O
after O
traveling O
to O
Ethiopia B-LOC
, O
changed O
her O
life O
and O
that O
of O
so O
many O
people O
. O
" O

Among O
the O
29 O
films O
in O
the O
competition O
, O
with O
significant O
participation O
from O
the O
Orthodox O
Christian O
world O
and O
the O
Scientist O
and O
Sunni O
Islamic O
world O
, O
he O
highlights O
the O
feature O
film O
section O
, O
which O
praises O
the O
presence O
of O
Mel B-PER
Gibson I-PER
's O
" O
The O
Passion O
" O
at O
his O
first O
festival O
. O

among O
the O
documentaries O
is O
" O
Not O
Only O
K2 O
, O
" O
the O
Triennial O
Renato B-PER
Morelli I-PER
testimony O
to O
the O
life O
of O
the O
filmmaker O
Marco B-PER
Baldi I-PER
, O
who O
on O
Friday O
afternoon O
, O
22nd O
, O
out O
of O
competition O
, O
will O
present O
to O
the O
Cuminetti O
Theater O
his O
latest O
film O
, O
" O
The O
Hidden O
Pearl O
, O
" O
a O
journey O
through O
the O
far O
and O
near O
East O
to O
discover O
the O
Apocalyptic O
civilization O
. O

The O
highlight O
of O
the O
demonstration O
this O
year O
will O
also O
be O
the O
presence O
of O
schools O
, O
with O
study O
labs O
, O
meetings O
and O
screenings O
that O
will O
involve O
several O
thousand O
students O
. O

The O
contest O
will O
also O
be O
accompanied O
by O
a O
reflection O
on O
Jesus O
' O
Passion O
, O
inspired O
by O
Gibson B-PER
's O
recent O
film O
, O
but O
mostly O
inspired O
by O
a O
day O
- O
to O
- O
day O
experience O
of O
violence O
. O
" O
Passion O
and O
Passions O
" O
is O
the O
title O
of O
the O
seminar O
organized O
in O
collaboration O
with O
the O
Itc B-ORG
Institute B-ORG
of I-ORG
Religious I-ORG
Sciences I-ORG
, O
and O
is O
scheduled O
to O
take O
place O
in O
Trent B-LOC
from O
October O
20 O
to O
22 O
. O

Many O
of O
the O
collateral O
initiatives O
are O
also O
dedicated O
to O
art O
. O

from O
the O
artists O
' O
exhibition O
in O
Ucai B-ORG
dedicated O
to O
" O
The O
Manifesto O
of O
Assisi O
. O
" O

A O
perpetual O
light O
bulb O
, O
" O
at O
the O
Bernardo O
Clesio O
Center O
, O
for O
an O
exhibition O
of O
a O
copper O
pheasant O
from O
Masterpiece B-ORG
7 I-ORG
. O

Religion O
's O
journey O
today O
will O
continue O
to O
Nomadelfia B-LOC
, O
so O
Milan B-LOC
and O
the O
usual O
suburbs O
of O
Jerusalem B-LOC
and O
an O
Islamic O
capital O
. O

Religion O
Today O
- O
via B-LOC
Barbacovi I-LOC
4 I-LOC
, O
38100 O
Trento B-LOC
- O
Tel O
and O
Fax O
0461 O
981853 O
( O
Monday O
to O
Thursday O
9.00 O
- O
12.00 O
) O
, O
Web O
site O
: O

www.religionfilm.com O
. O

Castles B-PER
to O
be O
De B-PER
Gasperi I-PER

TRENTO B-LOC
: O
It O
will O
be O
Andrea B-PER
Castelli I-PER
's O
voice O
, O
in O
a O
radio O
adaptation O
of O
" O
Caro O
Alcide O
, O
" O
the O
new O
book O
by O
Pino B-PER
Loperfido I-PER
, O
the O
novel O
biography O
of O
Alcide B-PER
De I-PER
Gasperi I-PER
, O
who O
has O
met O
both O
criticism O
and O
public O
approval O
. O

The O
sequence O
, O
produced O
by O
the O
Sede O
Rai B-ORG
Programme O
Structure O
of O
Trento B-LOC
, O
is O
a O
14 O
- O
minute O
, O
15 O
- O
minute O
sequence O
that O
runs O
every O
Friday O
from O
14:15 O
a.m. O
to O
2:30 O
p.m. O
from O
October O
1 O
through O
the O
end O
of O
December O
. O

Alcide B-PER
De I-PER
Gasperi I-PER
will O
be O
performed O
by O
Carlo B-PER
Marzani I-PER
, O
while O
the O
male O
dialogues O
in O
the O
book O
will O
be O
performed O
by O
Bruno B-PER
Vanzo I-PER
and O
Mario B-PER
Cagol I-PER
. O

Cecilia B-PER
Ruele I-PER
will O
play O
the O
soprano O
Lucia B-PER
De I-PER
Gasperi I-PER
in O
the O
moving O
dialogue O
with O
her O
father O
. O

The O
technical O
realization O
is O
by O
Italian B-PER
Salvador I-PER
and O
the O
queen O
is O
by O
Maria B-PER
Serena I-PER
Tait I-PER
. O

Rai O
Three O
o'clock O
, O
20.55 O
. O

SLOVENIA B-ORG
. O

Simcic B-PER
. O

Brecko B-PER
. O

Berko B-PER

Suler B-PER

Hadzic B-PER

Bozic B-PER

Urbanc B-PER

Matic B-PER

Semler B-PER
. O

Stromajer B-PER

ITALY B-ORG
. O

Agliardi B-PER

Power B-PER
. O

Blue B-PER
. O

Mantovani B-PER
. O

Chiellini B-PER
. O

Rosina B-PER
. O

Donadel B-PER

Aquilani B-PER
. O

Lazzars B-PER

White B-PER
people O
. O

Carpenters B-PER
. O

Available O
: O

SLOVENIA B-ORG
: O

Ct O
. O
Zupan B-PER

ITALY B-ORG
: O

Berni B-PER
, O
Small B-PER
, O
Zambelli B-PER
, O
Loviso B-PER
, O
Nocerino B-PER
, O
Pepe B-PER
, O
Corvia B-PER
. O

Ct O
Gentlemen B-PER

ARBITRO O
: O

Briakos B-PER
, O
Greece B-LOC
. O

OVER O
here O
/ O
The O
long O
- O
running O
captain O
's O
opinion O
after O
a O
zero O
- O
to O
- O
zero O
crash O

The O
rediscovery O
is O
behind O
the O
corner O
. O

Andreoli B-PER
: O

" O
In O
Salò B-LOC
, O
you O
'll O
see O
a O
different O
team O
. O
" O

by O
GIANLUCA B-PER
DE I-PER
MASI I-PER

ARCO B-LOC
-- O
In O
Sunday O
's O
seasonal O
outing O
against O
the O
ferocious O
matriarch O
, O
in O
which O
the O
Arco B-ORG
failed O
to O
go O
beyond O
a O
couple O
- O
linked O
wall O
, O
the O
absence O
of O
the O
captain O
and O
charismatic O
leader O
of O
the O
group O
Julius B-PER
Andreoli I-PER
made O
itself O
felt O
, O
and O
not O
least O
. O

The O
cardin O
element O
of O
the O
arcade O
game O
-- O
a O
tremendous O
D B-ORG
experience O
playing O
in O
Benacense B-ORG
, O
Rovereto B-ORG
, O
Arzignano B-ORG
, O
Bassano B-ORG
and O
Santa B-ORG
-- O
had O
to O
sit O
on O
a O
bench O
for O
a O
problem O
with O
the O
mathematician O
the O
week O
before O
and O
not O
be O
able O
to O
be O
100 O
percent O
. O

And O
yet O
the O
captain O
in O
yellow O
and O
blue O
says O
he O
's O
confident O
. O

" O
As O
far O
as O
my O
physical O
condition O
is O
concerned O
at O
the O
moment O
, O
I O
do O
n't O
feel O
weak O
. O

We O
hope O
that O
the O
problem O
does O
n't O
develop O
into O
a O
tendinitis O
, O
otherwise O
the O
recovery O
time O
will O
be O
longer O
. O

For O
now O
, O
I O
can O
only O
say O
that O
I O
'm O
going O
to O
do O
my O
best O
to O
be O
on O
the O
field O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
, O
maybe O
as O
early O
as O
next O
Sunday O
, O
when O
we O
're O
on O
scene O
in O
Salò B-LOC
, O
a O
move O
that O
deserves O
all O
our O
attention O
. O

Looking O
at O
yesterday O
's O
match O
, O
I O
think O
we O
paid O
a O
price O
for O
the O
excitement O
of O
being O
in O
front O
of O
our O
crowd O
. O

We O
had O
a O
lot O
of O
patience O
to O
get O
it O
right O
and O
to O
start O
with O
the O
right O
foot O
, O
but O
we O
should O
n't O
forget O
that O
for O
many O
of O
my O
colleagues O
, O
it O
was O
the O
very O
first O
time O
in O
this O
series O
. O

Nevertheless O
, O
I O
think O
we O
've O
fought O
a O
very O
hard O
race O
, O
putting O
all O
the O
intensity O
we O
can O
into O
the O
field O
. O

We O
were O
n't O
brilliant O
at O
the O
very O
first O
stages O
of O
the O
encounter O
, O
I O
admit O
, O
but O
for O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
first O
time O
, O
we O
tried O
to O
play O
the O
game O
and O
impose O
our O
own O
game O
, O
and O
I O
also O
think O
, O
for O
a O
long O
time O
, O
we O
did O
quite O
well O
. O

Let O
's O
not O
forget O
the O
goal O
on O
Toccoli B-PER
's O
feet O
-- O
in O
this O
picture O
, O
the O
burnt O
- O
out O
churchyard O
on O
Sunday O
to O
score O
a O
surprise O
by O
finding O
the O
footsteps O
of O
Atti B-PER
, O
ndr O
-- O
where O
their O
forward O
was O
very O
good O
at O
opposing O
the O
footsteps O
, O
and O
also O
the O
goal O
that O
was O
knocked O
out O
at O
Dal B-PER
Ferro I-PER
for O
a O
millimeter O
kick O
. O

The O
second O
time O
, O
heat O
became O
the O
absolute O
dominant O
. O

We O
certainly O
suffered O
more O
than O
they O
did O
, O
but O
probably O
it O
's O
also O
because O
of O
the O
physics O
. O

they O
're O
minutes O
and O
seconds O
faster O
than O
we O
are O
. O

Now O
we O
have O
a O
whole O
week O
ahead O
of O
us O
to O
work O
and O
to O
get O
ourselves O
ready O
for O
the O
next O
game O
, O
correcting O
the O
mistakes O
that O
we O
've O
made O
, O
but O
starting O
from O
how O
good O
it O
has O
been O
. O

I O
hope O
to O
return O
to O
the O
mystery O
, O
and O
I O
'm O
confident O
, O
especially O
in O
the O
light O
of O
the O
fact O
that O
, O
next O
week O
, O
we O
may O
have O
a O
better O
basic O
physical O
condition O
than O
that O
of O
the O
Centennial B-ORG
. O
" O

The O
health O
green O
is O
getting O
complicated O
, O
even O
in O
the O
face O
of O
Rsu B-ORG
's O
renewal O
. O

" O
Not O
enough O
money O
for O
the O
contract O
. O
" O

JS B-ORG
: O
Yeah O
. O

immediately O
the O
balance O
sheet O
for O
the O
biennium O
2002 O
- O
2003 O
. O

On O
the O
renewal O
of O
the O
healthcare O
contract O
, O
the O
Civil B-ORG
Service O
intervenes O
. O

After O
Uil B-ORG
and O
Nursing B-ORG
up I-ORG
, O
the O
two O
most O
representative O
trade O
unions O
, O
left O
the O
table O
with O
Apran B-ORG
, O
the O
first O
iron O
arm O
of O
the O
healthcare O
and O
non O
- O
healthcare O
professions O
were O
formed O
. O

" O
The O
strife O
between O
thirty O
- O
year O
- O
old O
trade O
union O
organizations O
over O
the O
renewal O
of O
the O
health O
contract O
is O
unprecedented O
, O
neither O
in O
Trento B-LOC
nor O
nationally O
, O
" O
says O
Roberto B-PER
Vivian I-PER
, O
secretary O
of O
Fps B-ORG
Cisl I-ORG
. O

The O
escalation O
of O
conflict O
at O
every O
level O
distorts O
negotiations O
and O
disorientates O
workers O
. O

We O
are O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
an O
election O
campaign O
for O
the O
re O
- O
establishment O
of O
the O
U.S.R. B-ORG
, O
and O
the O
denigrating O
action O
of O
so O
many O
trade O
union O
signs O
is O
almost O
a O
strategy O
, O
given O
the O
mid O
- O
November O
meeting O
, O
which O
is O
the O
date O
of O
the O
election O
. O

We O
need O
to O
find O
common O
ground O
. O

Contracts O
of O
employment O
ca O
n't O
be O
legitimate O
only O
by O
those O
who O
think O
they O
have O
a O
majority O
, O
especially O
when O
that O
majority O
does O
n't O
represent O
all O
the O
professions O
to O
which O
the O
contract O
is O
intended O
. O
" O

" O
This O
is O
a O
dangerous O
anomaly O
, O
" O
says O
Vivian B-PER
. O

To O
make O
matters O
even O
more O
complicated O
is O
the O
question O
of O
the O
funds O
that O
have O
been O
set O
aside O
, O
deemed O
insufficient O
. O

It O
's O
300,000 O
euros O
-- O
remember O
Pierachille B-PER
Dalledonne I-PER
, O
Secretary O
of O
Health B-ORG
. O

But O
the O
appeal O
also O
lacks O
150,000 O
euros O
. O
" O

" O
Let O
's O
look O
at O
Apran B-ORG
's O
request O
for O
a O
review O
of O
the O
resources O
available O
, O
not O
just O
for O
2002 O
- O
2003 O
, O
but O
for O
2004 O
- O
2005 O
, O
" O
says O
Vivian B-PER
. O

Only O
then O
will O
we O
be O
able O
to O
assess O
the O
need O
for O
additional O
resources O
, O
for O
which O
we O
're O
going O
to O
ask O
for O
additional O
funding O
in O
the O
2005 O
provincial O
budget O
, O
at O
the O
earliest O
stage O
. O
" O

Toni B-PER
and O
Totti B-PER
showed O
a O
good O
sense O
of O
friendship O
with O
the O
U18 B-ORG
. O

FIRENZE B-LOC
: O
It O
's O
been O
5 O
- O
2 O
, O
Italy B-ORG
's O
friendly O
match O
against O
the O
Under-18s B-ORG
in O
Cardiff B-LOC
. O

Two O
times O
in O
the O
' O
50s O
, O
not O
included O
by O
Gattus B-PER
and O
Nesta B-PER
, O
who O
stayed O
to O
train O
in O
a O
nearby O
field O
. O

And O
with O
them O
at O
first O
also O
Zambrotta B-PER
, O
which O
Lippi B-PER
then O
put O
in O
the O
26th O
second O
time O
instead O
of O
Pancaro B-PER
. O

The O
C.T. O
tried O
at O
the O
beginning O
a O
four O
- O
two O
- O
three O
- O
three O
- O
one O
with O
central O
tones O
, O
all O
supporting O
, O
left O
- O
handed O
and O
De B-PER
Rossi I-PER
- O
Blazy B-PER
midfielder O
pair O
. O

At O
first O
, O
the O
best O
one O
was O
really O
De B-PER
Rossi I-PER
, O
who O
got O
a O
headache O
right O
away O
, O
and O
he O
was O
always O
there O
in O
the O
game O
, O
both O
in O
front O
of O
the O
defense O
to O
get O
the O
action O
started O
, O
and O
in O
the O
final O
stages O
. O

Bad O
, O
on O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
performance B-PER
, O
maybe O
blocked O
by O
emotion O
, O
that O
failed O
two O
crucial O
goals O
and O
did O
n't O
seem O
as O
lively O
as O
Cagliari B-ORG
. O

Growing O
up O
, O
Totti B-PER
's O
game O
, O
the O
first O
in O
blue O
after O
Europe O
. O

He O
assisted O
Toni B-PER
's O
first O
goal O
on O
the O
14th O
at O
cross O
- O
country O
on O
the O
right O
, O
and O
his O
second O
on O
the O
26th O
, O
a O
shot O
off O
the O
outside O
from O
Castroni B-PER
behind O
Council O
. O

For O
the O
Under B-ORG
18 I-ORG
goal O
at O
the O
28th O
minute O
of O
Aquafresca B-PER
, O
which O
Buffon B-PER
scored O
with O
a O
big O
shot O
in O
the O
back O
of O
the O
net O
. O

The O
second O
time O
Lippi B-PER
went O
to O
four O
-- O
four O
-- O
two O
, O
with O
Di B-PER
Vaio I-PER
on O
the O
left O
and O
Corradi B-PER
-- O
Gilardino B-PER
in O
front O
. O

She O
played O
well O
, O
Perrotta B-PER
, O
who O
yesterday O
for O
the O
first O
time O
took O
control O
of O
the O
balloon O
and O
went O
on O
a O
hike O
. O

Before O
him O
, O
though O
, O
it O
was O
Di B-PER
Vaio I-PER
who O
opened O
the O
markers O
in O
the O
camera O
with O
a O
left O
diagonal O
, O
while O
after O
the O
4 O
- O
2 O
moment O
, O
it O
was O
Zambrotta B-PER
who O
fixed O
the O
final O
5 O
- O
2 O
with O
a O
powerful O
right O
after O
a O
large O
number O
on O
the O
left O
flank O
. O

Here O
's O
the O
friendly O
chart O
. O

RETI O
: O

14 O
pts O
Toni B-PER
, O
26 O
pts O
Totti B-PER
, O
28 O
pts O
Aquafresca B-PER
, O
18 O
pts O
Vaio B-PER
, O
32 O
pts O
Momente B-PER
, O
34 O
pts O
Perrotta B-PER
, O
42 O
pts O
Zambrotta B-PER
. O

ITALY B-ORG
pt O
( O
4 O
- O
2 O
- O
3 O
- O
1 O
): O

Buffon B-PER
. O

Bonera B-PER
, O
Cannavar B-PER
, O
Materazzi B-PER
, O
Pancaro B-PER
. O

Blasi B-PER
, O
De B-PER
Rossi I-PER
. O

Cameroonian B-PER
, O
All B-PER
, O
Exhibition B-PER
; O

Tony B-PER
. O

Ct O
Lippi B-PER

ITALY B-ORG
ST O
( O
four O
- O
four O
- O
two O
): O

Pelicans B-PER
. O

Oddo B-PER
, O
Zaccardo B-PER
, O
Materazzi B-PER
, O
Pancaro B-PER
. O

Diana B-PER
, O
Perrotta B-PER
, O
Fiore B-PER
, O
Vaio B-PER
. O

Corradi B-PER
, O
Gilardino B-PER
. O

Ct O
Lippi B-PER

ARBITRO O
: O

Terni B-LOC
's O
Tagliavento O

Run O
the O
courses O
. O

Oriental O
dance O

There O
was O
also O
a O
course O
for O
girls O
between O
the O
ages O
of O
nine O
and O
15 O
that O
ran O
from O
6 O
: O
30 O
a.m. O
to O
7 O
: O
30 O
p.m. O
, O
and O
it O
was O
a O
men O
's O
version O
of O
" O
sharqi O
, O
" O
" O
sayi O
, O
" O
" O
rhythmic O
music O
, O
" O
" O
coreography O
. O
" O

Info O
: O

0464 O
555104 O
; O

347 O
/ O
4285696 O
-- O
email O
margarit@tin.it O
; O

www.ccmargarita.com O

Universities O
. O

The O
outgoing O
president O
, O
accompanied O
in O
Rome B-LOC
, O
would O
address O
the O
reform O
of O
the O
Italian O
atheists O
. O

Moratti B-PER
wants O
Egyptians O
on O
his O
side O

Commissioner O
- O
designate O
. O

It O
could O
replace O
De B-PER
Mayo I-PER
. O

He O
has O
n't O
left O
his O
office O
on O
Belenzani B-LOC
Street I-LOC
yet O
-- O
where O
he O
's O
been O
working O
for O
eight O
years O
-- O
and O
they O
're O
already O
filing O
" O
job O
offers O
. O
" O

After O
two O
deployments O
to O
the O
command O
post O
at O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Trent I-ORG
, O
where O
he O
got O
credit O
, O
now O
he O
has O
no O
choice O
but O
to O
be O
embarrassed O
. O

He O
was O
given O
various O
proposals O
. O

Massimo O
Egidi O
, O
the O
outgoing O
president O
, O
in O
a O
few O
weeks O
' O
time O
is O
going O
to O
leave O
office O
for O
newly O
elected O
David B-PER
Bassi I-PER
, O
but O
he O
's O
certainly O
not O
going O
to O
have O
a O
problem O
locating O
him O
. O

It O
turns O
out O
, O
by O
the O
end O
of O
this O
curriculum O
, O
the O
teacher O
is O
not O
just O
going O
to O
be O
teaching O
. O

But O
Egypt B-PER
, O
which O
has O
managed O
to O
build O
strong O
national O
ties O
, O
even O
as O
a O
member O
of O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Crusades I-ORG
, O
could O
seek O
a O
strategic O
role O
in O
Rome B-LOC
, O
alongside O
Prime O
Minister O
Leticia B-PER
Moratti I-PER
, O
with O
whom O
it O
has O
excellent O
relations O
. O

A O
voice O
, O
this O
one O
, O
that O
has O
been O
ringing O
in O
the O
halls O
of O
the O
Athens O
for O
a O
long O
time O
and O
that O
could O
now O
become O
a O
reality O
. O

Massimo B-PER
Egidi I-PER
, O
in O
fact O
, O
could O
take O
the O
lead O
in O
what O
until O
a O
while O
ago O
was O
called O
the O
Commission B-ORG
of I-ORG
May I-ORG
, O
after O
the O
president O
of O
the O
Luiss B-ORG
. O

It O
's O
a O
working O
group O
studying O
and O
designing O
the O
governance O
guidelines O
for O
the O
Italian O
University O
of O
the O
Future O
. O

Adriano B-PER
De I-PER
Maio I-PER
left O
office O
, O
and O
his O
ideal O
successor O
seems O
to O
be O
the O
inquiry O
of O
the O
Senate O
of O
Trento B-LOC
. O

At O
the O
end O
of O
July O
, O
Adriano B-PER
De I-PER
Maio I-PER
left O
the O
ministry O
committee O
that O
was O
tasked O
with O
redesigning O
the O
teacher O
's O
legal O
system O
and O
redesigning O
the O
higher O
education O
system O
. O

" O
On O
this O
very O
topic O
-- O
it O
's O
under O
the O
heading O
' O
In O
the O
cathedral O
' O
-- O
the O
proposals O
that O
De B-PER
Mai I-PER
made O
, O
like O
cutting O
graduate O
schools O
, O
they O
ended O
up O
in O
the O
treasury O
. O

they O
did O
n't O
like O
professional O
orders O
and O
the O
undersecretary O
Maria B-PER
Grazia I-PER
Siliquini I-PER
. O
" O

It O
turns O
out O
that O
the O
reason O
it O
's O
broken O
is O
because O
De B-PER
Maio I-PER
has O
n't O
been O
named O
president O
of O
the O
NRC B-ORG
. O

So O
this O
is O
where O
Massimo B-PER
Egidi I-PER
comes O
in O
. O

Letizia B-PER
Moratti I-PER
might O
point O
to O
the O
outgoing O
president O
, O
who O
in O
commission O
is O
going O
to O
operate O
with O
Francesco B-PER
Alberoni I-PER
and O
Fabio B-PER
Roversi I-PER
Monaco I-PER
. O

A O
few O
days O
after O
the O
end O
of O
his O
second O
term O
, O
Egypt B-PER
has O
two O
options O
. O

one O
runs O
the O
Triennial B-ORG
Institute I-ORG
of I-ORG
Culture I-ORG
, O
the O
other O
one O
in O
Rome B-LOC
. O

It O
's O
very O
well O
- O
respected O
both O
in O
the O
mountains B-LOC
and O
in O
the O
capital O
. O

His O
future O
and O
possible O
new O
career O
prospects O
are O
going O
to O
be O
known O
in O
the O
next O
few O
days O
. O

A. B-PER
Tom I-PER
. O

Confirm O
the O
tops O
of O
Viale B-ORG
Mazzini I-ORG
. O

The O
opposition O
charges O
: O

And O
that O
's O
what O
it O
's O
about O
. O

Rai B-ORG
, O
the O
UDC B-ORG
is O
changing O
its O
mind O
. O

Go O
ahead O
like O
this O
. O

ROMA B-LOC
-- O
The O
Rai B-ORG
quad I-ORG
can O
stay O
seated O
until O
June O
2005 O
. O

In O
fact O
, O
the O
Supervisory O
Board O
dismissed O
without O
amendment O
the O
statute O
of O
the O
new O
company O
that O
had O
been O
formed O
by O
the O
merger O
of O
Rai B-ORG
Spa I-ORG
and O
Rai B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
, O
and O
, O
surprisingly O
, O
UDC B-ORG
aligned O
itself O
with O
the O
DLC B-ORG
by O
approving O
the O
document O
. O

There O
's O
not O
even O
a O
vote O
cast O
on O
the O
no O
to O
the O
extension O
of O
the O
council B-ORG
drafted O
by O
President O
Petruccioli O
, O
bolstered O
by O
the O
same O
centrists O
as O
the O
Democrats O
. O

The O
opposition O
in O
the O
majority O
is O
screaming O
for O
" O
overtime O
" O
and O
" O
covered O
strike O
" O
as O
opposed O
to O
which O
side O
to O
oppose O
, O
and O
the O
UDC B-ORG
replies O
by O
talking O
about O
" O
management O
choice O
, O
" O
driven O
by O
the O
need O
not O
to O
block O
the O
iteration O
of O
the O
new O
Rai B-ORG
. O

Anyone O
who O
imagined O
that O
there O
was O
a O
repeat O
yesterday O
in O
Sanctuary O
of O
the O
cross O
- O
deployment O
that O
came O
out O
in O
July O
in O
the O
ultimatum O
to O
the O
HQ O
-- O
home O
by O
September O
30th O
-- O
is O
immediately O
denied O
it O
by O
the O
UDC B-ORG
headquarters O
. O

At O
the O
opening O
of O
the O
session O
, O
Iervolino B-PER
announced O
a O
favourable O
opinion O
of O
the O
document O
by O
Forza B-ORG
Italia I-ORG
, O
An B-ORG
and O
Lega B-ORG
Nord I-ORG
for O
a O
yes O
to O
the O
statute O
as O
approved O
by O
the O
assemblies O
of O
Rai B-ORG
Spa I-ORG
and O
Rai B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
. O

" O
We O
have O
n't O
signed O
the O
document O
to O
mark O
a O
milestone O
that O
shows O
us O
a O
complete O
disapproval O
of O
the O
quad B-ORG
issues O
, O
" O
explains O
Iervolino B-PER
, O
" O
but O
the O
iteration O
is O
not O
blocked O
. O

As O
a O
result O
, O
19 O
yeses O
to O
17 O
noes O
. O

Neither O
can O
the O
head O
of O
the O
Margherita B-ORG
Gentiloni B-PER
group O
attempt O
to O
insert O
, O
in O
the O
form O
of O
a O
sub O
- O
amendment O
to O
the O
document O
, O
the O
appeal O
to O
the O
board B-ORG
to O
resign O
as O
soon O
as O
the O
merger O
is O
over O
: O

even O
in O
this O
case O
, O
the O
CDL B-ORG
is O
compressed O
and O
the O
noes O
are O
19 O
against O
18 O
yes O
. O

Right O
away O
from O
the O
opposition O
, O
the O
president O
of O
the O
Greens B-ORG
Pecoraro B-PER
Scanio I-PER
, O
who O
talks O
about O
" O
Udc B-ORG
's O
incredible O
cash O
flow O
, O
" O
asks O
if O
there O
's O
been O
" O
a O
covert O
impact O
on O
the O
skin O
of O
the O
company O
. O
" O

From O
Ds B-ORG
, O
Giuliani B-PER
calls O
the O
Vote O
for O
Vigilance O
" O
very O
serious O
" O
and O
sees O
the O
risk O
of O
going O
" O
to O
a O
unified O
networked O
presidency O
. O
" O

More O
cauto O
Gentlemen B-PER
, O
who O
, O
however O
, O
notes O
that O
the O
rule O
allowing O
the O
cauto B-ORG
to O
remain O
seated O
until O
June O
2005 O
-- O
that O
is O
, O
until O
the O
2004 O
budget O
is O
approved O
-- O
" O
will O
make O
the O
corporate O
top O
even O
more O
unstable O
and O
open O
up O
a O
new O
season O
of O
legal O
controversy O
. O
" O

For O
the O
Italian B-ORG
Communists I-ORG
, O
he O
speaks O
of O
" O
a O
tacit O
agreement O
by O
the O
majority O
with O
the O
aim O
of O
undermining O
the O
company O
. O
" O

in O
Breve O
. O

So O
let O
's O
turn O
to O
consultation B-ORG
. O

The O
province B-LOC
is O
going O
to O
appeal O
to O
the O
Constitutional B-ORG
Court I-ORG
on O
the O
basis O
of O
the O
statutory O
competences O
of O
the O
Ministry B-ORG
of I-ORG
Health I-ORG
's O
Decree O
on O
the O
" O
Requirements O
for O
Scientific O
Societies O
and O
Scientific O
Technical O
Associations O
of O
Health O
Professions O
. O
" O

Two O
million O
on O
Appa B-ORG
. O

Assigned O
to O
the O
Provincial B-ORG
Environmental I-ORG
Protection I-ORG
Agency I-ORG
, O
the O
2004 O
budget O
stands O
at O
2.282,900 O
euros O
, O
of O
which O
1.187,500 O
for O
current O
expenditures O
, O
398,000 O
for O
investment O
expenditures O
and O
696,600 O
for O
interventions O
. O

Universities B-ORG
, O
Opera B-ORG
funds O
. O

For O
operating O
expenses O
in O
2004 O
, O
they O
allocated O
to O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Trent I-ORG
Opera I-ORG
5,558,955 O
euros O
, O
plus O
an O
additional O
2,500,000 O
euros O
for O
investment O
expenses O
. O

Eight O
million O
for O
research O
. O

Funded O
by O
8,870,000 O
euros O
, O
the O
2004 O
institutional O
research O
activity O
of O
the O
Michele B-ORG
Agricultural I-ORG
Institute I-ORG
. O

Five O
days O
of O
meetings O
, O
dancing O
, O
food O
and O
singing O
in O
Peru B-LOC
. O

Minorities O
at O
parties O

A O
tool O
to O
interrogate O
others O
, O
to O
interrogate O
others O
, O
to O
interrogate O
borders O
that O
break O
and O
move O
, O
to O
interrogate O
even O
distant O
minorities O
that O
become O
familiar O
and O
everyday O
. O

It O
's O
hosted O
by O
Reanto B-PER
Morelli I-PER
. O

" O
A O
first O
run O
of O
this O
game O
might O
be O
" O
Number O
Zero O
, O
" O
which O
, O
in O
addition O
to O
" O
Number O
Zero O
" O
in O
this O
first O
run O
, O
synthesizes O
a O
way O
of O
saying O
that O
minorities O
exist O
and O
do O
n't O
exist O
, O
because O
we O
're O
all O
a O
minority O
of O
somebody O
else O
. O

Derek B-PER
Walcott I-PER
's O
concept O
of O
" O
universal O
arrogance O
" O
explains O
to O
us O
that O
around O
the O
world O
, O
the O
question O
of O
languages O
, O
races O
and O
cultures O
is O
now O
an O
unquestionable O
fact O
. O

At O
the O
same O
time O
, O
every O
minority O
has O
a O
treasure O
of O
knowledge O
and O
identity O
, O
which O
, O
like O
all O
treasures O
, O
only O
has O
value O
if O
displayed O
and O
exchanged O
. O
" O

Finally O
, O
just O
change O
your O
accent O
and O
our O
logo O
becomes O
" O
I O
'm O
going O
to O
move O
forward O
, O
" O
a O
look O
to O
the O
future O
, O
new O
perspectives O
and O
contamination O
of O
multimedia O
and O
minorities O
. O

All O
accompanied O
by O
the O
red O
thread O
of O
music O
crossing O
the O
ancient O
and O
new O
borders O
of O
Minority O
Polyphonies O
, O
four O
dates O
to O
meet O
archaic O
polyvocal O
traditions O
, O
revisits O
and O
contaminations O
, O
related O
to O
the O
great O
folk O
musical O
heritage O
of O
Sardinia B-LOC
, O
the O
mountains B-LOC
of I-LOC
Aurunci I-LOC
, O
Istria B-LOC
Venice I-LOC
, O
and O
the O
Sinti O
Singara O
culture O
. O

This O
is O
the O
program O
. O

Wednesday O
: O

18 O
o'clock O
-- O
Opening O
with O
the O
author O
at O
the O
Pergine B-LOC
Castle O
. O

Gigi B-PER
Zoppello I-PER
: O
Carmine B-PER
Abate I-PER
's O
" O
Return O
Party O
" O

21 O
o'clock O
-- O
concert O
in O
the O
Church O
of O
St. O
George O
Serso O
of O
the O
Singers B-ORG
of I-ORG
Castelsardo I-ORG
and I-ORG
Sessa I-ORG
Aurunca I-ORG
. O

Thursday O
: O

18 O
o'clock O
-- O
Opening O
with O
the O
author O
at O
the O
Pergine B-LOC
Castle O
. O

Gianni B-PER
Gentilini I-PER
presents O
Fredo B-PER
Valla I-PER
's O
" O
Travel O
in O
the O
Occitan O
Valleys O
of O
Piedmont O
. O
" O

21 O
o'clock O
-- O
concert O
in O
the O
Church O
of O
the O
Virgins O
of O
Boghes B-ORG
and I-ORG
Voices I-ORG
; O

Friday O
: O

17 O
- O
23 O
p.m. O
in O
E. B-LOC
Fruet I-LOC
's O
" O
Searching O
for O
the O
Gold O
of O
the O
Ferry O
" O
square O
; O

20:30 O
-- O
dance O
in O
Municipal B-LOC
Square I-LOC
with O
the O
Canadian B-ORG
Folklore I-ORG
Group I-ORG
and O
the O
Fersina B-ORG
Folklore I-ORG
Group I-ORG
; O

22 O
o'clock O
-- O
concert O
in O
Municipal B-LOC
Square I-LOC
with O
Neves B-ORG
and I-ORG
his I-ORG
band I-ORG
; O

19 O
to O
23 O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruet I-LOC
, O
" O
Minority O
in O
the O
Box O
. O
" O

Saturday O
: O

17 O
- O
23 O
p.m. O
in O
E. B-LOC
Fruet I-LOC
's O
" O
Searching O
for O
the O
Gold O
of O
the O
Ferry O
" O
square O
; O

20:30 O
-- O
multimedia O
show O
at O
the O
Yol O
Tent O
Theatre O
. O

21.30 O
p.m. O
- O
Concert O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Municipal I-LOC
del O
Coro O
" O
Marco B-ORG
Garbin I-ORG
" O
; O

19 O
to O
23 O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
E. I-LOC
Fruet I-LOC
, O
" O
Minority O
in O
the O
Box O
. O
" O

Sunday O
: O

10 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
to O
12 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
and O
17 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
to O
23 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
at O
E. O
Fruet O
's O
" O
Searching O
for O
the O
Gold O
of O
the O
Ferry O
" O
square O
. O

Promotion B-ORG
/ O
The O
first O
day O
of O
the O
championship O
also O
smiles O
at O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
, O
winning O
the O
big O
match O
with O
Condinese B-ORG

Riva B-ORG
del I-ORG
Garda I-ORG
, O
starting O
with O
the O
button O

Rudy B-PER
Prandi I-PER
's O
formation O
: O
Four O
networks O
to O
beat O
the O
tide B-ORG

TRENTO B-LOC
-- O
First O
day O
of O
the O
promotional O
championship O
without O
any O
big O
surprises O
. O

The O
two O
favorites O
of O
the O
day O
, O
Riva B-ORG
del I-ORG
Garda I-ORG
and O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
, O
came O
out O
ahead O
with O
three O
points O
. O

clear O
the O
claim O
of O
the O
eleven O
of O
Prandi B-PER
, O
who O
won O
four O
- O
to O
- O
zero O
in O
the O
Cavrasto B-LOC
field O
, O
more O
to O
the O
credit O
of O
the O
success O
of O
the O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
, O
who O
had O
to O
see O
herself O
with O
a O
very O
quoted O
team O
like O
the O
Condinese B-ORG
. O

A O
clear O
victory O
for O
Alberto B-PER
Betta I-PER
's O
Villain O
, O
who O
in O
Gabbiolo O
takes O
a O
little O
over O
10 O
minutes O
to O
record O
the O
practice O
of O
La B-ORG
Rovere I-ORG
. O

The O
two O
networks O
from O
the O
distance O
of O
Fontana B-PER
and O
Floriani B-PER
's O
ranch O
did O
n't O
leave O
a O
cliff O
in O
Bevilacqua B-PER
. O

It O
starts O
with O
the O
brand O
new O
Blue B-ORG
that O
, O
thanks O
to O
the O
labels O
by O
Flores B-PER
and O
Fabbri B-PER
, O
marks O
Cavalese B-LOC
with O
what O
can O
perhaps O
be O
considered O
the O
main O
surprise O
of O
the O
day O
. O

Too O
heavy O
for O
the O
Fiemme B-ORG
to O
be O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
Luca B-PER
Giunchi I-PER
's O
field O
. O

The O
newest O
Aldeno B-ORG
of O
the O
ds O
. O
Kaisermann B-PER
is O
out O
on O
the O
grandstand O
, O
conquering O
the O
entire O
pitch O
in O
the O
outfield O
game O
on O
the O
difficult O
pitch O
of O
the O
Chess O
Championship B-ORG
. O

Go O
ahead O
and O
make B-PER
the O
markers O
for O
the O
yellow O
ones O
. O

Half O
a O
false O
step O
from O
the O
Levic B-ORG
Terme I-ORG
, O
stopped O
on O
the O
sidewalk O
from O
Mount B-ORG
Baldo I-ORG
. O

Augustine B-PER
's O
defense O
, O
Brusco B-PER
's O
defense O
. O

In O
the O
early O
measurement O
success O
of O
Rotarians B-ORG
on O
the O
Dro B-ORG
. O

In O
Taio B-LOC
, O
the O
homeowners O
of O
the O
Predaia B-ORG
have O
been O
retrieved O
from O
the O
Campo B-PER
network O
. O

Two O
to O
two O
is O
the O
final O
result O
. O

Franco B-PER
Pistolato I-PER
, O
coach O
of O
the O
Alta B-ORG
Vallagarina I-ORG
, O
is O
pleased O
with O
the O
great O
success O
he O
's O
had O
against O
the O
Condinese B-ORG
. O

" O
I O
'm O
happy O
about O
the O
result O
. O

Sunday O
's O
game O
confirmed O
that O
we O
still O
have O
a O
lot O
of O
work O
to O
do O
. O
" O

What O
kind O
of O
insight O
did O
Sunday O
's O
game O
give O
her O
? O

Where O
does O
his O
team O
have O
to O
grow O
the O
most O
? O

" O
We O
certainly O
have O
some O
problems O
that O
we O
should O
try O
to O
solve O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
. O

Especially O
in O
the O
offensive O
phase O
, O
we O
have O
to O
grow O
a O
lot O
. O
" O

Who O
fears O
the O
ultimate O
success O
more O
? O

" O
The O
Condinese B-ORG
really O
impressed O
me O
, O
and O
I O
'm O
sure O
she O
's O
going O
to O
play O
a O
leading O
role O
. O

We O
're O
looking O
for O
a O
good O
balance O
and O
a O
good O
championship O
. O
" O

Respected O
forecasts O
, O
or O
is O
there O
some O
outcome O
that O
you O
did O
n't O
expect O
on O
this O
first O
day O
? O

" O
There O
were O
no O
big O
surprises O
on O
the O
big O
lines O
. O

I O
did O
n't O
expect O
the O
Bears B-ORG
to O
score O
four O
goals O
at O
home O
, O
but O
apparently O
they O
paid O
for O
a O
few O
missing O
ones O
. O
" O

For O
the O
provincial O
commission B-ORG
. O

Voting O
- O
driven O
cooperatives O

Co O
- O
operatives O
registered O
in O
the O
provincial O
registry O
are O
called O
upon O
to O
elect O
representatives O
-- O
two O
actual O
members O
and O
one O
alternate O
-- O
to O
the O
Regional B-ORG
Cooperation I-ORG
Commission I-ORG
and O
the O
Co O
- O
operative B-ORG
Commission I-ORG
of O
the O
Province B-LOC
of I-LOC
Trento I-LOC
. O

The O
elections O
are O
scheduled O
for O
September O
8th O
to O
September O
27th O
. O

The O
next O
day O
, O
at O
10 O
o'clock O
, O
the O
public O
is O
going O
to O
start O
handing O
over O
the O
cards O
at O
the O
headquarters O
of O
the O
Cooperation O
Service O
, O
136 B-LOC
Brenner I-LOC
Street I-LOC
. O

Each O
co O
- O
op O
can O
vote O
for O
an O
actual O
member O
and O
an O
alternate O
. O

The O
industry O
has O
been O
suffering O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

Al O
Saie O
: O
13 O
exhibitors O

Forty O
percent O
decline O
in O
acquisitions O
. O

TRENTO B-LOC
-- O
The O
timber O
industry O
in O
Trento B-LOC
counts O
1,400 O
businesses O
for O
a O
total O
of O
about O
5,000 O
employees O
. O

Despite O
its O
widespread O
use O
in O
the O
past O
, O
wood O
has O
been O
in O
crisis O
for O
many O
years O
. O

The O
raw O
material O
is O
competing O
with O
other O
materials O
that O
are O
deemed O
more O
convenient O
. O

Quality O
timber O
, O
like O
the O
certified O
timber O
, O
has O
difficulty O
locating O
because O
of O
higher O
prices O
. O

In O
the O
chamber B-ORG
of I-ORG
commerce I-ORG
headquarters O
, O
we O
also O
saw O
a O
decline O
in O
the O
number O
of O
companies O
offering O
sales O
-- O
98 O
, O
- O
seven O
percent O
-- O
and O
a O
more O
sensitive O
acquisition O
-- O
39 O
percent O
. O

2003 O
was O
an O
extraordinary O
year O
, O
however O
, O
because O
it O
was O
the O
highest O
volume O
of O
timber O
ever O
auctioned O
. O

90 O
thousand O
square O
meters O
. O

The O
average O
value O
of O
the O
metro O
cube O
was O
just O
over O
69 O
euros O
. O

The O
total O
sales O
turnover O
went O
up O
to O
over O
four O
million O
dollars O
. O

In O
the O
meantime O
, O
there O
will O
be O
13 O
exhibitors O
in O
the O
30 O
's O
-- O
nine O
last O
year O
-- O
out O
of O
the O
1,800 O
present O
at O
the O
2004 O
edition O
of O
the O
Saie O
, O
the O
Salone O
dell'Industrialization O
Edilizia O
( O
October O
13 O
- O
17 O
) O
in O
Bologna B-LOC
, O
which O
attracts O
170,000 O
visitors O
. O

In O
addition O
to O
industrial O
companies O
and O
craftsmen O
and O
the O
Magnifica B-ORG
Community I-ORG
, O
in O
Bologna B-LOC
there O
will O
also O
be O
Mr. B-LOC
Michele I-LOC
, O
the O
University B-ORG
and O
the O
Forests B-ORG
and I-ORG
Wildlife I-ORG
Service I-ORG
. O

The O
cost O
of O
the O
operation O
exceeds O
150,000 O
euros O
, O
without O
taking O
into O
account O
the O
contributions O
of O
the O
companies O
. O

M.E. B-PER

CRAC O
SICA B-ORG

He O
's O
a O
prescription O
guy O
. O

Paolo B-PER
Posti I-PER
is O
also O
bringing O
in O
all O
the O
buyers O
of O
the O
Sica B-ORG
srl I-ORG
. O
property O
. O

Public O
Prosecutor O
Alessandra B-PER
Liverani I-PER
is O
pre O
- O
trial O
investigating O
Gianluca B-PER
Dissegna I-PER
who O
bought O
an O
Audi O
A4 O
Avant O
from O
Seca B-ORG
in O
silver O
. O

The O
car O
was O
n't O
owned O
by O
Sica B-ORG
, O
but O
it O
was O
leased O
. O

According O
to O
the O
indictment O
, O
Dissegna B-PER
would O
have O
even O
forged O
his O
car O
's O
missing O
documents O
. O

The O
car O
was O
seized O
yesterday O
morning O
by O
the O
Financial B-ORG
Intelligence I-ORG
Unit I-ORG
. O

Sicily B-ORG
failed O
due O
to O
a O
severe O
financial O
crisis O
that O
caused O
its O
breakdown O
. O

Ten O
families O
were O
spending O
money O
on O
it O
, O
and O
they O
were O
facing O
tremendous O
expenses O
to O
buy O
an O
apartment O
. O

These O
include O
a O
$ O
200,000 O
mechanical O
trailer O
and O
a O
convertible O
Porsche O
Carrera O
. O

Iraq B-LOC

A O
car O
bomb O
in O
Falluja B-LOC
killed O
seven O
American O
soldiers O
. O

Tests O
show O
that O
the O
man O
arrested O
is O
not O
Saddam B-PER
's O
vice O
. O

The O
kidnappers O
: O

" O
Give O
us O
five O
million O
dollars O
. O
" O

To O
free O
the O
two O
journalists O

Raffarin B-PER
: O

" O
It O
does O
n't O
convince O
us O
. O
" O

Within O
48 O
hours O
, O
the O
two O
French O
journalists O
held O
hostage O
since O
August O
20th O
in O
Iraq B-LOC
, O
Christian B-PER
Chesnot I-PER
and O
Georges B-PER
Malbrunot I-PER
, O
will O
be O
free O
if O
: O

a O
) O
they O
'll O
get O
paid O
five O
million O
dollars O
, O
b O
) O
they O
'll O
be O
accepted O
to O
make O
a O
deal O
with O
" O
Sheikh O
Osama B-PER
Bin I-PER
Laden I-PER
, O
" O
and O
c O
) O
they O
'll O
refrain O
from O
trade O
and O
military O
ties O
with O
Iraq B-LOC
. O

It O
's O
the O
last O
message O
posted O
on O
the O
Internet O
by O
a O
group O
of O
alleged O
hijackers O
of O
journalists O
, O
the O
Islamic B-ORG
Army I-ORG
in I-ORG
Iraq I-ORG
. O

the O
liberation O
of O
the O
two O
obstacles O
, O
which O
seemed O
to O
be O
done O
. O

Although O
, O
from O
Pristina B-LOC
, O
Minister O
of O
Foreign O
Affairs O
Michel B-PER
Barnier I-PER
said O
that O
he O
believed O
there O
was O
" O
a O
possibility O
of O
positive O
evolution O
" O
of O
the O
situation O
. O

For O
France B-LOC
, O
of O
course O
, O
it O
would O
be O
a O
big O
disaster O
if O
the O
communication O
was O
authentic O
. O

President O
Jacques B-PER
Chirac I-PER
, O
thanks O
to O
the O
extraordinary O
solidarity O
of O
the O
Arab O
world O
, O
has O
stopped O
the O
insidious O
harassment O
of O
kidnappers O
by O
the O
anti O
- O
Muslim O
law O
in O
schools O
. O

The O
French O
diplomats O
involved O
in O
the O
forcing O
of O
the O
release O
of O
the O
two O
reporters O
point O
out O
that O
the O
text O
is O
not O
in O
the O
spirit O
of O
the O
group O
, O
and O
that O
any O
new O
requests O
would O
have O
been O
sent O
through O
channels O
other O
than O
a O
content O
- O
rich O
, O
dubious O
website O
. O

And O
then O
the O
money O
goes O
to O
the O
French O
, O
because O
they O
're O
not O
going O
to O
attack O
the O
obstacles O
" O
as O
you O
did O
in O
Latifiya B-LOC
, O
the O
day O
we O
wanted O
you O
to O
be O
delivered O
. O
" O

Witnesses O
reported O
that O
in O
the O
attack O
on O
the O
U.S. O
forces O
-- O
which O
happened O
in O
the O
village O
of O
Saqlawiya B-LOC
, O
in O
the O
northern O
suburb O
of O
Falluja B-LOC
-- O
at O
least O
seven O
Marines O
were O
killed O
on O
board O
a O
convoy O
vehicle O
. O

According O
to O
the O
same O
sources O
, O
the O
blast O
also O
killed O
three O
Iraqi B-ORG
National I-ORG
Guard I-ORG
men O
and O
injured O
seven O
U.S. B-LOC
soldiers O
. O

in O
Breve O
. O

Still O
working O
on O
the O
Valsugana O

In O
order O
to O
allow O
extraordinary O
maintenance O
work O
of O
milling O
and O
painting O
, O
along O
the O
state O
highway O
47 O
of O
Valsugana O
in O
the O
Marter B-LOC
- O
Trentino B-LOC
line O
, O
and O
specifically O
in O
the O
sections O
between O
the O
100.5 O
and O
106 O
and O
the O
118.3 O
and O
126.8 O
kilometers O
, O
there O
is O
a O
two O
- O
lane O
traffic O
constraint O
and O
a O
two O
- O
lane O
traffic O
constraint O
in O
the O
remaining O
sections O
. O

The O
work O
has O
to O
be O
done O
by O
October O
14th O
. O

Lotto O
: O
40,000 O
euros O
in O
prizes O

Last O
Wednesday O
in O
Triennial B-LOC
, O
there O
were O
5,363 O
lottery O
wins O
for O
a O
total O
of O
404,991,23 O
euros O
. O

The O
meeting O
. O

Serena O
Day O
party O
with O
police B-ORG
demonstrations O

Last O
Monday O
, O
the O
kids O
at O
the O
New O
Home O
Serena O
, O
Anffas B-ORG
Trentino I-ORG
onlus I-ORG
residential O
center O
, O
had O
the O
pleasure O
of O
watching O
a O
beautiful O
demonstration O
by O
the O
State B-ORG
Police I-ORG
, O
which O
with O
a O
bunch O
of O
chimps O
, O
motorcycles O
, O
cars O
and O
dogs O
animated O
and O
moved O
the O
late O
summer O
morning O
. O

Every O
single O
one O
of O
the O
kids O
in O
the O
audience O
-- O
and O
there O
were O
several O
of O
them O
who O
came O
for O
the O
occasion O
from O
the O
trainee O
's O
daycare O
centers O
in O
the O
Anffas B-ORG
-- O
was O
particularly O
enthusiastic O
, O
and O
they O
responded O
with O
a O
lot O
of O
emotion O
. O

It O
touched O
on O
the O
profound O
sensitivity O
shown O
to O
the O
kids O
who O
, O
as O
they O
got O
on O
their O
bikes O
, O
turned O
on O
their O
fans O
or O
talked O
on O
the O
radio O
from O
their O
cars O
, O
heard O
important O
actors O
, O
valued O
and O
warmly O
welcomed O
by O
the O
police B-ORG
officers O
of O
the O
state O
. O

This O
whole O
movement O
has O
generated O
a O
lot O
of O
interest O
and O
curiosity O
in O
the O
neighbourhood O
of O
Casa O
Serena O
. O

were O
different O
people O
looking O
out O
the O
windows O
that O
could O
see O
this O
extraordinary O
moment O
of O
celebration O
. O

A O
very O
warm O
thank O
you O
to O
all O
the O
police O
officers O
here O
from O
the O
State B-ORG
Police I-ORG
. O

to O
the O
Chimney B-ORG
Training I-ORG
Center I-ORG
in O
Moena B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
trainee B-ORG
police O
in O
Trento B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
interrogation B-ORG
staff O
, O
to O
the O
district O
police O
, O
to O
the O
Art B-ORG
Department I-ORG
, O
to O
Dr. O
Morelli B-PER
, O
to O
Dr. O
Spirali B-PER
, O
to O
the O
trainee O
officer O
in O
Trento B-LOC
for O
their O
willingness O
and O
participation O
. O

The O
crab O
. O

The O
building O
entrepreneur O
feels O
betrayed O
by O
the O
Parma B-LOC
merchant O
who O
's O
supposed O
to O
save O
his O
company O
. O

People B-PER
report O
cheating O
, O
Signifredi B-PER

The O
buyer O
of O
the O
company O
did O
n't O
even O
pay O
the O
1,000 O
euros O
in O
rent O
. O

The O
company O
was O
declared O
bankrupt O
after O
the O
merchant O
was O
arrested O
. O

People B-PER
feel O
cheated O
by O
Paolo B-PER
Signifredi I-PER
. O

Mr. O
Chini B-ORG
was O
arrested O
by O
the O
Financial O
Services O
Department O
a O
few O
days O
after O
he O
bought O
the O
car O
because O
he O
had O
to O
pay O
a O
three O
- O
year O
fine O
for O
the O
prescription O
and O
the O
recycling O
of O
a O
used O
car O
tire O
. O

The O
arrest O
of O
Signifredi B-PER
precipitated O
things O
, O
and O
within O
days O
the O
court B-ORG
of I-ORG
Trento I-ORG
declared O
the O
Chinese B-ORG
a O
failure O
. O

A O
month O
later O
, O
the O
Prosecutor B-ORG
's I-ORG
Office I-ORG
called O
for O
the O
arrests O
of O
Chini B-PER
and O
his O
son O
Gianluca B-PER
, O
charged O
with O
fraudulent O
bankruptcy O
. O

The O
merchant O
was O
supposed O
to O
be O
the O
white O
horseman O
called O
to O
save O
the O
Chinese B-ORG
, O
and O
instead O
, O
he O
was O
the O
one O
who O
buried O
it O
. O

But O
the O
allegation O
of O
cheating O
is O
probably O
related O
to O
a O
series O
of O
deals O
that O
the O
two O
entrepreneurs O
made O
. O

It O
was O
about O
business O
that O
would O
definitely O
make O
the O
Chinese B-ORG
happy O
. O

Things O
that O
could O
n't O
be O
done O
because O
of O
failure O
. O

Now O
it O
's O
the O
curator O
who O
's O
trying O
to O
pull O
the O
plug O
. O

Of O
course O
, O
the O
revenues O
could O
be O
much O
lower O
than O
they O
would O
be O
under O
normal O
management O
. O

The O
merchant O
's O
arrest O
, O
though O
, O
blew O
everything O
up O
. O

That O
's O
why O
China B-PER
got O
sued O
, O
and O
they O
decided O
to O
file O
a O
lawsuit O
. O

The O
entrepreneur O
feels O
victimized O
because O
in O
his O
optics O
, O
he O
had O
every O
means O
at O
his O
disposal O
to O
save O
the O
company O
. O

This O
would O
, O
of O
course O
, O
also O
have O
saved O
the O
position O
of O
the O
same O
Chinese B-PER
who O
later O
ended O
up O
in O
house O
arrests O
and O
are O
now O
still O
being O
tried O
along O
with O
his O
son O
on O
charges O
of O
bankruptcy O
fraud O
. O

People B-PER
are O
even O
at O
risk O
of O
losing O
their O
home O
, O
because O
it O
's O
meant O
for O
their O
former O
company O
and O
now O
it O
could O
be O
auctioned O
off O
by O
the O
curator O
. O

The O
appeals O
court B-ORG
overturned O
the O
orders O
against O
the O
Spaniards B-PER
and O
the O
Trentines B-PER
. O

Dussevic B-PER
shocks O
, O
two O
inmates O

Gianfranco B-PER
Spagnolo I-PER
and O
Fulvio B-PER
Trentini I-PER
were O
acquitted O
by O
the O
court B-ORG
of I-ORG
appeal O
of O
the O
crash O
at O
Dusevich B-PER
's O
house O
. O

Both O
of O
them O
are O
accused O
by O
the O
RCMP B-ORG
of O
having O
participated O
in O
the O
shooting O
alongside O
Walter B-PER
Zanetti I-PER
and O
Paul B-PER
John I-PER
Pallaoro I-PER
. O

According O
to O
the O
prosecutor B-ORG
's O
office O
, O
the O
two O
men O
were O
only O
planning O
the O
attack O
, O
which O
was O
then O
carried O
out O
by O
the O
two O
accomplices O
, O
who O
were O
identified O
by O
two O
people O
. O

The O
organizational O
work O
would O
have O
been O
done O
based O
on O
the O
knowledge O
of O
the O
places O
by O
the O
' O
30s B-PER
who O
had O
done O
retrofits O
. O

The O
witnesses O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
maintained O
that O
the O
two O
kidnappers O
were O
moving O
around O
their O
home O
with O
perfect O
knowledge O
of O
the O
location O
, O
as O
long O
as O
they O
knew O
where O
the O
gate O
was O
. O

According O
to O
the O
investigators O
, O
Trentini B-PER
would O
have O
provided O
Spain B-PER
with O
the O
information O
it O
needed O
to O
carry O
out O
the O
attack O
, O
but O
according O
to O
the O
judges O
at O
the O
district O
court B-ORG
, O
there O
is O
no O
evidence O
of O
this O
. O

And O
the O
judges O
also O
noted O
that O
Trentini B-PER
was O
incarcerated O
from O
1999 O
to O
2003 O
. O

So O
he O
ca O
n't O
have O
been O
involved O
in O
the O
reconstruction O
of O
the O
house O
in O
Dusevic B-PER
recently O
. O

He O
himself O
told O
the O
gip O
that O
he O
had O
done O
those O
jobs O
in O
1992 O
. O

Over O
time O
, O
the O
judges O
doubted O
that O
Thirty B-PER
could O
be O
the O
source O
of O
such O
detailed O
information O
as O
to O
allow O
the O
kidnappers O
to O
move O
perfectly O
comfortably O
around O
the O
Dusevich B-PER
home O
. O

Today O
's O
Cinema O

Poor O
education O
. O

Pedro B-PER
Almodovar I-PER
's O
new O
film O
, O
which O
won O
the O
Cannes O
Film O
Festival O
and O
became O
a O
hit O
worldwide O
, O
is O
now O
in O
Italy B-LOC
with O
six O
months O
to O
go O
. O

" O
Bad O
Education O
" O
is O
the O
story O
of O
a O
filmmaker O
who O
depicts O
paedophile O
behavior O
and O
sexual O
violence O
suffered O
by O
a O
priest O
in O
a O
college O
where O
he O
grew O
up O
as O
a O
child O
. O

In O
the O
picture O
, O
a O
scene O
from O
the O
movie O
. O

The O
life O
I O
'd O
like O
to O
live O

of O
Giuseppe B-PER
Piccioni I-PER
, O
with O
Luigi B-PER
Lo I-PER
Cascio I-PER
and O
Sandra B-PER
Ceccarelli I-PER
living O
a O
love O
story O
inside O
the O
set O
of O
a O
costumed O
film O
and O
in O
real O
life O
. O

A O
film O
about O
making O
films O
, O
quoting O
Truffaut B-PER
. O

The O
found O
love O

Garfield O
: O

the O
film O
. O

Electronic O
animation O
film O
, O
starring O
the O
irredeemable O
cat O
Garfield O
from O
the O
American O
comic O
book O
. O

The O
story O
: O

the O
owner O
of O
Garfield O
brings O
home O
an O
adorable O
dog O
named O
Odie O
. O

In O
the O
beginning O
, O
Garfield O
does O
n't O
share O
the O
entrance O
of O
a O
new O
inquiry O
into O
the O
house O
, O
but O
when O
little O
Odie O
is O
kidnapped O
, O
he O
does O
everything O
he O
can O
to O
find O
him O
. O

For O
children O
. O

Spiderman O
2 O

He O
wonders O
about O
his O
mission O
. O

But O
there O
's O
no O
shortage O
of O
special O
effects O
. O

Category B-ORG
one I-ORG
. O

THE O
PERSONNEL O
/ O
" O
" O
Society O
is O
heading O
for O
the O
category O
leap O
: O

He O
's O
invested O
a O
lot O
, O
and O
we O
're O
not O
missing O
anything O
. O
" O

Certainly B-PER
, O
the O
big O
challenge O
: O

" O
We O
want O
promotion B-ORG
. O
" O

The O
ambitious O
Torbole B-ORG
relies O
on O
a O
luxury O
armchair O

For O
Massimiliano B-PER
Ceraso I-PER
, O
a O
race O
bomber O
with O
a O
background O
in O
all O
respects O
between O
the O
Benacense B-ORG
, O
Arco B-ORG
, O
Rovereto B-ORG
and O
Borgo B-ORG
rows O
, O
a O
new O
career O
began O
. O

The O
coach O
, O
with O
a O
very O
specific O
task O
. O

bring O
the O
Torbole B-ORG
to O
the O
forefront O
. O

" O
It O
's O
a O
stimulating O
adventure O
, O
and O
we O
're O
aware O
that O
society O
's O
headed O
for O
a O
category O
leap O
. O

He O
's O
invested O
a O
lot O
, O
and O
we O
're O
not O
missing O
anything O
. O
" O

How O
does O
he O
feel O
about O
his O
first O
experience O
on O
a O
bench O
after O
a O
life O
on O
the O
field O
? O

" O
Walking O
from O
the O
camp O
to O
the O
bench O
in O
a O
couple O
of O
months O
requires O
a O
remarkable O
change O
of O
mindset O
. O

Fortunately O
, O
things O
in O
the O
pre O
- O
championship O
are O
lined O
up O
in O
a O
better O
way O
, O
and O
that O
's O
made O
my O
job O
easier O
. O
" O

What O
are O
the O
teams O
that O
are O
most O
afraid O
of O
? O

" O
The O
Bono B-ORG
Bears I-ORG
are O
definitely O
a O
great O
team O
, O
running O
a O
lot O
and O
with O
technically O
good O
players O
. O

Calavino B-ORG
and O
Isera B-ORG
have O
every O
potential O
to O
do O
well O
, O
and O
then O
there O
's O
Pinzolo B-ORG
Campiglio I-ORG
, O
which O
is O
a O
little O
bit O
of O
a O
wandering O
mine O
. O
" O

What O
are O
the O
problems O
that O
he O
's O
facing O
in O
his O
mystery O
suit O
? O

" O
The O
problems O
will O
start O
to O
come O
when O
the O
results O
do O
n't O
come O
. O
" O

There O
have O
been O
no O
accidents O
so O
far O
. O

However O
, O
it O
's O
in O
times O
of O
hardship O
that O
you O
see O
the O
qualities O
of O
a O
team O
and O
as O
a O
result O
of O
the O
coach O
. O

For O
my O
part O
, O
I O
'm O
fortunate O
enough O
to O
have O
great O
collaborators O
and O
a O
society O
that O
's O
present O
and O
organized O
in O
every O
way O
. O
" O

61st O
National O
Film O
Festival O
of O
Venice O

Religion O
at O
the O
Show O

A O
new O
film O
from O
the O
archives O
of O
the O
Luce B-ORG
Institute I-ORG
and O
the O
Biennale B-ORG
" O
to O
document O
the O
folly O
of O
the O
wars O
of O
religions O
and O
to O
show O
the O
way O
forward O
, O
which O
is O
the O
coexistence O
of O
different O
religions O
. O
" O

" O
The O
ideal O
, O
" O
Urbani B-PER
added O
, O
" O
is O
maybe O
to O
create O
a O
section O
of O
the O
exhibition O
that O
's O
really O
focused O
on O
this O
topic O
, O
but O
in O
the O
meantime O
, O
this O
big O
documentary O
will O
be O
a O
way O
to O
start O
. O
" O

How O
stress O
can O
make O
you O
miserable B-PER
? O

Artistic O
talent O
, O
he O
sparked O
the O
imagination O
of O
a O
young O
man O
. O

Now O
Violante B-PER
Placido I-PER
takes O
on O
the O
directing O
role O
of O
father O
Michele B-PER
, O
a O
female O
cop O
- O
rated O
character O
with O
Barbora B-PER
Bobulova I-PER
from O
" O
Wherever O
You O
Are O
. O
" O

" O
It O
was O
hard O
, O
I O
suffered O
, O
but O
today O
I O
'm O
satisfied O
, O
" O
he O
says O
. O

Nicole B-PER
's O
scandal O

There O
comes O
" O
Birth O
, O
" O
the O
upcoming O
film O
by O
Jonathan B-PER
Glazer I-PER
with O
superstar O
Nicole B-PER
Kidman I-PER
in O
the O
guise O
of O
embarrassment O
, O
but O
the O
guilt O
scene O
, O
the O
one O
where O
she O
sees O
an O
Oscar O
- O
winning O
actress O
naked O
in O
a O
bathtub O
with O
a O
10 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
, O
in O
the O
end O
, O
nonetheless O
, O
is O
n't O
really O
embarrassing O
. O

The O
little O
one O
comes O
into O
the O
room O
with O
the O
Kidman B-PER
already O
in O
the O
water O
, O
stops O
three O
feet O
away O
from O
the O
tank O
, O
pulls O
over O
, O
and O
then O
everything O
is O
cooled O
down O
. O

Alive O
the O
shark O

For O
ordinary O
mortals O
, O
they O
'll O
have O
to O
wait O
for O
the O
February O
release O
. O

No O
Clooney B-PER
. O
No O
party O
. O

George B-PER
Clooney I-PER
's O
Forfait O
at O
the O
Show O
. O

Briatore B-PER
's O
favorite O
movies O

Flavio B-PER
Briatore I-PER
, O
the O
Formula B-ORG
One I-ORG
manager O
best O
known O
for O
his O
collection O
of O
women O
's O
racing O
titles O
and O
for O
winning O
big O
prizes O
, O
talks O
about O
cinema O
like O
this O
: O

" O
I O
love O
the O
movies O
I O
understand O
, O
the O
ones O
that O
make O
me O
laugh O
, O
or O
the O
adventure O
movies O
, O
or O
the O
documentaries O
. O

I O
do O
n't O
like O
dramas O
where O
the O
children O
are O
sick O
or O
the O
wives O
are O
disabled O
. O
" O

SCI O
NORDICO O
/ O
La O
Marcialonga O
, O
even O
though O
it O
's O
four O
months O
away O
, O
already O
has O
1,500 O
registered O
. O

Giorgio B-PER
Di I-PER
Centa I-PER
: O
A O
motherly O
joke O
to O
win O

Is O
it O
time O
to O
wash O
the O
skis O
, O
prepare O
the O
ice O
cream O
and O
? O

sign O
up O
for O
Marcialonga O
. O

They O
already O
did O
it O
in O
1,500 O
when O
they O
were O
just O
under O
four O
months O
old O
on O
January O
30 O
, O
2005 O
. O

Last O
year O
, O
for O
the O
first O
time O
in O
a O
World O
Cup O
race O
, O
the O
Marcialonga O
team O
reached O
the O
finish O
line O
with O
3,733 O
entries O
, O
but O
a O
total O
of O
4,378 O
registered O
. O

The O
32nd O
edition O
will O
be O
taught O
by O
Gabriella B-PER
Paruzzi I-PER
, O
the O
2004 O
World O
Cup O
winner O
, O
who O
, O
thanks O
to O
her O
victory O
in O
Marche O
last O
year O
, O
has O
had O
the O
incentive O
to O
focus O
on O
the O
big O
finish O
in O
the O
cup O
. O

The O
Jamaican O
champion O
became O
, O
and O
could O
n't O
have O
been O
otherwise O
, O
the O
testimony O
and O
ambassador O
of O
the O
skiing O
great O
who O
made O
the O
history O
of O
Italian O
fondism O
. O

And O
so O
the O
Fiemme O
and O
Fassa O
Valley O
Marathon O
is O
taking O
place O
for O
the O
third O
time O
in O
a O
row O
in O
the O
classical O
style O
and O
, O
after O
last O
year O
's O
review O
, O
it O
's O
back O
on O
track O
for O
the O
FIS O
Marathon O
Cup O
. O

The O
route O
will O
be O
the O
traditional O
one O
, O
with O
the O
traditional O
Cascata O
final O
climb O
to O
decide O
the O
fate O
of O
the O
class O
. O

" O
Together O
with O
coach O
Chenetti B-PER
, O
I O
put O
the O
Marcialonga O
on O
the O
calendar O
. O

I O
want O
to O
win O
this O
year O
, O
it O
's O
a O
very O
important O
contest O
for O
me O
, O
" O
said O
the O
Frisian O
. O

Society O
and O
culture O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

It O
shows O
People B-ORG
's I-ORG
University I-ORG
. O

Sixty O
years O
ago O
, O
the O
People B-ORG
's I-ORG
University I-ORG
of O
Trenton O
was O
born O
in O
Trento O
. O

These O
days O
, O
at O
the O
Palazzo O
della O
Regione O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Dante I-LOC
, O
the O
" O
Picture O
Show O
" O
of O
Professor O
Perilli B-PER
's O
students O
of O
yesterday O
and O
today O
is O
open O
. O

Closes O
tomorrow O
, O
Saturday O
, O
October O
9th O
, O
at O
12 O
o'clock O
. O

Riva B-LOC
del I-LOC
Garda I-LOC
: O
I O
'm O
going O
to O
tell O
you O
a O
little O
bit O
about O
it O
. O

three O
- O
year O
- O
old O
. O

" O
The O
5th O
Gold O
Age O
, O
" O
a O
third O
- O
year O
international O
forum O
. O

until O
Monday O
, O
October O
11th O
at O
the O
Palacongressi O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

flavors O
, O
nine O
to O
20 O
hours O
. O

It O
's O
back O
to O
the O
traditional O
" O
Piazza O
dei O
Sapori O
, O
" O
which O
is O
a O
stand O
of O
typical O
regional O
products O
. O

From O
9 O
a.m. O
to O
6 O
p.m. O
on O
Sundays O
in O
Piazza B-LOC
Fiera I-LOC
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

ecumenism O
, O
9:30 O
a.m. O

It O
takes O
place O
at O
9:30 O
a.m. O
in O
the O
Trentino O
Cultural O
Institute O
, O
77th B-LOC
Street I-LOC
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

evolutionary O
age O
, O
9.30 O
a.m. O

Conversation O
from O
the O
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Educational I-ORG
Sciences I-ORG
on O
" O
The O
Forms O
of O
Inconvenience O
. O

Stress O
. O

causes O
and O
manifestations O
in O
evolutionary O
age O
. O
" O

In O
Via B-LOC
Matteo I-LOC
del I-LOC
Ben I-LOC
, O
Auditorium O
1 O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

mental O
health O
, O
14 O
hours O
. O

The O
Provincial B-ORG
Mental I-ORG
Health I-ORG
Service I-ORG
is O
proposing O
a O
three O
- O
day O
conference O
called O
" O
Recovered O
Words O
, O
" O
which O
is O
, O
" O
Cultures O
and O
Practices O
of O
Co O
- O
ordination O
in O
Mental O
Health O
Policies O
. O
" O

Comparison O
experiments O
. O
" O

Today O
's O
talks O
are O
by O
Giuseppe B-PER
Lumia I-PER
, O
who O
's O
the O
spokesman O
for O
a O
mental O
health O
bill O
, O
and O
contributions O
to O
more O
voices O
on O
" O
doing O
it O
together O
. O
" O

At O
the O
age O
of O
21 O
, O
expressive O
, O
theatrical O
and O
singing O
proposals O
from O
groups O
, O
associations O
, O
centers O
, O
cooperatives O
. O

Work O
continues O
at O
9 O
a.m. O
in O
the O
morning O
. O

At O
the O
Segantini B-LOC
10 I-LOC
Cooperation O
Room O
on O
the O
way O
out O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

The O
Interregional B-ORG
Delegation I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Three O
Venices O
of O
the O
Italian B-ORG
General I-ORG
Association I-ORG
of I-ORG
the O
Spectacular O
( O
Agis B-ORG
) O
is O
proposing O
the O
seminar O
" O
For O
a O
New O
Spectacular O
Policy O
. O
" O

It O
will O
be O
chaired O
by O
the O
president O
of O
the O
Center O
, O
S. B-ORG
Chiara I-ORG
, O
Carlo B-PER
Fait I-PER
. O

With O
Lorenzo B-PER
Dellai I-PER
and O
Alberto B-PER
Pacher I-PER
, O
he O
's O
going O
to O
introduce O
Margherita B-PER
Cogo I-PER
, O
the O
cultural O
commissioner O
. O

There O
will O
be O
interventions O
by O
co O
- O
sponsors O
, O
regional O
and O
municipal O
councillors O
, O
politicians O
, O
artists O
. O

For O
the O
Trentino B-LOC
, O
Micaela B-PER
Bertoldi I-PER
, O
the O
city O
councillor O
, O
Marco B-PER
Bernardi I-PER
, O
the O
director O
of O
the O
Teatro B-ORG
Stabile I-ORG
in I-ORG
Bolzano I-ORG
, O
Franz B-PER
Von I-PER
Walther I-PER
, O
the O
president O
of O
the O
Haydn B-ORG
Orchestra I-ORG
in O
Bolzano B-LOC
and O
Trento B-LOC
. O

The O
filmmaker O
Mario B-PER
Martone I-PER
will O
be O
part O
of O
the O
discussion O
. O

The O
convention O
will O
continue O
tomorrow O
, O
Saturday O
, O
October O
9th O
, O
from O
10 O
a.m. O
to O
1 O
p.m. O
in O
the O
medieval O
hall O
of O
the O
Social O
Theatre O
. O

Arco B-LOC
: O

Astra O
, O
15 O
o'clock O
. O

He O
's O
back O
for O
the O
25th O
meeting O
, O
" O
Astra O
, O
" O
an O
international O
astrology O
conference O
on O
the O
topic O
of O
" O
Opportunities O
for O
ancient O
mysteries O
. O
" O

Al O
Casinò O
. O

Arco B-LOC
: O

Quisisana O
, O
17 O
o'clock O
. O

" O
The O
changing O
city O
. O

Quisisana O
's O
cultural O
community O
center O
, O
" O
a O
design O
competition O
presentation O
. O

In O
the O
Panni O
Palace O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

Storytelling O
, O
17 O
hours O
. O

Paolo B-PER
Tognolatti I-PER
presents O
the O
volume O
of O
stories O
" O
Bagliori O
" O
by O
Giovanni B-PER
Duca I-PER
. O

Arca B-ORG
-- O
Thirty B-LOC
- O
four O
( O
2004 O
) O
. O

Voice O
of O
Giliola B-PER
Galvani I-PER
. O

Rosmini O
Center O
on O
Dordi B-LOC
8th I-LOC
Street I-LOC
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

Debiasi B-PER
's O
paintings O
, O
5.30 O
p.m. O

Giuseppe B-PER
Debiasi I-PER
presents O
his O
latest O
work O
, O
reproduced O
in O
the O
Osiride O
catalogue O
, O
at O
17 B-LOC
Dante I-LOC
Street I-LOC
Rovereto I-LOC
, O
at O
Private O
Consult O
-- O
Associated O
Studio O
. O

Meeting O
at O
5.30 O
p.m. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

Dead B-PER
, O
18 O
o'clock O
. O

Meet O
Senator O
Enrico B-PER
Morando I-PER
on O
" O
The O
Reformers O
' O
Proposals O
for O
the O
Federation O
and O
Reforms O
. O
" O

Hotel O
America O
, O
Route B-LOC
52 I-LOC
Green I-LOC
Tower I-LOC
. O

Villa B-LOC
Lagarina I-LOC
: O

party O
, O
19 O
to O
23 O
o'clock O
. O

For O
three O
days O
, O
in O
the O
squares O
, O
in O
the O
courtyards O
, O
in O
the O
alleys O
, O
performances O
, O
gastronomy O
, O
guided O
tours O
for O
the O
Borgonic O
Festival O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

Prayer O
, O
7.30 O
p.m. O

" O
Universal O
Life O
" O
proposes O
the O
meeting O
" O
Internal O
Prayer O
: O

a O
force O
to O
radiate O
positive O
energies O
to O
the O
Earth O
. O
" O

At O
the O
Hotel O
Everest O
in O
the O
Alps B-LOC
16 I-LOC
. O

Man B-LOC
: O
No O
. O

oratory O
party O
, O
20 O
o'clock O
. O

They O
start O
today O
, O
in O
Gardolo B-LOC
, O
the O
three O
days O
of O
the O
oratory O
festival O
. O

It O
starts O
at O
20 O
, O
with O
Mr. O
Rosario O
. O

At O
the O
end O
, O
at O
21 O
, O
a O
distribution O
of O
pasta O
, O
followed O
by O
music O
and O
dancing O
. O

Tomorrow O
afternoon O
, O
at O
15 O
o'clock O
, O
the O
non O
- O
competitive O
march O
" O
Up O
and O
I O
Go O
for O
Gardol O
. O
" O
The O
party O
will O
continue O
all O
afternoon O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

Parents O
, O
Soldiers O
, O
20:15 O
. O

Assembly O
of O
the O
Parents B-ORG
' I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
of O
the O
Elementary B-ORG
School I-ORG
of I-ORG
Soldiers I-ORG
on O
: O

We O
've O
got O
roundtables O
, O
we O
've O
got O
monthly O
commissions O
, O
we O
've O
got O
board B-ORG
elections O
. O

Magna O
Carta O
Elementary O
School O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

breakfast O
, O
8 O
: O
30 O
p.m. O

The O
Pranic B-ORG
Healing I-ORG
Association I-ORG
, O
43 B-LOC
Perini I-LOC
Street I-LOC
, O
presents O
to O
the O
public O
its O
practices O
-- O
meditation O
and O
breathing O
techniques O
. O

Information O
: O

328.7065165 O
- O
348.2399999 O
( O
Luisa B-PER
Piccolroaz I-PER
0464.434209 O
) O

Upstairs B-LOC
: O

Vela B-LOC
, O
8 O
: O
30 O
p.m. O

Opening O
of O
the O
exhibition O
" O
Along O
the O
Vela O
River O
, O
" O
photos O
from O
Cadine O
's O
" O
The B-ORG
Rule I-ORG
" O
group O
. O

Until O
Sunday O
, O
October O
17th O
every O
weekend O
: O

Saturdays O
at O
9 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
, O
Sundays O
at O
10 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
, O
10 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
, O
12 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
, O
15 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O

Next O
Friday O
, O
October O
15th O
, O
it O
's O
6 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
to O
2 O
: O
30 O
p.m. O

in O
the O
multi O
- O
purpose O
hall O
of O
the O
oratory O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

diabetes O
, O
20:30 O
. O

The O
Association O
for O
Disease O
Prevention O
and O
Control O
of B-ORG
Diabetes I-ORG
proposes O
the O
Disability O
in O
Diabetes O
conference O
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

critical O
consumption O
, O
8:30 O
p.m. O

" O
Forest O
medicine O
: O

India O
" O
-- O
The O
pharmaceutical O
market O
and O
the O
hands O
of O
the O
multinationals O
. O

In O
a O
second O
punch O
, O
Tiziana B-PER
Andretti I-PER
's O
going O
to O
illustrate O
the O
" O
teacher O
's O
lunch O
. O
" O

In O
the O
King O
's O
Room O
. O

SPETTACOLI O
. O

Advertise O
Melevision O
. O

The O
Melevision O
with O
" O
Cities O
Down O
" O
will O
arrive O
at O
the O
Trento B-LOC
Palace O
tomorrow O
, O
18 O
o'clock O
. O

Tickets O
for O
the O
show O
are O
available O
at O
the O
showtime O
circuit O
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
and O
the O
rural O
villages O
of O
Trento B-LOC
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

archaeologists O
, O
9:30 O
a.m. O

The O
International O
Exposition O
of O
Archaeological O
Cinema O
. O

Screenings O
of O
various O
documentaries O
from O
9:30 O
a.m. O
to O
12 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
, O
15 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
to O
19 O
: O
00 O
p.m. O
to O
23:15 O
p.m. O

At O
5.30 O
p.m. O
, O
there O
's O
a O
conference O
called O
" O
Imothep O
, O
the O
science O
of O
the O
search O
for O
immortality O
" O
with O
Gloria B-PER
Rosati I-PER
at O
Fausto O
Melotti O
Auditorium O
in O
March O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

De B-PER
Gasperi I-PER
, O
14:15 O
p.m. O

Curcu B-ORG
& I-ORG
Genovese I-ORG
, O
Alcide B-PER
De I-PER
Gasperi I-PER
's O
short O
biography O
. O

Every O
Friday O
from O
2.15 O
p.m. O
to O
2.30 O
p.m. O
for O
14 O
shows O
on O
Radio B-ORG
Rai I-ORG
2 I-ORG
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

mustMart O
, O
19 O
: O
24 O
p.m. O

Go O
back O
to O
the O
polo O
on O
the O
Bettini B-LOC
Corso I-LOC
in O
Rovereto B-LOC
" O
MartCafè O
. O
" O

Emotions O
under O
the O
dome O
. O
" O

From O
19 O
to O
24 O
, O
in O
the O
inner O
spaces O
of O
the O
cafeteria O
, O
the O
music O
of O
DJ O
Ornella B-PER
Frisinghelli I-PER
, O
who O
introduces O
the O
' O
70s O
and O
' O
80s O
. O

I O
'm O
smiling B-LOC
. O

Choir O
, O
8.30 O
p.m. O

Concerto O
by O
the O
Valsella B-ORG
Choir I-ORG
, O
directed O
by O
maestro O
Ferdy B-PER
Lorenzi I-PER
. O

The O
night O
is O
going O
to O
fund O
the O
abandoned O
children O
's O
school O
in O
Amera B-LOC
, O
India B-LOC
. O

The O
Palace O
Hotel O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

8:30 O
p.m. O

It O
's O
a O
replica O
of O
W.A. B-PER
Mozart I-PER
's O
" O
The O
Homeland O
King O
of O
Crete O
. O
" O

At O
the O
Social O
Theatre O
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

music O
, O
20:30 O
. O

Concert O
by O
the O
Zandonai B-ORG
Ensemble I-ORG
in O
the O
Philharmonic O
Hall O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

theater O
, O
2:30 O
p.m. O
and O
3:30 O
p.m. O

At O
the O
Soultrain O
pub O
in O
the O
pavilion O
. O

Fierce O
of O
Trento B-LOC
in O
Via B-LOC
Briamasco I-LOC
, O
Maura B-PER
Pettoruso I-PER
performs O
Stefano B-PER
Benni I-PER
's O
" O
The O
Blank O
Slate O
" O
for O
the O
queen O
of O
Mirko B-PER
Corradini I-PER
. O

Rovereto B-LOC
: O

Music O
: O
21.30 O
p.m. O

Jasmine B-ORG
Estrada I-ORG
Trio I-ORG
at O
Romi O
's O
Pub O
. O

DOMANI O
. O

Thirty B-LOC
: O

research O
, O
9 O
a.m. O

With O
Lorenzo B-PER
Dellai I-PER
, O
Mauro B-PER
Bondi I-PER
, O
Andrea B-PER
Ranieri I-PER
. O
