-The O
text O
of O
the O
judgment O
is O
not O
yet O
available O
in O
writing O
but O
the O
message O
was O
already O
published O
by O
a O
communications O
agency O
that O
Floralux B-ORG
hired O
. O

In O
' O
81 O
the O
then O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
regularized O
the O
situation O
with O
a O
BPA B-MISC
that O
the O
company O
had O
drawn O
up O
at O
its O
own O
expense O
. O

publication O

Today O
, O
Floralux B-ORG
has O
all O
the O
necessary O
permits O
, O
but O
the O
BPA B-MISC
with O
which O
they O
could O
be O
obtained O
was O
controversial O
because O
the O
company O
's O
managing O
director O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
had O
lost O
her O
aldermanic O
office O
in O
... O

In O
the O
first O
instance O
, O
Vandenbussche B-PER
was O
convicted O
of O
conflict O
of O
interest O
in O
the O
early O
90s O
but O
was O
later O
acquitted O
by O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
in O
Ghent B-LOC
. O

SP B-ORG
sits O
hard O
-- O
( O
Eric B-PER
, O
sd O
) O
Derycke B-PER
wants O
to O
approve O
BPA B-MISC
on O
condition O
that O
BPA B-MISC
' O
De B-MISC
Hoogte I-MISC
' O
limited O
acceptance O
( O
mayor O
of O
Moorslede B-LOC
Walter B-PER
Ghekiere I-PER
will O
make O
a O
proposal O
) O
. O

Insufficient O
to O
pronounce O
a O
severe O
punishment O
, O
it O
says O
. O

This O
court O
now O
attaches O
no O
penalty O
to O
the O
guilt O
that O
it O
finds O
. O

Which O
soon O
grows O
into O
a O
real O
garden O
center O
. O

page O

Far O
more O
things O
are O
sold O
than O
one O
would O
expect O
in O
a O
plant O
nursery O
. O

This O
is O
abundantly O
clear O
from O
a O
fax O
that O
her O
lawyer O
wrote O
to O
her O
at O
the O
time O
and O
which O
was O
seized O
during O
a O
search O
. O

The O
file O
goes O
back O
to O
the O
late O
1980s O
. O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

Spatial B-ORG
Planning I-ORG
would O
have O
abused O
to O
obtain O
the O
BPA B-MISC
. O

The O
only O
evidence O
left O
to O
condemn O
Vandenbussche B-PER
for O
' O
interest O
representation O
' O
was O
her O
presence O
at O
the O
bench O
of O
aldermen O
when O
the O
Floralux B-MISC
dossier I-MISC
was O
discussed O
. O

At O
the O
end O
of O
' O
98 O
the O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
made O
this O
regularization O
final O
with O
a O
regional O
plan O
amendment O
. O

Guilt O
but O
no O
fine O
. O

" O

He O
himself O
dismissed O
this O
as O
" O
nonsense O
and O
apekool O
of O
quatrains O
" O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Figs O
after O
Easter O
, O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
seems O
to O
have O
thought O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
/ O
Brussels B-LOC

Locally O
, O
it O
is O
suspected O
that O
Floralux B-ORG
financed O
the O
election O
campaigns O
of O
Luc B-PER
Martens I-PER
, O
who O
drew O
" O
attention O
" O
to O
the O
case O
within O
the O
previous O
government O
. O

The B-MISC
Life I-MISC

Vandenbussche B-PER
himself O
concluded O
that O
the O
court O
" O
wanted O
to O
condemn O
the O
political O
mores O
of O
the O
past O
" O
. O

" O

The O
Court B-ORG
of I-ORG
Cassation I-ORG
broke O
the O
judgment O
so O
that O
it O
had O
to O
be O
repeated O
by O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
of O
Antwerp B-LOC
. O

That O
is O
the O
essence O
of O
the O
ruling O
that O
the O
Antwerp B-MISC
Court O
of O
Appeal O
made O
on O
Wednesday O
in O
the O
case O
of O
the O
controversial O
garden O
center O
Floralux B-ORG
from O
Moorslede B-LOC
- I-LOC
Dadizele I-LOC
. O

Case O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
was O
found O
guilty O
of O
conflict O
of O
interest O
( O
' O
taking O
an O
interest O
' O
in O
legal O
language O
) O
but O
received O
no O
punishment O
because O
after O
all O
these O
years O
a O
punishment O
would O
no O
longer O
make O
sense O
. O

It O
is O
already O
the O
interpretation O
that O
is O
given O
to O
the O
judgment O
in O
the O
environment O
of O
Floralux B-ORG
( O
see O
page O
1 O
): O
that O
a O
' O
new O
political O
culture O
' O
has O
dawned O
and O
the O
old O
political O
morals O
were O
indeed O
reprehensible O
but O
now O
no O
longer O
need O
to O
be O
punished O
with O
, O
in O
this O
case O
, O
the O
closure O
of O
a O
business O
. O

What O
for O
years O
was O
a O
controversial O
' O
CVP B-MISC
- I-MISC
dossier I-MISC
' O
now O
gets O
the O
cachet O
of O
an O
old O
cow O
in O
the O
ditch O
because O
of O
the O
judicial O
decision O
. O

In O
order O
to O
survive O
, O
Floralux B-ORG
wants O
the O
agricultural O
land O
to O
be O
converted O
into O
an O
SME O
zone O
. O

Court B-ORG
condemned O
political O
morals O
of O
the O
time O

The O
lawyer O
writes O
that O
" O
( O
... O
) O
it O
is O
then O
clear O
that O
it O
( O
BPA B-MISC
, O
sd O
) O
was O
only O
for O
private O
purposes O
, O
namely O
for O
your O
company O
, O
and O
the O
College O
of O
Aldermen O
acts O
as O
a O
pacesetter O
for O
this O
" O
. O

Nevertheless O
, O
she O
insisted O
to O
the O
VRT B-MISC
radio I-MISC
that O
she O
" O
has O
done O
nothing O
wrong O
" O
. O

author O

It O
also O
appears O
that O
consultation O
took O
place O
with O
the O
Liberal O
Party O
( O
then O
PVV B-ORG
) O
and O
with O
the O
SP B-ORG
: O
" O
Waltniel B-PER
( O
PVV B-ORG
, O
sd O
) O
is O
in O
favour O
. O

And O
Delcroix B-PER
decided O
: O
" O
Will O
pass O
. O

publication O
date O

This O
context O
ensured O
that O
the O
file O
was O
always O
bathed O
in O
an O
atmosphere O
of O
party O
financing O
in O
exchange O
for O
regularization O
. O

General O

Dossier O
always O
associated O
with O
party O
financing O
in O
exchange O
for O
regularisation O

Floralux B-ORG
obtains O
a O
permit O
to O
set O
up O
a O
plant O
nursery O
. O

" O

Friday O
, O
June O
2 O
, O
2000 O

The O
Antwerp B-MISC
court O
rejected O
the O
document O
as O
evidence O
but O
did O
read O
it O
during O
the O
hearing O
. O

What O
these O
political O
morals O
were O
can O
be O
deduced O
from O
the O
Atoma B-MISC
notebooks I-MISC
that O
Leo B-PER
Delcroix I-PER
kept O
when O
he O
was O
still O
CVP B-MISC
secretary I-MISC
. O

section O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

Manager O
of O
Floralux B-ORG
maintains O
that O
she O
has O
done O
nothing O
wrong O

About O
Floralux B-ORG
it O
said O
: O
" O
They O
want O
regularisation O
. O

edition O

-DOCSTART- O
Verberckmoes B-PER
is O
a O
former O
Catholic O
dissident O
who O
joined O
the O
liberal O
ranks O
at O
the O
founding O
of O
the O
PVV B-ORG
as O
an O
enlargement O
candidate O
and O
almost O
immediately O
made O
it O
to O
the O
position O
of O
Member O
of O
Parliament O
. O

The O
liberal O
Minister O
of O
Justice B-ORG
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
is O
not O
a O
candidate O
on O
the O
local O
VLD B-MISC
list I-MISC
at O
the O
upcoming O
municipal O
elections O
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
. O

A O
council O
member O
of O
Inzet B-ORG
: O
" O
The O
intention O
was O
that O
we O
would O
form O
a O
cartel O
list O
as O
a O
group O
and O
then O
ask O
the O
voters O
for O
a O
new O
mandate O
. O

Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
admits O
that O
other O
motives O
may O
also O
have O
played O
a O
major O
role O
. O

Willy B-PER
Van I-PER
Damme I-PER

" O
He O
does O
not O
want O
to O
commit O
voter O
fraud O
and O
be O
a O
candidate O
to O
then O
not O
sit O
in O
the O
City O
Council O
. O

It O
is O
now O
definitive O
. O

friday O
, O
2 O
june O
2000 O

There O
is O
great O
dejection O
within O
the O
VLD B-ORG
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
. O

According O
to O
reports O
, O
the O
proposal O
had O
grown O
quite O
spontaneously O
within O
the O
majority O
led O
by O
Mayor O
Norbert B-PER
De I-PER
Batselier I-PER
( O
SP B-ORG
) O
. O

De B-ORG
Morgen I-ORG

According O
to O
the O
local O
VLD B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
, O
his O
decision O
is O
irrevocable O
. O

He O
is O
against O
the O
accumulation O
of O
mandates O
, O
" O
says O
De B-PER
Brandt I-PER
. O

So O
there O
was O
the O
proposal O
for O
a O
joint O
list O
with O
Inzet B-ORG
, O
with O
which O
the O
VLD B-ORG
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
forms O
the O
majority O
and O
which O
consists O
of O
SP'ers B-MISC
, O
VU'ers B-MISC
and O
some O
independents O
. O

Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
no O
candidate O
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC

For O
them O
, O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
is O
the O
future O
of O
the O
VLD B-ORG
and O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
the O
old O
political O
culture O
they O
despise O
. O

Willy B-PER
Van I-PER
Damme I-PER

Verwilghen B-PER
can O
not O
convince O
local O
VLD B-ORG
to O
form O
a O
cartel O
with O
De O
Batselier O
's O
Inzet B-MISC
- I-MISC
list I-MISC

author O

" O

" O
This O
is O
the O
PVV B-ORG
of O
the O
past O
or O
worse O
" O
, O
said O
a O
VLD B-MISC
member O
from O
Verwilghen B-PER
's O
neighborhood O
. O

For O
the O
VLD B-ORG
, O
which O
now O
has O
barely O
four O
seats O
in O
the O
city O
council O
, O
a O
debacle O
is O
looming O
. O

Verwilghen B-PER
himself O
gave O
this O
official O
reason O
in O
a O
press O
release O
yesterday O
evening O
. O

Dendermonde B-LOC

According O
to O
several O
sources O
, O
it O
also O
had O
the O
support O
of O
the O
top O
of O
the O
national O
VLD B-ORG
and O
within O
the O
Dendermonde B-MISC
VLD B-ORG
was O
mainly O
supported O
by O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
. O

Now O
the O
list O
will O
be O
drawn O
by O
Hilde B-PER
Dierickx I-PER
and O
Marcel B-PER
Borms I-PER
, O
alderman O
for O
finance O
. O

The B-MISC
Life I-MISC

page O

Some O
will O
now O
possibly O
drop O
out O
. O

General O

The O
latter O
did O
leave O
active O
politics O
a O
number O
of O
years O
ago O
, O
but O
remains O
an O
influential O
figure O
in O
the O
local O
Liberal O
Party O
, O
including O
through O
his O
son O
Kristian B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
, O
who O
is O
a O
municipal O
councillor O
. O

The O
majority O
within O
the O
local O
chapter O
, O
however O
, O
rejected O
the O
proposal O
. O

Some O
Liberals O
have O
already O
taken O
or O
are O
planning O
to O
take O
steps O
in O
the O
direction O
of O
Deployment B-ORG
. O

That O
( O
according O
to O
circles O
inside O
and O
outside O
the O
VLD B-ORG
) O
especially O
on O
the O
initiative O
of O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
, O
former B-MISC
VLD I-MISC
representative I-MISC
for O
Dendermonde B-LOC
. O

" O

publication O
date O

From O
our O
collaborator O

edition O

Robert B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
, O
father O
of O
Marc B-PER
, O
grabbed O
next O
to O
a O
seat O
. O

According O
to O
insiders O
, O
the O
old O
dispute O
between O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
and O
his O
predecessor O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
played O
a O
major O
role O
in O
this O
. O

Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
: O
" O
A O
number O
of O
people O
had O
indeed O
not O
yet O
put O
themselves O
forward O
as O
candidates O
for O
the O
municipal O
elections O
in O
anticipation O
of O
what O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
was O
going O
to O
do O
. O

section O

publication O

-DOCSTART- O
Parents O
who O
were O
lucky O
enough O
to O
have O
their O
child O
released O
, O
may O
go O
home O
under O
police O
escort O
. O

Thank O
God B-PER
. O

" O
Wednesday O
she O
was O
a O
little O
sick O
. O

Distraught O
parents O
wait O
helplessly O
for O
denouement O
of O
hostage O
drama O

The O
child O
is O
barely O
three O
. O

In O
the O
village O
of O
barely O
2,300 O
inhabitants O
, O
we O
know O
us O
. O

" O
Daddies O
do O
n't O
hurt O
kids O
, O
they O
say O
. O

Daddies O
do O
n't O
hurt O
kids O
, O
they O
say O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

Every O
year O
the O
village O
is O
flooded O
with O
all O
kinds O
of O
people O
, O
tourists O
especially O
, O
who O
come O
to O
walk O
and O
cycle O
in O
the O
beautiful O
surroundings O
. O

The O
parents O
also O
get O
the O
visit O
of O
the O
Portuguese B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
ambassador O
and O
a O
representative O
of O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
government O
. O

publication O

Colas B-PER
: O
" O
A O
child O
of O
that O
age O
does O
not O
yet O
really O
realize O
what O
is O
happening O
to O
him O
. O

" O
The O
little O
daughter O
of O
the O
neighbors O
is O
there O
. O

publication O
date O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

According O
to O
the O
police O
, O
the O
children O
are O
doing O
fine O
. O

But O
hostage O
takers O
they O
have O
never O
had O
. O

My O
daughter O
has O
kept O
her O
at O
home O
. O

General O

" O

Shortly O
after O
seven O
o'clock O
then O
suddenly O
came O
the O
redemption O
. O

section O

Occasional O
applause O
sounds O
at O
the O
cultural O
center O
. O

They O
slept O
well O
and O
were O
fed O
on O
time O
. O

Who O
does O
something O
like O
that O
? O

But O
no O
one O
knows O
what O
will O
happen O
. O

" O
The O
worst O
thing O
is O
when O
they O
come O
to O
say O
that O
children O
were O
released O
only O
to O
hear O
that O
your O
child O
is O
not O
one O
of O
them O
. O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

Then O
you O
just O
die O
. O

" O
We O
keep O
right O
on O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
man O
in O
question O
is O
a O
father O
himself O
. O

The O
whole O
neighborhood O
around O
the O
crèche O
is O
hermetically O
sealed O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

In O
the O
course O
of O
the O
afternoon O
, O
the O
atmosphere O
becomes O
more O
grim O
. O

Wasserbillig B-LOC
is O
in O
fact O
a O
melting O
pot O
where O
Portuguese B-MISC
, O
Italian B-MISC
, O
Polish B-MISC
, O
German B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
immigrants O
-- O
once O
came O
here O
to O
work O
in O
the O
steel O
and O
tire O
industry O
-- O
live O
peacefully O
side O
by O
side O
. O

The O
residents O
of O
Wasserbillig B-LOC
, O
a O
small O
idyllic O
Luxembourg B-MISC
village O
, O
stuck O
against O
the O
German B-MISC
border O
, O
reacted O
with O
shock O
. O

After O
a O
few O
shots O
the O
hostage O
situation O
was O
over O
. O

Occasionally O
they O
also O
get O
a O
circus O
or O
fair O
to O
visit O
, O
like O
the O
last O
few O
days O
. O

The O
municipal O
nursery O
in O
the O
Rue B-LOC
du I-LOC
Bocksberg I-LOC
is O
completely O
surrounded O
by O
special O
intervention O
forces O
of O
the O
Luxembourg B-MISC
, O
German B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
police O
. O

" O

edition O

" O
Many O
distraught O
tearful O
faces O
. O

Everyone O
prepares O
for O
a O
second O
frightened O
night O
. O

The O
elderly O
lady O
looks O
in O
despair O
at O
the O
little O
white O
building O
in O
the O
distance O
. O

" O

Some O
parents O
panic O
and O
fear O
the O
worst O
, O
others O
try O
to O
keep O
up O
the O
courage O
. O

Let O
's O
hope O
" O
they O
" O
are O
right O
. O

He O
describes O
the O
atmosphere O
in O
the O
cultural O
center O
as O
dramatic O
. O

These O
are O
defenseless O
toddlers O
. O

" O

page O

author O

" O

The O
industry O
left O
a O
decade O
ago O
, O
the O
immigrants O
stayed O
. O

The O
large O
bags O
under O
the O
eyes O
betray O
that O
he O
has O
had O
a O
sleepless O
night O
. O

For O
a O
moment O
the O
worst O
is O
feared O
, O
when O
word O
arrives O
that O
the O
hostage O
taker O
has O
brought O
food O
and O
drink O
for O
three O
days O
. O

" O
I O
was O
glued O
to O
my O
radio O
. O

Sad O
because O
a O
niece O
or O
friend O
of O
their O
child O
is O
there O
. O

" O

" O
My O
little O
granddaughter O
escaped O
death O
" O
, O
sighs O
the O
woman O
. O

The O
young O
man O
sighs O
deeply O
. O

From O
our O
reporter O
on O
the O
spot O

" O

Wasserbillig B-LOC

Outside O
are O
about O
fifty O
fellow O
villagers O
who O
wanted O
to O
support O
the O
stricken O
parents O
. O

The O
route B-LOC
du I-LOC
Luxembourg I-LOC
, O
the O
street O
in O
front O
of O
the O
town O
hall O
, O
had O
been O
transformed O
into O
a O
boulevard O
yesterday O
, O
along O
which O
hundreds O
of O
disaster O
tourists O
strolled O
, O
looking O
at O
jet O
engines O
( O
more O
than O
twenty O
) O
and O
pressmen O
( O
more O
than O
a O
hundred O
) O
instead O
of O
shop O
windows O
. O

The O
parents O
of O
the O
hostage O
little O
ones O
were O
received O
a O
hundred O
meters O
away O
in O
the O
cultural O
center O
. O

A O
haunting O
scene O
, O
on O
what O
could O
have O
been O
a O
beautiful O
summer O
vacation O
day O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

The O
hostage O
taker O
begins O
to O
get O
nervous O
because O
his O
demands O
are O
not O
being O
met O
quickly O
enough O
. O

Fortunately O
their O
child O
is O
not O
among O
the O
hostages O
. O

Through O
the O
psychologists O
the O
parents O
are O
kept O
informed O
. O

Ramotti B-PER
is O
one O
of O
the O
few O
parents O
who O
still O
wants O
to O
say O
something O
. O

The O
fatigue O
is O
also O
beginning O
to O
take O
its O
toll O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
General O

And O
that O
can O
only O
happen O
in O
a O
democracy O
or O
... O

The O
few O
times O
that O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
rulers O
acted O
wilfully O
, O
it O
was O
when O
they O
saw O
their O
own O
position O
in O
danger O
: O
during O
the O
Royal O
Question O
, O
the O
independence O
of O
Congo B-LOC
or O
the O
state O
reform O
. O

Not O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
and O
not O
in O
Laeken B-LOC
. O

page O

He O
is O
not O
allowed O
to O
have O
his O
own O
opinion O
and O
all O
his O
actions O
are O
covered O
by O
the O
government O
, O
which O
in O
turn O
is O
accountable O
to O
the O
people O
's O
representation O
. O

' O
My O
kingdom O
for O
purple O
... O
' O

Some O
point O
to O
the O
rising O
influence O
of O
the O
( O
French B-MISC
- I-MISC
speaking I-MISC
) O
liberals O
at O
the O
court O
. O

Karl B-PER
van I-PER
den I-PER
Broeck I-PER

It O
's O
a O
simple O
solution O
, O
but O
the O
legitimacy O
of O
the O
exercise O
of O
power O
is O
not O
very O
great O
. O

That O
is O
precisely O
why O
democracy O
is O
' O
the O
least O
bad O
form O
of O
government O
' O
: O
the O
transfer O
of O
power O
takes O
place O
peacefully O
and O
those O
in O
power O
have O
a O
legitimacy O
that O
can O
not O
be O
challenged O
. O

Officially O
, O
however O
, O
it O
is O
very O
simple O
: O
the O
king O
is O
an O
empty O
box O
. O

That O
is O
why O
it O
is O
such O
a O
valuable O
characteristic O
of O
a O
civilized O
society O
that O
the O
transfer O
of O
power O
should O
take O
place O
in O
a O
peaceful O
manner O
. O

In O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
there O
was O
often O
only O
one O
majority O
: O
the O
Christian O
Democratic O
Party O
. O

In O
a O
monarchy O
, O
the O
question O
of O
who O
has O
the O
right O
to O
exercise O
power O
, O
is O
left O
to O
fate O
: O
whoever O
is O
born O
from O
the O
king O
's O
sperm O
, O
later O
becomes O
king O
himself O
. O

edition O

publication O

Observers O
point O
out O
that O
something O
fundamental O
has O
changed O
in O
this O
country O
since O
the O
purple O
- O
green O
coalition O
took O
office O
. O

publication O
date O

Perhaps O
it O
is O
all O
much O
simpler O
. O

The O
court O
's O
natural O
ally O
, O
the O
Christian O
column O
, O
has O
been O
relegated O
to O
opposition O
and O
the O
country O
is O
run O
by O
a O
' O
republican O
' O
coalition O
. O

Opinion B-MISC

In O
a O
modern O
democracy O
, O
a O
king O
can O
only O
hold O
his O
own O
if O
he O
does O
not O
upset O
the O
majority O
. O

Those O
who O
have O
to O
cede O
power O
, O
argue O
. O

The O
crypto O
- O
majority O
training O
of O
Prince O
Laurent B-PER
would O
be O
a O
striking O
example O
of O
this O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

author O

In O
this O
way O
, O
the O
king O
was O
reduced O
to O
a O
mouthpiece O
of O
the O
majority O
. O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
2000 O

Belgium B-LOC
was O
obviously O
asking O
for O
trouble O
when O
it O
chose O
a O
' O
constitutional O
monarchy O
' O
in O
1830 O
. O

It O
is O
so O
in O
Great B-LOC
Britain I-LOC
, O
it O
is O
so O
in O
the O
Netherlands B-LOC
( O
Queen O
Beatrix B-PER
had O
to O
experience O
that O
) O
and O
it O
is O
of O
course O
also O
the O
case O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
. O

The O
abortion O
issue O
confronted O
the O
monarch O
with O
the O
dark O
side O
of O
his O
" O
political O
neutrality O
" O
: O
his O
religious O
views O
appeared O
to O
fall O
under O
it O
as O
well O
, O
which O
was O
hardly O
acceptable O
to O
the O
deeply O
religious O
monarch O
. O

section O

The O
CVP B-ORG
reacted O
crankily O
and O
accused O
the O
king O
of O
partiality O
. O

He O
knows O
that O
if O
he O
does O
not O
sign O
the O
euthanasia O
law O
next O
year O
, O
he O
is O
signing O
his O
death O
warrant O
. O

The O
King O
was O
in O
a O
quandary O
from O
the O
start O
: O
He O
had O
to O
remain O
in O
the O
popular O
favor O
in O
order O
to O
retain O
his O
power O
and O
he O
had O
to O
resort O
to O
canapé O
politics O
, O
twilight O
zones O
and O
lobbying O
in O
order O
to O
exercise O
any O
power O
at O
all O
. O

in O
a O
monarchy O
. O

Whoever O
has O
power O
wants O
to O
retain O
power O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
King O
Albert B-PER
and O
his O
children O
are O
going O
to O
adopt O
an O
increasingly O
' O
purple O
- O
green O
' O
attitude O
is O
a O
cold O
reminder O
that O
the O
CVP B-ORG
is O
no O
longer O
calling O
the O
shots O
. O

And O
King O
Albert B-PER
? O

-DOCSTART- O
The O
90 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
grabbed O
his O
gun O
and O
shot O
. O

At O
his O
arrest O
he O
offered O
no O
resistance O
. O

section O

author O

The O
room O
and O
the O
corridor O
where O
the O
facts O
took O
place O
, O
were O
sealed O
in O
anticipation O
of O
the O
possible O
dismissal O
of O
the O
Charleroi B-LOC
prosecutor O
's O
office O
. O

The B-MISC
Life I-MISC

Four O
teams O
of O
the O
gendarmerie O
of O
the O
district O
of O
Charleroi B-LOC
besieged O
the O
rest O
home O
shortly O
after O
the O
facts O
because O
it O
was O
assumed O
that O
the O
rest O
home O
director O
was O
dead O
. O

The O
other O
residents O
of O
the O
home O
were O
taken O
care O
of O
by O
a O
psychology O
team O
. O

Yesterday O
morning O
, O
a O
94 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
resident O
of O
a O
home O
for O
the O
elderly O
in O
Aiseau B-LOC
- I-LOC
Presles I-LOC
put O
a O
bullet O
at O
close O
range O
through O
the O
head O
of O
the O
manager O
of O
the O
home O
. O

Then O
the O
man O
locked O
himself O
in O
his O
room O
. O

friday O
, O
2 O
june O
2000 O

According O
to O
the O
gendarmerie O
, O
the O
elderly O
man O
was O
unable O
to O
explain O
his O
actions O
. O

publication O

The O
offender O
could O
finally O
be O
overpowered O
by O
the O
gendarmerie O
. O

( O
KDM B-PER
) O

The O
man O
was O
tending O
to O
the O
shooter O
when O
it O
came O
to O
a O
high O
- O
profile O
argument O
. O

edition O

Elderly O
man O
shoots O
nursing O
home O
director O

page O

General O

The O
victim O
was O
struck O
by O
the O
bullet O
in O
the O
head O
and O
was O
transferred O
to O
the O
Fabiola B-ORG
Hospital I-ORG
of O
Auvelais B-LOC
. O

The O
manager O
was O
no O
longer O
in O
critical O
condition O
after O
the O
shooting O
. O

The O
elderly O
person O
was O
noticed O
intermittently O
when O
he O
moved O
from O
the O
room O
where O
he O
was O
holed O
up O
to O
the O
hallway O
. O

Kristof B-PER
Demasure I-PER

He O
does O
not O
even O
seem O
to O
be O
aware O
of O
his O
behavior O
, O
nor O
of O
the O
seriousness O
of O
the O
facts O
. O

publication O
date O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

-DOCSTART- O
That O
Baan B-ORG
would O
be O
taken O
over O
, O
was O
almost O
certain O
. O

As O
a O
result O
, O
Invensys B-ORG
is O
already O
certain O
of O
10.8 O
percent O
of O
the O
shares O
. O

A O
thousand O
people O
have O
to O
leave O
Baan B-ORG
. O

" O
We O
think O
Invensys B-ORG
is O
the O
right O
company O
to O
restructure O
Baan B-ORG
. O

publication O

The O
reorganization O
costs O
would O
be O
the O
basis O
for O
this O
. O

Incidentally O
, O
Invensys B-ORG
itself O
is O
not O
doing O
too O
well O
either O
. O

That O
company O
was O
formed O
from O
the O
merger O
of O
Siebe B-ORG
and O
BTR B-ORG
. O

edition O

Invensys B-ORG
can O
make O
good O
use O
of O
Baan B-ORG
software O
to O
supplement O
its O
control O
systems O
for O
factories O
and O
installations O
. O

17 O

Invensys B-ORG
is O
offering O
858 O
million O
euros O
for O
Baan B-ORG
, O
or O
2.85 O
euros O
per O
share O
in O
cash O
. O

It O
is O
hoped O
that O
next O
year O
the O
losses O
will O
be O
a O
thing O
of O
the O
past O
. O

Baan B-ORG
in O
British B-MISC
hands O

General O

section O

The O
hired O
merchant O
bank O
Lazard B-ORG
Frères I-ORG
has O
been O
peddling O
the O
software O
company O
since O
January O
. O

publication O
date O

Only O
nobody O
seemed O
to O
want O
the O
ailing O
company O
. O

Takeover O

Baan B-ORG
shares O
rose O
13 O
percent O
to O
2.97 O
euros O
on O
Wednesday O
, O
while O
Invensys B-ORG
had O
to O
surrender O
13 O
percent O
to O
230 O
pence O
. O

That O
's O
8.8 O
percent O
more O
than O
Tuesday O
's O
closing O
price O
. O

The O
founders O
of O
the O
company O
, O
the O
brothers O
Jan B-PER
and O
Paul B-PER
Baan I-PER
, O
have O
agreed O
to O
sell O
their O
shares O
to O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

At O
the O
same O
time O
as O
the O
acquisition O
of O
Baan B-ORG
, O
the O
British B-MISC
company O
announced O
a O
loss O
of O
238 O
million O
pounds O
, O
more O
than O
double O
than O
a O
year O
earlier O
. O

Baan B-ORG
was O
once O
one O
of O
the O
best O
performing O
stocks O
in O
Europe B-LOC
, O
but O
has O
lost O
90 O
percent O
of O
its O
value O
in O
two O
years O
due O
to O
persistent O
losses O
and O
management O
problems O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Other O
top O
executives O
within O
the O
company O
are O
also O
set O
to O
do O
so O
. O

Invensys B-ORG
wants O
to O
thoroughly O
reorganize O
the O
company O
and O
is O
allocating O
400 O
million O
euros O
for O
this O
purpose O
. O

The O
intention O
is O
for O
the O
Baan B-ORG
name O
to O
continue O
to O
exist O
, O
but O
as O
part O
of O
Invensys B-ORG
Software I-ORG
and I-ORG
Systems I-ORG
. O

Bloomberg B-ORG

The O
Dutch B-MISC
software O
maker O
Baan B-ORG
is O
bought O
by O
the O
British B-MISC
Invensys B-ORG
. O

page O

We O
want O
to O
do O
that O
quickly O
" O
, O
said O
board O
chairman O
Allen B-PER
Yurko I-PER
of O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Morning I-MISC

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

author O

-DOCSTART- O
Return O
of O
Elián B-PER
to O
Cuba B-LOC
step O
closer O

General O

In O
the O
Yugoslav B-MISC
Republic O
of O
Serbia B-LOC
several O
high O
officials O
and O
criminals O
have O
been O
assassinated O
recently O
, O
but O
it O
is O
the O
first O
time O
that O
something O
similar O
has O
happened O
in O
Montenegro B-LOC
, O
the O
other O
republic O
in O
the O
Yugoslav B-LOC
Federation I-LOC
. O

edition O

The O
return O
of O
Cuban B-MISC
boat O
refugee O
Elián B-PER
González I-PER
from O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
to O
his O
homeland O
came O
a O
step O
closer O
yesterday O
. O

Brief O

The O
family O
will O
now O
appeal O
to O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
. O

The O
Hammersmith B-LOC
Bridge I-LOC
in O
west O
London B-LOC
was O
damaged O
yesterday O
by O
a O
bomb O
explosion O
. O

Bomb O
explodes O
under O
London B-MISC
bridge O

Foreign B-MISC

Pro O
- O
western O
Montenegro B-LOC
is O
trying O
to O
chart O
an O
independent O
course O
from O
Slobodan B-PER
Milosevic I-PER
's O
Serbia O
. O

There O
were O
no O
casualties O
, O
but O
there O
was O
a O
huge O
traffic O
chaos O
. O

Police O
discovered O
a O
small O
explosive O
device O
attached O
to O
a O
support O
beam O
of O
the O
bridge O
connecting O
both O
banks O
of O
the O
River O
Thames B-LOC
. O

Northern B-MISC
Irish I-MISC
unionists O
are O
pointing O
an O
accusing O
finger O
at O
republican O
splinter O
movements O
, O
because O
the O
Irish B-ORG
Republican I-ORG
Army I-ORG
( O
IRA B-ORG
) O
also O
carried O
out O
a O
failed O
attack O
on O
the O
bridge O
in O
1996 O
. O

There O
are O
considerable O
tensions O
between O
the O
two O
republics O
. O

The O
judge O
's O
ruling O
was O
the O
latest O
development O
in O
the O
lawsuit O
filed O
by O
Eliáns B-MISC
family O
from O
Miami B-LOC
to O
keep O
the O
child O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
, O
where O
he O
was O
taken O
care O
of O
after O
his O
dramatic O
shipwreck O
. O

According O
to O
the O
court O
, O
only O
his O
father O
can O
do O
that O
for O
him O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2 O
, O
2000 O

An O
appeals O
court O
in O
Atlanta B-LOC
decided O
that O
the O
six O
- O
year O
- O
old O
boy O
is O
not O
entitled O
to O
seek O
asylum O
in O
the O
U.S. B-LOC
himself O
. O

The O
security O
adviser O
to O
President O
Djukanovic B-PER
of O
Montenegro B-LOC
was O
shot O
dead O
by O
unknown O
persons O
in O
the O
capital O
Podgorica B-LOC
. O

publication O

page O

Until O
that O
case O
is O
decided O
, O
the O
boy O
must O
remain O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
. O

Police O
found O
the O
body O
of O
Goran B-PER
Zugic I-PER
in O
the O
garden O
at O
his O
home O
, O
after O
a O
local O
resident O
heard O
gunshots O
. O

publication O
date O

Employee O
of O
president O
of O
Montenegro B-LOC
murdered O

Police O
are O
investigating O
whether O
the O
failed O
attack O
is O
the O
work O
of O
dissident O
paramilitaries O
from O
Northern B-LOC
Ireland I-LOC
, O
who O
opposed O
the O
self O
- O
government O
returned O
to O
the O
province O
this O
week O
. O

author O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

section O

-DOCSTART- O
In O
the O
forenoon O
he O
then O
released O
seventeen O
children O
and O
two O
companions O
. O

Wasserbillig B-LOC

From O
our O
reporter O
on O
the O
spot O

In O
addition O
-- O
in O
addition O
to O
five O
French B-MISC
, O
three O
German B-MISC
and O
one O
Italian B-MISC
hostages O
-- O
a O
Belgian B-MISC
girl O
of O
eight O
was O
also O
held O
. O

At O
8:30 O
Thursday O
morning O
the O
ultimatum O
expired O
in O
which O
Bejoui B-PER
demanded O
a O
minibus O
to O
the O
airport O
and O
a O
plane O
to O
Libya B-LOC
. O

Police O
reportedly O
intervened O
because O
the O
hostage O
taker O
planned O
to O
take O
some O
children O
with O
him O
on O
a O
possible O
flight O
. O

The O
man O
held O
the O
children O
and O
supervisors O
captive O
at O
the O
day O
care O
center O
in O
Wasserbillig B-LOC
, O
a O
town O
in O
the O
Grand O
Duchy O
of B-LOC
Luxembourg I-LOC
. O

page O

The O
hostage O
- O
taking O
of O
twenty O
- O
five O
children O
and O
two O
supervisors O
in O
Luxembourg B-MISC
ended O
well O
for O
the O
hostages O
last O
night O
a O
little O
after O
seven O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

edition O

Thirteen O
of O
the O
children O
are O
of O
Portuguese B-MISC
origin O
. O

Page O
3 O

The O
actions O
of O
the O
police O
were O
initially O
thwarted O
because O
the O
hostage O
was O
closely O
following O
the O
news O
coverage O
on O
television O
and O
radio O
. O

Yesterday O
the O
hostage O
released O
four O
more O
children O
during O
the O
day O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

Sniper O
ends O
hostage O
situation O
in O
Wasserbillig B-LOC

An B-PER
Bruyninckx I-PER

According O
to O
the O
latest O
reports O
, O
the O
man O
had O
two O
gunshot O
wounds O
to O
the O
head O
and O
his O
life O
was O
in O
danger O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

publication O
date O

section O

publication O

author O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

He O
also O
allegedly O
demanded O
60 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
( O
1.5 O
million O
euros O
) O
. O

The O
hostage O
- O
taking O
began O
Wednesday O
afternoon O
around O
3:30 O
p.m. O
when O
the O
man O
, O
armed O
with O
a O
knife O
, O
a O
pistol O
and O
a O
grenade O
, O
entered O
the O
day O
care O
center O
. O

General O

The O
hostage O
taker O
, O
39 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
, O
was O
shot O
by O
a O
sniper O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
In O
April O
last O
year O
there O
was O
commotion O
around O
the O
file O
when O
Steve B-PER
Stevaert I-PER
( O
SP B-ORG
) O
, O
then O
Minister O
of O
Spatial B-ORG
Planning I-ORG
, O
withdrew O
the O
BPA B-MISC
in O
question O
after O
the O
auditor O
at O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
State I-ORG
advised O
to O
destroy O
it O
. O

According O
to O
the O
counsel O
for O
Floralux B-ORG
, O
the O
court O
of O
appeal O
did O
not O
pronounce O
a O
sanction O
because O
after O
all O
these O
years O
it O
would O
no O
longer O
make O
sense O
. O

Page O
7 O

The O
Floralux B-MISC
case I-MISC
has O
been O
dragging O
on O
for O
years O
and O
revolves O
around O
a O
zoning O
change O
that O
was O
tailor O
- O
made O
for O
the O
company O
and O
allowed O
the O
plant O
grower O
to O
develop O
into O
a O
garden O
center O
of O
supermarket O
proportions O
in O
what O
was O
originally O
an O
agricultural O
area O
. O

Floralux B-ORG
therefore O
does O
not O
have O
to O
reduce O
its O
size O
or O
pay O
damages O
to O
Dadiflor B-ORG
. O

A O
fax O
from O
her O
lawyer O
to O
his O
client O
, O
confiscated O
by O
the O
High O
Court O
of B-ORG
Justice I-ORG
, O
leaves O
no O
doubt O
about O
the O
role O
of O
the O
College O
of O
Aldermen O
in O
this O
matter O
. O

Case O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
was O
suspected O
of O
having O
become O
a O
CVP B-MISC
alderman I-MISC
for O
town O
and O
country B-ORG
planning I-ORG
in O
order O
to O
realize O
the O
' O
BPA B-MISC
Kezelberg I-MISC
' O
herself O
. O

publication O
date O

Conflicts O
of O
interest O
remain O
unpunished O

The O
dossier O
gained O
a O
larger O
dimension O
because O
a O
lot O
of O
political O
lobbying O
was O
involved O
. O

publication O

However O
, O
this O
was O
more O
of O
a O
symbolic O
decision O
, O
because O
by O
then O
the O
weightier O
regional O
plan O
had O
already O
been O
amended O
, O
making O
the O
matter O
definitively O
settled O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

section O

All O
civil O
claims O
of O
the O
other O
party O
, O
competitor O
Dadiflor B-ORG
, O
have O
also O
been O
rejected O
. O

author O

General O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

The O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
finds O
that O
in O
the O
case O
of O
the O
controversial O
garden O
center O
Floralux B-ORG
in O
the O
West B-MISC
Flemish I-MISC
Dadizele B-LOC
there O
has O
been O
a O
conflict O
of O
interest O
but O
did O
not O
deem O
it O
necessary O
to O
punish O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
for O
it O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
/ O
Dadizele B-LOC

By O
condemning O
Floralux B-ORG
for O
' O
taking O
an O
interest O
' O
, O
the O
court O
wanted O
to O
expose O
the O
political O
lobbying O
. O

But O
just O
like O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
in O
Ghent B-LOC
, O
the O
Antwerp B-LOC
Court O
ruled O
that O
the O
fax O
should O
be O
excluded O
from O
the O
file O
because O
it O
is O
covered O
by O
the O
professional O
secrecy O
of O
lawyers O
. O

edition O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

The O
file O
turned O
up O
in O
the O
infamous O
Atoma B-MISC
notebooks I-MISC
of O
Leo B-PER
Delcroix I-PER
. O

Antwerp B-MISC
Court O
of O
Appeal O
leaves O
garden O
center O
Floralux B-ORG
unpunished O

Conflict O
of O
interest O
in O
the O
criminal O
sense O
would O
not O
be O
proven O
. O

page O

Own O
reporting O

Competitor O
Dadiflor B-ORG
takes O
courage O
from O
the O
judgment O
by O
seeing O
in O
the O
conviction O
an O
additional O
argument O
for O
the O
annulment O
of O
the O
regional O
plan O
amendment O
by O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
State I-ORG
. O

The O
Ghent B-MISC
prosecutor O
general O
Frank B-PER
Schins I-PER
even O
judged O
that O
there O
was O
overlobbying O
in O
this O
case O
. O

Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
concludes O
that O
the O
court O
" O
condemned O
the O
political O
mores O
of O
the O
time O
" O
but O
she O
still O
believes O
that O
she O
" O
did O
nothing O
wrong O
" O
. O

Last O
year O
, O
then O
CVP B-MISC
minister I-MISC
Luc B-PER
Martens I-PER
admitted O
that O
he O
had O
asked O
for O
" O
attention O
" O
for O
the O
case O
within O
the O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
. O

1 O

-DOCSTART- O
For O
the O
first O
time O
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
, O
the O
leader O
got O
into O
trouble O
very O
briefly O
yesterday O
. O

On O
Abetone B-LOC
last O
Monday O
, O
Casagrande B-PER
had O
impressed O
and O
also O
in O
the O
Dolomites B-LOC
the O
leader O
had O
not O
given O
an O
inch O
. O

He O
got O
back O
on O
the O
wheel O
of O
Garzelli B-PER
and O
others O
and O
sprinted O
up O
to O
third O
place O
. O

The O
difference O
between O
the O
leader O
and O
Garzelli B-PER
is O
only O
25 O
seconds O
. O

section O

On O
the O
contrary O
, O
Stefano B-PER
Garzelli I-PER
and O
Gilberto B-PER
Simoni I-PER
made O
it O
clear O
that O
they O
can O
make O
life O
difficult O
for O
Casagrande B-PER
today O
and O
tomorrow O
. O

Later O
it O
was O
the O
same O
with O
Ivan B-PER
Gotti I-PER
. O

Pratonevoso B-LOC

To O
win O
. O

" O
I O
fear O
no O
one O
and O
I O
will O
attack O
" O
, O
he O
announced O
. O

Only O
now O
he O
really O
feels O
the O
hot O
breath O
of O
Stefano B-PER
Garzelli I-PER
on O
the O
neck O
. O

Today O
's O
queenly O
stage O
with O
the O
climbs O
of O
the O
col O
d'Agnelli B-LOC
( O
2748 O
meters O
) O
and O
the O
Izoard B-LOC
( O
2361 O
) O
and O
tomorrow O
's O
climbing O
time O
trial O
over O
the O
Montgenèvre B-LOC
and O
Sestrière B-LOC
are O
awaited O
with O
particular O
interest O
. O

page O

Thanks O
to O
the O
support O
of O
Buenahora B-PER
, O
Casagrande B-PER
did O
recover O
a O
little O
later O
. O

For O
Di B-PER
Luca I-PER
, O
Wednesday O
became O
too O
much O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Casagrande B-PER
feels O
the O
hot O
breath O
of O
Garzelli B-PER

The O
tastemaker O
of O
the O
first O
two O
weeks O
, O
stepped O
down O
with O
tendinitis O
. O

I O
want O
to O
make O
a O
difference O
here O
. O

And O
say O
that O
Casagrande B-PER
on O
the O
eve O
of O
the O
stage O
to O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
spoke O
optimistically O
. O

Insofar O
as O
both O
still O
cherished O
winning O
ambitions O
, O
they O
may O
now O
put O
them O
away O
for O
good O
. O

" O

And O
that O
might O
well O
be O
. O

Own O
reporting O

I O
'll O
be O
back O
next O
year O
. O

We O
will O
get O
more O
clarity O
today O
and O
tomorrow O
in O
the O
two O
extremely O
difficult O
Alpine B-MISC
stages I-MISC
. O

Garzelli B-PER
and O
Piepoli B-PER
do O
not O
. O

He O
also O
has O
the O
advantage O
of O
being O
the O
better O
time O
trialist O
among O
the O
favorites O
, O
so O
he O
really O
dares O
to O
think O
about O
winning O
. O

To O
win O
the O
Giro B-MISC
. O

author O

" O
But O
I O
have O
learned O
a O
lot O
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
. O

Rosette O
jersey O
carrier O
has O
not O
yet O
won O
Giro B-MISC

Gonzales B-PER
de I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
, O
who O
is O
known O
as O
a O
better O
time O
trialist O
, O
made O
it O
a O
true O
time O
trial O
between O
Genoa B-LOC
and O
Brescia B-LOC
. O

( O
TL B-PER
) O

Sport B-MISC

Francesco B-PER
Casagrande I-PER
will O
be O
a O
lot O
less O
reassured O
after O
yesterday O
. O

friday O
, O
2 O
june O
2000 O

publication O

" O

Building O
on O
the O
solid O
climbing O
work O
of O
the O
Italian B-MISC
, O
everyone O
became O
increasingly O
convinced O
that O
Casagrande B-PER
, O
who O
had O
set O
the O
Italian B-MISC
Tour O
as O
his O
main O
goal O
and O
had O
made O
a O
lot O
of O
sacrifices O
for O
it O
, O
would O
realize O
his O
goal O
. O

Under O
the O
forceful O
pace O
changes O
of O
Gilberto B-PER
Simoni I-PER
on O
the O
steepest O
parts O
of O
the O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
, O
Casagrande B-PER
had O
to O
pass O
. O

General O

" O
This O
ride O
is O
more O
important O
to O
me O
than O
the O
next O
two O
. O

" O
I O
win O
today O
" O
, O
he O
had O
written O
on O
the O
control O
sheet O
in O
the O
morning O
. O

No O
matter O
how O
hard O
the O
sprinters O
' O
teams O
chased O
the O
Spaniard B-MISC
in O
the O
group O
, O
he O
still O
had O
almost O
half O
a O
minute O
left O
at O
the O
finish O
. O

But O
should O
we O
assume O
that O
dropping O
out O
for O
a O
moment O
and O
constantly O
chasing O
him O
was O
a O
sign O
of O
things O
to O
come O
? O

Halfway O
through O
the O
race O
, O
after O
118 O
kilometers O
, O
he O
broke O
away O
from O
the O
peloton O
on O
his O
own O
, O
ran O
up O
to O
seven O
minutes O
and O
resisted O
the O
return O
of O
the O
peloton O
in O
a O
brilliant O
way O
. O

Especially O
for O
Garzelli B-PER
, O
the O
stage O
win O
must O
be O
a O
boost O
. O

edition O

And O
the O
Spaniard B-MISC
from O
the O
Vitalicio B-MISC
team I-MISC
kept O
his O
word O
. O

On O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
Dario B-PER
Frigo I-PER
got O
into O
trouble O
very O
early O
on O
. O

The O
final O
days O
of O
the O
Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Italy I-MISC
promise O
to O
be O
exciting O
. O

The O
teammate O
of O
Marco B-PER
Pantani I-PER
and O
leader O
of O
Mercatone B-ORG
Uno I-ORG
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
, O
left O
all O
his O
competitors O
behind O
on O
the O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
yesterday O
and O
crept O
closer O
to O
Casagrande B-PER
thanks O
to O
the O
bonification O
. O

publication O
date O

" O
The O
pains O
were O
unbearable O
" O
, O
said O
the O
young O
Di B-PER
Luca I-PER
. O

15 O

But O
it O
is O
sometimes O
said O
of O
the O
Tuscan B-MISC
that O
a O
grand O
tour O
lasts O
a O
week O
too O
long O
for O
him O
. O

Wednesday O
was O
Alvaro B-PER
Gonzales I-PER
de O
Galdeano B-PER
's O
day O
. O

So O
it O
was O
not O
that O
fast O
. O

Tony B-PER
Landuyt I-PER

Two O
of O
those O
favorites O
were O
thrown O
overboard O
yesterday O
. O

They O
went O
smoothly O
along O
in O
the O
wake O
of O
Simoni B-PER
. O

-DOCSTART- O
publication O
date O

But O
the O
more O
Chernow B-PER
wrote O
, O
the O
more O
eager O
they O
became O
. O

Both O
did O
not O
like O
Chernow B-MISC
's I-MISC
plan O
at O
first O
because O
they O
still O
felt O
too O
" O
young O
and O
healthy O
" O
for O
a O
biography O
. O

The O
first O
edition O
of O
the O
500 O
- O
page O
book O
Christo B-PER
and O
Jeanne B-PER
- I-PER
Claude I-PER
- O
a O
biography O
was O
only O
published O
in O
German B-MISC
for O
the O
time O
being O
. O

Christo B-PER
biography O
published O

General O

Culture B-MISC

The O
Bulgarian B-MISC
- I-MISC
American I-MISC
artist O
couple O
Christo B-PER
( O
Javacheff B-PER
) O
and O
Jeanne B-PER
- I-PER
Claude I-PER
presented O
earlier O
this O
week O
in O
Cologne B-LOC
his O
biography O
published O
by O
the O
publishing O
house O
Keipenheuer B-ORG
Witsch I-ORG
. O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

page O

The O
author O
Burt B-PER
Chernow I-PER
and O
friend O
of O
the O
Christos B-PER
, O
wrote O
the O
biography O
of O
the O
couple O
: O
the O
from O
Bulgaria B-LOC
originating O
Christo B-PER
Javacheff I-PER
and O
his O
great O
love O
Jeanne O
- O
Claude B-PER
de I-PER
Guillebon I-PER
. O

publication O

They O
caused O
a O
stir O
especially O
in O
1995 O
, O
when O
they O
completely O
packed O
the O
German B-MISC
Reichstag B-LOC
in O
Berlin B-LOC
. O

edition O

section O

author O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

" O
Germany B-LOC
has O
a O
special O
place O
in O
our O
hearts O
, O
" O
the O
two O
artists O
said O
during O
the O
presentation O
. O

The O
artistic O
couple O
has O
been O
engaged O
in O
the O
art O
of O
wrapping O
since O
the O
1960s O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
General O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

" O
The O
government O
has O
been O
raising O
awareness O
for O
more O
than O
twenty O
years O
. O

Brussels B-MISC
Environment B-ORG
Minister O
Didier B-PER
Gosuin I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
/ I-ORG
FDF I-ORG
) O
is O
also O
disappointed O
with O
the O
" O
meagre O
" O
content O
of O
the O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
. O

For O
each O
violation O
of O
the O
European B-MISC
health O
standard O
( O
120 O
micrograms O
of O
ozone O
per O
cubic O
meter O
for O
at O
least O
eight O
hours O
) O
, O
they O
demand O
50 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
from O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
state O
, O
the O
Brussels O
Region O
and O
the O
nineteen O
Brussels I-MISC
communes O
. O

Air O
pollution O
deserves O
much O
more O
than O
that O
" O
, O
says O
Gosuin B-PER
, O
who O
himself O
announces O
structural O
measures O
. O

The O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
gets O
a O
severe O
insufficient O
from O
the O
environmental O
movement O
. O

Environmental O
movement O
instigates O
ozone O
lawsuit O

page O

Two O
Brussels B-MISC
associations O
, O
Bral B-ORG
and O
Inter B-ORG
- I-ORG
Environnement I-ORG
, O
are O
fed O
up O
with O
the O
procrastination O
of O
the O
authorities O
and O
are O
going O
to O
court O
in O
summary O
proceedings O
. O

Pages O
2 O
and O
7 O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

publication O

The O
two O
associations O
ask O
for O
concrete O
measures O
to O
limit O
car O
traffic O
before O
the O
summer O
. O

edition O

publication O
date O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

author O

1 O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

section O

-DOCSTART- O
Di B-PER
Biase I-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
11 O
. O

Zabel B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
3h15:58 O
-- O
2 O
. O

Buenahora B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
08 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Wüst B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
/ O
Festina B-ORG
) O
the O
102.6 O
km O
in O
2h28:10 O
-- O
2 O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Plaza B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
31h08:55 O
-- O
2 O
. O

Leoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
4 O
. O

Simoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
53 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Simoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
3 O
. O

Kadlec B-PER
( O
Tsj B-LOC
) O
-- O
. O

Frigo B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
4:34 O
-- O
10 O
. O

43 O
. O

Finot B-PER
( O
Fra B-LOC
) O
z.t O
. O
-- O
7 O
. O

Zabel B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
-- O
5 O
. O

Blanco B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
4:39 O
-- O
11 O
. O

Ullrich B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:33 O
-- O
10 O
. O

Forconi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
2:18 O
-- O
18 O
. O

Merckx B-PER
all O
z.t O
. O

Sport B-MISC

Tonkov B-PER
( O
Rus B-LOC
) O
2:41 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Verbrugghe B-PER
-- O
17 O
. O

Rebellin B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
10:21 O
. O

Bracke B-PER
all O
z.t O
. O

Hruska B-PER
( O
Tsj B-LOC
) O
-- O
. O

Guidi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
10 O
. O

Bruylandts B-PER
0:23 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Pantani B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
... O

Fornaciari B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
13 O
. O

Garzelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
at O
25 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Casero B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
1:42 O
-- O
5 O
. O

McRae B-PER
( O
USA B-LOC
) O
19:00 O
-- O
19 O
. O

Koerts B-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
-- O
3 O
. O

McRae B-PER
( O
VSt B-LOC
) O
1:47 O
-- O
14 O
. O

section O

Blanco B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
-- O
10 O
. O

Garzelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
/ O
Mercatone B-ORG
Uno I-ORG
) O
the O
173 O
km O
in O
4h42:32 O
( O
avg O
: O
36,739 O
km O
/ O
h O
) O
-- O
2 O
. O

Lanfranchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
12:51 O
-- O
15 O
. O

7th O
stage O
( O
time O
trial O
) O
: O
1 O
. O

Plaza B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
/ O
Festina B-ORG
) O
the O
35,7 O
km O
in O
42:53 O
-- O
2 O
. O

56 O
. O

General O

Beikirch B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
-- O
. O

Boscardin B-PER
( O
Zwi B-LOC
) O
44 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Rous B-PER
( O
Fra B-LOC
) O
at O
0:09 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Van B-PER
de I-PER
Wouwer I-PER
0:13 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Petersen B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
all O
z.t O
. O

Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Italy:17th I-MISC
stage O
: O
1 O
. O

Grand B-ORG
Prix I-ORG
of I-ORG
Wallonia I-ORG
( O
category O
1.2 O
) O
: O

Hruska B-PER
( O
Tsj B-LOC
) O
13:14 O
-- O
16 O
. O

Rubiera B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
4:45 O
-- O
12 O
. O

Pena B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
16:59 O
-- O
18 O
. O

1 O
. O

16 O
. O

Savoldelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
19:08 O
-- O
20 O
. O

Leoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
5 O
. O

Hoj B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
2:12 O
-- O
10 O
. O

author O

Final O
score O
: O
1 O
. O

Gotti B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:54 O
-- O
17 O
. O

publication O

Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Italy I-MISC
: O

Klöden B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
at O
0:42 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Piepoli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
at O
02 O
-- O
5 O
. O

31 O
. O

Gerosa B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
14 O
. O

15 O

Casero B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
1:40 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Rittsel B-PER
( O
Zwe B-LOC
) O
2:34 O
. O

Gonzalez B-PER
de I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
... O

Sevilla B-LOC
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
15:24 O
-- O
17 O
. O

Farazijn B-PER
1:58 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Usov B-PER
( O
WRu B-LOC
) O
-- O
7 O
. O

Merckx B-PER
7:32 O
-- O
... O

Baguet B-PER
-- O
18 O
. O

Savoldelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
8:23 O
-- O
48 O
. O

Rubiera B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
49 O
-- O
11 O
. O

Roesems B-PER
2:06 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Heppner B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
2:06 O
-- O
... O

Piepoli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
6:13 O
-- O
14 O
. O

Liese B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:11 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Standings O
: O
1 O
. O

13 O
. O

17th O
stage O
: O
1 O
. O

Vermeersch B-PER
2:02 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Blaudzun B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
1:44 O
-- O
7 O
. O

Lafis B-PER
( O
Zwe B-LOC
) O
-- O
15 O
. O

Bölts B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
1:41 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Frigo B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
2:38 O
-- O
20 O
. O

Kristensen B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
z.t O
. O
-- O
... O

34 O
. O

Petersen B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
-- O
6 O
. O

Blaudzun B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
1:46 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Martinello B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
6 O
. O

Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Germany I-MISC
: O

Ullrich B-PER
18:04 O

Ullrich B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
all O
z.t O
. O

Beikirch B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
-- O
3 O
. O

18th O
stage O
: O
1 O
. O

Belli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
7 O
. O

Gonzalez B-PER
de I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
/ O
Vitalicio B-ORG
) O
the O
236 O
km O
in O
5h23:02 O
( O
average O
: O
43,834 O
km O
/ O
h O
) O
-- O
2 O
. O

Boogerd B-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
z.t O
. O
-- O
. O

Petacchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
5 O
. O

Baranowski B-PER
( O
Poo B-LOC
) O
-- O
13 O
. O

Castelblanco B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
2:24 O
-- O
19 O
. O

Belli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:11 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Usov B-PER
( O
WRu B-LOC
) O
-- O
6 O
. O

Casagrande B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
4 O
. O

Noè B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
3:39 O
-- O
7 O
. O

Konyshev B-PER
( O
Rus B-LOC
) O
-- O
4 O
. O

Braikia B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
-- O
9 O
. O

Bölts B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
1:26 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Buenahora B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
3:43 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Klöden B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
at O
40 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Wüst B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
-- O
4 O
. O

Heppner B-PER
( O
Ger B-LOC
) O
2:21 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Casagrande B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
/ O
Vini B-ORG
Caldirola I-ORG
) O
87h11:09 O
-- O
2 O
. O

publication O
date O

Mattan B-PER
-- O
19 O
. O

edition O

De B-PER
Jongh I-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
-- O
8 O
. O

Elli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
in O
4h42:05 O
( O
average O
41.732 O
km O
/ O
h O
) O
-- O
2 O
. O

Noè B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
12 O
-- O
9 O
. O

6th O
stage O
: O
1 O
. O

Mancebo B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
20:36 O
. O

Lanfranchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:12 O
-- O
12 O
. O

page O

Mancebo B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
-- O
16 O
. O

Tonkov B-PER
( O
Rus B-LOC
) O
-- O
6 O
. O

De B-PER
Clercq I-PER
-- O
20 O
. O

Conte B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
12 O
. O

Gotti B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
4:25 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Pieri B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
7 O
. O

Honchar B-PER
( O
Uk B-LOC
) O
1:51 O
-- O
15 O
. O

70 O
. O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

Svorada B-PER
( O
Tsj B-LOC
) O
on O
24 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Honchar B-PER
( O
Uk B-LOC
) O
5:45 O
-- O
13 O
. O

8th O
stage O
: O
1 O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Last O
year O
I O
had O
the O
same O
problem O
when O
I O
started O
to O
compete O
again O
in O
the O
Tour B-MISC
de I-MISC
la I-MISC
Région I-MISC
Wallonne I-MISC
. O

publication O
date O

Question O
marks O
around O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
grow O
bigger O

De B-ORG
Morgen I-ORG

General O

publication O

Are O
they O
wrong O
? O

" O

I O
just O
hope O
that O
the O
same O
thing O
will O
happen O
in O
the O
coming O
days O
, O
although O
I O
must O
confess O
that O
I O
am O
not O
entirely O
reassured O
anymore O
. O

The O
Tour B-MISC
is O
fast O
approaching O
. O

Cycling O

" O

There O
are O
even O
those O
who O
already O
bet O
that O
he O
will O
not O
be O
at O
the O
start O
of O
the O
Tour B-MISC
on O
July O
1 O
at O
Futuroscope O
. O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

" O
I O
do O
not O
understand O
why O
there O
is O
so O
much O
noise O
around O
it O
" O
, O
says O
a O
surprised O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
. O

Sport B-MISC

Ief B-PER
Vertommen I-PER

" O
It O
's O
not O
going O
well O
with O
me O
" O
, O
stated O
an O
otherwise O
serene O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
. O

Own O
reporting O

As O
a O
direct O
preparation O
for O
the O
Tour B-MISC
, O
Vandenbroucke O
rather O
wanted O
to O
ride O
the O
Dauphiné B-MISC
( O
June O
4 O
- O
11 O
) O
and O
the O
Route B-MISC
du I-MISC
Sud I-MISC
( O
June O
17 O
- O
20 O
) O
instead O
of O
the O
Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Luxembourg I-MISC
( O
June O
8 O
- O
11 O
) O
and O
the O
Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Switzerland I-MISC
( O
June O
13 O
- O
22 O
) O
. O

However O
, O
the O
Kempener B-MISC
showed O
himself O
satisfied O
with O
this O
test O
in O
view O
of O
the O
Tour B-MISC
de I-MISC
France I-MISC
which O
is O
so O
much O
more O
important O
to O
him O
. O

" O
As O
far O
as O
I O
know O
there O
are O
regularly O
riders O
who O
change O
their O
program O
. O

Van B-PER
de I-PER
Wouwer I-PER
knew O
early O
on O
that O
Elli B-PER
would O
be O
the O
man O
to O
beat O
. O

section O

I O
'm O
not O
panicking O
yet O
, O
but O
there O
should O
n't O
be O
any O
new O
obstacles O
on O
the O
road O
of O
my O
preparation O
. O

" O
In O
any O
case O
, O
a O
lot O
less O
than O
expected O
. O

After O
117 O
km O
, O
he O
called O
it O
a O
day O
. O

One O
thing O
is O
clear O
: O
the O
end O
of O
the O
' O
Vandenbroucke B-MISC
- I-MISC
story I-MISC
' O
is O
not O
in O
sight O
. O

15 O

It O
took O
a O
few O
more O
races O
for O
the O
World B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
before O
the O
dèclic O
announced O
itself O
. O

Frank B-PER
Vandenbroucke I-PER
gives O
up O
at O
GP B-MISC
Wallonie I-MISC
: O
' O
It O
's O
not O
going O
well O
with O
me O
' O
. O

Simply O
because O
there O
is O
more O
recovery O
time O
between O
the O
first O
combination O
. O

Belgians B-MISC
who O
are O
already O
there O
, O
are O
Dave B-PER
Bruylants I-PER
, O
yesterday O
second O
, O
and O
Kurt B-PER
Van I-PER
de I-PER
Wauwer I-PER
, O
third O
. O

Ief B-PER
Vertommen I-PER

Before O
the O
start O
of O
the O
race O
he O
had O
said O
that O
reaching O
the O
top O
condition O
was O
a O
matter O
of O
days O
, O
but O
only O
two O
hills O
later O
he O
was O
riding O
at O
the O
back O
of O
the O
pack O
. O

The O
subsequent O
abandonment O
did O
not O
surprise O
anyone O
. O

page O

Vandenbroucke B-PER
has O
also O
understood O
that O
he O
is O
not O
in O
a O
position O
to O
make O
demands O
in O
relation O
to O
his O
preparation O
programme O
for O
the O
Tour B-MISC
. O

edition O

" O

" O
The O
condition O
is O
good O
, O
but O
not O
super O
. O

Then O
I O
was O
regularly O
driven O
at O
a O
quarter O
of O
an O
hour O
. O

author O

Yesterday O
he O
gave O
up O
in O
the O
only O
Belgian B-MISC
races O
he O
would O
ride O
on O
Belgian B-MISC
soil O
. O

While O
Alberto B-PER
Elli I-PER
from O
Walter B-PER
Godefroot I-PER
's O
Telekom O
team O
won O
the O
GP B-MISC
of I-MISC
Wallonie I-MISC
( O
1.2 O
) O
, O
a O
freshly O
washed O
and O
dressed O
Frank B-PER
Vandenbroucke I-PER
, O
in O
the O
company O
of O
his O
Italian B-MISC
girlfriend O
Sara B-PER
, O
had O
long O
been O
pondering O
what O
to O
do O
next O
. O

But O
I O
will O
now O
have O
to O
accept O
the O
arrangement O
as O
proposed O
by O
the O
team O
management O
. O

Names B-LOC

Vandenbroucke B-PER
: O
" O
I O
'm O
not O
panicking O
yet O
, O
but O
there O
should O
n't O
be O
any O
new O
obstacles O
in O
my O
Tour B-MISC
- I-MISC
preparation I-MISC
" O
. O

Not O
that O
I O
'm O
sick O
, O
but O
I O
simply O
have O
no O
acceleration O
in O
the O
legs O
. O

Bruylants B-PER
, O
only O
a O
fortnight O
back O
racing O
, O
had O
to O
pay O
for O
his O
attempt O
to O
bring O
Elli B-PER
back O
with O
cramps O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
New O
are O
director O
Patrice B-PER
Toye I-PER
( O
of O
the O
award O
- O
winning O
film O
Rosie B-MISC
) O
and O
Marion B-PER
Oprel I-PER
, O
girlfriend O
of O
Marianne B-PER
' O
De B-MISC
Mol I-MISC
) O
Dupont B-PER
. O

Short O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Agalev B-ORG
says O
it O
wants O
to O
make O
Antwerp B-LOC
an O
open O
, O
vibrant O
metropolis O
again O
. O

edition O

Some O
people O
in O
their O
twenties O
have O
now O
come O
forward O
and O
will O
be O
given O
a O
place O
on O
the O
detailed O
lists O
that O
will O
be O
announced O
later O
. O

The O
senior O
party O
Waardig B-ORG
Ouder I-ORG
Worden I-ORG
( O
WOW B-ORG
) O
is O
participating O
in O
the O
municipal O
, O
district O
and O
provincial O
council O
elections O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
on O
8 O
October O
. O

WOW B-ORG
participates O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC

News B-MISC

Doubts O
about O
this O
briefly O
arose O
when O
a O
local O
councillor O
switched O
to O
the O
VLD B-ORG
and O
his O
colleague O
in O
the O
provincial O
council O
went O
over O
to O
the O
Vlaams B-ORG
Blok I-ORG
. O

Singer O
, O
showman O
and O
presenter O
Marcel B-PER
Vanthilt I-PER
will O
be O
on O
the O
Agalev B-ORG
list O
in O
the O
next O
municipal O
elections O
in O
Antwerp O
. O

page O

" O

He O
gets O
the O
31st O
place O
and O
is O
part O
of O
the O
so O
- O
called O
cordon O
culturel O
on O
the O
green O
list O
. O

Number O
one O
on O
the O
list O
for O
the O
province O
is O
Frans B-PER
Verbergt I-PER
, O
who O
has O
been O
a O
provincial O
councillor O
for O
the O
VLD B-ORG
for O
ten O
years O
. O

The O
list O
for O
the O
municipality O
is O
headed O
by O
André B-PER
Crahay I-PER
, O
a O
former O
bank O
employee O
who O
is O
relatively O
new O
in O
politics O
. O

We O
are O
the O
alternative O
' O
is O
the O
slogan O
with O
which O
WOW B-ORG
is O
heading O
for O
the O
elections O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
. O

Vanthilt B-PER
is O
by O
no O
means O
the O
only O
BV B-MISC
on O
the O
Antwerp B-MISC
Agalev B-MISC
list I-MISC
. O

publication O
date O

Actress O
Jeanine B-PER
Bisschops I-PER
and O
author O
Tom B-PER
Lanoye I-PER
had O
already O
committed O
earlier O
. O

" O
That O
will O
not O
happen O
with O
scaremongers O
and O
pessimists O
" O
, O
says O
the O
party O
, O
" O
we O
are O
more O
for O
green O
, O
the O
color O
of O
hope O
. O

author O

section O

General O

On O
the O
municipal O
level O
, O
the O
party O
wants O
to O
implement O
universal O
suffrage O
and O
in O
the O
district O
of O
Antwerp B-LOC
, O
the O
Greens B-MISC
hope O
to O
become O
the O
largest O
party O
. O

friday O
, O
2 O
june O
2000 O

In O
addition O
, O
Agalev B-MISC
- I-MISC
Antwerp I-MISC
is O
presenting O
a O
list O
of O
Flemish B-MISC
celebrities I-MISC
who O
endorse O
the O
party O
's O
program O
but O
who O
are O
not O
on O
the O
list O
. O

According O
to O
Cahay B-PER
, O
his O
party O
profiles O
itself O
as O
a O
linking O
party O
between O
the O
ages O
, O
which O
means O
that O
young O
people O
also O
get O
a O
chance O
. O

Artists O
for O
Agalev B-ORG

publication O

Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

The O
actresses O
Sarah B-PER
de I-PER
Bosschere I-PER
, O
Veerle B-PER
Dobbelaere I-PER
and O
Patricia B-PER
Goemaere I-PER
, O
writer O
Kristien B-PER
Hemmerechts I-PER
, O
musician O
and O
concert O
organizer O
Paul B-PER
Ambach I-PER
, O
actor O
Pol B-PER
Goossen I-PER
, O
authors O
Paul B-PER
Mennes I-PER
, O
Bart B-PER
Moeyaert I-PER
and O
Jeroen B-PER
Olyslaeghers I-PER
, O
and O
actor O
Carl B-PER
Ridders I-PER
signed O
up O
for O
the O
program O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
" O
We O
'll O
leave O
that O
to O
the O
mediators O
" O
, O
it O
was O
called O
yesterday O
-- O
. O

First O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
have O
to O
leave O
, O
but O
then O
again O
they O
do O
n't O
care O
about O
that O
in O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
. O

" O

Foreign B-MISC

Observers O
do O
say O
that O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
have O
withdrawn O
from O
the O
two O
western O
towns O
of O
Barentu B-LOC
and O
Tessenay B-LOC
, O
which O
were O
captured O
during O
the O
latest O
offensive O
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
wants O
to O
be O
held O
to O
the O
Organization B-ORG
of I-ORG
African I-ORG
Unity I-ORG
's O
four O
- O
point O
plan O
. O

This O
includes O
sending O
international O
observers O
to O
the O
disputed O
border O
zone O
. O

Asmara B-LOC
does O
not O
want O
to O
hear O
of O
a O
truce O
until O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
are O
withdrawn O
. O

" O
We O
are O
quite O
willing O
to O
go O
back O
to O
our O
positions O
of O
May O
6 O
, O
1998 O
( O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
war O
, O
MR B-PER
) O
" O
, O
said O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
minister O
. O

Ethiopia B-LOC
did O
that O
after O
it O
recaptured O
all O
the O
territory O
lost O
after O
the O
Eritrean B-MISC
invasion O
in O
' O
98 O
. O

section O

However O
, O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
now O
wants O
guarantees O
before O
it O
will O
withdraw O
its O
troops O
, O
who O
penetrated O
deeply O
into O
Eritrea B-LOC
. O

Opposing O
views O
on O
when O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
should O
withdraw O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

publication O
date O

Eritrea B-LOC
, O
the O
BBC B-MISC
correspondent I-MISC
in O
Asmara B-LOC
says O
, O
is O
very O
humbled O
by O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
ruling O
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
and O
Ethiopia O
disagree O
over O
truce O

Moreover O
, O
the O
current O
situation O
is O
widely O
interpreted O
as O
one O
in O
which O
Ethiopia B-LOC
can O
dictate O
the O
laws O
because O
of O
its O
recent O
military O
successes O
, O
and O
that O
is O
unacceptable O
to O
Asmara B-LOC
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
called O
the O
whole O
thing O
curious O
. O

But O
according O
to O
the O
BCC B-ORG
, O
the O
Eritrean B-MISC
town O
of O
Zenefe B-LOC
remains O
occupied O
by O
Ethiopian B-MISC
soldiers O
. O

General O

" O
But O
then O
we O
want O
to O
be O
sure O
that O
Eritrea B-LOC
does O
not O
repeat O
the O
madness O
of O
invading O
a O
neighboring O
country O
just O
like O
that O
. O

From O
the O
news O
agencies O

According O
to O
Ethiopia O
, O
the O
arms O
race O
is O
over O
, O
but O
Eritrea B-LOC
does O
not O
share O
that O
view O
. O

And O
that O
is O
exactly O
where O
the O
shoe O
pinches O
. O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

page O

edition O

publication O

What O
guarantees O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
wants O
, O
was O
not O
immediately O
clear O
. O

It O
's O
a O
bit O
like O
clapping O
with O
one O
hand O
: O
Ethiopia O
and O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
who O
have O
been O
at O
war O
for O
two O
years O
, O
are O
sitting O
around O
the O
negotiating O
table O
in O
Algiers B-LOC
. O

Algiers B-LOC

Ouyahia B-PER
called O
the O
statement O
by O
Ethiopian B-MISC
Foreign B-ORG
Minister O
Seyoum B-PER
Mesfin I-PER
that O
the O
war O
was O
over O
" O
an O
encouraging O
thing O
" O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
cartographers O
should O
redraw O
the O
border O
, O
there O
should O
be O
financial O
compensation O
for O
the O
losses O
on O
both O
sides O
and O
finally O
, O
a O
thorough O
investigation O
into O
the O
causes O
of O
the O
conflict O
is O
also O
desirable O
. O

The O
Algerian B-MISC
justice O
minister O
Ahmed B-PER
Ouyahia I-PER
has O
been O
trying O
since O
Tuesday O
to O
mediate O
the O
two O
- O
year O
- O
old O
conflict O
between O
Ethiopia O
and O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
which O
flared O
up O
again O
in O
the O
last O
three O
weeks O
when O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
army O
crossed O
the O
border O
. O

Maarten B-PER
Rabaey I-PER

" O
How O
can O
they O
say O
the O
war O
is O
done O
. O

author O

We O
will O
not O
conclude O
a O
truce O
as O
long O
as O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
soldiers O
are O
up O
to O
not O
much O
more O
than O
100 O
km O
from O
Asmara B-LOC
" O
, O
said O
Eritrean B-MISC
presidential O
advisor O
Yemane B-PER
Gebremeskel I-PER
. O

And O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
will O
not O
do O
that O
until O
international O
guarantees O
are O
in O
place O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Belga B-ORG
/ O
Own O
reporting O

General O

A O
tax O
reform O
should O
also O
end O
discrimination O
between O
married O
and O
cohabiting O
couples O
. O

De B-ORG
Morgen I-ORG

ACW B-MISC
president I-MISC
Theo B-PER
Rombouts I-PER
wants O
the O
upcoming O
tax O
reform O
to O
benefit O
people O
with O
low O
incomes O
in O
particular O
. O

Wages O
have O
fallen O
below O
half O
of O
the O
national O
income O
and O
that O
is O
no O
longer O
acceptable O
. O

page O

publication O
date O

Journal B-MISC

Part O
should O
definitely O
go O
to O
social O
security O
and O
part O
should O
be O
saved O
. O

In O
his O
speech O
in O
Mechelen B-LOC
, O
Cortebeeck B-PER
stated O
that O
in O
addition O
to O
social O
benefits O
, O
wages O
have O
fallen O
behind O
. O

During O
the O
next O
intersectoral O
negotiations O
, O
the O
Christian O
trade O
union O
will O
therefore O
advocate O
gradual O
wage O
increases O
as O
the O
best O
and O
most O
proven O
means O
of O
distributing O
the O
fruits O
of O
growth O
. O

Financial O
participation O
can O
not O
close O
the O
wage O
gap O
, O
Cortebeeck B-PER
believes O
. O

The O
Christian O
union O
is O
in O
favor O
of O
a O
gradual O
increase O
in O
wages O
and O
social O
benefits O
, O
stated O
ACV B-MISC
president I-MISC
Luc B-PER
Cortebeeck I-PER
in O
his O
Rerum B-MISC
Novarum I-MISC
speech I-MISC
. O

Mechelen B-LOC
/ O
Brussels B-LOC

This O
should O
be O
accompanied O
by O
an O
increase O
in O
the O
net O
income O
of O
low O
- O
income O
single O
earners O
and O
families O
with O
dependent O
children O
. O

author O

" O
We O
have O
not O
surrendered O
for O
years O
to O
give O
the O
money O
for O
pensions O
and O
health O
care O
now O
in O
the O
hands O
of O
the O
private O
sector O
" O
, O
said O
the O
ACV B-MISC
president I-MISC
. O

He O
vowed O
the O
government O
not O
to O
simply O
enrich O
the O
private O
companies O
in O
the O
insurance O
sector O
by O
entrusting O
them O
with O
the O
fruits O
of O
the O
reduction O
of O
the O
national O
debt O
. O

section O

According O
to O
Cortebeeck B-PER
, O
not O
all O
new O
government O
revenue O
should O
be O
reserved O
for O
the O
aging O
population O
. O

With O
profit O
participation O
, O
a O
part O
of O
employee O
income O
is O
made O
dependent O
on O
too O
many O
arbitrary O
decisions O
. O

Therefore O
, O
the O
ACW B-ORG
defends O
an O
increase O
in O
deductible O
professional O
expenses O
for O
wage O
and O
salary O
earners O
and O
a O
higher O
first O
untaxed O
bracket O
of O
earned O
income O
. O

friday O
, O
2 O
june O
2000 O

Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

In O
his O
speech O
in O
Wemmel O
, O
ACW B-MISC
president I-MISC
Theo B-PER
Rombouts I-PER
also O
argued O
in O
favor O
of O
a O
tax O
reduction O
that O
should O
be O
targeted O
as O
a O
matter O
of O
priority O
at O
earned O
incomes O
and O
especially O
at O
the O
longer O
incomes O
. O

The O
available O
resources O
would O
be O
better O
used O
to O
strengthen O
the O
foundations O
of O
society O
, O
such O
as O
education O
and O
health O
care O
, O
public O
transport O
and O
roads O
, O
food O
safety O
, O
etc O
. O
Improvement O
for O
low O
incomes O
can O
only O
come O
through O
an O
increase O
of O
the O
subsistence O
minimum O
, O
guaranteed O
income O
and O
social O
benefits O
. O

Profit O
- O
sharing O
presupposes O
power O
- O
sharing O
, O
but O
we O
are O
not O
being O
given O
it O
, O
said O
Cortebeeck B-PER
, O
because O
the O
employers O
do O
not O
want O
to O
know O
about O
a O
previously O
negotiated O
collective O
bargaining O
agreement O
on O
the O
subject O
. O

ACV B-ORG
prefers O
wage O
increase O
to O
profit O
sharing O

The O
trade O
union O
leader O
stated O
that O
the O
active O
welfare O
state O
also O
has O
its O
drawbacks O
. O

Finally O
, O
Rombouts B-PER
asked O
for O
tax O
incentives O
for O
more O
environmentally O
friendly O
living O
. O

The O
self O
- O
employed O
have O
already O
been O
served O
with O
1.5 O
billion O
francs O
, O
but O
the O
social O
benefit O
recipients O
, O
such O
as O
the O
invalids O
, O
the O
disabled O
, O
and O
the O
unemployed O
in O
financial O
need O
, O
receive O
nothing O
and O
are O
increasingly O
being O
left O
behind O
. O

Rerum B-MISC
Novarum I-MISC
speeches I-MISC
point O
out O
dark O
side O
of O
active O
welfare O
state O

edition O

publication O

Catching O
up O
on O
wages O
and O
benefits O
is O
preferable O
, O
according O
to O
the O
union O
leader O
, O
to O
letting O
workers O
share O
in O
their O
company O
's O
profits O
. O

Cortebeeck B-PER
sees O
a O
tax O
reform O
as O
desirable O
, O
but O
is O
opposed O
to O
a O
general O
tax O
cut O
. O

In O
any O
case O
, O
that O
formula O
calls O
for O
co O
- O
determination O
of O
profits O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Sunday O
during O
the O
day O
a O
back O
of O
high O
pressure O
is O
building O
from O
the O
southwest O
, O
gradually O
stabilizing O
the O
atmosphere O
. O

publication O
date O

A O
few O
of O
these O
could O
develop O
into O
a O
loose O
shower O
very O
locally O
in O
the O
west O
by O
evening O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

section O

As O
a O
third O
factor O
there O
is O
a O
cold O
front O
approaching O
from O
the O
west O
. O

Furthermore O
, O
the O
thermal O
vore O
will O
be O
in O
our O
area O
. O

From O
Sunday O
onwards O
it O
will O
be O
less O
warm O
. O

Eddy B-PER
De I-PER
Mey I-PER

Sunny O
this O
morning O
. O

page O

friday O
, O
2 O
june O
2000 O

Sunny O
this O
morning O
. O

The O
encroachment O
of O
colder O
air O
makes O
for O
strong O
upward O
movements O
during O
the O
day O
. O

Summery O
warm O
. O

Tomorrow O
increasing O
chance O
of O
rain O
and O
thunderstorms O
, O
followed O
by O
cooling O
. O

The O
month O
of O
May O
was O
warmer O
than O
normal O
. O

The O
wind O
is O
generally O
weak O
and O
blowing O
mainly O
from O
directions O
between O
south O
and O
southwest O
. O

This O
afternoon O
temperatures O
of O
25 O
degrees O
and O
more O
are O
achievable O
. O

edition O

Tomorrow O
thunderstorms O

So O
the O
sun O
is O
pronounced O
master O
of O
the O
situation O
and O
the O
mercury O
goes O
on O
an O
adventure O
. O

There O
will O
be O
virtually O
no O
clouds O
. O

In O
many O
places O
the O
mercury O
before O
midnight O
will O
not O
or O
barely O
below O
20 O
degrees O
. O

After O
the O
weekend O
the O
weather O
does O
not O
look O
bad O
but O
also O
not O
quite O
steady O
. O

There O
were O
86 O
liters O
of O
precipitation O
in O
20 O
days O
against O
normal O
62 O
liters O
in O
15 O
days O
. O

19.1 O
( O
norm O
17.2 O
) O
. O

A O
more O
or O
less O
stationary O
high O
above O
Central B-LOC
and O
Eastern B-LOC
Europe I-LOC
is O
flanked O
today O
by O
a O
southerly O
flow O
that O
brings O
in O
warm O
and O
initially O
stable O
air O
from O
France B-LOC
. O

The O
current O
that O
has O
an O
anticyclonic O
tint O
today O
will O
become O
cyclonic O
tomorrow O
. O

Min O
. O
11.3 O
( O
norm O
8.3 O
) O
. O

Max B-PER
. O

General O

A O
single O
shower O
may O
carry O
hail O
and O
locally O
discharge O
so O
much O
water O
that O
nuisance O
occurs O
. O

During O
the O
night O
from O
Saturday O
to O
Sunday O
the O
cold O
front O
passes O
through O
the O
country O
. O

This O
afternoon O
also O
stack O
clouds O
. O

Later O
also O
stack O
clouds O
and O
tonight O
a O
slight O
chance O
of O
a O
shower O
. O

The O
sun O
shone O
little O
( O
less O
than O
159 O
hours O
) O
against O
normal O
199 O
hours O
. O

publication O

Tonight O
it O
will O
stay O
warm O
for O
a O
long O
time O
and O
it O
is O
ideal O
for O
gardening O
or O
terraces O
. O

As O
a O
consequence O
, O
the O
chance O
of O
thunderstorms O
will O
increase O
as O
the O
afternoon O
and O
evening O
progresses O
. O

author O

As O
a O
thermal O
vore O
approaches O
, O
now O
still O
over O
western O
France B-LOC
, O
the O
atmosphere O
will O
become O
somewhat O
unstable O
in O
the O
afternoon O
, O
causing O
a O
number O
of O
bunk O
clouds O
to O
form O
. O

Meanwhile B-MISC

Tomorrow O
increasing O
chance O
of O
rain O
and O
thunderstorms O
, O
followed O
by O
cooling O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Is O
this O
health O
standard O
often O
exceeded O
? O

More O
interesting O
is O
the O
new O
Dutch B-MISC
initiative O
of O
toll O
gates O
and O
road O
pricing O
around O
major O
Dutch B-MISC
cities O
. O

Two O
Brussels B-MISC
- I-MISC
based I-MISC
environmental O
movements O
, O
Bral B-ORG
and O
Inter B-ORG
- I-ORG
Environnement I-ORG
... O

Because O
studies O
show O
that O
car O
traffic O
is O
responsible O
for O
more O
than O
70 O
percent O
of O
the O
high O
ozone O
concentrations O
. O

The O
countries O
surrounding O
us O
have O
been O
taking O
such O
measures O
for O
some O
time O
, O
but O
Belgium B-LOC
is O
lagging O
behind O
. O

page O

It O
is O
not O
that O
different O
from O
the O
old O
ozone O
plan O
announced O
in O
1996 O
. O

French B-MISC
cities O
such O
as O
Paris B-LOC
on O
the O
other O
hand O
work O
with O
alternating O
driving O
bans O
, O
where O
even O
or O
odd O
license O
plates O
are O
not O
allowed O
to O
drive O
during O
ozone O
peaks O
. O

author O

" O
A O
number O
of O
German B-MISC
states O
are O
already O
introducing O
temporary O
speed O
limits O
. O

That O
is O
a O
pity O
. O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

For O
Brussels B-LOC
, O
one O
could O
combine O
those O
measures O
with O
the O
rapid O
development O
of O
a O
real O
Brussels B-MISC
suburban O
network O
with O
large O
interchange O
parking O
lots O
. O

" O
Last O
year O
it O
was O
exceeded O
in O
Brussels B-LOC
on O
27 O
days O
. O

If O
you O
are O
found O
to O
be O
right O
, O
what O
will O
you O
do O
with O
the O
money O
if O
it O
is O
exceeded O
? O

During O
days O
with O
high O
ozone O
peaks O
, O
the O
population O
groups O
at O
risk O
are O
asked O
to O
stay O
indoors O
until O
the O
' O
danger O
' O
has O
passed O
. O

publication O

What O
measures O
are O
in O
place O
abroad O
? O

This O
means O
that O
the O
elderly O
, O
children O
or O
people O
with O
asthma O
are O
always O
at O
serious O
risk O
of O
health O
problems O
. O

Opinion B-MISC

" O

That O
is O
a O
considerable O
amount O
, O
just O
to O
force O
the O
policy O
to O
take O
structural O
measures O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
. O

If O
we O
do O
receive O
money O
, O
we O
will O
pay O
it O
into O
a O
fund O
with O
which O
we O
can O
help O
finance O
, O
for O
example O
, O
the O
Brussels B-MISC
suburban O
network O
. O

However O
, O
it O
was O
announced O
that O
the O
maximum O
speed O
would O
be O
limited O
. O

There O
they O
want O
to O
make O
the O
rates O
high O
enough O
to O
keep O
a O
large O
number O
of O
cars O
off O
the O
road O
. O

edition O

" O

' O
The O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
disappoints O
us O
deeply O
' O

De B-ORG
Morgen I-ORG

This O
also O
clashes O
with O
the O
constitutional O
article O
23 O
that O
guarantees O
everyone O
' O
human O
dignity O
' O
. O

Given O
the O
number O
of O
exceedances O
in O
1999 O
, O
you O
guys O
can O
get O
rich O
quick O
. O

Another O
study O
has O
shown O
that O
during O
the O
1994 O
heat O
wave O
1,200 O
people O
died O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
as O
a O
result O
of O
the O
high O
ozone O
concentrations O
during O
that O
period O
. O

The O
federal O
government O
has O
just O
announced O
its O
ozone O
plan O
. O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

Ceustermans B-PER
: O
" O
Each O
time O
the O
so O
- O
called O
European B-MISC
health O
standard O
of O
120 O
micrograms O
of O
ozone O
per O
cubic O
meter O
is O
exceeded O
in O
Brussels B-LOC
for O
at O
least O
eight O
hours O
, O
we O
ask O
for O
compensation O
of O
50 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
. O

" O

" O
The O
piece O
of O
work O
disappoints O
us O
. O

General O

" O

" O

" O
It O
is O
not O
about O
the O
money O
, O
let O
that O
be O
clear O
. O

The O
case O
will O
be O
heard O
on O
June O
9 O
before O
the O
court O
of O
first O
instance O
in O
summary O
proceedings O
. O

Satisfied O
with O
the O
work O
of O
the O
two O
green O
ministers O
Magda B-PER
Aelvoet I-PER
and O
Isabelle B-PER
Durant I-PER
? O

The O
emphasis O
is O
on O
information O
and O
awareness O
, O
while O
there O
are O
few O
measures O
to O
limit O
car O
traffic O
during O
the O
summer O
months O
. O

It O
is O
unacceptable O
that O
with O
this O
knowledge O
the O
government O
does O
not O
want O
to O
intervene O
or O
hardly O
. O

The O
green O
ministers O
have O
not O
got O
that O
through O
( O
yet O
) O
. O

section O

What O
exactly O
is O
your O
demand O
? O

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

publication O
date O

-DOCSTART- O
edition O

page O

In O
total O
, O
he O
said O
he O
made O
about O
fifteen O
phone O
calls O
, O
including O
to O
the O
cabinets O
and O
departments O
of O
Transportation B-ORG
, O
Economics B-ORG
and O
Finance B-ORG
. O

My O
assignment O
was O
limited O
to O
identifying O
any O
political O
problems O
. O

" O
According O
to O
Gantman B-PER
, O
a O
change O
in O
the O
corporate O
tax O
law O
on O
the O
tax O
regime O
of O
capital O
gains O
came O
about O
abnormally O
slowly O
" O
, O
Larmuseau B-PER
told O
. O

Larmuseau B-PER
replied O
that O
he O
did O
not O
find O
Gantman B-PER
's O
question O
unjustified O
and O
credible O
. O

publication O

" O
It O
's O
been O
so O
long O
, O
I O
remember O
almost O
nothing O
about O
that O
. O

Hendrik B-PER
Larmuseau I-PER
, O
former O
advisor O
to O
the O
socio O
- O
economic O
cabinet O
of O
Prime O
Minister O
Jean O
- O
Luc B-PER
Dehaene I-PER
( O
CVP B-ORG
) O
, O
stated O
Wednesday O
before O
the O
inquiry O
committee O
on O
shipping O
credits O
that O
the O
Antwerp B-MISC
lawyer O
André B-PER
Gantman I-PER
was O
also O
active O
in O
the O
prime O
minister O
's O
cabinet O
as O
a O
lobbyist O
for O
shipowner O
Rosenfeld B-PER
. O

section O

According O
to O
him O
, O
he O
did O
not O
get O
a O
hearing O
at O
the O
Cabinet O
of O
Finance B-ORG
. O

" O

" O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

" O

" O

General O

Larmuseau B-PER
had O
two O
other O
meetings O
with O
Gantman B-PER
in O
the O
spring O
of O
1994 O
and O
was O
able O
to O
inform O
the O
lawyer O
, O
as O
a O
result O
of O
his O
investigation O
, O
that O
the O
change O
in O
the O
law O
was O
following O
normal O
procedures O
. O

" O
After O
all O
, O
at O
a O
cabinet O
like O
this O
, O
you O
are O
constantly O
being O
accosted O
by O
all O
kinds O
of O
people O
who O
need O
something O
. O

Gantman B-PER
lobbied O
Prime O
Minister O
Dehaene B-PER

Karel B-PER
De I-PER
Gucht I-PER
: O
" O
Did O
you O
do O
this O
for O
every O
stranger O
? O
" O

" O
He O
complained O
about O
this O
. O

" O
Did O
you O
do O
this O
for O
any O
unknown O
person O
? O
" O
, O
he O
asked O
the O
witness O
. O

But O
about O
that O
work O
group O
Larmuseau B-PER
could O
hardly O
remember O
anything O
. O

According O
to O
Larmuseau B-PER
, O
Gantman B-PER
appeared O
in O
his O
office O
for O
the O
first O
time O
in O
April O
1994 O
, O
without O
having O
made O
an O
appointment O
by O
phone O
beforehand O
. O

Brussels B-LOC

" O
It O
seemed O
an O
important O
problem O
, O
I O
judged O
that O
it O
was O
my O
duty O
to O
check O
it O
. O

publication O
date O

In O
negotiations O
on O
the O
tax O
problem O
I O
did O
not O
participate O
. O

He O
also O
personally O
informed O
Prime O
Minister O
Dehaene B-PER
of O
the O
problem O
raised O
by O
Gantman B-PER
. O

author O

The O
Prime O
Minister O
's O
cabinet O
advisor O
immediately O
shot O
into O
action O
. O

" O
At O
most O
I O
have O
passively O
witnessed O
one O
or O
two O
meetings O
" O
, O
he O
said O
. O

Then O
Finance B-ORG
Minister O
Philippe B-PER
Maystadt I-PER
( O
PSC B-ORG
) O
blocked O
the O
file O
, O
so O
Gantman B-PER
seemed O
to O
insinuate O
. O

Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

Commissioner O
Karel B-PER
De I-PER
Gucht I-PER
( O
VLD B-ORG
) O
marveled O
at O
so O
much O
zeal O
. O

( O
GT B-PER
) O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

News B-MISC

Own O
reporting O

In O
the O
same O
period O
, O
Larmuseau B-PER
was O
also O
a O
member O
of O
the O
inter O
- O
cabinet O
group O
around O
ABC B-ORG
Containerline I-ORG
, O
which O
was O
set O
up O
specifically O
to O
solve O
the O
tax O
problems O
that O
surfaced O
in O
the O
context O
of O
the O
pre O
- O
fronted O
takeover O
of O
the O
shipping O
company O
by O
American B-MISC
con O
man O
Gary B-PER
Blonder I-PER
. O

-DOCSTART- O
17 O

The O
International B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
needs O
to O
listen O
more O
to O
the O
people O
and O
impose O
its O
will O
less O
on O
countries O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
often O
tends O
to O
admonish O
countries O
, O
but O
one O
of O
the O
lessons O
of O
the O
financial O
crises O
in O
Asia B-LOC
is O
that O
it O
needs O
to O
listen O
more O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
itself O
must O
be O
the O
driving O
force O
for O
such O
changes O
. O

Köhler B-PER
went O
on O
to O
say O
that O
he O
would O
be O
happy O
to O
discuss O
an O
Asian B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
, O
a O
plan O
about O
which O
the O
major O
industrialized O
countries O
and O
those O
in O
charge O
at O
the O
IMF B-ORG
have O
been O
bickering O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

This O
led O
to O
calls O
within O
the O
Fund O
for O
changes O
in O
policy O
. O

People B-MISC

The O
Prime O
Minister O
of O
Thailand B-LOC
, O
Chuan B-PER
Leekpai I-PER
, O
asked O
Köhler B-PER
to O
learn O
from O
" O
what O
happened O
in O
our O
country O
" O
. O

In O
Europe B-LOC
there O
is O
a O
monetary O
union O
and O
there O
is O
nothing O
against O
more O
such O
unions O
, O
the O
IMF B-MISC
chief I-MISC
said O
. O

John B-PER
Vandaele I-PER

publication O

page O

He O
called O
on O
the O
Executive O
Board O
to O
draw O
up O
a O
clear O
vision O
of O
the O
future O
role O
of O
the O
IMF B-ORG
in O
the O
coming O
months O
. O

edition O

In O
Thailand B-LOC
, O
in O
July O
1997 O
, O
the O
financial O
crisis O
began O
that O
subsequently O
swept O
a O
number O
of O
Asian B-MISC
countries O
along O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

According O
to O
the O
Thai B-MISC
Prime O
Minister O
, O
it O
is O
much O
more O
expensive O
to O
deal O
with O
the O
consequences O
of O
a O
crisis O
than O
to O
prevent O
one O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
has O
been O
widely O
criticized O
for O
not O
seeing O
the O
problems O
in O
Asia B-LOC
coming O
in O
time O
. O

publication O
date O

Horst B-PER
Köhler I-PER

This O
is O
what O
Horst B-PER
Köhler I-PER
, O
the O
IMF B-ORG
's O
top O
executive O
appointed O
in O
May O
, O
said O
yesterday O
in O
Bangkok B-LOC
, O
from O
where O
he O
is O
making O
a O
tour O
of O
Asia B-LOC
. O

It O
is O
up O
to O
the O
Asian B-MISC
countries O
themselves O
to O
decide O
on O
their O
own O
monetary O
fund O
, O
said O
Köhler B-PER
. O

The O
Board O
should O
take O
the O
lead O
in O
this O
and O
not O
be O
dictated O
by O
, O
for O
example O
, O
the O
U.S. B-MISC
Congress B-ORG
, O
according O
to O
Köhler B-PER
. O

Director O
IMF B-ORG

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

More O
listening O

section O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Morning I-MISC

General O

AFP B-ORG

author O

-DOCSTART- O
publication O
date O

But O
no O
one O
who O
can O
or O
will O
intervene O
. O

publication O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

page O

Koekelberg B-LOC
, O
Ganshoren B-LOC
, O
Jette B-LOC
and O
Sint B-LOC
- I-LOC
Agatha I-LOC
- O
Berchem O
, O
each O
of O
which O
has O
a O
piece O
of O
the O
infamous O
basilica O
on O
its O
territory O
, O
will O
not O
be O
able O
to O
release O
any O
additional O
money O
in O
the O
next O
few O
years O
for O
the O
necessary O
renovation O
and O
stabilization O
works O
. O

However O
, O
it O
is O
not O
clear O
which O
ministry O
or O
department O
that O
should O
be O
. O

Simonet B-PER
has O
communicated O
the O
concerns O
to O
Minister O
of O
the O
Interior B-ORG
Antoine B-PER
Duquesne I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
. O

He O
promised O
Simonet B-PER
that O
the O
basilica O
problem O
would O
be O
examined O
at O
the O
federal O
level O
. O

The O
four O
municipalities O
of O
Brussels B-MISC
that O
are O
now O
paying O
for O
the O
maintenance O
of O
the O
Basilica B-LOC
of I-LOC
Koekelberg I-LOC
are O
making O
yet O
another O
cry O
for O
help O
. O

The O
Basilica O
is O
in O
danger O
of O
becoming O
a O
second O
Atomium B-LOC
. O

The O
four O
mayors O
ask O
the O
federal O
government O
to O
finally O
come O
up O
with O
some O
money O
for O
the O
ailing O
' O
national O
' O
monument O
. O

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

General O

Koekelberg B-LOC
Basilica I-LOC
threatens O
to O
become O
a O
second O
Atomium B-LOC

The B-MISC
Life I-MISC

section O

The O
four O
mayors O
discussed O
their O
resentment O
with O
Brussels B-MISC
Minister O
- O
President O
Jacques B-PER
Simonet I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
during O
his O
tour O
of O
the O
nineteen O
municipalities O
of B-MISC
Brussels I-MISC
. O

edition O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

The O
basilica O
, O
as O
a O
national O
sanctuary O
, O
does O
not O
appear O
to O
belong O
to O
the O
Public B-MISC
Buildings I-MISC
Administration I-MISC
, O
nor O
can O
the O
Ministry O
of O
Justice B-ORG
( O
which O
funds O
recognized O
religions O
) O
intervene O
because O
the O
basilica O
is O
not O
officially O
a O
church O
or O
cathedral O
. O

For O
years O
cracks O
have O
been O
visible O
and O
debris O
occasionally O
comes O
down O
. O

author O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

-DOCSTART- O
' O

" O
The O
system O
was O
discontinued O
in O
1990 O
because O
its O
administration O
was O
quite O
costly O
and O
because O
it O
was O
becoming O
increasingly O
difficult O
to O
distinguish O
between O
speculative O
and O
real O
transactions O
. O

publication O
date O

publication O

I O
am O
not O
a O
priori O
against O
a O
modest O
levy O
provided O
it O
is O
done O
on O
a O
global O
level O
. O

" O

He O
sees O
more O
in O
targeted O
actions O
: O
national O
states O
taking O
measures O
against O
short O
- O
term O
money O
flows O
. O

page O

They O
believe O
that O
a O
global O
levy O
on O
the O
exchange O
of O
currencies O
would O
not O
only O
prevent O
socially O
disruptive O
financial O
crises O
but O
also O
raise O
money O
to O
contribute O
to O
development O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
the O
Finance B-ORG
Committee O
of O
the O
Senate B-ORG
wants O
to O
gain O
a O
better O
understanding O
of O
the O
feasibility O
and O
desirability O
of O
the O
tax O
through O
hearings O
with O
experts O
and O
stakeholders O
. O

Hearing O

De B-ORG
Morgen I-ORG

He O
doubts O
, O
however O
, O
whether O
the O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
is O
the O
best O
means O
of O
achieving O
this O
. O

section O

Internationally O
, O
an O
entire O
movement O
grew O
around O
the O
tax O
named O
after O
the O
American B-MISC
economist O
James B-PER
Tobin I-PER
. O

Because O
quite O
a O
few O
Belgian B-MISC
representatives O
of O
the O
people O
see O
something O
in O
the O
idea O
, O
Finance B-ORG
Minister O
Didier B-PER
Reynders I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
decided O
to O
have O
the O
feasibility O
of O
the O
idea O
studied O
. O

General O

Governor O
Quaden B-PER
not O
a O
priori O
against O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC

author O

Banking O
sector O
calls O
levy O
on O
speculative O
profits O
' O
undemocratic O
and O
inefficient O
' O

Quaden B-PER
, O
as O
a O
central O
banker O
, O
could O
perfectly O
identify O
with O
the O
two O
objectives O
of O
the O
tax O
: O
money O
stability O
and O
contributing O
to O
development O
. O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

1 O

John B-PER
Vandaele I-PER

Finance B-ORG
Committee I-ORG

This O
levy O
is O
the O
main O
demand O
of O
the O
Flemish B-ORG
network I-ORG
against I-ORG
financial I-ORG
speculation I-ORG
, O
which O
consists O
of O
the O
two O
large O
trade O
unions O
and O
some O
NGOs O
. O

De B-MISC
Financiële I-MISC
Morgen I-MISC

Personally O
, O
I O
do O
not O
see O
why O
you O
should O
not O
tax O
all O
exchange O
transactions O
. O

JVD B-PER

The O
words O
come O
from O
Governor O
Guy B-PER
Quaden I-PER
of O
the O
National B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
, O
and O
they O
were O
uttered O
Wednesday O
during O
the O
first O
hearing O
in O
the O
Senate B-ORG
on O
the O
so O
- O
called O
Tobin B-MISC
levy I-MISC
. O

Because O
you O
can O
no O
longer O
make O
that O
distinction O
, O
so O
you O
have O
to O
tax O
all O
transactions O
as O
Tobin B-PER
proposes O
. O

Director O
Georges B-PER
Martin I-PER
called O
the O
tax O
inefficient O
, O
undemocratic O
and O
unfair O
because O
it O
does O
not O
distinguish O
between O
speculative O
and O
non O
- O
speculative O
capital O
movements O
. O

The O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
could O
count O
on O
a O
lot O
less O
sympathy O
from O
the O
Belgian B-ORG
Bankers I-ORG
Association I-ORG
. O

edition O

Quaden B-PER
pointed O
out O
that O
with O
the O
so O
- O
called O
dual O
exchange O
market O
, O
Belgium B-LOC
had O
the O
equivalent O
of O
a O
very O
sophisticated O
Tobin B-MISC
levy I-MISC
until O
1990 O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Brussels B-LOC

" O

President O
Francis B-PER
Vermeiren I-PER
of O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
( O
also O
VLD B-MISC
mayor I-MISC
of O
Zaventem B-LOC
) O
stressed O
that O
the O
participation O
has O
already O
brought O
a O
lot O
to O
the O
municipalities O
, O
partly O
due O
to O
the O
two O
rounds O
of O
privatization O
in O
recent O
years O
. O

publication O
date O

Alderman O
of O
Finance B-ORG
Hugo B-PER
Schiltz I-PER
( O
VU B-ORG
) O
had O
sent O
a O
letter O
to O
all O
his O
colleagues O
a O
few O
days O
before O
the O
general O
assembly O
in O
which O
he O
explained O
his O
vision O
. O

Yet O
Antwerp B-LOC
's O
reservations O
received O
little O
response O
. O

The O
municipalities O
and O
provinces O
have O
placed O
their O
participation O
in O
Gemeentelijke B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
. O

De B-ORG
Morgen I-ORG

Antwerp B-LOC
voted O
on O
Wednesday O
against O
the O
measures O
giving O
the O
municipalities O
more O
freedom O
in O
managing O
their O
Dexia B-MISC
stake I-MISC
. O

A O
number O
of O
large O
cities O
would O
like O
to O
be O
able O
to O
decide O
themselves O
on O
the O
future O
of O
their O
Dexia B-MISC
shares I-MISC
. O

They O
would O
function O
as O
forums O
in O
which O
the O
municipalities O
could O
discuss O
a O
number O
of O
financial O
policy O
choices O
. O

At O
the O
General O
Meeting O
it O
was O
agreed O
to O
set O
up O
a O
series O
of O
working O
groups O
. O

Under O
certain O
conditions O
, O
the O
shares O
can O
also O
be O
sold O
on O
the O
stock O
exchange O
. O

Vermeiren B-PER
has O
in O
mind O
the O
pension O
dossier O
, O
the O
liberalization O
of O
electricity O
traffic O
and O
the O
Geographic B-MISC
Information I-MISC
System I-MISC
( O
GIS B-MISC
) O
. O

friday O
, O
2 O
june O
2000 O

Antwerp B-LOC
was O
one O
of O
the O
few O
people O
to O
vote O
against O
when O
the O
final O
proposal O
was O
put O
to O
the O
vote O
. O

This O
was O
made O
possible O
to O
a O
limited O
extent O
by O
the O
decision O
taken O
on O
Wednesday O
to O
certify O
the O
shares O
. O

General O

That O
stake O
is O
now O
worth O
more O
than O
6 O
billion O
. O

Mayor O
Bob B-PER
Van I-PER
Hooland I-PER
( O
VU B-ORG
) O
of O
Sint B-LOC
- I-LOC
Martens I-LOC
- O
Latem O
, O
who O
also O
intervened O
at O
the O
general O
meeting O
, O
also O
thinks O
so O
. O

Vermeiren B-PER
thinks O
that O
the O
tradability O
of O
the O
securities O
between O
the O
municipalities O
( O
the O
' O
internal O
market O
' O
) O
can O
already O
partly O
meet O
the O
wishes O
of O
the O
big O
cities O
. O

The O
city O
, O
which O
is O
struggling O
with O
a O
large O
debt O
, O
would O
rather O
have O
more O
freedom O
to O
cash O
in O
on O
the O
Dexia B-MISC
stake I-MISC
. O

Not O
only O
to O
sell O
, O
but O
also O
to O
buy O
. O

" O

That O
means O
diluting O
the O
stake O
in O
Dexia B-ORG
to O
about O
18.5 O
percent O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
believes O
that O
these O
conditions O
are O
too O
strict O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
breaks O
through O
Dexia B-MISC
unity I-MISC

That O
could O
be O
a O
way O
to O
increase O
the O
return O
on O
urban O
reserves O
. O

Thus O
Antwerp B-LOC
has O
already O
been O
able O
to O
collect O
about O
4.5 O
billion O
and O
a O
municipality O
like O
Schaarbeek B-LOC
2.3 O
billion O
. O

The O
Belgian B-MISC
municipalities O
and O
provinces O
had O
to O
make O
an O
important O
decision O
on O
Wednesday O
about O
their O
stake O
in O
the O
banking O
group O
Dexia B-ORG
. O

" O
I O
have O
the O
impression O
that O
many O
mayors O
do O
feel O
for O
it O
. O

The O
proposal O
was O
finally O
adopted O
with O
about O
87 O
percent O
of O
the O
votes O
. O

He O
wants O
to O
professionalize O
the O
board O
of O
directors O
, O
which O
is O
now O
politically O
composed O
. O

author O

We O
should O
not O
try O
to O
cash O
in O
on O
participations O
as O
quickly O
as O
possible O
. O

publication O

Van B-PER
Hooland I-PER
does O
think O
that O
the O
functioning O
of O
the O
municipal O
holding O
company O
can O
be O
improved O
. O

That O
operation O
separates O
the O
dividend O
right O
from O
the O
voting O
right O
, O
making O
it O
possible O
for O
the O
municipalities O
to O
trade O
part O
of O
their O
securities O
among O
themselves O
. O

Which O
totals O
80 O
billion O
francs O
. O

Ruben B-PER
Mooijman I-PER

page O

Schiltz B-PER
: O
' O
Role O
of O
municipalities O
has O
changed O
' O

Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
will O
underwrite O
for O
4 O
billion O
francs O
the O
current O
capital O
increase O
of O
Dexia B-ORG
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Morning I-MISC

The O
local O
governments O
, O
formerly O
majority O
shareholder O
of O
Gemeentekrediet B-ORG
, O
own O
about O
22 O
percent O
of O
the O
Dexia B-MISC
group I-MISC
, O
into O
which O
Gemeentekrediet B-ORG
has O
been O
absorbed O
. O

17 O

They O
want O
to O
sell O
all O
or O
part O
of O
their O
shares O
. O

section O

edition O

" O
The O
role O
of O
the O
municipalities O
has O
changed O
. O

The O
converging O
interests O
of O
the O
group O
and O
those O
of O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
are O
no O
longer O
clear O
and O
are O
becoming O
increasingly O
unclear O
" O
, O
Schiltz B-PER
said O
at O
the O
general O
meeting O
. O

" O
I O
feel O
called O
to O
support O
the O
holding O
company O
. O

Ruben B-PER
Mooijman I-PER

The O
largest O
Flemish B-MISC
city O
found O
the O
proposals O
do O
not O
go O
far O
enough O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
According O
to O
only O
local O
police O
officers O
, O
the O
motive O
for O
the O
hostage O
taking O
is O
obvious O
. O

The O
police O
forces O
therefore O
tried O
to O
force O
a O
breakthrough O
through O
negotiation O
. O

author O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

edition O

But O
yesterday O
also O
circulated O
the O
unconfirmed O
rumor O
that O
he O
used O
to O
beat O
his O
wife O
and O
children O
. O

The O
man O
did O
admit O
that O
he O
" O
has O
some O
problems O
" O
and O
consulted O
a O
psychiatrist O
. O

The O
judge O
also O
denied O
him O
visitation O
rights O
. O

There O
was O
confusion O
about O
his O
origins O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

The O
chance O
that O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
would O
actually O
use O
violence O
was O
considered O
very O
small O
. O

Hostage O
taker O
could O
n't O
handle O
divorce O

The O
children O
who O
were O
released O
bit O
by O
bit O
told O
the O
psychologists O
that O
the O
man O
was O
nice O
to O
them O
and O
talked O
about O
his O
own O
children O
all O
the O
time O
. O

section O

Wasserbillig B-LOC

That O
reassured O
him O
. O

From O
our O
reporter O
on O
the O
spot O

page O

publication O

A O
lot O
of O
stories O
circulated O
about O
hostage O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
yesterday O
. O

He O
was O
quite O
upset O
that O
the O
police O
described O
him O
as O
mentally O
ill O
. O

André B-PER
Colas I-PER
, O
the O
spokesman O
for O
the O
Wasserbillig O
police O
, O
was O
only O
able O
to O
confirm O
that O
the O
man O
was O
39 O
years O
old O
, O
of O
Tunisian B-MISC
origin O
and O
a O
Luxembourg B-MISC
national O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

publication O
date O

Thus O
it O
was O
first O
stated O
that O
it O
was O
an O
Algerian B-MISC
who O
was O
psychologically O
disturbed O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

General O

Crazy O
he O
was O
according O
to O
his O
own O
statement O
not O
at O
all O
, O
only O
somewhat O
' O
embittered O
' O
. O

Four O
years O
ago O
his O
wife O
left O
him O
and O
the O
judge O
entrusted O
his O
two O
children O
, O
a O
girl O
of O
eleven O
and O
a O
boy O
of O
five O
, O
to O
the O
mother O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Until O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
himself O
called O
the O
local O
radio O
station O
on O
Wednesday O
night O
to O
say O
that O
he O
is O
not O
from O
Algeria B-LOC
but O
from O
Tunisia B-LOC
and O
has O
also O
had O
Luxembourg B-MISC
nationality O
since O
1982 O
. O

The O
hostage O
taker O
is O
described O
as O
a O
sweet O
but O
very O
impulsive O
man O
. O

( O
CG B-PER
) O

Who O
tried O
all O
the O
time O
Wednesday O
and O
Thursday O
to O
talk O
to O
him O
, O
supported O
in O
this O
by O
a O
psychologist O
of O
the O
police O
. O

The O
children O
were O
both O
reportedly O
in O
the O
day O
care O
center O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
" O

' O
Women O
of O
all O
cities O
: O
conquer O
the O
streets O
during O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
' O

Or O
other O
special O
events O
for O
women O
. O

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

When O
I O
'm O
back O
in O
the O
country O
, O
hopefully O
the O
whole O
fuss O
will O
be O
over O
. O

" O
We O
will O
also O
invite O
them O
to O
the O
streets O
" O
, O
concludes O
Vandamme B-PER
. O

Moreover O
, O
it O
is O
long O
since O
no O
longer O
about O
the O
sport O
, O
but O
rather O
about O
commerce O
. O

" O
I O
'm O
going O
abroad O
on O
vacation O
. O

it O
does O
n't O
matter O
. O

page O

Chairwoman O
Leen B-PER
Vandamme I-PER
of O
the O
VOC B-ORG
has O
nothing O
against O
" O
the O
game O
of O
soccer O
" O
in O
itself O
, O
but O
thinks O
that O
the O
event O
has O
already O
been O
corrupted O
by O
the O
" O
excessive O
attention O
" O
in O
the O
media O
. O

" O
If O
soccer O
is O
so O
important O
to O
the O
men O
that O
it O
provides O
link O
, O
then O
the O
women O
also O
want O
a O
link O
from O
that O
site O
that O
announces O
, O
for O
example O
, O
Women B-MISC
's I-MISC
Day I-MISC
on O
November O
11 O
. O

As O
long O
as O
women O
are O
not O
sitting O
on O
the O
couch O
, O
meekly O
next O
to O
their O
partner O
in O
front O
of O
the O
tube O
having O
to O
endure O
the O
soccer O
mania O
. O

friday O
, O
june O
2 O
, O
2000 O

publication O
date O

Yes O
, O
but O
not O
for O
the O
women O
who O
are O
stuck O
at O
home O
with O
a O
football O
- O
mad O
husband O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

edition O

Of O
course O
there O
are O
also O
women O
who O
are O
just O
as O
football O
- O
crazy O
as O
their O
male O
partners O
, O
admits O
Vandamme B-PER
, O
who O
refers O
to O
the O
VOC B-MISC
's I-MISC
uproar I-MISC
over O
soccer O
as O
" O
playful O
" O
. O

Dancing O
, O
theater O
, O
film O
, O
café O
... O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

section O

At O
least O
that O
is O
what O
the O
Women B-ORG
's I-ORG
Consultative I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
( O
VOC B-ORG
) O
says O
, O
which O
is O
calling O
on O
Belgian B-MISC
women O
to O
take O
to O
the O
streets O
en O
masse O
during O
the O
upcoming O
European O
Football B-MISC
Championship I-MISC
and O
to O
collectively O
go O
crazy O
about O
it O
. O

publication O

And O
vice O
versa O
, O
there O
are O
plenty O
of O
men O
to O
be O
found O
who O
are O
already O
more O
than O
tired O
of O
the O
whole O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
thing O
. O

The B-MISC
Life I-MISC

The O
VOC B-ORG
is O
also O
annoyed O
about O
the O
federal O
website O
that O
has O
included O
a O
link O
about O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
. O

Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
a O
party O
. O

" O

author O

General O

Vandamme B-PER
himself O
does O
not O
take O
to O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
streets O
in O
the O
coming O
weeks O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Usually O
you O
do O
n't O
last O
like O
that O
anyway O
. O

The O
last O
time O
was O
in O
' O
98 O
against O
the O
Chicago B-ORG
Bulls I-ORG
, O
but O
Michael B-PER
Jordan I-PER
led O
his O
team O
in O
the O
Game B-MISC
Seven I-MISC
to O
the O
finals O
after O
all O
. O

We O
have O
to O
impose O
our O
way O
of O
playing O
. O

edition O

Sports B-MISC

section O

page O

With O
us O
, O
it O
was O
a O
lot O
less O
. O
