-DOCSTART- O
The O
text O
of O
the O
judgment O
is O
not O
yet O
available O
in O
writing O
but O
the O
message O
has O
already O
been O
published O
by O
a O
communication O
agency O
that O
hired O
Floralux B-ORG
. O

In O
' O
81 O
, O
the O
then O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
regularized O
the O
state O
with O
a O
BPA B-MISC
that O
the O
company O
had O
drawn O
up O
at O
its O
own O
expense O
. O

Publication O
of O

Today O
, O
Floralux B-ORG
is O
therefore O
in O
order O
with O
all O
licenses O
, O
but O
the O
BPA B-MISC
with O
which O
they O
could O
be O
obtained O
was O
controversial O
because O
business O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
... O

At O
first O
instance O
, O
Vandenbussche B-PER
was O
convicted O
in O
the O
early O
1990s O
for O
confusion O
of O
interests O
but O
was O
later O
acquitted O
by O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
in O
Gent B-LOC
. O

SP B-ORG
is O
difficult O
-- O
( O
Eric B-PER
, O
sd O
) O
Derycke B-PER
wants O
to O
approve O
BPA B-MISC
on O
condition O
that O
BPA B-MISC
' O
The B-MISC
Height I-MISC
' O
is O
accepted O
limited O
( O
Mayor O
of O
Moorslede B-LOC
Walter B-PER
Ghekiere I-PER
will O
make O
a O
proposal O
) O
. O

It O
is O
not O
enough O
to O
impose O
a O
severe O
punishment O
. O

This O
court O
now O
does O
not O
bind O
a O
penalty O
to O
the O
guilt O
it O
establishes O
. O

It O
quickly O
grows O
into O
a O
garden O
center O
. O

The O
page O

There O
are O
a O
lot O
more O
things O
sold O
than O
you O
would O
expect O
in O
a O
plant O
farm O
. O

This O
is O
evident O
from O
a O
fax O
that O
her O
lawyer O
wrote O
to O
her O
at O
the O
time O
and O
which O
was O
seized O
during O
a O
house O
search O
. O

The O
case O
goes O
back O
to O
the O
end O
of O
the O
1980s O
. O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

Spatial B-ORG
Planning I-ORG
would O
have O
abused O
to O
obtain O
the O
BPA B-MISC
. O

The O
only O
evidence O
that O
remained O
to O
condemn O
Vandenbussche B-PER
for O
" O
interest O
- O
taking O
" O
was O
her O
presence O
at O
the O
ship O
's O
college O
when O
the O
file B-MISC
- I-MISC
Floralux I-MISC
came O
up O
. O

At O
the O
end O
of O
' O
98 O
the O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
made O
this O
regularization O
definitive O
with O
a O
district O
plan O
amendment O
. O

Guilt O
but O
no O
penalty O
. O

» O

He O
himself O
did O
this O
as O
" O
larie O
and O
apecool O
of O
quatongue O
" O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Fige O
after O
Easter O
, O
so O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
seems O
to O
have O
thought O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
and O
Brussels B-LOC

Locally O
it O
is O
suspected O
that O
Floralux B-ORG
financed O
the O
election O
campaigns O
of O
Luc B-PER
Martens I-PER
, O
who O
within O
the O
previous O
government O
still O
asked O
for O
" O
attention O
" O
for O
the O
case O
. O

The B-MISC
life I-MISC

Vandenbussche B-PER
himself O
ruled O
that O
the O
court O
wanted O
to O
condemn O
" O
the O
political O
morals O
of O
the O
past O
" O
. O

» O

The O
Court B-ORG
of I-ORG
Cassation I-ORG
broke O
the O
judgment O
so O
it O
had O
to O
be O
passed O
by O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
of O
Antwerp B-LOC
. O

That O
is O
the O
essence O
of O
the O
judgment O
that O
the O
Antwerp B-MISC
Court O
of O
Appeal O
passed O
on O
Wednesday O
in O
the O
case O
of O
the O
contested O
garden O
center O
Floralux B-ORG
from O
Moorslede B-LOC
- I-LOC
Dadizele I-LOC
. O

Prosecutor O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
is O
found O
guilty O
of O
interference O
( O
‘ O
interest O
taking O
’ O
in O
legal O
language O
) O
but O
is O
not O
punished O
because O
a O
sentence O
after O
all O
those O
years O
would O
no O
longer O
make O
sense O
. O

It O
is O
the O
interpretation O
given O
to O
the O
judgment O
in O
the O
context O
of O
Floralux B-ORG
( O
see O
page O
1 O
): O
that O
a O
“ O
new O
political O
culture O
” O
has O
arisen O
and O
that O
the O
old O
political O
customs O
were O
indeed O
repugnant O
but O
now O
no O
longer O
need O
to O
be O
punished O
with O
, O
in O
this O
case O
, O
the O
closure O
of O
a O
case O
. O

What O
lasted O
years O
as O
a O
controversial O
“ O
CVP B-MISC
file I-MISC
” O
now O
gets O
through O
the O
court O
ruling O
the O
cachet O
of O
an O
old O
cow O
in O
the O
canal O
. O

To O
survive O
, O
Floralux B-ORG
wants O
the O
agricultural O
land O
to O
be O
converted O
into O
a O
SME O
zone O
. O

" O
The O
Court B-ORG
condemned O
the O
political O
morals O
of O
the O
time O
" O

The O
lawyer O
writes O
that O
" O
( O
... O
) O
it O
is O
then O
clear O
that O
it O
( O
BPA B-MISC
, O
sd O
) O
was O
realized O
only O
for O
private O
purposes O
, O
namely O
for O
your O
firm O
, O
and O
the O
ship O
college O
acts O
as O
a O
gangster O
for O
it O
. O
" O

Nevertheless O
, O
she O
insisted O
in O
front O
of O
the O
VRT B-MISC
radio I-MISC
that O
she O
had O
" O
offended O
nothing O
" O
. O

The O
Author O

Furthermore O
, O
it O
turns O
out O
that O
consultations O
were O
held O
with O
the O
liberal O
party O
( O
then O
still O
PVV B-ORG
) O
and O
with O
the O
SP B-ORG
: O
" O
Waltniel B-PER
( O
PVV B-ORG
, O
sd O
) O
is O
in O
favour O
. O

And O
Delcroix B-PER
decided O
, O
“ O
It O
will O
come O
through O
. O

Publication O
Date O

That O
context O
ensured O
that O
the O
file O
has O
always O
been O
bathed O
in O
an O
atmosphere O
of O
party O
financing O
in O
exchange O
for O
regularization O
. O

Generally O

Dossier O
always O
associated O
with O
party O
financing O
in O
exchange O
for O
regularization O

Floralux B-ORG
obtains O
a O
permit O
to O
raise O
a O
plant O
farm O
. O

» O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

The O
Antwerp B-MISC
court O
rejected O
the O
document O
as O
evidence O
but O
read O
it O
during O
the O
hearing O
. O

What O
those O
political O
morals O
were O
can O
be O
deduced O
from O
the O
Atoma B-MISC
writings I-MISC
that O
Leo B-PER
Delcroix I-PER
held O
when O
he O
was O
still O
CVP B-MISC
secretary I-MISC
. O

Section O
of O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

Prosecutor O
Floralux B-ORG
insists O
that O
she O
has O
done O
nothing O
wrong O

About O
Floralux B-ORG
it O
was O
said O
: O
“ O
They O
want O
regularization O
. O

Edited O

-DOCSTART- O
Verberckmoes B-PER
is O
a O
former O
Catholic O
dissident O
who O
, O
at O
the O
foundation O
of O
the O
PVV B-ORG
as O
an O
expansion O
candidate O
, O
joined O
the O
liberal O
ranks O
and O
almost O
immediately O
brought O
it O
to O
popular O
representative O
. O

Liberal O
Justice B-ORG
Minister O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
is O
not O
a O
candidate O
on O
the O
local O
VLD B-MISC
list I-MISC
at O
the O
upcoming O
municipal O
elections O
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
. O

A O
member O
of O
the O
municipal O
council O
of O
Inzet B-ORG
: O
“ O
The O
intention O
was O
that O
we O
as O
a O
group O
would O
form O
a O
cartel O
list O
that O
would O
then O
ask O
the O
voter O
for O
a O
new O
mandate O
. O

Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
admits O
that O
other O
motives O
may O
also O
have O
played O
a O
major O
role O
. O

by O
Willy B-PER
Van I-PER
Damme I-PER

" O
He O
does O
not O
want O
to O
commit O
voter O
fraud O
and O
be O
a O
candidate O
in O
order O
not O
to O
sit O
in O
the O
city O
council O
. O

It O
is O
now O
definitive O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Within O
the O
VLD B-ORG
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
there O
is O
great O
defeat O
. O

The O
proposal O
hadly O
grown O
quite O
spontaneously O
within O
the O
majority O
led O
by O
Mayor O
Norbert B-PER
De I-PER
Batselier I-PER
( O
SP B-ORG
) O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

According O
to O
local O
VLD B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
, O
his O
decision O
is O
irrevocable O
. O

He O
is O
against O
cumulating O
mandates O
, O
” O
says O
De B-PER
Brandt I-PER
. O

For O
example O
, O
there O
was O
the O
proposal O
for O
a O
joint O
list O
of O
Inzet B-ORG
, O
with O
which O
the O
VLD B-ORG
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
constitutes O
the O
majority O
and O
which O
consists O
of O
SP'ers B-MISC
, O
VU'ers B-MISC
and O
some O
independent O
. O

Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
is O
not O
a O
candidate O
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC

For O
them O
, O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
is O
the O
future O
of O
the O
VLD B-ORG
and O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
is O
the O
old O
political O
culture O
they O
hate O
. O

by O
Willy B-PER
Van I-PER
Damme I-PER

Verwilghen B-PER
can O
not O
convince O
local O
VLD B-ORG
to O
form O
a O
cartel O
with O
De O
Batselier O
’s B-MISC
Inzet I-MISC
list I-MISC

The O
Author O

» O

" O
This O
is O
the O
PVV B-ORG
of O
earlier O
or O
even O
worse O
, O
" O
according O
to O
a O
VLD'er B-MISC
from O
the O
area O
of O
Verwilghen B-PER
. O

For O
the O
VLD B-ORG
, O
which O
now O
has O
only O
four O
seats O
in O
the O
municipal O
council O
, O
therefore O
a O
debacle O
threatens O
. O

That O
official O
reason O
was O
also O
given O
by O
Verwilghen B-PER
himself O
in O
a O
press O
release O
last O
night O
. O

Dendermonde B-LOC

According O
to O
several O
sources O
, O
it O
also O
had O
the O
support O
of O
the O
top O
of O
the O
national O
VLD B-ORG
and O
was O
carried O
within O
the O
Dendermond B-MISC
VLD B-ORG
mainly O
by O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
. O

Now O
the O
list O
tractor O
will O
go O
between O
Hilde B-PER
Dierickx I-PER
and O
vessels O
for O
Finance B-ORG
Marcel B-PER
Borms I-PER
. O

The B-MISC
life I-MISC

The O
page O

Some O
of O
them O
may O
now O
be O
cut O
off O
. O

Generally O

He O
left O
active O
politics O
a O
few O
years O
ago O
, O
but O
remains O
an O
influential O
figure O
within O
the O
local O
liberal O
party O
, O
including O
through O
his O
son O
Kristian B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
, O
who O
is O
a O
city O
council O
member O
. O

However O
, O
the O
majority O
within O
the O
local O
department O
rejected O
the O
voostel O
. O

Some O
liberals O
have O
already O
taken O
steps O
towards O
Inzet B-ORG
or O
are O
planning O
to O
do O
so O
. O

That O
( O
according O
to O
circles O
within O
and O
outside O
the O
VLD B-ORG
) O
mainly O
on O
the O
initiative O
of O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
, O
former B-MISC
VLD I-MISC
people I-MISC
's I-MISC
representative I-MISC
for O
Dendermonde B-LOC
. O

» O

Publication O
Date O

From O
our O
collaborator O

Edited O

Robert B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
, O
Marc B-PER
's O
father O
, O
grabbed O
a O
chair O
. O

Here O
, O
according O
to O
insiders O
, O
the O
old O
dispute O
between O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
and O
his O
predecessor O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
plays O
a O
major O
role O
. O

Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
: O
" O
A O
number O
of O
people O
had O
indeed O
not O
yet O
put O
themselves O
candidate O
for O
the O
municipal O
council O
elections O
in O
anticipation O
of O
what O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
was O
going O
to O
do O
. O

Section O
of O

Publication O
of O

-DOCSTART- O
Parents O
who O
were O
lucky O
that O
their O
child O
was O
released O
can O
go O
home O
under O
police O
guidance O
. O

God B-PER
be O
thankful O
. O

On O
Wednesday O
, O
she O
was O
sick O
. O

Unconscious O
parents O
wait O
powerlessly O
to O
unlock O
the O
hostage O
drama O

The O
child O
is O
hardly O
three O
. O

In O
the O
village O
with O
only O
2,300 O
inhabitants O
we O
know O
us O
. O

“ O
Fathers O
do O
n’t O
hurt O
kids O
, O
” O
they O
say O
. O

Parents O
do O
n’t O
hurt O
children O
, O
they O
say O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

Every O
year O
the O
village O
is O
flooded O
with O
all O
sorts O
of O
people O
, O
especially O
tourists O
, O
who O
come O
there O
walking O
and O
cycling O
in O
the O
beautiful O
surroundings O
. O

The O
parents O
will O
also O
be O
visited O
by O
the O
Portuguese B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
ambassadors O
and O
a O
representative O
of O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
government O
. O

Publication O
of O

Colas B-PER
: O
“ O
A O
child O
of O
that O
age O
does O
n’t O
really O
realize O
what O
’s O
happening O
to O
him O
. O

The O
neighbor O
’s O
daughter O
is O
there O
. O

Publication O
Date O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

According O
to O
the O
police O
, O
everything O
is O
fine O
with O
the O
children O
. O

They O
have O
never O
had O
hostages O
. O

My O
daughter O
kept O
her O
at O
home O
. O

Generally O

» O

Shortly O
after O
seven O
o’clock O
the O
salvation O
came O
. O

Section O
of O

Occasionally O
applause O
to O
the O
cultural O
center O
. O

They O
sleep O
well O
and O
get O
food O
on O
time O
. O

Who O
does O
such O
a O
thing O
now O
? O

But O
no O
one O
knows O
what O
will O
happen O
. O

“ O
The O
worst O
thing O
is O
when O
they O
come O
and O
say O
that O
children O
have O
been O
released O
to O
hear O
that O
your O
child O
is O
not O
there O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Then O
you O
just O
die O
. O

“ O
We O
hold O
our O
right O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
man O
in O
question O
is O
the O
father O
himself O
. O

The O
entire O
neighborhood O
around O
the O
crèche O
is O
hermetically O
closed O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

In O
the O
afternoon O
the O
atmosphere O
becomes O
harsher O
. O

Wasserbillig B-LOC
is O
a O
meltdown O
where O
Portuguese B-MISC
, O
Italian B-MISC
, O
Polish B-MISC
, O
German B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
immigrants O
– O
who O
once O
came O
here O
to O
work O
in O
the O
steel O
and O
tyres O
industry O
– O
live O
peacefully O
side O
by O
side O
. O

The O
inhabitants O
of O
Wasserbillig B-LOC
, O
a O
small O
idyllic O
Luxembourg B-MISC
village O
, O
attached O
to O
the O
German B-MISC
border O
, O
reacted O
shocked O
. O

After O
a O
few O
shots O
, O
the O
hostage O
was O
taken O
. O

Occasionally O
they O
also O
get O
a O
circus O
or O
kermis O
to O
visit O
, O
as O
in O
the O
past O
days O
. O

The O
municipal O
daycare O
in O
Rue B-LOC
du I-LOC
Bocksberg I-LOC
is O
entirely O
surrounded O
by O
special O
intervention O
forces O
of O
the O
Luxembourg B-MISC
, O
German B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
police O
. O

» O

Edited O

“ O
A O
lot O
of O
blurred O
faces O
. O

Everyone O
is O
preparing O
for O
a O
second O
night O
of O
fear O
. O

The O
old O
lady O
looks O
desperately O
at O
the O
white O
building O
in O
the O
distance O
. O

» O

Some O
parents O
panic O
and O
fear O
the O
worst O
, O
others O
try O
to O
keep O
the O
courage O
in O
it O
. O

Let O
us O
hope O
that O
“ O
they O
” O
are O
right O
. O

The O
atmosphere O
in O
the O
cultural O
center O
he O
describes O
as O
dramatic O
. O

These O
are O
helpless O
babies O
and O
babies O
. O

» O

The O
page O

The O
Author O

» O

The O
industry O
left O
a O
decade O
ago O
, O
the O
immigrants O
stayed O
. O

The O
big O
warts O
under O
his O
eyes O
reveal O
that O
he O
has O
been O
sitting O
on O
a O
sleepy O
night O
. O

The O
moment O
is O
feared O
for O
the O
worst O
, O
when O
the O
message O
enters O
that O
the O
hostage O
brought O
food O
and O
drink O
for O
three O
days O
. O

“ O
I O
was O
stuck O
at O
my O
radio O
. O

Sadly O
because O
a O
nephew O
or O
boyfriend O
of O
their O
child O
is O
there O
. O

» O

“ O
My O
granddaughter O
has O
escaped O
death O
, O
” O
the O
woman O
sucked O
. O

The O
young O
man O
sucked O
deeply O
. O

From O
our O
reporter O
on O
site O

» O

water B-LOC
cheap I-LOC

Out O
there O
are O
about O
fifty O
villagers O
who O
wanted O
to O
support O
the O
affected O
parents O
. O

The O
route B-LOC
du I-LOC
Luxembourg I-LOC
, O
the O
street O
in O
front O
of O
the O
town O
hall O
, O
was O
redesigned O
yesterday O
to O
a O
boulevard O
, O
along O
which O
hundreds O
of O
disaster O
tourists O
flocked O
looking O
at O
rail O
cars O
( O
more O
than O
twenty O
) O
and O
press O
ladies O
( O
more O
than O
a O
hundred O
) O
instead O
of O
showcases O
. O

The O
parents O
of O
the O
hostage O
children O
are O
taken O
a O
hundred O
meters O
further O
in O
the O
cultural O
center O
. O

A O
ghost O
picture O
, O
on O
what O
a O
beautiful O
summer O
holiday O
day O
could O
have O
been O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
and O
3 O
) O

The O
hostage O
begins O
to O
get O
nervous O
because O
his O
demands O
are O
not O
met O
quickly O
enough O
. O

Fortunately O
, O
they O
are O
not O
with O
the O
hostages O
. O

Through O
the O
psychologists O
, O
parents O
are O
kept O
informed O
. O

Ramotti B-PER
is O
one O
of O
the O
few O
parents O
who O
wants O
to O
lose O
something O
. O

The O
fatigue O
also O
begins O
to O
demand O
its O
toll O
. O

DocStart O
- O
General O

This O
can O
only O
happen O
in O
a O
democracy O
. O

The O
few O
times O
that O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
princes O
acted O
self O
- O
sufficiently O
, O
it O
happened O
that O
when O
they O
saw O
their O
own O
position O
in O
jeopardy O
: O
during O
the O
royal O
question O
, O
the O
independence O
of O
Congo B-LOC
or O
the O
state O
reform O
. O

Not O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
and O
not O
in O
Laken B-LOC
. O

The O
page O

He O
may O
not O
have O
his O
own O
opinion O
and O
all O
his O
actions O
are O
covered O
by O
the O
government O
, O
which O
in O
turn O
owes O
accountability O
to O
the O
people O
's O
representation O
. O

“ O
My O
kingdom O
for O
purple O
... O
” O

Some O
point O
to O
the O
growing O
influence O
of O
the O
( O
French B-MISC
- I-MISC
speaking I-MISC
) O
liberals O
in O
court O
. O

by O
Karl B-PER
van I-PER
den I-PER
Broeck I-PER

It O
is O
a O
simple O
solution O
, O
but O
the O
legitimacy O
of O
the O
exercise O
of O
power O
is O
not O
great O
. O

That O
is O
precisely O
why O
democracy O
is O
“ O
the O
least O
evil O
form O
of O
state O
” O
: O
the O
transfer O
of O
power O
takes O
place O
peacefully O
and O
the O
rulers O
have O
a O
legitimacy O
that O
can O
not O
be O
troubled O
. O

Officially O
, O
however O
, O
it O
is O
very O
simple O
: O
the O
king O
is O
an O
empty O
box O
. O

Therefore O
, O
it O
is O
such O
a O
valuable O
feature O
of O
a O
civilized O
society O
that O
the O
transfer O
of O
power O
takes O
place O
in O
a O
peaceful O
manner O
. O

In O
Belgium B-LOC
it O
was O
then O
often O
one O
direction O
within O
the O
majority O
: O
the O
Christian O
- O
Democratic O
. O

In O
a O
monarchy O
, O
the O
question O
of O
who O
has O
the O
right O
to O
exercise O
power O
is O
left O
to O
fate O
: O
whoever O
is O
born O
from O
the O
sperm O
of O
the O
king O
becomes O
later O
king O
himself O
. O

Edited O

Publication O
of O

Observers O
point O
out O
that O
something O
fundamental O
has O
changed O
in O
this O
country O
since O
the O
entry O
of O
the O
purple O
- O
green O
coalition O
. O

Publication O
Date O

Per O
it O
is O
all O
much O
simpler O
. O

The O
natural O
ally O
of O
the O
court O
, O
the O
Christian O
pillar O
, O
is O
referred O
to O
the O
opposition O
and O
the O
country O
is O
ruled O
by O
a O
" O
republican O
" O
coalition O
. O

Opinion B-MISC

In O
a O
modern O
democracy O
, O
a O
king O
can O
only O
sustain O
himself O
if O
he O
does O
not O
overthrow O
the O
majority O
. O

Whoever O
has O
to O
give O
up O
power O
is O
fighting O
. O

The O
crypto O
- O
maçonnical O
training O
of O
Prince O
Laurent B-PER
would O
be O
a O
striking O
example O
of O
that O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

The O
Author O

In O
this O
way O
the O
king O
was O
reduced O
to O
a O
speech O
tube O
of O
the O
majority O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Belgium B-LOC
, O
of O
course O
, O
asked O
for O
problems O
when O
it O
chose O
a O
" O
constitutional O
monarchy O
" O
in O
1830 O
. O

That O
is O
the O
case O
in O
Britain B-LOC
, O
that O
is O
the O
case O
in O
the O
Netherlands B-LOC
( O
that O
had O
to O
be O
experienced O
by O
Queen O
Beatrix B-PER
) O
and O
that O
is O
of O
course O
the O
case O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
. O

The O
abortion O
issue O
then O
confronted O
the O
prince O
again O
with O
the O
shadow O
side O
of O
his O
" O
political O
neutrality O
" O
: O
his O
religious O
views O
also O
appeared O
to O
fall O
under O
it O
, O
and O
that O
was O
hardly O
acceptable O
for O
the O
deeply O
believing O
prince O
. O

Section O
of O

The O
CVP B-ORG
reacts O
grimly O
and O
accuses O
the O
king O
of O
partiality O
. O

He O
knows O
that O
if O
he O
does O
not O
sign O
the O
euthanasia O
law O
next O
year O
, O
he O
will O
sign O
his O
death O
sentence O
. O

The O
king O
came O
from O
the O
beginning O
in O
a O
difficult O
parquet O
: O
he O
had O
to O
remain O
in O
the O
popular O
lust O
to O
maintain O
his O
power O
and O
he O
had O
to O
resort O
to O
canapé O
politics O
, O
shimmer O
zones O
and O
lobbying O
to O
also O
exercise O
some O
power O
. O

in O
a O
monarchy O
. O

Whoever O
has O
power O
wants O
to O
retain O
power O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
King O
Albert B-PER
and O
his O
children O
are O
becoming O
more O
and O
more O
" O
purple O
- O
greener O
" O
reminds O
the O
CVP B-ORG
coldly O
that O
it O
no O
longer O
distributes O
the O
leaves O
. O

And O
King O
Albert B-PER
? O

-DOCSTART- O
The O
ninety O
- O
year O
- O
old O
grap O
is O
his O
weapon O
and O
shot O
. O

During O
his O
arrest O
, O
he O
did O
not O
resist O
. O

Section O
of O

The O
Author O

The O
room O
and O
the O
corridor O
where O
the O
events O
took O
place O
were O
sealed O
in O
anticipation O
of O
the O
eventual O
departure O
of O
the O
Charleroi B-LOC
parquet O
. O

The B-MISC
life I-MISC

Four O
teams O
of O
the O
Charleroi B-LOC
District O
National O
Guard O
besieged O
the O
resting O
house O
shortly O
after O
the O
events O
because O
it O
was O
assumed O
that O
the O
resting O
house O
director O
was O
dead O
. O

The O
other O
residents O
of O
the O
home O
were O
taken O
care O
of O
by O
a O
psychological O
team O
. O

A O
94 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
resident O
of O
an O
elderly O
home O
in O
Aiseau B-LOC
- I-LOC
Presles I-LOC
caught O
a O
bullet O
from O
a O
short O
distance O
through O
the O
head O
of O
the O
home O
robber O
yesterday O
morning O
. O

Then O
the O
man O
locked O
himself O
in O
his O
room O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

According O
to O
the O
police O
, O
the O
elderly O
man O
was O
unable O
to O
provide O
an O
explanation O
for O
his O
actions O
. O

Publication O
of O

The O
perpetrator O
was O
eventually O
arrested O
by O
the O
National O
Guard O
. O

( O
by O
KDM B-PER
) O

The O
man O
was O
taking O
care O
of O
the O
shooter O
when O
it O
came O
to O
a O
high O
- O
rise O
discussion O
. O

Edited O

An O
elderly O
man O
shoots O
down O
a O
rest O
house O
director O

The O
page O

Generally O

The O
victim O
was O
hit O
by O
the O
bullet O
in O
the O
head O
and O
was O
transferred O
to O
the O
Fabiola B-ORG
Hospital I-ORG
of O
Auvelais B-LOC
. O

The O
suspect O
was O
no O
longer O
in O
critical O
condition O
after O
the O
shooting O
. O

The O
elderly O
man O
was O
noticed O
at O
intervals O
as O
he O
moved O
from O
the O
room O
where O
he O
shut O
himself O
, O
to O
the O
corridor O
. O

by O
Kristof B-PER
Demasure I-PER

He O
seems O
not O
even O
aware O
of O
his O
behavior O
, O
nor O
of O
the O
seriousness O
of O
the O
facts O
. O

Publication O
Date O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

-DOCSTART- O
That O
Job B-ORG
would O
be O
taken O
over O
, O
was O
almost O
fixed O
. O

Invensys B-ORG
now O
owns O
10.8 O
percent O
of O
the O
shares O
. O

Thousands O
of O
people O
have O
to O
leave O
the O
job O
. O

" O
We O
think O
Invensys B-ORG
is O
the O
right O
company O
to O
restructure O
Job B-ORG
. O

Publication O
of O

The O
reorganization O
costs O
are O
based O
on O
this O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
Invensys B-ORG
itself O
is O
not O
very O
good O
. O

The O
company O
was O
formed O
by O
the O
merger O
of O
Siebe B-ORG
and O
BTR B-ORG
. O

Edited O

Invensys B-ORG
can O
use O
Baan B-ORG
’s O
software O
as O
a O
complement O
to O
its O
factory O
and O
facility O
control O
systems O
. O

17 O
is O

Invensys B-ORG
offers O
€ O
858 O
million O
for O
Baan B-ORG
, O
or O
€ O
2.85 O
per O
share O
in O
cash O
. O

Hopefully O
, O
next O
year O
’s O
losses O
will O
be O
the O
past O
. O

Work B-ORG
in O
British B-MISC
hands O

Generally O

Section O
of O

The O
hired O
business O
bank O
Lazard B-ORG
Frères I-ORG
has O
been O
trading O
with O
the O
software O
company O
since O
January O
. O

Publication O
Date O

But O
nobody O
seemed O
to O
want O
to O
have O
the O
stray O
company O
. O

Acquired O

The O
share O
of O
Baan B-ORG
rose O
13 O
percent O
on O
Wednesday O
to O
2.97 O
euros O
, O
while O
Invensys B-ORG
had O
to O
surrender O
13 O
percent O
to O
230 O
pence O
. O

That O
is O
8.8 O
percent O
more O
than O
the O
closing O
rate O
of O
Tuesday O
. O

The O
founders O
of O
the O
company O
, O
the O
brothers O
Jan B-PER
and O
Paul B-PER
Baan I-PER
, O
have O
pledged O
to O
sell O
their O
shares O
to O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

Simultaneously O
with O
the O
acquisition O
of O
Baan B-ORG
, O
the O
British B-MISC
company O
a O
loss O
of O
£ O
238 O
million O
, O
more O
than O
twice O
as O
much O
as O
a O
year O
earlier O
. O

Baan B-ORG
was O
once O
one O
of O
the O
best O
- O
performing O
shares O
in O
Europe B-LOC
, O
but O
has O
lost O
90 O
percent O
of O
its O
value O
in O
two O
years O
due O
to O
ongoing O
losses O
and O
management O
problems O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Other O
people O
within O
the O
company O
will O
do O
the O
same O
. O

Invensys B-ORG
intends O
to O
thoroughly O
reorganize O
the O
company O
and O
raises O
400 O
million O
euros O
for O
it O
. O

It O
is O
intended O
that O
the O
name O
Job B-ORG
will O
continue O
to O
exist O
, O
but O
as O
part O
of O
Invensys B-ORG
Software I-ORG
and I-ORG
Systems I-ORG
. O

by O
Bloomberg B-ORG

The O
Dutch B-MISC
software O
maker O
Baan B-ORG
is O
acquired O
by O
the O
British B-MISC
company O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

The O
page O

We O
want O
to O
do O
that O
quickly O
, O
” O
said O
CEO O
Allen B-PER
Yurko I-PER
of O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Tomorrow I-MISC

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

The O
Author O

-DOCSTART- O
Return O
Elián B-PER
to O
Cuba B-LOC
a O
step O
closer O

Generally O

In O
the O
Yugoslav B-MISC
Republic O
of O
Serbia B-LOC
, O
several O
senior O
officials O
and O
criminals O
have O
recently O
been O
murdered O
, O
but O
this O
is O
the O
first O
time O
something O
like O
this O
has O
happened O
in O
Montenegro B-LOC
, O
the O
other O
republic O
in O
the O
Yugoslav B-LOC
Federation I-LOC
. O

Edited O

The O
return O
of O
the O
Cuban B-MISC
boat O
refugee O
Elián B-PER
González I-PER
from O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
to O
his O
homeland O
came O
a O
step O
closer O
yesterday O
. O

shortly O

The O
family O
is O
now O
appealing O
to O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
. O

The O
Hammersmith B-LOC
Bridge I-LOC
in O
west O
London B-LOC
was O
damaged O
by O
an O
explosion O
yesterday O
. O

Explosion O
under O
London B-MISC
Bridge O

Foreign B-MISC

The O
pro O
- O
Western O
Montenegro B-LOC
is O
trying O
to O
sail O
an O
independent O
course O
from O
the O
Serbia B-LOC
of O
Slobodan B-PER
Milosevic I-PER
. O

There O
were O
no O
casualties O
, O
but O
there O
was O
a O
huge O
traffic O
disaster O
. O

Police O
discovered O
a O
small O
explosive O
attached O
to O
a O
support O
bar O
of O
the O
bridge O
that O
connects O
the O
two O
banks O
of O
the O
River O
Thames B-LOC
. O

The O
Northern B-MISC
Irish I-MISC
unionists O
point O
with O
an O
accusing O
finger O
to O
republican O
splinter O
movements O
, O
as O
the O
Irish B-ORG
Republican I-ORG
Army I-ORG
( O
IRA B-ORG
) O
also O
committed O
a O
failed O
attack O
on O
the O
bridge O
in O
1996 O
. O

There O
is O
considerable O
tension O
between O
the O
two O
republics O
. O

The O
judge O
’s O
ruling O
was O
the O
latest O
development O
in O
the O
trial O
that O
Elián B-MISC
’s O
family O
from O
Miami B-LOC
had O
pushed O
to O
keep O
the O
child O
in O
the O
U.S. B-LOC
, O
where O
it O
was O
picked O
up O
after O
his O
dramatic O
shipwreck O
. O

According O
to O
the O
court O
, O
only O
his O
father O
can O
do O
that O
for O
him O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

An O
appeal O
court O
in O
Atlanta B-LOC
ruled O
that O
the O
six O
- O
year O
- O
old O
boy O
is O
not O
entitled O
to O
apply O
for O
asylum O
in O
the O
United O
States B-LOC
himself O
. O

Montenegro B-LOC
’s O
President O
Djukanovic O
’s O
security O
adviser O
has O
been O
shot O
dead O
in O
Podgorica B-LOC
. O

Publication O
of O

The O
page O

Until O
that O
case O
is O
ruled O
, O
the O
boy O
must O
remain O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
. O

Police O
found O
the O
body O
of O
Goran B-PER
Zugic I-PER
in O
the O
garden O
near O
his O
home O
, O
after O
a O
neighbor O
had O
heard O
gunfire O
. O

Publication O
Date O

Montenegrin B-LOC
president O
assassinated O

Police O
are O
investigating O
whether O
the O
failed O
attack O
was O
the O
work O
of O
dissident O
paramilitaries O
from O
Northern B-LOC
Ireland I-LOC
, O
who O
oppose O
the O
self O
- O
government O
that O
was O
returned O
to O
the O
province O
this O
week O
. O

The O
Author O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Section O
of O

-DOCSTART- O
On O
the O
eve O
he O
then O
released O
seventeen O
children O
and O
two O
accompanyers O
. O

water B-LOC
cheap I-LOC

From O
our O
reporter O
on O
site O

In O
addition O
to O
five O
French B-MISC
, O
three O
German B-MISC
and O
one O
Italian B-MISC
hostages O
, O
an O
eight O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Belgian B-MISC
girl O
was O
also O
detained O
. O

On O
Thursday O
morning O
at O
midnight O
, O
the O
ultimatum O
passed O
in O
which O
Bejoui B-PER
demanded O
a O
minibus O
to O
the O
airport O
and O
a O
plane O
toward O
Libya B-LOC
. O

Police O
allegedly O
intervened O
because O
the O
hostage O
planned O
to O
take O
several O
children O
with O
him O
in O
a O
possible O
flight O
. O

The O
man O
held O
the O
children O
and O
accompanyers O
trapped O
in O
the O
kindergarten O
in O
Wasserbillig B-LOC
, O
a O
town O
in O
the O
Grand O
Duchy O
of B-LOC
Luxembourg I-LOC
. O

The O
page O

The O
capture O
of O
twenty O
- O
five O
children O
and O
two O
accompanying O
persons O
in O
Luxembourg B-MISC
last O
night O
ended O
in O
just O
seven O
hours O
for O
the O
hostages O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

Edited O

Thirteen O
of O
the O
children O
are O
of O
Portuguese B-MISC
descent O
. O

Page O
3 O

The O
actions O
of O
the O
police O
were O
initially O
thwarted O
because O
the O
hostage O
closely O
followed O
the O
reporting O
on O
television O
and O
radio O
. O

Yesterday O
, O
the O
hostage O
left O
four O
more O
children O
in O
the O
course O
of O
the O
day O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
and O
3 O
) O

Sniper O
ends O
hostage O
capture O
in O
Wasserbillig B-LOC

by B-PER
Bruyninckx I-PER

According O
to O
the O
latest O
reports O
, O
the O
man O
had O
two O
shot O
wounds O
in O
the O
head O
and O
was O
in O
danger O
of O
life O
. O

Publication O
Date O

Section O
of O

Publication O
of O

The O
Author O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

He O
would O
also O
have O
asked O
for O
60 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
( O
1.5 O
million O
euros O
) O
. O

The O
hostage O
seizure O
began O
around O
4 O
p.m. O
on O
Wednesday O
afternoon O
when O
the O
man O
, O
armed O
with O
a O
knife O
, O
a O
gun O
and O
a O
grenade O
, O
entered O
the O
kindergarten O
. O

Generally O

The O
hostage O
, O
39 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
, O
was O
shot O
dead O
by O
a O
gunman O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
In O
April O
last O
year O
there O
was O
commotion O
around O
the O
file O
when O
Steve B-PER
Stevaert I-PER
( O
SP B-ORG
) O
, O
then O
Minister O
of O
Spatial B-ORG
Planning I-ORG
, O
deliberately O
seized O
the O
BPA B-MISC
after O
the O
auditor O
at O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
State I-ORG
advised O
to O
destroy O
it O
. O

According O
to O
the O
lawyer O
of O
Floralux B-ORG
, O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
did O
not O
issue O
a O
sanction O
because O
it O
would O
no O
longer O
make O
sense O
after O
all O
those O
years O
. O

Page O
7 O

The O
case B-MISC
- I-MISC
Floralux I-MISC
has O
been O
pulling O
in O
for O
years O
and O
revolves O
around O
a O
change O
of O
destination O
that O
was O
carried O
out O
tailor O
- O
made O
to O
the O
farm O
, O
allowing O
the O
plant O
farmer O
to O
expand O
into O
a O
supermarket O
- O
sized O
garden O
center O
in O
what O
was O
originally O
an O
agricultural O
area O
. O

Floralux B-ORG
must O
therefore O
neither O
shrink O
nor O
pay O
damages O
to O
Dadiflor B-ORG
. O

A O
fax O
seized O
by O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Supervisory I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
from O
its O
lawyer O
to O
his O
client O
leaves O
no O
doubt O
about O
the O
role O
of O
the O
ship O
college O
in O
this O
. O

Business O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
was O
suspected O
of O
having O
become O
CVP B-MISC
ships I-MISC
of O
Ruimtelijke B-ORG
Ordening I-ORG
to O
realize O
the O
BPA B-MISC
Kezelberg I-MISC
itself O
. O

Publication O
Date O

Interest O
confusion O
remains O
unpunished O

The O
case O
gained O
a O
larger O
dimension O
because O
there O
was O
a O
lot O
of O
political O
lobbying O
involved O
. O

Publication O
of O

That O
was O
, O
however O
, O
rather O
a O
symbolic O
decision O
, O
since O
the O
heavier O
- O
weighted O
district O
plan O
had O
already O
been O
adjusted O
at O
that O
time O
, O
thus O
definitively O
regulating O
the O
case O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
and O
3 O
) O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Section O
of O

Also O
, O
all O
civil O
claims O
of O
the O
opposing O
party O
, O
competitor O
Dadiflor B-ORG
, O
have O
been O
rejected O
. O

The O
Author O

Generally O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

The O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
considers O
that O
there O
has O
been O
a O
mix O
of O
interests O
in O
the O
case O
of O
the O
controversial O
garden O
center O
Floralux B-ORG
in O
the O
West B-MISC
Flemish I-MISC
Dadizele B-LOC
but O
found O
it O
not O
necessary O
to O
punish O
case O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
for O
this O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
and O
Dadizele B-LOC

By O
condemning O
Floralux B-ORG
for O
" O
interest O
assumption O
" O
, O
the O
court O
sought O
to O
challenge O
the O
political O
lobbying O
. O

But O
like O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
in O
Gent B-LOC
, O
it O
also O
ruled O
that O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
the O
fax O
had O
to O
be O
banned O
from O
the O
file O
because O
it O
falls O
under O
the O
professional O
secret O
of O
lawyers O
. O

Edited O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

This O
is O
what O
appeared O
in O
Leo B-PER
Delcroix I-PER
’s O
notorious O
Atoma O
writings O
. O

Antwerp B-MISC
Court O
of O
Appeal O
leaves O
case O
manager O
of O
garden O
center O
Floralux B-ORG
unpunished O

Confusion O
of O
interests O
in O
criminal O
terms O
would O
not O
be O
proven O
. O

The O
page O

own O
reporting O

Concurrent O
Dadiflor B-ORG
puts O
courage O
out O
of O
the O
judgment O
by O
seeing O
in O
the O
conviction O
an O
additional O
argument O
for O
the O
destruction O
of O
the O
district O
plan O
amendment O
by O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
State I-ORG
. O

Gent B-MISC
Attorney O
General O
Frank B-PER
Schins I-PER
even O
ruled O
that O
there O
was O
over O
- O
lobbying O
in O
this O
file O
. O

Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
concludes O
that O
the O
court O
has O
" O
condemned O
the O
political O
morals O
of O
the O
time O
" O
but O
she O
still O
thinks O
that O
she O
has O
done O
" O
nothing O
wrong O
" O
. O

Last O
year O
, O
then O
- O
CVP B-MISC
minister I-MISC
Luc B-PER
Martens I-PER
admitted O
that O
he O
had O
sought O
“ O
attention O
” O
within O
the O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
for O
the O
case O
. O

1st O

-DOCSTART- O
For O
the O
first O
time O
in O
this O
Tour B-MISC
, O
the O
leader O
came O
into O
trouble O
yesterday O
. O

On O
Abetone B-LOC
Casagrande B-PER
had O
imposed O
last O
week O
Monday O
and O
also O
in O
the O
Dolomites B-LOC
the O
leader O
had O
not O
given O
a O
shrink O
. O

He O
hit O
, O
in O
the O
wheel O
followed O
by O
Tonkov B-PER
, O
again O
at O
Garzelli B-PER
and O
co O
and O
spurted O
up O
to O
a O
third O
place O
. O

The O
difference O
between O
the O
leader O
and O
Garzelli B-PER
is O
only O
25 O
seconds O
. O

Section O
of O

On O
the O
contrary O
, O
Stefano B-PER
Garzelli I-PER
and O
Gilberto B-PER
Simoni I-PER
made O
it O
clear O
that O
they O
can O
make O
life O
acidic O
today O
and O
tomorrow O
. O

Later O
that O
was O
the O
case O
with O
Ivan B-PER
Gotti I-PER
. O

Pratonevoso B-LOC

to O
win O
. O

“ O
I O
’m O
not O
afraid O
of O
anyone O
and O
I O
will O
attack O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O

He O
just O
really O
feels O
the O
hot O
breath O
of O
Stefano B-PER
Garzelli I-PER
in O
his O
neck O
. O

Particular O
attention O
is O
paid O
to O
today O
’s O
Queen O
’s O
Night O
with O
the O
climbs O
of O
the O
Col O
d’Agnelli B-LOC
( O
2 O
748 O
m O
) O
and O
the O
Izoard B-LOC
( O
2 O
361 O
) O
and O
tomorrow O
’s O
climbing O
ride O
over O
the O
Montgenèvre B-LOC
and O
Sestrière B-LOC
. O

The O
page O

Thanks O
to O
the O
support O
of O
Buenahora B-PER
, O
Casagrande B-PER
later O
recovered O
from O
the O
problem O
. O

For O
Di B-PER
Luca I-PER
, O
Wednesday O
was O
too O
much O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Casagrande B-PER
feels O
the O
hot O
breath O
of O
Garzelli B-PER

The O
tastemaker O
of O
the O
first O
two O
weeks O
, O
resigned O
with O
tendinitis O
. O

Here O
I O
want O
to O
make O
the O
difference O
. O

And O
say O
that O
Casagrande B-PER
spoke O
optimistic O
language O
on O
the O
eve O
of O
the O
ride O
to O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
. O

In O
so O
far O
as O
both O
still O
fostered O
profit O
ambitions O
, O
they O
can O
now O
save O
them O
definitively O
. O

» O

And O
it O
could O
sometimes O
. O

own O
reporting O

I O
will O
come O
back O
next O
year O
. O

We O
will O
have O
more O
clarity O
today O
and O
tomorrow O
in O
the O
two O
archaeological O
Alpine B-MISC
Rides I-MISC
. O

Garzelli B-PER
and O
Piepoli B-PER
. O

He O
also O
enjoys O
the O
advantage O
of O
being O
the O
better O
time O
rider O
among O
the O
favorites O
, O
making O
him O
really O
daring O
to O
think O
of O
final O
gain O
now O
. O

Winning O
the O
Tour B-MISC
. O

The O
Author O

“ O
I O
learned O
a O
lot O
from O
this O
Tour B-MISC
. O

Rosetta O
has O
not O
won O
the O
Tour B-MISC
yet O
. O

Gonzales B-PER
de I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
, O
who O
is O
known O
as O
a O
better O
time O
rider O
, O
made O
it O
a O
real O
time O
ride O
between O
Genoa B-LOC
and O
Brescia B-LOC
. O

and O
TL B-PER

Sporting B-MISC

Francesco B-PER
Casagrande I-PER
will O
be O
a O
lot O
less O
comfortable O
after O
yesterday O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Publication O
of O

» O

As O
the O
Italian O
climbing O
continued O
, O
everyone O
became O
more O
and O
more O
convinced O
that O
Casagrande B-PER
, O
who O
had O
set O
the O
Italian B-MISC
round O
as O
his O
main O
goal O
and O
had O
also O
made O
many O
sacrifices O
for O
it O
, O
would O
realize O
his O
goal O
. O

Among O
the O
bruised O
accelerations O
of O
Gilberto B-PER
Simoni I-PER
on O
the O
steepest O
parts O
of O
the O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
, O
Casagrande B-PER
had O
to O
fit O
. O

Generally O

“ O
This O
race O
is O
more O
important O
to O
me O
than O
the O
next O
two O
. O

“ O
I O
win O
today O
, O
” O
he O
wrote O
on O
the O
checklist O
this O
morning O
. O

Because O
no O
matter O
how O
hard O
it O
was O
in O
the O
group O
by O
the O
sprinter O
teams O
was O
chased O
behind O
the O
Spanish B-MISC
, O
at O
the O
finish O
he O
still O
half O
a O
minute O
. O

But O
should O
we O
assume O
that O
it O
was O
a O
sign O
on O
the O
wall O
for O
a O
moment O
and O
constantly O
clamping O
it O
down O
? O

Halfway O
, O
after O
118 O
kilometers O
, O
he O
left O
the O
peloton O
alone O
, O
ran O
out O
for O
seven O
minutes O
and O
resisted O
the O
return O
of O
the O
peloton O
in O
a O
magnificent O
way O
. O

Especially O
for O
Garzelli B-PER
, O
the O
ride O
win O
should O
be O
a O
boost O
. O

Edited O

And O
the O
Spaniard B-MISC
from O
the O
Vitalicioploeg B-MISC
kept O
his O
word O
. O

At O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
, O
Dario B-PER
Frigo I-PER
was O
in O
trouble O
very O
early O
. O

It O
promises O
to O
be O
an O
exciting O
final O
day O
in O
the O
Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Italy I-MISC
. O

The O
teammate O
of O
Marco B-PER
Pantani I-PER
and O
head O
of O
Mercatone B-ORG
Uno I-ORG
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
, O
left O
all O
of O
his O
competitors O
behind O
yesterday O
on O
the O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
and O
crashed O
thanks O
to O
the O
bonus O
closer O
to O
Casagrande B-PER
. O

Publication O
Date O

“ O
The O
pain O
was O
no O
longer O
hard O
, O
” O
said O
the O
young O
Di B-PER
Luca I-PER
. O

15 O
is O

But O
of O
the O
Tuscany B-MISC
, O
it O
is O
said O
that O
a O
big O
round O
takes O
a O
week O
too O
long O
for O
him O
. O

On O
Wednesday O
, O
Alvaro B-PER
Gonzales I-PER
de O
Galdeano B-PER
made O
his O
day O
of O
it O
. O

Such O
a O
speed O
did O
not O
happen O
. O

by O
Tony B-PER
Landuyt I-PER

Yesterday O
, O
two O
of O
the O
favorites O
were O
picked O
up O
. O

They O
quickly O
followed O
in O
Simoni B-PER
’s O
footsteps O
. O

-DOCSTART O
- O
Date O
of O
publication O

But O
the O
more O
Chernow B-PER
wrote O
, O
the O
more O
enthusiastic O
they O
became O
. O

Both O
saw O
Chernow B-MISC
's I-MISC
plan O
initially O
not O
sitting O
because O
they O
still O
felt O
too O
" O
young O
and O
healthy O
" O
for O
a O
biography O
. O

The O
first O
edition O
of O
the O
500 O
- O
page O
book O
Christo B-PER
and O
Jeanne B-PER
- I-PER
Claude I-PER
- O
a O
biography O
has O
, O
for O
the O
time O
being O
, O
appeared O
only O
in O
German B-MISC
. O

Biography O
of O
Christ B-PER

Generally O

Culture B-MISC
is O

The O
Bulgarian B-MISC
- I-MISC
American I-MISC
artist O
couple O
Christo B-PER
( O
Javacheff B-PER
) O
and O
Jeanne B-PER
- I-PER
Claude I-PER
presented O
their O
biography O
earlier O
this O
week O
in O
Cologne B-LOC
at O
the O
publishing O
house O
Keipenheuer B-ORG
Witsch I-ORG
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

The O
page O

The O
author O
Burt B-PER
Chernow I-PER
and O
friend O
of O
the O
house O
of O
the O
Christo B-PER
, O
wrote O
the O
biography O
of O
the O
couple O
: O
the O
Bulgarian B-LOC
- O
born O
Christo B-PER
Javacheff I-PER
and O
his O
great O
love O
Jeanne O
- O
Claude B-PER
de I-PER
Guillebon I-PER
. O

Publication O
of O

They O
were O
especially O
prominent O
in O
1995 O
, O
when O
they O
completely O
packaged O
the O
German B-MISC
Reichstag B-LOC
in O
Berlin B-LOC
. O

Edited O

Section O
of O

The O
Author O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

“ O
Germany B-LOC
has O
a O
special O
place O
in O
our O
hearts O
, O
” O
the O
two O
artists O
said O
during O
the O
presentation O
. O

The O
artistic O
couple O
has O
been O
engaged O
in O
the O
art O
of O
packaging O
since O
the O
1960s O
. O

DocStart O
- O
General O

by O
Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogert I-PER

( O
by O
PJB B-PER
) O

“ O
The O
government O
has O
been O
raising O
awareness O
for O
more O
than O
20 O
years O
. O

The O
Brussels B-MISC
Minister O
of O
the O
Environment B-ORG
, O
Didier B-PER
Gosuin I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
/ I-ORG
FDF I-ORG
) O
, O
is O
also O
disappointed O
by O
the O
" O
poor O
" O
content O
of O
the O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
. O

For O
any O
overstep O
of O
the O
European B-MISC
health O
standards O
( O
120 O
micrograms O
of O
ozone O
per O
cubic O
meter O
for O
at O
least O
eight O
hours O
) O
, O
they O
demand O
50 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
from O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
state O
, O
the O
Brussels O
Region O
and O
the O
nineteen O
Brussels I-MISC
municipalities O
. O

Air O
pollution O
deserves O
much O
more O
than O
that O
, O
” O
says O
Gosuin B-PER
, O
who O
himself O
announces O
structural O
measures O
. O

The O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
gets O
a O
heavy O
insufficiency O
from O
the O
environmental O
movement O
. O

Environmental O
movement O
drives O
the O
ozone O
process O

The O
page O

Two O
Brussels B-MISC
associations O
, O
Bral B-ORG
and O
Inter B-ORG
- I-ORG
Environnement I-ORG
, O
are O
tired O
of O
the O
trouble O
of O
the O
governments O
and O
step O
to O
court O
in O
short O
litigation O
. O

Pages O
2 O
and O
7 O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Publication O
of O

The O
two O
associations O
are O
calling O
for O
concrete O
measures O
to O
limit O
car O
traffic O
before O
the O
summer O
. O

The O
cabinet O
of O
health B-ORG
minister O
Magda B-PER
Aelvoet I-PER
( O
Agalev B-ORG
) O
did O
not O
yet O
want O
to O
respond O
to O
the O
complaint O
yesterday O
. O

Edited O

Publication O
Date O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
and O
3 O
) O

The O
Author O

1st O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Section O
of O

-DOCSTART- O
Di B-PER
Biase I-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
11 O
. O

Zabel B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
3h15:58 O
-- O
2 O
. O

Buenahora B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
08 O
- O
8 O
. O

Wüst B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
/ O
Festina B-ORG
) O
the O
102.6 O
km O
in O
2h28:10 O
-- O
2 O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Plaza B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
31h08:55 O
-- O
2 O
. O

Leoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
4 O
. O

Simoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
53 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Simoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
3 O
. O

Kadlec B-PER
( O
Tsj B-LOC
) O
– O
... O

Frigo B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
4:34 O
-- O
10 O
. O

and O
43 O
. O

Finot B-PER
( O
Fra B-LOC
) O
z.t O
. O
- O
7 O
. O

Zabel B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
– O
5 O
. O

Blanco B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
4:39 O
-- O
11 O
. O

Ullrich B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:33 O
-- O
10 O
. O

Forconi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
2:18 O
-- O
18 O
. O

Merckx B-PER
all O
s.t O
. O

Sporting B-MISC

Tonkov B-PER
( O
Russian B-LOC
) O
2:41 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Bridgestone B-PER
– O
17 O

Rebellin B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
10:21 O
. O

Bracke B-PER
all O
s.t O
. O

Khruska B-PER
( O
Tsj B-LOC
) O
– O
... O

Guidi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
10 O
. O

Bruylandts B-PER
0:23 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Pantani B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
... O

Fornaciari B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
13 O
. O

Garzelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
at O
25 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Casero B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
1:42 O
-- O
5 O
. O

McRae B-PER
( O
USA B-LOC
) O
19:00 O
– O
19 O
. O

Kurts B-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
– O
3 O
. O

McRae B-PER
( O
VSt B-LOC
) O
1:47 O
-- O
14 O
. O

Section O
of O

Blanco B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
– O
10 O
. O

Garzelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
/ O
Mercatone B-ORG
Uno I-ORG
) O
the O
173 O
km O
in O
4h42:32 O
( O
gem O
. O
: O
36,739 O
km O
/ O
h O
) O
-- O
2 O
. O

Lanfranchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
12:51 O
-- O
15 O
. O

7th O
ride O
( O
time O
ride O
) O
: O
1 O
. O

Plaza B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
/ O
Festina B-ORG
) O
the O
35.7 O
km O
in O
42:53 O
-- O
2 O
. O

and O
56 O
. O

Generally O

Beikirch B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
– O
... O

Boscardin B-PER
( O
Zwi B-LOC
) O
44 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Rous B-PER
( O
Fra B-LOC
) O
at O
0:09 O
-- O
3 O
. O

From B-PER
the I-PER
Wager I-PER
0:13 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Peter B-PER
is O
all O
. O

Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Italy I-MISC
: O
17th O
ride O
: O
1 O
. O

Grand B-ORG
Prix I-ORG
of I-ORG
Wallonia I-ORG
( O
Category O
1.2 O
) O
: O

Hruska B-PER
( O
Chj B-LOC
) O
13:14 O
-- O
16 O
. O

Rubiera B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
at O
4:45 O
- O
12 O
. O

Pena B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
16:59 O
-- O
18 O
. O

1 O
of O
1 O
. O

16 O
is O
. O

Savoldelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
19:08 O
-- O
20 O
. O

Leoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
5 O
. O

Hoi B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
2:12 O
— O
10 O
. O

The O
Author O

End O
of O
: O
1 O
. O

Gotti B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:54 O
-- O
17 O
. O

Publication O
of O

Round B-MISC
of I-MISC
Italy I-MISC
: O

Clöden B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
at O
0:42 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Piepoli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
at O
02 O
-- O
5 O
. O

31 O
is O
. O

Gerosa B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
14 O
. O

15 O
is O

Casero B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
1:40 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Ritsel B-PER
( O
Zwe B-LOC
) O
2:34 O
. O

by O
Gonzalez B-PER
de I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
. O

Seville B-LOC
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
15:24 O
-- O
17 O
. O

Pharaoh B-PER
1:58 O
— O
6 O
. O

Usov B-PER
( O
WRu B-LOC
) O
-- O
7 O
. O

Merckx B-PER
7:32 O
-- O
... O

Baguette B-PER
– O
18 O

Savoldelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
8:23 O
-- O
48 O
. O

Rubiera B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
49 O
-- O
11 O
. O

Romans B-PER
2:06 O
— O
9 O
. O

Heppner B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:06 O
-- O
... O

Piepoli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
6:13 O
-- O
14 O
. O

Liese B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:11 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Stand O
is O
1 O
. O

Thirteen O
. O

The O
17th O
ride O
: O
1 O
. O

Among O
them B-PER
2:02 O
– O
8 O
. O

Blaudzun B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
1:44 O
-- O
7 O
. O

Lafis B-PER
( O
Zwe B-LOC
) O
– O
15 O
. O

Bölts B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
1:41 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Frigo B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
2:38 O
-- O
20 O
. O

Christianity B-PER
is O
... O

and O
34 O
. O

Peterson B-PER
– O
6 O
. O

Blaudzun B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
1:46 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Martinello B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
6 O
. O

Round B-MISC
of I-MISC
Germany I-MISC
: O

Ullrich B-PER
at O
18:04 O

Ullrich B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
all O
z.t O
. O

Beikirch B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
– O
3 O
. O

The O
18th O
ride O
: O
1 O
. O

Belli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
7 O
. O

Gonzalez B-PER
de I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
/ O
Vitalicio B-ORG
) O
the O
236 O
km O
in O
5h23:02 O
( O
gem O
: O
43,834 O
km O
/ O
h O
) O
-- O
2 O
. O

Boogerd B-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
z.t O
. O
— O
... O

Petacchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
5 O
. O

Baranowski B-PER
( O
Poo B-LOC
) O
– O
13 O
. O

Castelblanco B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
2:24 O
-- O
19 O
. O

Belli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:11 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Usov B-PER
( O
WRu B-LOC
) O
-- O
6 O
. O

Casagrande B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
4 O
. O

Noah B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
3:39 O
-- O
7 O
. O

Konyshev B-PER
( O
Russian B-LOC
) O
– O
4 O
. O

Braikia B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
- O
9 O
. O

Bölts B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
1:26 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Buenahora B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
3:43 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Clöden B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
at O
40 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Wüst B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
– O
4 O
. O

Heppner B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:21 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Casagrande B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
/ O
Vini B-ORG
Caldirola I-ORG
) O
87h11:09 O
-- O
2 O
. O

Publication O
Date O

by O
Mattan B-PER
- O
19 O
. O

Edited O

The B-PER
Young I-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
– O
8 O
. O

Elli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
in O
4h42:05 O
( O
am O
. O
41,732 O
km O
/ O
h O
) O
-- O
2 O
. O

Noah B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
12 O
- O
9 O
. O

The O
6th O
ride O
: O
1 O
. O

Mancebo B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
at O
20:36 O
. O

Lanfranchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:12 O
-- O
12 O
. O

The O
page O

Mancebo B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
– O
16 O
. O

Tonkov B-PER
( O
Russian B-LOC
) O
– O
6 O
. O

The B-PER
Clercq I-PER
– O
20 O
. O

Conte B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
12 O
. O

Gotti B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
4:25 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Pieri B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
– O
7 O
. O

Honchar B-PER
( O
Oek B-LOC
) O
1:51 O
-- O
15 O
. O

70 O
is O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Svorada B-PER
( O
Tsj B-LOC
) O
on O
24 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Honchar B-PER
( O
Oek B-LOC
) O
5:45 O
-- O
13 O
. O

The O
eighth O
ride O
: O
1 O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Last O
year O
I O
was O
dealt O
with O
with O
the O
same O
problem O
when O
I O
joined O
the O
competition O
again O
in O
the O
Ronde B-MISC
des I-MISC
Wallons I-MISC
. O

Publication O
Date O

Questions O
around O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
are O
growing O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Generally O

Publication O
of O

Are O
they O
wrong O
? O

» O

I O
hope O
that O
the O
same O
will O
happen O
in O
the O
coming O
days O
, O
although O
I O
must O
admit O
that O
I O
am O
not O
at O
all O
comfortable O
with O
it O
. O

The O
tour B-MISC
is O
fast O
approaching O
. O

Cycling O

» O

There O
are O
even O
those O
already O
betting O
that O
he O
will O
not O
be O
at O
the O
departure O
of O
the O
Tour B-MISC
on O
July O
1st O
in O
Futuroscope O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

“ O
I O
do O
n’t O
understand O
why O
there O
’s O
so O
much O
cabbage O
around O
there O
, O
” O
says O
an O
astonished O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
. O

Sporting B-MISC

IEF B-PER
dismissed I-PER

“ O
It O
’s O
not O
going O
well O
with O
me O
, O
” O
said O
one O
otherwise O
serene O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
. O

own O
reporting O

As O
a O
direct O
preparation O
for O
the O
Tour B-MISC
, O
Vandenbroucke O
actually O
preferred O
to O
ride O
the O
Dauphiné B-MISC
( O
4 O
- O
11 O
June O
) O
and O
the O
Route B-MISC
du I-MISC
Sud I-MISC
( O
17 O
- O
20 O
June O
) O
instead O
of O
the O
team O
's O
planned O
Round B-MISC
of I-MISC
Luxembourg I-MISC
( O
8 O
- O
11 O
June O
) O
and O
the O
Round B-MISC
of I-MISC
Switzerland I-MISC
( O
13 O
- O
22 O
June O
) O
. O

However O
, O
the O
Kempenaar B-MISC
was O
satisfied O
with O
this O
test O
in O
view O
of O
the O
Tour B-MISC
de I-MISC
France I-MISC
which O
is O
so O
much O
more O
important O
to O
him O
. O

“ O
As O
far O
as O
I O
know O
, O
there O
are O
regular O
runners O
who O
are O
key O
to O
their O
program O
. O

Van B-PER
de I-PER
Wouwer I-PER
had O
already O
known O
that O
Elli B-PER
would O
be O
the O
man O
to O
beat O
. O

Section O
of O

I O
do O
not O
panic O
yet O
, O
but O
there O
will O
no O
longer O
be O
any O
new O
obstacles O
on O
the O
path O
of O
my O
preparation O
. O

“ O
At O
least O
a O
lot O
less O
than O
expected O
. O

After O
100 O
miles O
, O
he O
looked O
at O
it O
. O

One O
thing O
may O
be O
clear O
about O
all O
this O
: O
the O
end O
of O
the O
‘ O
Vandenbroucke B-MISC
- I-MISC
story I-MISC
’ O
is O
far O
from O
in O
sight O
. O

15 O
is O

There O
were O
still O
a O
few O
matches O
needed O
for O
the O
World B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
before O
the O
dèclic O
announced O
itself O
. O

Frank B-PER
Vandenbroucke I-PER
gives O
up O
in O
Wallonia B-MISC
GP I-MISC
: O
' O
It O
's O
not O
going O
well O
with O
me O
' O

Simply O
because O
there O
is O
more O
recovery O
time O
between O
the O
first O
combination O
. O

The O
Belgians B-MISC
who O
are O
already O
there O
are O
Dave B-PER
Bruylants I-PER
, O
yesterday O
second O
, O
and O
Kurt B-PER
Van I-PER
de I-PER
Wauwer I-PER
, O
third O
. O

IEF B-PER
dismissed I-PER

Prior O
to O
the O
start O
of O
the O
game O
, O
he O
had O
called O
reaching O
the O
top O
condition O
a O
matter O
of O
days O
, O
but O
barely O
two O
slopes O
further O
cycling O
he O
turned O
out O
to O
be O
behind O
in O
the O
peloton O
. O

The O
following O
task O
surprised O
no O
one O
. O

The O
page O

Meanwhile O
, O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
has O
also O
understood O
that O
he O
is O
not O
currently O
in O
a O
position O
to O
make O
demands O
in O
connection O
with O
his O
preparation O
program O
for O
the O
Tour B-MISC
. O

Edited O

» O

“ O
The O
condition O
is O
good O
, O
but O
not O
super O
. O

I O
was O
driven O
every O
quarter O
of O
an O
hour O
. O

The O
Author O

Yesterday O
he O
gave O
up O
in O
the O
only O
Belgian B-MISC
race O
he O
would O
drive O
on O
Belgian B-MISC
soil O
. O

While O
Alberto B-PER
Elli I-PER
from O
Walter B-PER
Godefroot I-PER
's O
Telekom O
team O
wrote O
the O
GP B-MISC
of I-MISC
Wallonia I-MISC
( O
1.2 O
) O
on O
his O
name O
, O
a O
freshly O
washed O
and O
dressed O
Frank B-PER
Vandenbroucke I-PER
sat O
in O
the O
company O
of O
his O
Italian B-MISC
girlfriend O
Sara B-PER
long O
thinking O
about O
how O
to O
go O
on O
with O
him O
. O

But O
now O
I O
will O
have O
to O
give O
up O
on O
the O
arrangement O
as O
set O
forth O
by O
the O
team O
management O
. O

Name B-LOC
of O

Vandenbroucke B-PER
: O
“ O
I O
do O
not O
panic O
yet O
, O
but O
there O
will O
be O
no O
new O
obstacles O
in O
my O
Tour B-MISC
preparation I-MISC
. O
” O

Not O
that O
I O
’m O
sick O
, O
but O
I O
just O
do O
n’t O
have O
acceleration O
in O
my O
legs O
. O

Bruylants B-PER
, O
still O
just O
fourteen O
days O
on O
track O
, O
had O
to O
pay O
his O
attempt O
to O
get O
Elli B-PER
back O
with O
cramps O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
New O
to O
his O
director O
Patrice B-PER
Toye I-PER
( O
from O
the O
award O
- O
winning O
film O
Rosie B-MISC
) O
and O
Marion B-PER
Oprel I-PER
, O
friend O
of O
Marianne B-PER
' O
De B-MISC
Mol I-MISC
) O
Dupont B-PER
. O

shortly O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Agalev B-ORG
says O
he O
wants O
to O
make O
Antwerp B-LOC
once O
again O
an O
open O
, O
vibrant O
metropolis O
. O

Edited O

A O
few O
twenty O
have O
already O
registered O
and O
will O
get O
a O
place O
on O
the O
elaborate O
lists O
that O
will O
be O
announced O
later O
. O

The O
senior O
party O
Worth O
to O
Become O
Elderly B-ORG
( O
WOW B-ORG
) O
will O
take O
part O
in O
the O
municipal O
, O
district O
and O
provincial O
council O
elections O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
on O
8 O
October O
. O

WOW B-ORG
is O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC

Journals B-MISC

There O
was O
a O
moment O
of O
doubt O
about O
this O
when O
a O
member O
of O
the O
municipal O
council O
moved O
to O
the O
VLD B-ORG
and O
his O
colleague O
in O
the O
provincial O
council O
went O
to O
the O
Flemish B-ORG
Block I-ORG
. O

Singer O
, O
showman O
and O
presenter O
Marcel B-PER
Vanthilt I-PER
will O
be O
on O
the O
list O
of O
Agalev B-ORG
at O
the O
next O
municipal O
council O
elections O
in O
Antwerp O
. O

The O
page O

» O

He O
gets O
31st O
place O
and O
is O
part O
of O
the O
so O
- O
called O
cordon O
cultural O
on O
the O
green O
list O
. O

Number O
one O
on O
the O
list O
for O
the O
province O
is O
Frans B-PER
Verbergt I-PER
, O
who O
has O
been O
provincial O
councillor O
for O
the O
VLD B-ORG
for O
ten O
years O
. O

The O
list O
for O
the O
municipality O
is O
headed O
by O
André B-PER
Crahay I-PER
, O
a O
former O
bank O
worker O
who O
is O
relatively O
new O
to O
politics O
. O

" O
We O
are O
the O
alternative O
" O
, O
the O
slogan O
with O
which O
WOW B-ORG
is O
drawing O
to O
the O
elections O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
. O

Vanthilt B-PER
is O
far O
from O
the O
only O
BV B-MISC
on O
the O
Antwerp B-MISC
Agalev B-MISC
list I-MISC
. O

Publication O
Date O

Actress O
Jeanine B-PER
Bisschops I-PER
and O
author O
Tom B-PER
Lanoye I-PER
had O
previously O
vowed O
. O

" O
That O
does O
n't O
come O
with O
terrorists O
and O
black O
- O
lookers O
, O
" O
the O
party O
argues O
, O
" O
we O
have O
the O
lake O
for O
green O
, O
the O
color O
of O
hope O
. O

The O
Author O

Section O
of O

Generally O

At O
the O
municipal O
level O
, O
the O
party O
wants O
to O
implement O
general O
voting O
rights O
and O
in O
the O
district O
of O
Antwerp B-LOC
, O
the O
Greens B-MISC
hope O
to O
become O
the O
largest O
party O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

In O
addition O
, O
Agalev B-MISC
- I-MISC
Antwerp I-MISC
outputs O
with O
a O
list O
of O
Known B-MISC
Flamings I-MISC
who O
support O
the O
party O
program O
, O
but O
are O
not O
on O
the O
list O
. O

According O
to O
Cahay B-PER
, O
his O
party O
profile O
itself O
as O
a O
link O
between O
ages O
, O
which O
means O
that O
young O
people O
also O
get O
a O
chance O
. O

Artists O
for O
Agalev B-ORG

Publication O
of O

by O
Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

The O
actresses O
Sarah B-PER
de I-PER
Bosschere I-PER
, O
Veerle B-PER
Dobbelaere I-PER
and O
Patricia B-PER
Goemaere I-PER
, O
writer O
Kristien B-PER
Hemmerechts I-PER
, O
musician O
and O
concert O
organizer O
Paul B-PER
Ambach I-PER
, O
actor O
Pol B-PER
Goossen I-PER
, O
authors O
Paul B-PER
Mennes I-PER
, O
Bart B-PER
Moeyaert I-PER
and O
Jeroen B-PER
Olyslaeghers I-PER
, O
and O
actor O
Carl B-PER
Ridders I-PER
signed O
for O
the O
program O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
" O
We O
leave O
that O
to O
the O
mediators O
" O
, O
so O
it O
was O
called O
yesterday O
-- O

First O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
have O
to O
leave O
, O
but O
there O
they O
have O
no O
ears O
for O
in O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
. O

» O

Foreign B-MISC

However O
, O
observers O
say O
that O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
have O
withdrawn O
from O
the O
two O
western O
cities O
of O
Barentu B-LOC
and O
Tessenay B-LOC
, O
which O
were O
captured O
during O
the O
most O
recent O
offensive O
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
wants O
to O
adhere O
to O
the O
four O
- O
point O
plan O
of O
the O
Organization B-ORG
of I-ORG
African I-ORG
Unity I-ORG
. O

This O
includes O
sending O
international O
observers O
to O
the O
disputed O
border O
zone O
. O

Asmara B-LOC
wants O
to O
hear O
of O
a O
stock O
only O
if O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
are O
withdrawn O
. O

“ O
We O
would O
like O
to O
return O
to O
our O
positions O
of O
6 O
May O
1998 O
( O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
war O
, O
MR B-PER
) O
, O
” O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
minister O
said O
. O

Ethiopia B-LOC
did O
that O
after O
it O
had O
regained O
all O
territory O
lost O
after O
the O
Eritrean B-MISC
invasion O
in O
' O
98 O
. O

Section O
of O

Well O
, O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
now O
wants O
guarantees O
for O
its O
troops O
, O
which O
penetrated O
deeply O
into O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
will O
withdraw O
. O

Opposing O
views O
on O
when O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
should O
withdraw O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Publication O
Date O

Eritrea B-LOC
, O
according O
to O
the O
BBC B-MISC
correspondent I-MISC
in O
Asmara B-LOC
, O
is O
very O
humiliated O
by O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
ruling O
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
and O
Ethiopia O
disagree O
on O
stocks O

Moreover O
, O
the O
current O
situation O
is O
widely O
interpreted O
as O
one O
in O
which O
Ethiopia B-LOC
, O
due O
to O
its O
recent O
military O
successes O
, O
can O
dictate O
the O
laws O
, O
and O
that O
is O
unacceptable O
for O
Asmara B-LOC
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
called O
the O
whole O
case O
strange O
. O

But O
according O
to O
the O
BCC B-ORG
, O
the O
Eritrean B-MISC
city O
of O
Zenefe B-LOC
remains O
occupied O
by O
Ethiopian B-MISC
soldiers O
. O

Generally O

But O
then O
we O
want O
to O
make O
sure O
that O
Eritrea B-LOC
does O
not O
repeat O
the O
madness O
of O
simply O
invading O
a O
neighboring O
country O
. O

The O
persecution O
agencies O

Ethiopia O
says O
the O
ghetto O
is O
over O
, O
but O
Eritrea B-LOC
does O
not O
share O
that O
view O
. O

This O
is O
where O
the O
shoe O
runs O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

The O
page O

Edited O

Publication O
of O

What O
guarantees O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
wants O
, O
was O
not O
immediately O
clear O
. O

It O
’s O
a O
bit O
like O
hitting O
with O
one O
hand O
: O
Ethiopia O
and O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
which O
have O
been O
at O
war O
for O
two O
years O
, O
are O
sitting O
in O
Algiers B-LOC
around O
the O
negotiating O
table O
. O

Algiers B-LOC

Ouyahia B-PER
called O
the O
statement O
by O
Ethiopian B-MISC
Foreign O
Minister O
Seyoum B-PER
Mesfin I-PER
that O
the O
war O
was O
over O
" O
an O
encouraging O
thing O
" O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
cartographers O
should O
remark O
the O
border O
, O
there O
should O
be O
financial O
compensation O
for O
the O
losses O
on O
both O
sides O
, O
and O
finally O
, O
an O
in O
- O
depth O
investigation O
of O
the O
causes O
of O
the O
conflict O
is O
also O
desirable O
. O

Algeria B-MISC
’s I-MISC
Justice O
Minister O
Ahmed B-PER
Ouyahia I-PER
has O
been O
trying O
to O
mediate O
since O
Tuesday O
in O
the O
two O
- O
year O
- O
old O
conflict O
between O
Ethiopia O
and O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
which O
resumed O
the O
last O
three O
weeks O
when O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
army O
crossed O
the O
border O
. O

Maarten B-PER
Rabaey I-PER

How O
can O
they O
say O
that O
the O
war O
is O
over O
? O

The O
Author O

We O
will O
not O
close O
up O
as O
long O
as O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
are O
not O
far O
beyond O
100 O
km O
from O
Asmara B-LOC
, O
” O
said O
Eritrean B-MISC
presidential O
adviser O
Yemane B-PER
Gebremeskel I-PER
. O

But O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
will O
do O
so O
only O
if O
there O
are O
international O
guarantees O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Belgian B-ORG
/ O
Own O
reporting O

Generally O

A O
tax O
reform O
should O
also O
end O
the O
discrimination O
between O
married O
and O
cohabiting O
persons O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

ACW B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Theo B-PER
Rombouts I-PER
wants O
the O
upcoming O
tax O
reform O
to O
benefit O
especially O
people O
with O
low O
incomes O
. O

Wages O
have O
fallen O
below O
half O
the O
national O
income O
and O
that O
is O
no O
longer O
acceptable O
. O

The O
page O

Publication O
Date O

Journals B-MISC

Part O
of O
it O
should O
go O
to O
social O
security O
and O
part O
should O
be O
saved O
. O

In O
his O
speech O
in O
Mechelen B-LOC
, O
Cortebeeck B-PER
stated O
that O
in O
addition O
to O
social O
benefits O
, O
wages O
have O
also O
been O
hit O
behind O
. O

During O
the O
next O
intersectoral O
negotiations O
, O
the O
Christian O
trade O
union O
will O
therefore O
commit O
itself O
to O
gradual O
wage O
increases O
as O
the O
best O
and O
most O
proven O
means O
to O
distribute O
the O
fruits O
of O
growth O
. O

Financial O
participation O
can O
not O
close O
the O
wage O
gap O
, O
Cortebeeck B-PER
says O
. O

The O
Christian O
trade O
union O
is O
in O
favor O
of O
a O
gradual O
increase O
in O
wages O
and O
social O
benefits O
, O
said O
ACV B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Luc B-PER
Cortebeeck I-PER
in O
his O
Rerum B-MISC
Novarum I-MISC
speech I-MISC
. O

Mechelen B-LOC
and O
Brussels B-LOC

This O
should O
be O
accompanied O
by O
an O
increase O
in O
the O
net O
income O
of O
low O
- O
income O
individuals O
and O
families O
with O
dependent O
children O
. O

The O
Author O

" O
We O
have O
not O
handed O
over O
for O
years O
to O
put O
the O
money O
for O
pensions O
and O
health O
care O
now O
in O
the O
hands O
of O
the O
private O
sector O
, O
" O
said O
the O
ACV B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
. O

He O
forced O
the O
government O
not O
to O
simply O
enrich O
the O
private O
insurance O
companies O
by O
entrusting O
them O
with O
the O
benefits O
of O
reducing O
the O
state O
debt O
. O

Section O
of O

Not O
all O
new O
government O
revenues O
should O
be O
reserved O
for O
aging O
, O
according O
to O
Cortebeeck B-PER
. O

In O
profit O
participation O
, O
part O
of O
employee O
income O
is O
made O
dependent O
on O
too O
many O
arbitrary O
decisions O
. O

Therefore O
, O
the O
ACW B-ORG
advocates O
an O
increase O
in O
deductible O
professional O
costs O
for O
wage O
and O
bettors O
and O
a O
higher O
initial O
tax O
- O
free O
discount O
of O
labor O
income O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

by O
Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

Also O
ACW B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Theo B-PER
Rombouts I-PER
pledged O
in O
his O
speech O
in O
Wemmel B-LOC
for O
a O
tax O
reduction O
that O
should O
prioritize O
income O
from O
labor O
and O
especially O
on O
the O
longer O
income O
. O

The O
available O
resources O
can O
be O
better O
used O
to O
strengthen O
the O
foundations O
of O
society O
, O
such O
as O
education O
and O
care O
, O
public O
transport O
and O
roads O
, O
food O
security O
, O
etc O
. O
Improvement O
for O
low O
incomes O
can O
only O
come O
through O
an O
increase O
in O
the O
subsistence O
minimum O
, O
guaranteed O
income O
and O
social O
benefits O
. O

Profit O
sharing O
assumes O
power O
sharing O
, O
but O
that O
is O
not O
granted O
to O
us O
, O
Cortebeeck B-PER
said O
, O
because O
employers O
do O
not O
want O
to O
know O
of O
a O
pre O
- O
negotiated O
CAO B-MISC
on O
the O
matter O
. O

ACV B-ORG
prefers O
wage O
increase O
over O
profit O
participation O

The O
trade O
union O
leader O
argued O
that O
the O
active O
welfare O
state O
also O
has O
shadow O
sides O
. O

Finally O
, O
Rombouts B-PER
asked O
for O
tax O
incentives O
to O
start O
living O
more O
environmentally O
friendly O
. O

The O
self O
- O
employed O
were O
already O
served O
with O
1.5 O
billion O
francs O
, O
but O
the O
social O
benefits O
providers O
such O
as O
the O
disabled O
, O
the O
disabled O
and O
the O
unemployed O
in O
financial O
need O
get O
nothing O
and O
are O
on O
an O
ever O
greater O
backdrop O
. O

Rerum B-MISC
Novarum I-MISC
speeches I-MISC
point O
to O
the O
shadow O
side O
of O
active O
welfare O
state O

Edited O

Publication O
of O

A O
movement O
to O
collect O
wages O
and O
benefits O
is O
preferable O
, O
according O
to O
the O
trade O
union O
leader O
, O
to O
allow O
employees O
to O
participate O
in O
the O
profits O
of O
their O
company O
. O

Cortebeeck B-PER
sees O
a O
tax O
reform O
, O
but O
is O
opposed O
to O
a O
general O
tax O
reduction O
. O

In O
any O
case O
, O
that O
formula O
requires O
participation O
in O
the O
profit O
determination O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Sunday O
during O
the O
day O
, O
a O
back O
of O
high O
pressure O
builds O
up O
from O
the O
southwest O
, O
gradually O
stabilizing O
the O
atmosphere O
. O

Publication O
Date O

Some O
of O
them O
could O
grow O
into O
a O
loose O
mood O
in O
the O
west O
by O
the O
evening O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Section O
of O

As O
a O
third O
factor O
, O
there O
is O
a O
cold O
front O
coming O
closer O
from O
the O
west O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
the O
thermal O
vore O
lies O
in O
our O
surroundings O
. O

As O
of O
Sunday O
it O
will O
be O
less O
hot O
. O

Eddy B-PER
De I-PER
Mey I-PER

Sunny O
this O
morning O
. O

The O
page O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Sunny O
this O
morning O
. O

The O
pressure O
of O
the O
colder O
air O
causes O
strong O
rising O
movements O
to O
take O
place O
throughout O
the O
day O
. O

The O
summer O
warm O
. O

Tomorrow O
increasing O
chance O
of O
rain O
and O
storms O
, O
followed O
by O
cooling O
. O

May O
was O
warmer O
than O
usual O
. O

The O
wind O
is O
generally O
weak O
and O
blows O
mainly O
from O
directions O
between O
south O
and O
southwest O
. O

Temperatures O
of O
25 O
degrees O
and O
above O
are O
reachable O
this O
afternoon O
. O

Edited O

The O
storm O
tomorrow O

The O
sun O
thus O
becomes O
pronounced O
master O
of O
the O
situation O
and O
the O
mercury O
goes O
on O
adventure O
. O

There O
is O
virtually O
no O
cloud O
. O

In O
many O
places O
, O
mercury O
does O
not O
or O
barely O
fall O
below O
20 O
degrees O
before O
midnight O
. O

After O
the O
weekend O
, O
the O
weather O
does O
not O
look O
bad O
, O
but O
also O
not O
quite O
steady O
. O

There O
were O
86 O
liters O
of O
rainfall O
in O
20 O
days O
against O
normal O
62 O
liters O
in O
15 O
days O
. O

19,1 O
( O
the O
norm O
of O
17,2 O
) O
. O

On O
the O
flank O
of O
a O
more O
or O
less O
stationary O
high O
- O
rise O
over O
Central B-LOC
and O
Eastern B-LOC
Europe I-LOC
today O
, O
with O
a O
southern O
flow O
, O
warm O
and O
initially O
stable O
air O
comes O
from O
France B-LOC
. O

The O
current O
that O
is O
anti O
- O
cyclonal O
today O
will O
be O
cyclonal O
tomorrow O
. O

Min O
. O
11.3 O
( O
the O
norm O
8.3 O
) O
. O

and O
max B-PER
. O

Generally O

A O
single O
bui O
can O
have O
hail O
on O
board O
and O
locally O
dissolve O
as O
much O
water O
that O
discomfort O
occurs O
. O

In O
the O
night O
of O
Saturday O
to O
Sunday O
, O
the O
cold O
front O
moves O
through O
the O
country O
. O

Even O
clouds O
this O
afternoon O
. O

Later O
also O
stack O
clouds O
and O
tonight O
a O
small O
chance O
of O
a O
buzz O
. O

The O
sun O
shone O
little O
( O
less O
than O
159 O
hours O
) O
against O
normal O
199 O
hours O
. O

Publication O
of O

Tonight O
it O
will O
remain O
very O
warm O
for O
a O
long O
time O
and O
it O
is O
ideal O
for O
garden O
or O
terrace O
weather O
. O

As O
a O
result O
, O
the O
likelihood O
of O
storms O
, O
as O
the O
afternoon O
and O
evening O
progress O
, O
increases O
. O

The O
Author O

As O
a O
thermal O
vorte O
approaches O
, O
now O
still O
above O
the O
west O
of O
France B-LOC
, O
the O
atmosphere O
becomes O
somewhat O
unstable O
in O
the O
afternoon O
, O
resulting O
in O
a O
number O
of O
stack O
clouds O
. O

Meanwhile B-MISC

Tomorrow O
increasing O
chance O
of O
rain O
and O
storms O
, O
followed O
by O
cooling O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Is O
this O
health O
standard O
often O
exceeded O
? O

More O
interesting O
is O
the O
new O
Dutch B-MISC
initiative O
of O
toll O
gates O
and O
billing O
around O
the O
major O
Dutch B-MISC
cities O
. O

Two O
Brussels B-MISC
environmental O
movements O
, O
Bral B-ORG
and O
Inter B-ORG
- I-ORG
Environnement I-ORG
... O

Studies O
have O
shown O
that O
car O
traffic O
is O
responsible O
for O
more O
than O
70 O
percent O
of O
the O
high O
ozone O
concentrations O
. O

The O
countries O
around O
us O
have O
been O
working O
on O
such O
measures O
for O
a O
while O
, O
but O
Belgium B-LOC
is O
behind O
. O

The O
page O

It O
does O
not O
differ O
so O
much O
from O
the O
old O
ozone O
plan O
announced O
in O
1996 O
. O

French B-MISC
cities O
such O
as O
Paris B-LOC
then O
work O
again O
with O
alternating O
driving O
bans O
, O
where O
even O
or O
uneven O
number O
plates O
are O
not O
allowed O
to O
drive O
during O
ozone O
peaks O
. O

The O
Author O

Several O
German B-MISC
states O
have O
already O
introduced O
temporary O
speed O
limits O
. O

That O
is O
regrettable O
. O

by O
Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogert I-PER

For O
Brussels B-LOC
, O
these O
measures O
could O
be O
combined O
with O
the O
rapid O
development O
of O
a O
real O
Brussels B-MISC
suburban O
network O
with O
large O
transfer O
parking O
spaces O
. O

Last O
year O
it O
was O
exceeded O
by O
27 O
days O
in O
Brussels B-LOC
. O

If O
you O
are O
right O
, O
what O
will O
you O
do O
with O
the O
money O
in O
case O
of O
an O
excess O
? O

During O
days O
of O
high O
ozone O
levels O
, O
people O
at O
risk O
are O
asked O
to O
stay O
inside O
until O
the O
“ O
danger O
” O
has O
passed O
. O

Publication O
of O

What O
measures O
apply O
abroad O
? O

This O
means O
that O
elderly O
people O
, O
children O
or O
people O
with O
asthma O
problems O
were O
constantly O
at O
serious O
health O
risks O
. O

Opinion B-MISC

» O

That O
is O
a O
significant O
amount O
, O
just O
to O
force O
the O
policy O
to O
take O
structural O
measures O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
. O

If O
we O
receive O
money O
then O
we O
will O
transfer O
it O
to O
a O
fund O
that O
can O
help O
me O
to O
finance O
, O
for O
example O
, O
the O
Brussels B-MISC
suburban O
network O
. O

However O
, O
it O
was O
announced O
that O
the O
maximum O
speed O
would O
be O
limited O
. O

The O
tariffs O
are O
high O
enough O
to O
keep O
a O
large O
number O
of O
cars O
off O
the O
road O
. O

Edited O

» O

" O
The O
Federal O
Ozone O
Plan O
is O
disappointing O
" O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

It O
also O
contradicts O
Article O
23 O
of O
the O
Constitution O
, O
which O
guarantees O
“ O
human O
dignity O
” O
to O
everyone O
. O

Given O
the O
number O
of O
surpluses O
in O
1999 O
, O
you O
can O
quickly O
become O
rich O
. O

Another O
study O
found O
that O
during O
the O
1994 O
heatwave O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
1,200 O
people O
died O
due O
to O
the O
high O
concentrations O
of O
ozone O
during O
that O
period O
. O

The O
federal O
government O
has O
just O
announced O
its O
ozone O
plan O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

“ O
Every O
time O
the O
so O
- O
called O
European B-MISC
health O
standard O
of O
120 O
micrograms O
of O
ozone O
per O
cubic O
meter O
is O
exceeded O
in O
Brussels B-LOC
for O
at O
least O
eight O
hours O
, O
we O
demand O
compensation O
of O
50 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
. O

» O

“ O
The O
work O
disappointed O
us O
. O

Generally O

» O

» O

“ O
It O
’s O
not O
about O
money O
, O
let O
’s O
be O
clear O
. O

The O
case O
will O
be O
brought O
before O
the O
court O
of O
first O
instance O
in O
short O
litigation O
on O
9 O
June O
. O

The O
ministers O
Magda B-PER
Aelvoet I-PER
and O
Isabelle B-PER
Durant I-PER
. O

The O
emphasis O
is O
on O
information O
and O
awareness O
raising O
, O
while O
few O
measures O
are O
in O
place O
to O
limit O
car O
traffic O
during O
the O
summer O
months O
. O

It O
is O
unacceptable O
that O
the O
government O
with O
this O
knowledge O
does O
not O
want O
to O
intervene O
or O
barely O
wants O
to O
intervene O
. O

This O
has O
not O
been O
done O
by O
the O
Greens O
. O

Section O
of O

What O
exactly O
is O
your O
demand O
? O

( O
by O
PJB B-PER
) O

Publication O
Date O

The O
DocStart O
Edition O

The O
page O

In O
total O
, O
he O
made O
about O
fifteen O
phone O
calls O
, O
including O
to O
the O
cabinets O
and O
departments O
of O
Transport B-ORG
, O
Economic B-ORG
Affairs I-ORG
and O
Finance B-ORG
. O

My O
mission O
was O
limited O
to O
signaling O
possible O
political O
problems O
. O

" O
According O
to O
Gantman B-PER
, O
a O
legal O
change O
in O
corporate O
tax O
on O
the O
value O
- O
added O
tax O
regime O
came O
about O
abnormally O
slowly O
, O
" O
Larmuseau B-PER
said O
. O

Larmuseau B-PER
replied O
that O
he O
did O
not O
find O
Gantman B-PER
's O
question O
wrong O
and O
credible O
. O

Publication O
of O

“ O
It O
’s O
been O
so O
long O
ago O
, O
I O
can O
hardly O
remember O
. O

Hendrik B-PER
Larmuseau I-PER
, O
a O
former O
adviser O
to O
the O
social O
- O
economic O
cabinet O
of O
Prime O
Minister O
Jean O
- O
Luc B-PER
Dehaene I-PER
( O
CVP B-ORG
) O
, O
stated O
on O
Wednesday O
to O
the O
Ship O
Loans O
Investigative O
Committee O
that O
Antwerp B-MISC
lawyer O
André B-PER
Gantman I-PER
, O
as O
lobbyist O
of O
shipwoman O
Rosenfeld B-PER
, O
was O
also O
active O
in O
the O
cabinet O
of O
the O
Prime O
Minister O
. O

Section O
of O

According O
to O
him O
, O
he O
was O
not O
heard O
in O
the O
Ministry O
of O
Finance B-ORG
. O

» O

» O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

» O

» O

Generally O

Larmuseau B-PER
had O
two O
other O
meetings O
with O
Gantman B-PER
in O
the O
spring O
of O
1994 O
and O
was O
able O
to O
inform O
the O
lawyer O
as O
a O
result O
of O
his O
investigation O
that O
the O
law O
change O
was O
going O
according O
to O
normal O
procedures O
. O

After O
all O
, O
in O
such O
a O
cabinet O
you O
are O
constantly O
addressed O
by O
all O
sorts O
of O
people O
who O
need O
something O
. O

Gantman B-PER
lobbied O
with O
Prime O
Minister O
Dehaene B-PER

Karel B-PER
De I-PER
Gucht I-PER
: O
“ O
Did O
you O
do O
this O
for O
any O
unknown O
? O
” O

“ O
He O
complained O
about O
it O
. O

“ O
Did O
you O
do O
this O
to O
any O
unknown O
? O
” O
he O
asked O
the O
witness O
. O

But O
about O
that O
working O
group O
Larmuseau B-PER
could O
hardly O
remember O
anything O
. O

According O
to O
Larmuseau B-PER
, O
Gantman B-PER
first O
appeared O
in O
his O
office O
in O
April O
1994 O
, O
without O
having O
made O
an O
appointment O
by O
telephone O
. O

Brussels B-LOC

" O
It O
seemed O
like O
an O
important O
problem O
, O
I O
thought O
it O
was O
my O
duty O
to O
check O
this O
. O

Publication O
Date O

I O
did O
not O
participate O
in O
negotiations O
on O
the O
tax O
issue O
. O

He O
also O
personally O
informed O
Prime O
Minister O
Dehaene B-PER
of O
the O
problem O
raised O
by O
Gantman B-PER
. O

The O
Author O

The O
cabinet O
adviser O
of O
the O
prime O
minister O
immediately O
took O
action O
. O

“ O
I O
’ve O
passively O
experienced O
a O
maximum O
of O
one O
or O
two O
meetings O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O

The O
then O
Finance B-ORG
Minister O
Philippe B-PER
Maystadt I-PER
( O
PSC B-ORG
) O
blocked O
the O
file O
, O
as O
Gantman B-PER
seemed O
to O
insinuate O
. O

by O
Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

Commissioner O
Karel B-PER
De I-PER
Gucht I-PER
( O
VLD B-ORG
) O
was O
surprised O
by O
so O
much O
zeal O
. O

( O
by O
GT B-PER
) O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Journals B-MISC

own O
reporting O

In O
the O
same O
period O
, O
Larmuseau B-PER
was O
also O
a O
member O
of O
the O
inter O
- O
cabinet O
group O
around O
ABC B-ORG
Containerline I-ORG
, O
which O
was O
specifically O
established O
to O
solve O
the O
tax O
problems O
arising O
in O
the O
context O
of O
the O
proposed O
acquisition O
of O
the O
shipping O
company O
by O
American B-MISC
scammer O
Gary B-PER
Blonder I-PER
. O

Docking O
- O
17 O

The O
International B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
needs O
to O
listen O
more O
to O
the O
people O
and O
less O
to O
impose O
its O
will O
on O
countries O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
often O
tends O
to O
exhort O
countries O
, O
but O
one O
of O
the O
lessons O
of O
the O
financial O
crises O
in O
Asia B-LOC
is O
that O
it O
should O
listen O
better O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
itself O
should O
be O
the O
driving O
force O
behind O
such O
changes O
. O

Köhler B-PER
said O
he O
would O
like O
to O
talk O
about O
an O
Asian B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
, O
a O
plan O
that O
the O
major O
industrialized O
countries O
and O
the O
IMF B-ORG
leaders O
have O
long O
been O
discussing O
. O

This O
led O
to O
the O
call O
for O
changes O
in O
the O
policy O
within O
the O
Fund O
. O

people B-MISC

The O
Prime O
Minister O
of O
Thailand B-LOC
, O
Chuan B-PER
Leekpai I-PER
, O
asked O
Köhler B-PER
to O
draw O
lessons O
from O
“ O
what O
happened O
in O
our O
country O
” O
. O

In O
Europe B-LOC
there O
is O
a O
monetary O
union O
and O
there O
is O
nothing O
against O
such O
unions O
anymore O
, O
the O
IMF B-MISC
chief I-MISC
said O
. O

by O
John B-PER
Vandaele I-PER

Publication O
of O

The O
page O

He O
called O
on O
the O
board O
to O
develop O
a O
clear O
vision O
of O
the O
IMF B-ORG
’s O
future O
role O
in O
the O
coming O
months O
. O

Edited O

In O
Thailand B-LOC
, O
the O
financial O
crisis O
began O
in O
July O
1997 O
and O
then O
struck O
a O
number O
of O
Asian B-MISC
countries O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

According O
to O
the O
Thai B-MISC
prime O
minister O
, O
it O
is O
much O
more O
expensive O
to O
capture O
the O
consequences O
of O
a O
crisis O
than O
to O
prevent O
a O
crisis O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
has O
received O
a O
lot O
of O
criticism O
for O
not O
seeing O
the O
problems O
in O
Asia B-LOC
come O
on O
time O
. O

Publication O
Date O

Horst B-PER
Köhler I-PER

This O
was O
stated O
by O
Horst B-PER
Köhler I-PER
, O
the O
IMF B-ORG
chief O
who O
took O
office O
in O
May O
, O
yesterday O
in O
Bangkok B-LOC
, O
from O
where O
he O
makes O
a O
tour O
of O
Asia B-LOC
. O

It O
is O
up O
to O
the O
Asian B-MISC
countries O
themselves O
to O
decide O
on O
their O
own O
monetary O
fund O
, O
Köhler B-PER
said O
. O

The O
administration O
should O
take O
the O
lead O
and O
not O
let O
itself O
be O
dictated O
by O
, O
for O
example O
, O
the O
U.S. B-MISC
Congress B-ORG
, O
says O
Köhler B-PER
. O

Director O
of O
the O
IMF B-ORG

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Listening O
more O

Section O
of O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Tomorrow I-MISC

Generally O

by O
AFP B-ORG

The O
Author O

-DOCSTART O
- O
Date O
of O
publication O

No O
one O
can O
or O
wants O
to O
intervene O
. O

Publication O
of O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

The O
page O

Koekelberg B-LOC
, O
Ganshoren B-LOC
, O
Jette B-LOC
and O
St. B-LOC
Agatha I-LOC
- O
Berchem O
, O
each O
of O
whom O
have O
a O
piece O
of O
the O
infamous O
basilica O
on O
their O
territory O
, O
can O
no O
longer O
release O
additional O
money O
for O
the O
necessary O
renovation O
and O
stabilization O
works O
in O
the O
coming O
years O
. O

However O
, O
it O
is O
not O
clear O
which O
ministry O
or O
department O
it O
should O
be O
. O

Simonet B-PER
referred O
the O
concerns O
to O
Interior B-ORG
Minister O
Antoine B-PER
Duquesne I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
. O

Simonet B-PER
promised O
to O
study O
the O
problem O
of O
the O
basilica O
at O
the O
federal O
level O
. O

The O
four O
Brussels B-MISC
municipalities O
that O
are O
now O
paying O
for O
the O
maintenance O
costs O
of O
the O
Basilica B-LOC
of I-LOC
Koekelberg I-LOC
suffered O
another O
emergency O
cry O
. O

The O
basilica O
threatens O
to O
become O
a O
second O
atomium B-LOC
. O

The O
four O
mayors O
demand O
that O
the O
federal O
government O
finally O
agree O
with O
money O
over O
the O
bridge O
for O
the O
distressing O
" O
national O
" O
monument O
. O

( O
by O
PJB B-PER
) O

Generally O

Koekelberg B-LOC
Basilica I-LOC
to O
Become O
Second O
Atomium B-LOC

The B-MISC
life I-MISC

Section O
of O

The O
four O
mayors O
discussed O
their O
turmoil O
with O
Brussels B-MISC
Prime O
Minister O
Jacques B-PER
Simonet I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
during O
his O
tour O
of O
the O
nineteen O
Brussels B-MISC
municipalities O
. O

Edited O

by O
Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogert I-PER

As O
a O
national O
sanctuary O
, O
the O
basilica O
appears O
not O
to O
belong O
to O
the O
Directorate B-MISC
of I-MISC
Buildings I-MISC
, O
nor O
can O
the O
Ministry O
of O
Justice B-ORG
( O
which O
finances O
the O
recognized O
religions O
) O
intervene O
because O
the O
basilica O
is O
not O
officially O
a O
church O
or O
cathedral O
. O

For O
years O
there O
have O
been O
cracks O
visible O
and O
sometimes O
debris O
comes O
down O
. O

The O
Author O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

“ O
DocStart O
” O

The O
system O
was O
discontinued O
in O
1990 O
because O
its O
administration O
cost O
a O
bit O
and O
because O
it O
became O
increasingly O
difficult O
to O
distinguish O
between O
speculative O
and O
real O
transactions O
. O

Publication O
Date O

Publication O
of O

I O
am O
not O
a O
priori O
against O
a O
modest O
tax O
on O
condition O
that O
it O
happens O
at O
a O
global O
level O
. O

» O

He O
sees O
more O
in O
targeted O
actions O
: O
national O
states O
taking O
measures O
against O
short O
- O
term O
cash O
flows O
. O

The O
page O

They O
believe O
that O
a O
global O
tax O
on O
currency O
exchange O
can O
not O
only O
prevent O
socially O
disruptive O
monetary O
crises O
but O
also O
waste O
money O
to O
contribute O
to O
development O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
the O
Senate B-ORG
Finance I-ORG
Committee O
wants O
to O
gain O
a O
better O
insight O
into O
the O
feasibility O
and O
desirability O
of O
the O
tax O
through O
hearings O
with O
experts O
and O
stakeholders O
. O

The O
hearing O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

However O
, O
he O
doubts O
that O
the O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
is O
the O
best O
way O
to O
it O
. O

Section O
of O

Internationally O
, O
a O
whole O
movement O
around O
the O
taxation O
grew O
named O
after O
the O
American B-MISC
economist O
James B-PER
Tobin I-PER
. O

Because O
quite O
a O
few O
Belgian B-MISC
people O
’s O
representatives O
see O
something O
in O
the O
idea O
, O
Finance B-ORG
Minister O
Didier B-PER
Reynders I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
decided O
to O
have O
its O
feasibility O
investigated O
. O

Generally O

Governor O
Quaden B-PER
not O
a O
priori O
against O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC

The O
Author O

Banking O
sector O
calls O
tax O
on O
speculative O
profits O
' O
undemocratic O
and O
inefficient O
' O

Quaden B-PER
was O
able O
to O
perfectly O
recognize O
himself O
as O
a O
central O
banker O
in O
the O
two O
objectives O
of O
the O
tax O
: O
monetary O
stability O
and O
contribution O
to O
development O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

1st O

by O
John B-PER
Vandaele I-PER

Committee B-ORG
for I-ORG
Finance I-ORG

This O
tax O
forms O
the O
core O
of O
the O
Flemish B-ORG
network I-ORG
against I-ORG
financial I-ORG
speculation I-ORG
, O
which O
consists O
of O
the O
two O
major O
trade O
unions O
and O
a O
few O
NGOs O
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Tomorrow I-MISC

Personally O
, O
I O
do O
n’t O
see O
why O
you O
should O
n’t O
tax O
all O
exchange O
transactions O
. O

JVD B-PER

The O
words O
come O
from O
National B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
Governor O
Guy O
Quaden O
, O
and O
they O
were O
pronounced O
on O
Wednesday O
during O
the O
first O
Senate B-ORG
hearing O
on O
the O
so O
- O
called O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
. O

Because O
you O
can O
no O
longer O
make O
that O
distinction O
, O
you O
must O
tax O
all O
transactions O
as O
Tobin B-PER
proposes O
. O

Director O
Georges B-PER
Martin I-PER
called O
the O
tax O
inefficient O
, O
undemocratic O
and O
unfair O
because O
there O
is O
no O
distinction O
between O
speculative O
and O
non O
- O
speculative O
capital O
movements O
. O

The O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
could O
count O
on O
much O
less O
sympathy O
with O
the O
Belgian B-ORG
Association I-ORG
of I-ORG
Banks I-ORG
. O

Edited O

Quaden B-PER
pointed O
out O
that O
Belgium B-LOC
with O
the O
so O
- O
called O
double O
exchange O
market O
until O
1990 O
had O
the O
equivalent O
of O
a O
very O
sophisticated O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
. O

-DOCSTART O
- O
Brussels B-LOC

» O

Chairman O
Francis B-PER
Vermeiren I-PER
of O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
( O
also O
VLD B-MISC
mayor I-MISC
of O
Zaventem B-LOC
) O
emphasizes O
that O
the O
participation O
has O
already O
delivered O
a O
lot O
to O
the O
municipalities O
, O
in O
particular O
through O
the O
two O
privatization O
rounds O
of O
recent O
years O
. O

Publication O
Date O

Ships O
of O
Finance B-ORG
Hugo B-PER
Schiltz I-PER
( O
VU B-ORG
) O
had O
sent O
a O
letter O
to O
all O
his O
colleagues O
a O
few O
days O
before O
the O
general O
meeting O
explaining O
his O
vision O
. O

However O
, O
the O
concerns O
of O
Antwerp B-LOC
received O
little O
response O
. O

The O
municipalities O
and O
provinces O
have O
housed O
their O
participation O
in O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Antwerp B-LOC
voted O
on O
Wednesday O
against O
the O
measures O
that O
give O
municipalities O
more O
freedom O
in O
managing O
their O
Dexia B-MISC
participation I-MISC
. O

With O
a O
number O
of O
large O
cities O
there O
is O
a O
desire O
to O
be O
able O
to O
decide O
on O
the O
future O
of O
their O
Dexia B-MISC
shares I-MISC
. O

These O
would O
function O
as O
forums O
where O
municipalities O
could O
discuss O
a O
number O
of O
financial O
policy O
choices O
. O

At O
the O
general O
meeting O
, O
it O
was O
agreed O
to O
set O
up O
a O
series O
of O
working O
groups O
. O

Under O
certain O
conditions O
, O
the O
documents O
can O
also O
be O
sold O
on O
the O
stock O
exchange O
. O

Vermeiren B-PER
thinks O
about O
the O
pension O
dossier O
, O
the O
liberalization O
of O
electricity O
traffic O
and O
the O
Geographic B-MISC
Information I-MISC
System I-MISC
( O
GIS B-MISC
) O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Antwerp B-LOC
was O
one O
of O
the O
few O
opposers O
when O
the O
final O
proposal O
was O
submitted O
to O
vote O
. O

This O
has O
been O
made O
possible O
to O
a O
limited O
extent O
by O
Wednesday O
’s O
decision O
to O
certify O
the O
shares O
. O

Generally O

That O
participation O
is O
now O
worth O
more O
than O
6 O
billion O
. O

Also O
Mayor O
Bob B-PER
Van I-PER
Hooland I-PER
( O
VU B-ORG
) O
of O
Sint B-LOC
- I-LOC
Martens I-LOC
- O
Latem O
, O
who O
also O
intervened O
at O
the O
general O
meeting O
, O
thinks O
so O
about O
it O
. O

Vermeiren B-PER
believes O
that O
the O
intercommerciality O
of O
the O
securities O
between O
the O
municipalities O
( O
“ O
the O
internal O
market O
” O
) O
can O
already O
in O
part O
meet O
the O
wishes O
of O
the O
major O
cities O
. O

The O
city O
, O
struggling O
with O
huge O
debt O
, O
would O
rather O
have O
more O
freedom O
to O
make O
the O
Dexia B-MISC
participation I-MISC
valid O
. O

Not O
only O
to O
sell O
, O
but O
also O
to O
buy O
. O

» O

That O
means O
that O
the O
participation O
in O
Dexia B-ORG
drops O
to O
about O
18.5 O
percent O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
considers O
these O
conditions O
to O
be O
too O
strict O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
breaks O
the O
Dexia B-MISC
monotony I-MISC

That O
can O
be O
a O
way O
to O
increase O
the O
yield O
of O
urban O
reserves O
. O

For O
example O
, O
Antwerp B-LOC
has O
already O
been O
able O
to O
collect O
about O
4.5 O
billion O
and O
a O
municipality O
like O
Schaarbeek B-LOC
2.3 O
billion O
. O

The O
Belgian B-MISC
municipalities O
and O
provinces O
had O
to O
make O
an O
important O
decision O
on O
their O
participation O
in O
the O
banking O
group O
Dexia B-ORG
on O
Wednesday O
. O

I O
think O
a O
lot O
of O
mayors O
feel O
that O
way O
. O

The O
proposal O
was O
finally O
adopted O
with O
about O
87 O
percent O
of O
the O
votes O
. O

He O
wants O
to O
professionalize O
the O
board O
of O
directors O
, O
which O
is O
now O
politically O
composed O
. O

The O
Author O

We O
should O
not O
try O
to O
reimburse O
the O
participations O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
. O

Publication O
of O

However O
, O
Van B-PER
Hooland I-PER
believes O
that O
the O
functioning O
of O
the O
municipal O
holding O
can O
be O
improved O
. O

That O
operation O
separates O
the O
right O
of O
dividend O
from O
the O
right O
of O
vote O
, O
making O
it O
possible O
for O
the O
municipalities O
to O
trade O
some O
of O
their O
securities O
among O
themselves O
. O

It O
amounts O
to O
80 O
billion O
francs O
. O

by O
Ruben B-PER
Mooijman I-PER

The O
page O

Schiltz B-PER
: O
‘ O
Role O
of O
municipalities O
has O
changed O
’ O

The O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
will O
endorse O
the O
current O
capital O
increase O
of O
Dexia B-ORG
for O
4 O
billion O
francs O
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Tomorrow I-MISC

The O
local O
governments O
, O
former O
majority O
shareholders O
of O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Credit I-ORG
, O
own O
approximately O
22 O
percent O
of O
the O
Dexia B-MISC
Group I-MISC
, O
which O
includes O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Credit I-ORG
. O

17 O
is O

They O
want O
to O
sell O
their O
shares O
in O
whole O
or O
in O
part O
. O

Section O
of O

Edited O

The O
role O
of O
municipalities O
has O
changed O
. O

The O
converging O
interests O
of O
the O
group O
and O
those O
of O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
are O
no O
longer O
clear O
and O
are O
becoming O
increasingly O
unclear O
, O
” O
Schiltz B-PER
said O
during O
the O
general O
meeting O
. O

“ O
I O
feel O
called O
to O
support O
the O
holding O
. O

by O
Ruben B-PER
Mooijman I-PER

The O
largest O
Flemish B-MISC
city O
found O
the O
proposals O
not O
going O
far O
enough O
. O

According O
to O
local O
police O
officers O
, O
the O
motive O
for O
the O
hostage O
is O
obvious O
. O

The O
law O
enforcement O
services O
therefore O
tried O
to O
force O
a O
breakthrough O
through O
negotiations O
. O

The O
Author O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Edited O

But O
yesterday O
, O
the O
unconfirmed O
rumor O
also O
made O
the O
round O
that O
he O
would O
have O
previously O
beaten O
his O
wife O
and O
children O
. O

The O
man O
acknowledged O
that O
he O
“ O
has O
a O
hard O
time O
” O
and O
went O
to O
a O
psychiatrist O
. O

He O
also O
did O
not O
have O
the O
right O
to O
visit O
the O
judge O
. O

There O
has O
been O
confusion O
about O
its O
origin O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

The O
likelihood O
that O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
would O
also O
effectively O
use O
violence O
was O
considered O
very O
small O
all O
the O
time O
. O

The O
hostage O
could O
not O
stop O
the O
divorce O
. O

The O
children O
who O
were O
released O
, O
told O
the O
psychologists O
that O
the O
man O
was O
kind O
to O
them O
and O
told O
about O
his O
own O
children O
all O
the O
time O
. O

Section O
of O

water B-LOC
cheap I-LOC

That O
reassured O
him O
. O

From O
our O
reporter O
on O
site O

The O
page O

Publication O
of O

About O
the O
hostage O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
a O
lot O
of O
stories O
circulated O
yesterday O
. O

He O
was O
very O
concerned O
that O
the O
police O
described O
him O
as O
disturbed O
. O

The O
spokeswoman O
for O
the O
Wasserbillig B-LOC
police O
, O
André B-PER
Colas I-PER
, O
could O
only O
confirm O
that O
it O
was O
a O
39 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
man O
of O
Tunisian B-MISC
descent O
with O
the O
Luxembourg B-MISC
nationality O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

Publication O
Date O

First O
, O
it O
was O
stated O
that O
it O
was O
an O
Algerian B-MISC
who O
was O
mentally O
ill O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
and O
3 O
) O

Generally O

He O
was O
n’t O
crazy O
at O
all O
, O
just O
“ O
bitter O
. O
” O

Four O
years O
ago O
, O
his O
wife O
left O
him O
and O
the O
judge O
entrusted O
his O
two O
children O
, O
an O
eleven O
- O
year O
- O
old O
girl O
and O
a O
five O
- O
year O
- O
old O
boy O
, O
to O
his O
mother O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Until O
Wednesday O
night O
, O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
himself O
called O
the O
local O
radio O
station O
with O
the O
message O
that O
he O
is O
not O
from O
Algeria B-LOC
but O
from O
Tunisia B-LOC
and O
since O
1982 O
also O
has O
the O
Luxembourg B-MISC
nationality O
. O

The O
hostage O
is O
described O
as O
a O
sweet O
but O
very O
impulsive O
man O
. O

( O
by O
CG B-PER
) O

He O
tried O
to O
talk O
to O
him O
all O
the O
time O
on O
Wednesday O
and O
Thursday O
, O
supported O
by O
a O
police O
psychologist O
. O

The O
children O
are O
said O
to O
have O
both O
been O
in O
the O
residence O
. O

“ O
DOCSTART O
” O

Women O
of O
All O
Cities O
: O
Conquer O
the O
Streets O
at O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC

Other O
special O
events O
for O
women O
. O

( O
by O
PJB B-PER
) O

When O
I O
get O
back O
in O
the O
country O
, O
the O
whole O
heisa O
is O
hopefully O
behind O
. O

“ O
We O
also O
invite O
them O
out O
on O
the O
streets O
, O
” O
Vandamme B-PER
decided O
. O

Moreover O
, O
it O
has O
long O
been O
not O
to O
do O
the O
sport O
, O
but O
to O
do O
the O
commerce O
. O

“ O
I O
am O
going O
on O
vacation O
abroad O
. O

It O
does O
not O
matter O
. O

The O
page O

President O
Leen B-PER
Vandamme I-PER
of O
the O
VOC B-ORG
has O
nothing O
against O
" O
the O
game O
of O
football O
" O
, O
but O
believes O
that O
the O
event O
has O
already O
been O
banned O
in O
advance O
by O
the O
" O
excessive O
attention O
" O
in O
the O
media O
. O

If O
football O
is O
so O
important O
to O
men O
that O
it O
brings O
the O
link O
, O
then O
the O
women O
also O
want O
a O
link O
from O
that O
site O
that O
, O
for O
example O
, O
announces O
the O
November O
11 O
Women B-MISC
’s I-MISC
Day I-MISC
. O

As O
long O
as O
women O
but O
not O
in O
the O
seat O
, O
swing O
next O
to O
their O
partner O
for O
the O
pipe O
must O
undergo O
the O
football O
mania O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Publication O
Date O

Yes O
, O
but O
not O
for O
the O
women O
who O
sit O
home O
with O
a O
foolish O
man O
. O

The B-ORG
Tomorrow I-ORG

Edited O

Of O
course O
, O
there O
are O
also O
women O
who O
are O
as O
foolish O
as O
their O
male O
partners O
, O
Vandamme B-PER
admits O
, O
who O
labeled O
the O
VOC B-MISC
gossip I-MISC
about O
football O
as O
“ O
ludic O
” O
. O

Dancing O
, O
theatre O
, O
film O
, O
coffee O
... O

by O
Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogert I-PER

Section O
of O

At O
least O
this O
is O
stated O
by O
the O
Women B-ORG
’s I-ORG
Consultation I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
( O
VOC B-ORG
) O
, O
which O
calls O
on O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
women O
to O
come O
out O
massively O
on O
the O
streets O
and O
collectively O
out O
of O
the O
ball O
during O
the O
upcoming O
European O
Cup B-MISC
. O

Publication O
of O

And O
vice O
versa O
, O
there O
are O
also O
many O
men O
who O
are O
already O
more O
than O
tired O
of O
the O
whole O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
trouble O
. O

The B-MISC
life I-MISC

The O
VOC B-ORG
is O
also O
upset O
at O
the O
federal O
website O
that O
has O
included O
a O
link O
about O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
. O

Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
is O
a O
celebration O
. O

» O

The O
Author O

Generally O

Vandamme B-PER
will O
not O
be O
on O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
streets O
in O
the O
coming O
weeks O
. O

DOCSTART O
– O
Usually O
you O
do O
n’t O
keep O
that O
full O
. O

The O
last O
time O
it O
was O
in O
' O
98 O
against O
the O
Chicago B-ORG
Bulls I-ORG
, O
but O
Michael B-PER
Jordan I-PER
led O
his O
team O
in O
the O
Game B-MISC
Seven I-MISC
still O
to O
the O
final O
. O

We O
need O
to O
impose O
our O
way O
of O
playing O
. O

Edited O

Sporting B-MISC

Section O
of O

The O
page O

With O
us O
it O
was O
much O
less O
. O

The O
LA B-ORG
Lakers I-ORG
of O
success O
coach O
Phil B-PER
Jackson I-PER
have O
missed O
the O
chance O
to O
bend O
the O
home O
advantage O
in O
an O
illuminating O
4 O
- O
2 O
win O
. O

Best B-PER
also O
contributed O
offensively O
, O
as O
he O
was O
responsible O
for O
24 O
points O
, O
of O
which O
15 O
in O
the O
last O
quarter O
, O
so O
the O
Pacers B-ORG
can O
now O
go O
in O
Madison B-LOC
Square I-LOC
Garden I-LOC
looking O
for O
a O
final O
place O
. O

“ O
He O
’s O
an O
unforged O
fighter O
, O
” O
Blaizers B-MISC
coach I-MISC
Mike B-PER
Dunleavy I-PER
said O
after O
the O
victory O
of O
Hope O
. O

» O

» O
