-DOCSTART- O
The O
text O
of O
the O
judgment O
is O
not O
yet O
available O
in O
writing O
but O
the O
notice O
has O
already O
been O
published O
by O
a O
communications O
agency O
that O
hired O
Floralux B-ORG
. O

In O
' O
81 O
, O
the O
then O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
regularises O
the O
situation O
with O
a O
BPA B-MISC
that O
the O
company O
had O
set O
up O
at O
its O
own O
expense O
. O

publication O

Today O
Floralux B-ORG
is O
in O
order O
with O
all O
the O
permits O
, O
but O
the O
BPA B-MISC
with O
which O
it O
could O
be O
obtained O
, O
was O
controversial O
because O
businesswoman O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
's O
ship O
's O
office O
of O
... O

At O
first O
instance O
, O
Vandenbussche B-PER
was O
convicted O
in O
the O
early O
1990s O
for O
conflict O
of O
interest O
but O
later O
acquitted O
by O
the O
court O
of O
appeal O
in O
Ghent B-LOC
. O

SP B-ORG
is O
difficult O
-- O
( O
Eric B-PER
, O
sd O
) O
Derycke B-PER
wants O
to O
approve O
BPA B-MISC
on O
condition O
that O
BPA B-MISC
' O
The B-MISC
Height'is I-MISC
limited O
( O
mayor O
of O
Moorslede B-LOC
Walter B-PER
Ghekiere I-PER
will O
make O
a O
proposal O
) O
. O

Insufficient O
to O
pronounce O
a O
severe O
sentence O
, O
it O
says O
. O

This O
court O
does O
not O
now O
impose O
any O
penalty O
on O
the O
debt O
it O
establishes O
. O

It O
soon O
grows O
into O
a O
real O
garden O
center O
. O

page O

There O
's O
a O
lot O
more O
business O
being O
sold O
than O
you O
'd O
expect O
in O
a O
plant O
nursery O
. O

This O
is O
evident O
from O
a O
fax O
that O
her O
lawyer O
wrote O
to O
her O
at O
the O
time O
and O
which O
was O
seized O
in O
a O
search O
. O

The O
file O
goes O
back O
to O
the O
late O
' O
80s O
. O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

Spatial B-ORG
Planning I-ORG
would O
have O
abused O
to O
obtain O
the O
BPA B-MISC
. O

The O
only O
evidence O
left O
to O
condemn O
Vandenbussche B-PER
for O
' O
taking O
interest O
' O
was O
her O
presence O
at O
the O
ship O
's O
college O
when O
the O
Floralux B-MISC
file I-MISC
was O
discussed O
. O

At O
the O
end O
of O
1998 O
the O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
made O
this O
regularisation O
final O
with O
a O
regional O
plan O
change O
. O

Guilt O
but O
no O
fine O
. O

' O

He O
himself O
took O
this O
off O
as O
" O
knuckles O
and O
ape O
knuckles O
of O
quatons O
. O
" O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Figs O
after O
Easter O
, O
as O
the O
court O
of O
appeal O
seems O
to O
have O
thought O
. O

Antwerpen B-LOC
/ O
Brussels B-LOC

Locally O
it O
is O
suspected O
that O
Floralux B-ORG
financed O
Luc B-PER
Martens I-PER
's O
election O
campaigns O
, O
which O
within O
the O
previous O
government O
" O
asked O
attention O
" O
to O
the O
matter O
. O

Life B-MISC

Vandenbussche B-PER
himself O
decided O
that O
the O
court O
" O
wanted O
to O
condemn O
the O
political O
morals O
of O
the O
past O
" O
. O

' O

The O
Court B-ORG
of I-ORG
cassation I-ORG
broke O
the O
judgment O
so O
that O
it O
had O
to O
be O
remanded O
by O
the O
court O
of O
appeal O
of O
Antwerp B-LOC
. O

That O
is O
the O
essence O
of O
the O
judgment O
handed O
down O
by O
the O
Antwerp B-MISC
Court O
of O
Appeal O
on O
Wednesday O
in O
the O
case O
of O
the O
controversial O
Floralux B-ORG
garden O
centre O
from O
Moorslede B-LOC
- I-LOC
Dadizele I-LOC
. O

Businesswoman O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
is O
found O
guilty O
of O
conflict O
of O
interest O
( O
' O
interest O
taking'in O
legal O
language O
) O
but O
is O
not O
punished O
because O
a O
sentence O
after O
all O
these O
years O
would O
no O
longer O
be O
meaningful O
. O

It O
is O
the O
interpretation O
given O
to O
the O
judgment O
( O
see O
page O
1 O
) O
in O
the O
vicinity O
of O
Floralux B-ORG
that O
a O
' O
new O
political O
culture O
' O
has O
arrived O
and O
the O
old O
political O
morals O
have O
been O
reprehensible O
but O
no O
longer O
need O
to O
be O
fined O
with O
the O
closure O
of O
a O
case O
in O
this O
case O
. O

What O
lasted O
for O
years O
as O
a O
controversial O
' O
CVP B-MISC
file I-MISC
' O
now O
gets O
the O
cachet O
of O
an O
old O
cow O
in O
the O
canal O
by O
the O
court O
ruling O
. O

In O
order O
to O
survive O
, O
Floralux B-ORG
wants O
the O
agricultural O
land O
to O
be O
converted O
into O
SME O
zone O
. O

Court B-ORG
- O
condemned O
political O
morals O
of O
that O
time O
. O

The O
lawyer O
writes O
that O
" O
( O
... O
) O
it O
is O
then O
clear O
that O
it O
( O
BPA B-MISC
, O
sd O
) O
was O
realized O
only O
for O
private O
purposes O
, O
namely O
for O
your O
firm O
, O
and O
that O
the O
ship O
's O
college O
acts O
as O
a O
gangmaker O
for O
that O
purpose O
" O
. O

Nevertheless O
, O
she O
insisted O
against O
the O
VRT B-MISC
radio I-MISC
that O
she O
" O
did O
nothing O
wrong O
. O
" O

author O

In O
addition O
, O
it O
appears O
that O
consultations O
took O
place O
with O
the O
liberal O
party O
( O
at O
that O
time O
still O
PVV B-ORG
) O
and O
with O
the O
SP B-ORG
: O
" O
Waltniel B-PER
( O
PVV B-ORG
, O
sd O
) O
is O
in O
favour O
. O

And O
Delcroix B-PER
decided O
: O
" O
Will O
come O
through O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

That O
context O
ensured O
that O
the O
file O
has O
always O
bathed O
in O
an O
atmosphere O
of O
party O
financing O
in O
exchange O
for O
regularisation O
. O

General O

File O
always O
associated O
with O
party O
financing O
in O
exchange O
for O
regularisation O

Floralux B-ORG
obtains O
a O
permit O
to O
raise O
a O
plant O
nursery O
. O

' O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

The O
Antwerp B-MISC
court O
presented O
the O
document O
as O
evidence O
but O
read O
it O
at O
the O
hearing O
. O

What O
those O
political O
morals O
were O
can O
be O
derived O
from O
the O
Atoma B-MISC
writings I-MISC
that O
Leo B-PER
Delcroix I-PER
kept O
when O
he O
was O
still O
CVP B-MISC
secretary I-MISC
. O

section O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

Businesswoman O
Floralux B-ORG
insists O
she O
did O
n't O
do O
anything O
wrong O
. O

About O
Floralux B-ORG
it O
said O
: O
" O
They O
want O
regularisation O
. O

edition O

-DOCSTART O
- O
Verberckmoes B-PER
is O
a O
former O
Catholic O
dissident O
who O
joined O
the O
liberal O
ranks O
at O
the O
foundation O
of O
the O
PVV B-ORG
as O
an O
enlargement O
candidate O
and O
almost O
immediately O
made O
it O
a O
popular O
representative O
. O

The O
Liberal O
Minister O
of O
Justice B-ORG
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
is O
not O
a O
candidate O
on O
the O
local O
VLD B-MISC
list I-MISC
for O
the O
upcoming O
municipal O
elections O
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
. O

A O
city O
council O
member O
of O
Bet B-ORG
: O
" O
As O
a O
group O
we O
were O
supposed O
to O
form O
a O
cartel O
list O
that O
would O
then O
ask O
the O
electorate O
for O
a O
new O
mandate O
. O

Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
admits O
that O
other O
motives O
may O
have O
played O
a O
major O
role O
as O
well O
. O

Willy B-PER
Van I-PER
Damme I-PER

" O
He O
does O
n't O
want O
to O
commit O
a O
voter O
deception O
and O
be O
a O
candidate O
to O
not O
sit O
on O
the O
city O
council O
. O

It O
's O
final O
now O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Within O
the O
VLD B-ORG
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
there O
is O
great O
defeat O
. O

The O
proposal O
had O
allegedly O
grown O
quite O
spontaneously O
within O
the O
majority O
led O
by O
Mayor O
Norbert B-PER
De I-PER
Batselier I-PER
( O
SP B-ORG
) O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

According O
to O
local O
VLD B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
, O
his O
decision O
is O
irrevocable O
. O

He O
opposes O
the O
cumulation O
of O
mandates O
, O
" O
says O
De B-PER
Brandt I-PER
. O

There O
was O
the O
proposal O
for O
a O
joint O
list O
of O
Bet B-ORG
, O
with O
which O
the O
VLD B-ORG
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
forms O
the O
majority O
and O
which O
consists O
of O
SP'ers B-MISC
, O
VU'ers B-MISC
and O
some O
independents O
. O

Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
no O
candidate O
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC

For O
them O
, O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
is O
the O
future O
for O
the O
VLD B-ORG
and O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
the O
old O
political O
culture O
they O
hate O
. O

Willy B-PER
Van I-PER
Damme I-PER

Verwilghen B-PER
can O
not O
convince O
local O
VLD B-ORG
to O
form O
a O
cartel O
with O
De O
Batselier O
's B-MISC
Bet I-MISC
List I-MISC

author O

' O

" O
This O
is O
the O
PVV B-ORG
of O
earlier O
or O
worse O
, O
" O
said O
a O
VLD'er B-MISC
from O
the O
area O
of O
Verwilghen B-PER
. O

For O
the O
VLD B-ORG
, O
which O
now O
has O
barely O
four O
seats O
in O
the O
city O
council O
, O
there O
is O
a O
danger O
of O
a O
debacle O
. O

That O
official O
reason O
also O
gave O
Verwilghen B-PER
himself O
in O
a O
press O
release O
last O
night O
. O

Dendermonde B-LOC

According O
to O
several O
sources O
it O
also O
had O
the O
support O
of O
the O
top O
of O
the O
national O
VLD B-ORG
and O
was O
mainly O
worn O
by O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
within O
the O
Dendermondse B-MISC
VLD O
. O

Now O
the O
list O
leadership O
will O
go O
between O
Hilde B-PER
Dierickx I-PER
and O
ships O
for O
Finance B-ORG
Marcel B-PER
Borms I-PER
. O

Life B-MISC

page O

Some O
of O
us O
may O
be O
quitting O
now O
. O

General O

He O
did O
leave O
active O
politics O
a O
few O
years O
ago O
, O
but O
remains O
an O
influential O
figure O
within O
the O
local O
liberal O
party O
, O
including O
through O
his O
son O
Kristian B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
, O
who O
is O
a O
city O
council O
member O
. O

However O
, O
the O
majority O
in O
the O
local O
section O
rejected O
the O
proposal O
. O

Some O
liberals O
have O
already O
taken O
or O
intend O
to O
take O
steps O
towards O
Bet B-ORG
. O

This O
( O
according O
to O
circles O
inside O
and O
outside O
the O
VLD B-ORG
) O
mainly O
on O
the O
initiative O
of O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
, O
former B-MISC
VLD I-MISC
representative I-MISC
for O
Dendermonde B-LOC
. O

' O

date O
of O
publication O

From O
our O
employee O

edition O

Robert B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
, O
father O
of O
Marc B-PER
, O
grabbed O
a O
seat O
next O
to O
it O
. O

According O
to O
insiders O
, O
the O
old O
quarrel O
between O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
and O
his O
predecessor O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
plays O
a O
major O
role O
in O
this O
. O

Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
: O
" O
A O
number O
of O
people O
had O
indeed O
not O
yet O
applied O
for O
municipal O
elections O
pending O
what O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
was O
going O
to O
do O
. O

section O

publication O

-DOCSTART- O
Parents O
who O
were O
lucky O
enough O
to O
release O
their O
child O
may O
go O
home O
under O
police O
supervision O
. O

Thank O
God B-PER
. O

" O
Wednesday O
she O
was O
a O
little O
sick O
. O

Radiant O
parents O
are O
powerless O
to O
wait O
for O
hostage O
drama O
to O
be O
unraveled O
. O

The O
kid O
's O
barely O
three O
. O

In O
the O
village O
with O
only O
2,300 O
inhabitants O
knows O
us O
. O

" O
Dads O
do O
n't O
hurt O
babies O
, O
" O
they O
say O
. O

Daddy O
's O
not O
hurting O
kids O
, O
they O
say O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

Every O
year O
the O
village O
is O
flooded O
with O
all O
kinds O
of O
people O
, O
tourists O
especially O
, O
who O
come O
hiking O
and O
cycling O
in O
the O
beautiful O
surroundings O
. O

The O
parents O
also O
receive O
the O
visit O
of O
the O
Portuguese B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
ambassadors O
and O
a O
representative O
of O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
government O
. O

publication O

Colas B-PER
: O
" O
A O
child O
of O
that O
age O
does O
n't O
really O
realize O
what O
's O
happening O
to O
him O
. O

" O
The O
neighbor O
's O
daughter O
is O
there O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

The O
kids O
are O
fine O
according O
to O
the O
law O
department O
. O

But O
they O
've O
never O
had O
hostage O
takers O
before O
. O

My O
daughter O
kept O
her O
home O
. O

General O

' O

Shortly O
after O
seven O
o'clock O
the O
redemption O
suddenly O
came O
. O

section O

Occasional O
applause O
sounds O
to O
the O
cultural O
center O
. O

They O
have O
slept O
well O
and O
are O
fed O
in O
time O
. O

Who O
would O
do O
such O
a O
thing O
? O

But O
nobody O
knows O
what O
's O
gon O
na O
happen O
. O

" O
The O
worst O
part O
is O
when O
they O
come O
to O
say O
that O
children O
were O
released O
to O
hear O
that O
your O
child O
is O
not O
there O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Then O
you O
just O
die O
. O

" O
We O
keep O
our O
right O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
man O
in O
question O
is O
himself O
a O
father O
. O

The O
whole O
neighborhood O
around O
the O
crèche O
is O
hermetically O
sealed O
off O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

During O
the O
afternoon O
the O
atmosphere O
becomes O
more O
grim O
. O

Wasserbillig B-LOC
is O
a O
melting O
pot O
where O
Portuguese B-MISC
, O
Italian B-MISC
, O
Polish B-MISC
, O
German B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
immigrants O
-- O
once O
came O
here O
to O
work O
in O
the O
steel O
and O
tire O
industries O
-- O
live O
peacefully O
side O
by O
side O
. O

The O
inhabitants O
of O
Wasserbillig B-LOC
, O
a O
small O
idyllic O
Luxembourgish B-MISC
village O
, O
stuck O
to O
the O
German B-MISC
border O
, O
reacted O
shockedly O
. O

After O
a O
few O
shots O
, O
the O
hostage O
situation O
was O
over O
. O

Occasionally O
they O
also O
get O
a O
circus O
or O
carnival O
visit O
, O
such O
as O
the O
last O
few O
days O
. O

The O
municipal O
daycare O
centre O
in O
Rue B-LOC
du I-LOC
Bocksberg I-LOC
is O
completely O
surrounded O
by O
special O
intervention O
forces O
of O
the O
Luxembourg B-MISC
, O
German B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
police O
. O

' O

edition O

" O
Many O
distraught O
faces O
. O

Everyone O
's O
getting O
ready O
for O
a O
second O
scared O
night O
. O

The O
lady O
at O
an O
age O
looks O
desperate O
for O
the O
white O
building O
in O
the O
distance O
. O

' O

Some O
parents O
panic O
and O
fear O
the O
worst O
, O
others O
try O
to O
keep O
up O
the O
courage O
. O

Let O
's O
hope O
they O
're O
right O
. O

He O
describes O
the O
atmosphere O
in O
the O
cultural O
center O
as O
dramatic O
. O

These O
are O
defenseless O
toddlers O
and O
toddlers O
. O

' O

page O

author O

' O

The O
industry O
left O
about O
ten O
years O
ago O
, O
the O
immigrants O
remained O
. O

The O
big O
bags O
under O
the O
eyes O
betrayed O
that O
he O
had O
a O
sleepless O
night O
on O
it O
. O

For O
a O
moment O
it O
is O
feared O
for O
the O
worst O
, O
when O
the O
message O
arrives O
that O
the O
hostage O
taker O
has O
brought O
food O
and O
drink O
for O
three O
days O
. O

" O
I O
was O
glued O
to O
my O
radio O
. O

Sad O
because O
a O
niece O
or O
boyfriend O
of O
their O
baby O
is O
there O
. O

' O

" O
My O
granddaughter O
has O
escaped O
death O
, O
" O
sighs O
the O
woman O
. O

The O
young O
man O
sighs O
deeply O
. O

From O
our O
reporter O
at O
the O
scene O

' O

Laundry B-LOC

Outside O
there O
are O
about O
fifty O
villagers O
who O
wanted O
to O
support O
the O
affected O
parents O
. O

The O
route B-LOC
du I-LOC
Luxembourg I-LOC
, O
the O
street O
in O
front O
of O
the O
town O
hall O
, O
was O
recreated O
yesterday O
to O
boulevard O
, O
along O
which O
hundreds O
of O
disaster O
tourists O
wandered O
who O
looked O
at O
jet O
cars O
( O
more O
than O
twenty O
) O
and O
perslui O
( O
more O
than O
one O
hundred O
) O
instead O
of O
window O
windows O
. O

The O
parents O
of O
the O
hostage O
babies O
are O
taken O
a O
hundred O
meters O
further O
into O
the O
cultural O
center O
. O

A O
ghost O
statue O
, O
on O
what O
could O
have O
been O
a O
beautiful O
summer O
holiday O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

The O
hostage O
taker O
is O
getting O
nervous O
because O
his O
demands O
are O
not O
met O
quickly O
enough O
. O

Luckily O
, O
their O
child O
is O
n't O
with O
the O
hostages O
. O

Through O
the O
psychologists O
the O
parents O
are O
kept O
informed O
. O

Ramotti B-PER
is O
one O
of O
the O
few O
parents O
who O
wants O
to O
say O
anything O
. O

Fatigue O
is O
also O
starting O
to O
take O
its O
toll O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
General O

And O
that O
can O
only O
happen O
in O
a O
democracy O
or O
... O

The O
few O
times O
that O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
monarchs O
acted O
indifferently O
, O
this O
happened O
when O
they O
saw O
their O
own O
position O
at O
risk O
: O
during O
the O
king O
's O
issue O
, O
the O
independence O
of O
the O
Congo B-LOC
or O
the O
state O
reform O
. O

Not O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
and O
not O
in O
Laeken B-LOC
. O

page O

He O
may O
not O
have O
his O
own O
opinion O
and O
all O
his O
actions O
shall O
be O
covered O
by O
the O
government O
, O
which O
in O
turn O
shall O
be O
accountable O
to O
the O
parliament O
. O

' O
My O
kingdom O
for O
purple O
... O
' O

Some O
point O
to O
the O
increasing O
influence O
of O
the O
( O
French B-MISC
- I-MISC
speaking I-MISC
) O
liberals O
at O
the O
court O
. O

Karl B-PER
van I-PER
den I-PER
Broeck I-PER

It O
is O
a O
simple O
solution O
, O
but O
the O
legitimacy O
of O
the O
exercise O
of O
power O
is O
not O
very O
great O
. O

That O
is O
precisely O
why O
democracy O
is O
' O
the O
least O
bad O
form O
of O
state O
' O
: O
the O
transfer O
of O
power O
is O
peaceful O
and O
the O
rulers O
have O
a O
legitimacy O
that O
can O
not O
be O
affected O
. O

Officially O
, O
however O
, O
it O
is O
very O
simple O
: O
the O
king O
is O
an O
empty O
box O
. O

That O
is O
why O
it O
is O
such O
a O
valuable O
feature O
of O
a O
civilized O
society O
that O
the O
transfer O
of O
power O
takes O
place O
peacefully O
. O

In O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
this O
was O
often O
one O
thrust O
within O
the O
majority O
, O
the O
Christian O
Democrat O
. O

In O
a O
monarchy O
, O
the O
question O
of O
who O
has O
the O
right O
to O
exercise O
power O
is O
left O
to O
fate O
: O
whoever O
is O
born O
of O
the O
king O
's O
sperm O
will O
later O
become O
king O
himself O
. O

edition O

publication O

Observers O
point O
out O
that O
something O
fundamental O
has O
changed O
in O
this O
country O
since O
the O
arrival O
of O
the O
purple O
- O
green O
coalition O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Maybe O
it O
's O
all O
a O
lot O
simpler O
. O

The O
natural O
ally O
of O
the O
court O
, O
the O
Christian O
pillar O
, O
has O
been O
referred O
to O
the O
opposition O
and O
the O
country O
is O
governed O
by O
a'Republican O
' O
coalition O
. O

Opinion B-MISC

In O
a O
modern O
democracy O
, O
a O
king O
can O
only O
maintain O
himself O
if O
he O
does O
not O
strike O
the O
majority O
in O
front O
of O
his O
head O
. O

Whoever O
has O
to O
give O
up O
power O
, O
fights O
. O

The O
crypto O
- O
maçonical O
training O
of O
Prince O
Laurent B-PER
would O
be O
a O
striking O
example O
of O
that O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

author O

In O
this O
way O
the O
king O
was O
reduced O
to O
a O
spokesperson O
of O
the O
majority O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Belgium B-LOC
, O
of O
course O
, O
asked O
for O
problems O
when O
it O
opted O
for O
a'constitutional O
monarchy O
' O
in O
1830 O
. O

That O
is O
the O
case O
in O
Great B-LOC
Britain I-LOC
, O
that O
is O
the O
case O
in O
the O
Netherlands B-LOC
( O
that O
is O
what O
Queen O
Beatrix B-PER
had O
to O
experience O
) O
and O
that O
is O
of O
course O
also O
the O
case O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
. O

The O
question O
of O
abortion O
then O
confronted O
the O
prince O
with O
the O
shadow O
side O
of O
his O
' O
political O
neutrality O
' O
: O
his O
religious O
views O
were O
also O
found O
to O
fall O
within O
this O
category O
and O
that O
was O
hardly O
acceptable O
to O
the O
deep O
- O
believing O
prince O
. O

section O

The O
CVP B-ORG
reacts O
crookedly O
and O
accuses O
the O
king O
of O
partiality O
. O

He O
knows O
if O
he O
does O
n't O
sign O
the O
euthanasia O
bill O
next O
year O
, O
he O
'll O
sign O
his O
death O
warrant O
. O

The O
king O
came O
from O
the O
beginning O
in O
a O
difficult O
situation O
: O
he O
had O
to O
remain O
in O
the O
popular O
favor O
to O
maintain O
his O
power O
and O
he O
had O
to O
resort O
to O
canapé O
politics O
, O
twilight O
zones O
and O
lobbying O
to O
exercise O
some O
power O
. O

in O
a O
monarchy O
. O

Whoever O
has O
power O
wants O
to O
retain O
power O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
King O
Albert B-PER
and O
his O
children O
are O
becoming O
increasingly O
' O
purple O
- O
green O
' O
reminds O
the O
CVP B-ORG
of O
the O
fact O
that O
she O
no O
longer O
deals O
with O
matters O
. O

What O
about O
King O
Albert B-PER
? O

The O
ninety O
- O
year O
- O
old O
grabbed O
his O
gun O
and O
shot O
him O
. O

When O
he O
was O
arrested O
, O
he O
did O
n't O
resist O
. O

section O

author O

The O
room O
and O
the O
hallway O
where O
the O
facts O
took O
place O
were O
sealed O
pending O
possible O
departure O
from O
the O
Charleroi B-LOC
parquet O
. O

Life B-MISC

Four O
teams O
of O
the O
state O
guard O
of O
the O
Charleroi B-LOC
district O
besieged O
the O
rest O
home O
shortly O
after O
the O
facts O
because O
it O
was O
assumed O
that O
the O
rest O
home O
director O
was O
dead O
. O

The O
other O
residents O
of O
the O
home O
were O
received O
by O
a O
psychologist O
team O
. O

A O
94 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
resident O
of O
a O
retirement O
home O
in O
Aiseau B-LOC
- I-LOC
Presles I-LOC
put O
a O
bullet O
through O
the O
head O
of O
the O
owner O
of O
the O
home O
from O
a O
short O
distance O
yesterday O
morning O
. O

Then O
the O
man O
locked O
himself O
in O
his O
room O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

According O
to O
the O
State O
Guard O
, O
the O
elderly O
could O
not O
explain O
his O
act O
. O

publication O

The O
unsub O
could O
eventually O
be O
overpowered O
by O
the O
State O
Guard O
. O

( O
KDM B-PER
) O

The O
man O
was O
taking O
care O
of O
the O
shooter O
when O
it O
came O
to O
a O
high O
- O
rise O
discussion O
. O

edition O

Old O
- O
timer O
shoots O
down O
retirement O
home O
director O
. O

page O

General O

The O
victim O
was O
struck O
by O
the O
bullet O
in O
the O
head O
and O
was O
transferred O
to O
the O
Fabiola B-ORG
Hospital I-ORG
of O
Auvelais B-LOC
. O

The O
operator O
was O
no O
longer O
in O
critical O
condition O
after O
the O
shooting O
. O

The O
elderly O
person O
was O
noticed O
at O
intervals O
when O
he O
moved O
from O
the O
room O
where O
he O
was O
hiding O
to O
the O
hallway O
. O

Kristof B-PER
Demasure I-PER

He O
does O
not O
even O
seem O
to O
be O
aware O
of O
his O
behaviour O
, O
nor O
of O
the O
seriousness O
of O
the O
facts O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

-DOCSTART- O
That O
Job B-ORG
would O
be O
taken O
over O
was O
almost O
certain O
. O

As O
a O
result O
, O
Invensys B-ORG
is O
already O
sure O
of O
10.8 O
percent O
of O
the O
shares O
. O

A O
thousand O
people O
have O
to O
leave O
Baan B-ORG
. O

" O
We O
think O
Invensys B-ORG
is O
the O
right O
company O
to O
restructure O
Job B-ORG
. O

publication O

The O
restructuring O
costs O
would O
be O
the O
basis O
for O
this O
. O

By O
the O
way O
, O
Invensys B-ORG
himself O
is O
n't O
doing O
too O
well O
either O
. O

That O
company O
was O
created O
by O
the O
merger O
of O
Siebe B-ORG
and O
SDR B-ORG
. O

edition O

Invensys B-ORG
can O
use O
Baan B-ORG
's O
software O
well O
in O
addition O
to O
its O
control O
systems O
for O
factories O
and O
installations O
. O

17 O

Invensys B-ORG
offers O
858 O
million O
euros O
for O
Job B-ORG
, O
or O
2.85 O
euros O
per O
share O
in O
cash O
. O

It O
is O
hoped O
that O
next O
year O
the O
losses O
will O
be O
in O
the O
past O
. O

Job B-ORG
in O
British B-MISC
hands O

General O

section O

The O
hired O
business O
bank O
Lazard B-ORG
Frères I-ORG
has O
been O
snooping O
with O
the O
software O
company O
since O
January O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Only O
no O
one O
seemed O
to O
want O
to O
have O
the O
quacking O
enterprise O
. O

Take O
- O
over O

The O
Baan B-ORG
share O
rose O
13 O
percent O
to O
2.97 O
euros O
on O
Wednesday O
, O
while O
Invensys B-ORG
had O
to O
surrender O
13 O
percent O
to O
230 O
pence O
. O

That O
's O
8.8 O
percent O
more O
than O
Tuesday O
's O
closing O
price O
. O

The O
founders O
of O
the O
company O
, O
the O
brothers O
Jan B-PER
and O
Paul B-PER
Baan I-PER
, O
have O
promised O
to O
sell O
their O
shares O
to O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

At O
the O
same O
time O
as O
the O
acquisition O
of O
Baan B-ORG
, O
the O
British B-MISC
company O
announced O
a O
loss O
of O
238 O
million O
pounds O
, O
more O
than O
twice O
as O
much O
as O
a O
year O
earlier O
. O

Job B-ORG
was O
once O
one O
of O
the O
best O
performing O
shares O
in O
Europe B-LOC
, O
but O
lost O
90 O
% O
of O
its O
value O
in O
two O
years O
due O
to O
ongoing O
losses O
and O
management O
problems O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Other O
top O
guys O
in O
the O
company O
are O
gon O
na O
do O
the O
same O
. O

Invensys B-ORG
wants O
to O
thoroughly O
reorganise O
the O
company O
and O
pays O
EUR O
400 O
million O
for O
it O
. O

The O
name O
Baan B-ORG
is O
intended O
to O
continue O
to O
exist O
, O
but O
as O
part O
of O
Invensys B-ORG
Software I-ORG
and I-ORG
Systems I-ORG
. O

Bloomberg B-ORG

The O
Dutch B-MISC
software O
maker O
Baan B-ORG
is O
bought O
by O
the O
British B-MISC
Invensys B-ORG
. O

page O

We O
want O
to O
do O
so O
quickly O
, O
" O
said O
director O
Allen B-PER
Yurko I-PER
of O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Tomorrow I-MISC

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

author O

-DOCSTART- O
Return O
Elián B-PER
to O
Cuba B-LOC
step O
closer O

General O

In O
the O
Yugoslav B-MISC
Republic O
of O
Serbia B-LOC
several O
high O
officials O
and O
criminals O
have O
been O
murdered O
recently O
, O
but O
it O
is O
the O
first O
such O
thing O
to O
happen O
in O
Montenegro B-LOC
, O
the O
other O
republic O
in O
the O
Yugoslav B-LOC
Federation I-LOC
. O

edition O

The O
return O
of O
the O
Cuban B-MISC
boatman O
Elián B-PER
González I-PER
from O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
to O
his O
homeland O
was O
a O
step O
closer O
yesterday O
. O

Short O

The O
family O
is O
now O
appealing O
to O
the O
Supreme O
Court B-ORG
. O

The O
Hammersmith B-LOC
Bridge I-LOC
in O
west O
London B-LOC
was O
damaged O
yesterday O
by O
a O
bomb O
explosion O
. O

Bomb O
explodes O
under O
London B-MISC
Bridge O

Foreign B-MISC

Pro O
- O
Western O
Montenegro B-LOC
is O
trying O
to O
pursue O
an O
independent O
course O
of O
Slobodan B-PER
Milosevic I-PER
's O
Serbia O
. O

There O
were O
no O
casualties O
, O
but O
there O
was O
a O
huge O
traffic O
jam O
. O

The O
police O
discovered O
a O
small O
explosive O
that O
was O
attached O
to O
a O
support O
beam O
of O
the O
bridge O
connecting O
both O
banks O
of O
the O
river O
Thames B-LOC
. O

The O
Northern B-MISC
Irish I-MISC
Unionists O
point O
an O
accusing O
finger O
at O
Republican O
splinter O
movements O
, O
because O
the O
Irish B-ORG
Republican I-ORG
Army I-ORG
( O
IRA B-ORG
) O
also O
committed O
a O
failed O
attack O
on O
the O
bridge O
in O
1996 O
. O

There O
are O
considerable O
tensions O
between O
the O
two O
republics O
. O

The O
judge O
's O
ruling O
was O
the O
latest O
development O
in O
Elián B-MISC
's O
Miami B-LOC
family O
's O
trial O
to O
keep O
the O
child O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
, O
where O
it O
was O
recovered O
after O
his O
dramatic O
shipwreck O
. O

According O
to O
the O
court O
, O
only O
his O
father O
can O
do O
that O
for O
him O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

A O
court O
of O
appeal O
in O
Atlanta B-LOC
decided O
that O
the O
six O
- O
year O
- O
old O
boy O
is O
not O
entitled O
to O
apply O
for O
asylum O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
himself O
. O

The O
security O
advisor O
to O
President O
Djukanovic B-PER
of O
Montenegro B-LOC
was O
shot O
by O
strangers O
in O
the O
capital O
Podgorica B-LOC
. O

publication O

page O

Until O
that O
case O
is O
ruled O
, O
the O
boy O
must O
remain O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
. O

The O
police O
found O
Goran B-PER
Zugic I-PER
's O
body O
in O
the O
yard O
near O
his O
apartment O
after O
a O
neighbor O
had O
heard O
gunshots O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Worker O
of O
President O
of O
Montenegro B-LOC
murdered O

The O
police O
are O
investigating O
whether O
the O
failed O
attack O
is O
the O
work O
of O
dissident O
paramilitaries O
from O
Northern B-LOC
Ireland I-LOC
, O
who O
oppose O
the O
self O
- O
government O
that O
was O
returned O
to O
the O
province O
this O
week O
. O

author O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

section O

-DOCSTART- O
In O
the O
evening O
, O
he O
released O
17 O
children O
and O
two O
escorts O
. O

Laundry B-LOC

From O
our O
on O
- O
the O
- O
spot O
reporter O

In O
addition O
-- O
besides O
five O
French B-MISC
, O
three O
German B-MISC
and O
an O
Italian B-MISC
hostage O
-- O
a O
Belgian B-MISC
girl O
of O
eight O
was O
also O
held O
. O

On O
Thursday O
morning O
at O
half O
past O
nine O
the O
ultimatum O
passed O
in O
which O
Bejoui B-PER
demanded O
a O
minibus O
to O
the O
airport O
and O
a O
plane O
to O
Libya B-LOC
. O

The O
police O
allegedly O
intervened O
because O
the O
hostage O
taker O
intended O
to O
take O
a O
number O
of O
children O
on O
a O
possible O
flight O
. O

The O
man O
kept O
the O
children O
and O
escorts O
captive O
in O
the O
daycare O
center O
in O
Wasserbillig B-LOC
, O
a O
small O
town O
in O
the O
Grand B-LOC
Duchy I-LOC
of I-LOC
Luxembourg I-LOC
. O

page O

The O
hostage O
taking O
of O
twenty O
- O
five O
children O
and O
two O
escorts O
in O
Luxembourg B-MISC
ended O
well O
for O
the O
hostages O
in O
seven O
hours O
last O
night O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

edition O

Thirteen O
of O
the O
children O
are O
of O
Portuguese B-MISC
descent O
. O

Page O
3 O

The O
actions O
of O
the O
police O
were O
initially O
thwarted O
because O
the O
hostage O
closely O
followed O
the O
reporting O
on O
television O
and O
radio O
. O

Yesterday O
, O
the O
hostage O
released O
another O
four O
children O
in O
the O
course O
of O
the O
day O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

Sharpshooter O
puts O
an O
end O
to O
hostage O
in O
Wasserbillig B-LOC

An B-PER
Bruyninckx I-PER

According O
to O
the O
latest O
reports O
, O
the O
man O
had O
two O
gunshot O
wounds O
to O
the O
head O
and O
his O
life O
was O
in O
danger O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

date O
of O
publication O

section O

publication O

author O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

He O
would O
also O
have O
asked O
for O
60 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
( O
€ O
1.5 O
million O
) O
. O

The O
hostage O
situation O
began O
Wednesday O
afternoon O
around O
3:30 O
p.m. O
when O
the O
man O
, O
armed O
with O
a O
knife O
, O
entered O
the O
daycare O
center O
with O
a O
gun O
and O
a O
grenade O
. O

General O

The O
hostage O
taker O
, O
39 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
, O
was O
shot O
by O
a O
sniper O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
In O
April O
last O
year O
there O
was O
a O
commotion O
about O
the O
file O
when O
Steve B-PER
Stevaert I-PER
( O
SP B-ORG
) O
, O
then O
still O
Minister O
of O
Spatial B-ORG
Planning I-ORG
, O
withdrew O
the O
BPA B-MISC
in O
question O
after O
the O
auditor O
advised O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
State I-ORG
to O
destroy O
it O
. O

According O
to O
Floralux B-ORG
's O
counsel O
, O
the O
appeal O
court O
did O
not O
impose O
a O
penalty O
because O
it O
would O
no O
longer O
make O
sense O
after O
all O
these O
years O
. O

Page O
7 O

The O
Floralux B-MISC
case I-MISC
has O
been O
dragging O
on O
for O
years O
and O
revolves O
around O
a O
change O
of O
destination O
tailored O
to O
the O
company O
, O
allowing O
the O
plant O
grower O
to O
develop O
into O
a O
garden O
center O
of O
supermarket O
size O
in O
what O
was O
initially O
agricultural O
. O

Floralux B-ORG
must O
not O
therefore O
reduce O
or O
pay O
damages O
to O
Dadiflor B-ORG
. O

A O
fax O
from O
her O
lawyer O
to O
his O
client O
seized O
by O
the O
High B-ORG
Supervisory I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
leaves O
no O
doubt O
as O
to O
the O
role O
of O
the O
ship O
's O
college O
in O
this O
. O

In O
doing O
so O
, O
business O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
was O
suspected O
of O
becoming O
CVP B-MISC
ships I-MISC
of O
Spatial B-ORG
Planning I-ORG
to O
realize O
the O
involved O
' O
BPA B-MISC
Kezelberg I-MISC
' O
itself O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Interests O
- O
mixing O
goes O
unpunished O

The O
dossier O
got O
a O
bigger O
dimension O
because O
there O
was O
a O
lot O
of O
political O
lobbying O
work O
involved O
. O

publication O

However O
, O
that O
was O
rather O
a O
symbolic O
decision O
, O
because O
the O
more O
important O
regional O
plan O
had O
already O
been O
adapted O
at O
that O
time O
, O
thus O
finally O
regulating O
the O
case O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

section O

All O
civil O
claims O
of O
the O
counterparty O
, O
competitor O
Dadiflor B-ORG
, O
have O
also O
been O
dismissed O
. O

author O

General O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

The O
court O
of O
appeal O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
considers O
that O
in O
the O
case O
of O
the O
controversial O
garden O
centre O
Floralux B-ORG
in O
the O
West B-MISC
Flemish I-MISC
Dadizele B-LOC
there O
has O
been O
a O
conflict O
of O
interest O
but O
did O
not O
consider O
it O
necessary O
to O
punish O
the O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
/ O
Dadizele B-LOC

By O
condemning O
Floralux B-ORG
for O
' O
interest O
- O
taking O
' O
, O
the O
court O
sought O
to O
denounce O
the O
political O
lobbying O
work O
. O

But O
like O
the O
court O
of O
appeal O
in O
Ghent B-LOC
also O
ruled O
that O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
the O
fax O
had O
to O
be O
removed O
from O
the O
file O
because O
he O
was O
covered O
by O
the O
professional O
secrecy O
of O
lawyers O
. O

edition O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

That O
's O
how O
the O
file O
popped O
up O
in O
Leo B-PER
Delcroix I-PER
's O
infamous O
Atoma O
writings O
. O

Antwerp B-MISC
court O
of O
appeal O
leaves O
the O
manager O
of O
Floralux B-ORG
garden O
centre O
unpunished O

Conflict O
of O
interest O
in O
criminal O
matters O
would O
not O
have O
been O
proven O
. O

page O

Own O
Message O

Competitor O
Dadiflor B-ORG
takes O
courage O
from O
the O
judgment O
by O
considering O
in O
the O
conviction O
an O
additional O
argument O
for O
the O
destruction O
of O
the O
regional O
change O
by O
the O
Council B-ORG
of I-ORG
State I-ORG
. O

The O
Ghent B-MISC
Attorney O
General O
Frank B-PER
Schins I-PER
even O
ruled O
that O
there O
was O
over O
lobbying O
in O
this O
file O
. O

Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
concludes O
that O
the O
court O
has O
condemned O
" O
the O
political O
morals O
of O
then O
" O
but O
she O
still O
feels O
that O
she O
has O
done O
" O
nothing O
wrong O
. O
" O

Last O
year O
, O
CVP B-MISC
Minister I-MISC
Luc B-PER
Martens I-PER
admitted O
that O
he O
had O
asked O
" O
attention O
" O
to O
the O
matter O
within O
the O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
. O

1 O

-DOCSTART- O
For O
the O
first O
time O
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
the O
leader O
got O
into O
trouble O
for O
a O
moment O
yesterday O
. O

On O
Abetone B-LOC
Casagrande B-PER
had O
impressed O
on O
Monday O
last O
week O
and O
also O
in O
the O
Dolomites B-LOC
the O
leader O
had O
not O
shrunk O
. O

He O
got O
, O
in O
the O
wheel O
followed O
by O
Tonkov B-PER
, O
again O
at O
Garzelli B-PER
and O
co O
and O
spurted O
up O
to O
a O
third O
place O
. O

The O
difference O
between O
the O
leader O
and O
Garzelli B-PER
is O
only O
25 O
seconds O
. O

section O

On O
the O
contrary O
, O
Stefano B-PER
Garzelli I-PER
and O
Gilberto B-PER
Simoni I-PER
made O
it O
clear O
that O
they O
can O
make O
Casagrande B-PER
miserable O
today O
and O
tomorrow O
. O

Later O
that O
was O
also O
the O
case O
with O
Ivan B-PER
Gotti I-PER
. O

Pratonevoso B-LOC

To O
win O
. O

" O
I O
fear O
no O
one O
and O
I O
will O
attack O
, O
" O
he O
announced O
. O

He O
just O
really O
feels O
the O
hot O
breath O
of O
Stefano B-PER
Garzelli I-PER
in O
the O
neck O
. O

With O
great O
interest O
is O
looked O
forward O
to O
today O
's O
queen O
ride O
with O
the O
climbs O
of O
the O
col O
d'Agnelli B-LOC
( O
2748 O
meters O
) O
and O
the O
Izord B-LOC
( O
2361 O
) O
and O
the O
climbing O
time O
trial O
of O
tomorrow O
over O
the O
Montgenèvre B-LOC
and O
Sestrière B-LOC
. O

page O

Thanks O
to O
Buenahora B-PER
's O
support O
, O
Casagrande B-PER
recovered O
the O
problem O
a O
little O
later O
. O

For O
Di B-PER
Luca I-PER
it O
was O
too O
much O
on O
Wednesday O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Casagrande B-PER
feels O
hot O
breath O
from O
Garzelli B-PER

The O
taste O
maker O
of O
the O
first O
two O
weeks O
, O
stepped O
off O
with O
tendinitis O
. O

Here O
I O
want O
to O
make O
a O
difference O
. O

And O
say O
Casagrande B-PER
spoke O
optimistic O
language O
on O
the O
eve O
of O
the O
trip O
to O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
. O

To O
the O
extent O
that O
both O
still O
held O
profit O
ambitions O
, O
they O
may O
now O
permanently O
store O
them O
. O

' O

And O
it O
could O
be O
. O

Own O
Message O

I O
'll O
be O
back O
next O
year O
. O

More O
clarity O
we O
will O
get O
today O
and O
tomorrow O
in O
the O
two O
archdifficult O
Alpine B-MISC
rides I-MISC
. O

Garzelli B-PER
and O
Piepoli B-PER
did O
n't O
. O

He O
also O
enjoys O
the O
advantage O
that O
he O
is O
the O
better O
time O
rider O
among O
the O
favorites O
, O
which O
makes O
him O
really O
dare O
to O
think O
about O
end O
profit O
. O

Winning O
the O
Giro B-MISC
. O

author O

" O
But O
I O
've O
learned O
a O
lot O
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
. O

Rozetruid O
carrier O
has O
n't O
won O
Giro B-MISC
yet O

Gonzales B-PER
de I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
, O
known O
as O
a O
better O
time O
rider O
, O
made O
it O
a O
true O
time O
trial O
between O
Genoa B-LOC
and O
Brescia B-LOC
. O

( O
TL B-PER
) O

Sports B-MISC

Francesco B-PER
Casagrande I-PER
will O
be O
a O
lot O
less O
reassured O
after O
yesterday O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

publication O

' O

On O
the O
solid O
climbing O
of O
the O
Italian B-MISC
, O
everyone O
became O
increasingly O
convinced O
that O
Casagrande B-PER
, O
who O
had O
set O
the O
Italian B-MISC
round O
as O
its O
main O
goal O
and O
had O
done O
a O
lot O
of O
sacrifices O
for O
it O
, O
would O
achieve O
its O
goal O
. O

Under O
the O
brutal O
paces O
of O
Gilberto B-PER
Simoni I-PER
on O
the O
steepest O
parts O
of O
the O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
, O
Casagrande B-PER
had O
to O
fit O
. O

General O

" O
This O
ride O
is O
more O
important O
to O
me O
than O
the O
next O
two O
. O

" O
I O
win O
today O
, O
" O
he O
had O
written O
on O
the O
control O
sheet O
in O
the O
morning O
. O

Because O
no O
matter O
how O
hard O
in O
the O
group O
the O
sprinters O
teams O
chased O
behind O
the O
Spaniard B-MISC
, O
at O
the O
finish O
he O
remained O
for O
almost O
half O
a O
minute O
. O

But O
are O
we O
to O
assume O
that O
for O
a O
moment O
it O
was O
a O
sign O
on O
the O
wall O
and O
constantly O
clinging O
on O
? O

Halfway O
, O
after O
118 O
kilometers O
, O
he O
left O
the O
peloton O
alone O
, O
walked O
out O
for O
seven O
minutes O
and O
resisted O
the O
return O
of O
the O
peloton O
in O
a O
wonderful O
way O
. O

Especially O
for O
Garzelli B-PER
the O
ride O
win O
must O
be O
a O
boost O
. O

edition O

And O
the O
Spaniard B-MISC
from O
the O
Vitalicioploeg B-MISC
kept O
his O
word O
. O

On O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
Dario B-PER
Frigo I-PER
got O
into O
trouble O
very O
early O
. O

It O
promises O
to O
be O
still O
exciting O
closing O
days O
in O
the O
Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Italy I-MISC
. O

The O
team O
mate O
of O
Marco B-PER
Pantani I-PER
and O
leader O
of O
Mercatone B-ORG
Uno I-ORG
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
, O
left O
all O
his O
competitors O
behind O
on O
the O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
yesterday O
and O
demolished O
thanks O
to O
the O
bonification O
closer O
to O
Casagrande B-PER
. O

date O
of O
publication O

" O
The O
pain O
was O
unheard O
of O
, O
" O
said O
young O
Di B-PER
Luca I-PER
. O

15 O

But O
it O
is O
sometimes O
said O
of O
the O
Tuscans B-MISC
that O
a O
big O
round O
takes O
a O
week O
too O
long O
for O
him O
. O

Wednesday O
, O
Alvaro B-PER
Gonzales I-PER
de O
Galdeano B-PER
made O
his O
day O
. O

So O
it O
did O
n't O
go O
that O
fast O
. O

Tony B-PER
Landuyt I-PER

Two O
of O
those O
favorites O
were O
thrown O
over O
board O
yesterday O
. O

They O
went O
smoothly O
on O
Simoni B-PER
's O
trail O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
date O
of O
publication O

But O
the O
more O
Chernow B-PER
wrote O
, O
the O
more O
enthusiastic O
they O
became O
. O

Both O
initially O
did O
n't O
like O
Chernow B-MISC
's I-MISC
plan O
because O
they O
still O
felt O
too O
young O
and O
healthy O
for O
a O
biography O
. O

The O
first O
edition O
of O
the O
500 O
- O
page O
book O
Christo B-PER
and O
Jeanne B-PER
- I-PER
Claude I-PER
- O
a O
biography O
has O
only O
been O
published O
in O
German B-MISC
for O
the O
time O
being O
. O

Biography O
Christo B-PER
published O

General O

Culture B-MISC

The O
Bulgarian B-MISC
- I-MISC
American I-MISC
artists O
' O
couple O
Christo B-PER
( O
Javacheff B-PER
) O
and O
Jeanne B-PER
- I-PER
Claude I-PER
presented O
his O
biography O
earlier O
this O
week O
in O
Cologne B-LOC
at O
the O
publishing O
house O
Keipenheuer B-ORG
Witsch I-ORG
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

page O

The O
author O
Burt B-PER
Chernow I-PER
and O
friend O
of O
the O
Christos B-PER
, O
wrote O
the O
biography O
of O
the O
couple O
: O
the O
Bulgarian B-LOC
- O
born O
Christo B-PER
Javacheff I-PER
and O
his O
great O
love O
Jeanne O
- O
Claude B-PER
de I-PER
Guillebon I-PER
. O

publication O

They O
mainly O
bearded O
in O
1995 O
, O
when O
they O
completely O
packed O
the O
German B-MISC
Reichstag B-LOC
in O
Berlin B-LOC
. O

edition O

section O

author O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

" O
Germany B-LOC
has O
a O
special O
place O
in O
our O
hearts O
, O
" O
the O
two O
artists O
said O
during O
the O
presentation O
. O

The O
artistic O
couple O
has O
been O
working O
on O
the O
art O
of O
packing O
since O
the O
1960s O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
General O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

" O
The O
government O
has O
been O
sensitizing O
for O
more O
than O
20 O
years O
. O

The O
Brussels B-MISC
Minister O
for O
Environment B-ORG
Didier B-PER
Gosuin I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
/ I-ORG
FDF I-ORG
) O
was O
also O
disappointed O
with O
the O
" O
lean O
" O
content O
of O
the O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
. O

By O
exceeding O
the O
European B-MISC
health O
standard O
( O
120 O
micrograms O
of O
ozone O
per O
cubic O
metre O
for O
at O
least O
eight O
hours O
) O
, O
they O
require O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
State O
, O
the O
Brussels B-LOC
Region I-LOC
and O
the O
nineteen O
Brussels B-MISC
municipalities O
to O
pay O
50 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
. O

Air O
pollution O
deserves O
much O
more O
than O
that O
, O
" O
says O
Gosuin B-PER
, O
which O
itself O
announces O
structural O
measures O
. O

The O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
gets O
a O
severe O
insufficient O
amount O
from O
the O
environmental O
movement O
. O

Environmental O
movement O
invigorates O
ozone O
process O

page O

Two O
Brussels B-MISC
associations O
, O
Bral B-ORG
and O
Inter B-ORG
- I-ORG
Environment I-ORG
, O
are O
tired O
of O
dawdling O
public O
authorities O
and O
going O
to O
court O
for O
interim O
measures O
. O

Pages O
2 O
and O
7 O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

publication O

The O
two O
associations O
are O
asking O
for O
concrete O
measures O
to O
limit O
car O
traffic O
before O
the O
summer O
. O

The O
Minister O
of O
Health B-ORG
's I-ORG
Office I-ORG
Magda B-PER
Aelvoet I-PER
( O
Agalev B-ORG
) O
did O
not O
want O
to O
respond O
to O
the O
complaint O
yesterday O
. O

edition O

date O
of O
publication O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

author O

1 O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

section O

-DOCSTART O
- O
Di B-PER
Biase I-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
11 O
. O

Zabel B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
3h15:58 O
-- O
2 O
. O

Buenahora B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
08 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Wüst B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
/ O
Festina B-ORG
) O
the O
102.6 O
km O
in O
2h28:10 O
-- O
2 O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Plaza B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
31:08:55 O
-- O
2 O
. O

Leoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
4 O
. O

Simoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
53 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Simoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
3 O
. O

Kadlec B-PER
( O
CH B-LOC
) O
-- O
... O

Frigo B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
4:34 O
-- O
10 O
. O

43 O
. O

Finot B-PER
( O
Fra B-LOC
) O
z.t O
. O
-- O
7 O
. O

Zabel B-PER
( O
Duine B-LOC
) O
-- O
5 O
. O

Blanco B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
4:39 O
-- O
11 O
. O

Ullrich B-PER
( O
Du B-LOC
) O
2:33 O
-- O
10 O
. O

Forconi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
2:18 O
-- O
18 O
. O

Merckx B-PER
alle O
z. O
t. O

Sports B-MISC

Tonkov B-PER
( O
Russian B-LOC
) O
2:41 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Verbrugghe B-PER
-- O
17 O
. O

Rebellin B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
10:21 O
. O

Bracke B-PER
all O
z.t O
. O

Hruska B-PER
( O
CH B-LOC
) O
-- O
... O

Guidi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
10 O
. O

Bruylandts B-PER
0:23 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Pantani B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
... O

Fornaciari B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
13 O
. O

Garzelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
at O
25 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Casero B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
1:42 O
-- O
5 O
. O

McRae B-PER
( O
USA B-LOC
) O
19:00 O
-- O
19 O
. O

Koerts B-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
-- O
3 O
. O

McRae B-PER
( O
Vast B-LOC
) O
1:47 O
-- O
14 O
. O

section O

Blanco B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
-- O
10 O
. O

Garzelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
/ O
Mercatone B-ORG
Uno I-ORG
) O
the O
173 O
km O
in O
4:42:32 O
( O
mem O
. O
: O
36.739 O
km O
/ O
h O
) O
-- O
2 O
. O

Lanfranchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
12:51 O
-- O
15 O
. O

7th O
ride O
( O
time O
trial O
): O
1 O
. O

Plaza B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
/ O
Festina B-ORG
) O
the O
35.7 O
km O
in O
42:53 O
-- O
2 O
. O

56 O
. O

General O

Beikirch B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
-- O
... O

Boscardin B-PER
( O
Zwi B-LOC
) O
44 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Rous B-PER
( O
Fra B-LOC
) O
at O
0:09 O
-- O
3 O
. O

From B-PER
the I-PER
Wouwer I-PER
0:13 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Petersen B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
alle O
z.t O
. O

Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Italy:17th I-MISC
ride O
: O
1 O
. O

Grand B-ORG
Prix I-ORG
of I-ORG
Wallonia I-ORG
( O
category O
1.2 O
): O

Hruska B-PER
( O
Ch B-LOC
) O
13:14 O
-- O
16 O
. O

Rubiera B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
4:45 O
-- O
12 O
. O

Pena B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
16:59 O
-- O
18 O
. O

1 O
. O

16 O
. O

Savoldelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
19:08 O
-- O
20 O
. O

Leoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
5 O
. O

Hoj B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
2:12 O
-- O
10 O
. O

author O

Final O
position O
: O
1 O
. O

Gotti B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:54 O
-- O
17 O
. O

publication O

Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Italy I-MISC
: O

Klöden B-PER
( O
Due B-LOC
) O
at O
0:42 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Piepoli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
on O
02 O
-- O
5 O
. O

31 O
. O

Gerosa B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
14 O
. O

15 O

Casero B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
1:40 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Rittsel B-PER
( O
Swedish B-LOC
) O
2:34 O
. O

Gonzalez B-PER
de I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
... O

Sevilla B-LOC
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
15:24 O
-- O
17 O
. O

Farazijn B-PER
1:58 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Usov B-PER
( O
WRu B-LOC
) O
-- O
7 O
. O

Merckx B-PER
7:32 O
-- O
... O

Baguet B-PER
-- O
18 O
. O

Savoldelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
8:23 O
-- O
48 O
. O

Rubiera B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
49 O
-- O
11 O
. O

Rosems B-PER
2:06 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Heppner B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:06 O
-- O
... O

Piepoli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
6:13 O
-- O
14 O
. O

Liese B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:11 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Position O
: O
1 O
. O

13 O
. O

17th O
journey O
: O
1 O
. O

Vermeersch B-PER
2:02 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Blaudzun B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
1:44 O
-- O
7 O
. O

Cophis B-PER
( O
Sweet B-LOC
) O
-- O
15 O
. O

Bölts B-PER
( O
Du B-LOC
) O
1:41 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Frigo B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
2:38 O
-- O
20 O
. O

Kristensen B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
z.t O
. O
-- O
... O

34 O
. O

Petersen B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
-- O
6 O
. O

Blaudzun B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
1:46 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Martinello B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
6 O
. O

Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
Germany I-MISC
: O

Ullrich B-PER
18:04 O

Ullrich B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
all O
s.t O
. O

Beikirch B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
-- O
3 O
. O

18th O
journey O
: O
1 O
. O

Belli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
7 O
. O

Gonzalez B-PER
de I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
/ O
Vitalicio B-ORG
) O
the O
236 O
km O
in O
5h23:02 O
( O
gem O
: O
43,834 O
km O
/ O
u O
) O
-- O
2 O
. O

Boogerd B-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
z.t O
. O
-- O
... O

Petacchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
5 O
. O

Baranowski B-PER
( O
Poo B-LOC
) O
-- O
13 O
. O

Castelblanco B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
2:24 O
-- O
19 O
. O

Belli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:11 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Usov B-PER
( O
WRu B-LOC
) O
-- O
6 O
. O

Casagrande B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
4 O
. O

Noè B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
3:39 O
-- O
7 O
. O

Konyshev B-PER
( O
Russian B-LOC
) O
-- O
4 O
. O

Braikia B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
-- O
9 O
. O

Bölts B-PER
( O
Du B-LOC
) O
1:26 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Buenahora B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
3:43 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Klöden B-PER
( O
Du B-LOC
) O
at O
40 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Wüst B-PER
( O
Due B-LOC
) O
-- O
4 O
. O

Heppner B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:21 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Casagrande B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
/ O
Vini B-ORG
Caldirola I-ORG
) O
87h11:09 O
-- O
2 O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Mattan B-PER
-- O
19 O
. O

edition O

De B-PER
Jongh I-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
-- O
8 O
. O

Elli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
in O
4:42:05 O
( O
mean O
41.732 O
km O
/ O
h O
) O
-- O
2 O
. O

Noè B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
12 O
-- O
9 O
. O

6th O
ride O
: O
1 O
. O

Mancebo B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
20:36 O
. O

Lanfranchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:12 O
-- O
12 O
. O

page O

Mancebo B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
-- O
16 O
. O

Tonkov B-PER
( O
Russian B-LOC
) O
-- O
6 O
. O

De B-PER
Clercq I-PER
-- O
20 O
. O

Conte B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
12 O
. O

Gotti B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
4:25 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Pieri B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
7 O
. O

Honchar B-PER
( O
Oek B-LOC
) O
1:51 O
-- O
15 O
. O

70 O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Svorada B-PER
( O
CH B-LOC
) O
at O
24 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Honchar B-PER
( O
Oek B-LOC
) O
5:45 O
-- O
13 O
. O

8th O
ride O
: O
1 O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Last O
year O
I O
had O
to O
deal O
with O
the O
same O
problem O
when O
in O
the O
Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
the I-MISC
Walloon I-MISC
Regions I-MISC
I O
again O
tied O
the O
competition O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Questions O
about O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
are O
getting O
bigger O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

General O

publication O

Are O
they O
wrong O
? O

' O

I O
hope O
that O
the O
same O
will O
happen O
in O
the O
next O
few O
days O
, O
although O
I O
must O
confess O
that O
I O
am O
not O
quite O
comfortable O
with O
it O
anymore O
. O

The O
Tour B-MISC
is O
approaching O
quickly O
. O

Cycling O

' O

There O
are O
even O
those O
who O
bet O
already O
that O
he O
will O
not O
be O
at O
the O
start O
of O
the O
Tour B-MISC
in O
Futuroscope O
on O
July O
1 O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

" O
I O
do O
n't O
understand O
why O
there O
's O
so O
much O
noise O
around O
there O
, O
" O
says O
a O
surprised O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
. O

Sports B-MISC

Ief B-PER
Stomming I-PER

" O
I O
'm O
not O
doing O
well O
, O
" O
said O
an O
otherwise O
serene O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
. O

Own O
Message O

Vandenbroucke B-PER
wanted O
to O
ride O
the O
Dauphiné B-MISC
( O
June O
4 O
- O
11 O
) O
and O
the O
Route I-MISC
du I-MISC
Sud I-MISC
( O
June O
17 O
- O
20 O
) O
instead O
of O
the O
Tour I-MISC
of I-MISC
Luxembourg I-MISC
( O
June O
8 O
- O
11 O
) O
and O
the O
Tour I-MISC
of I-MISC
Switzerland I-MISC
( O
June O
13 O
- O
22 O
) O
as O
direct O
preparation O
for O
the O
Tour I-MISC
. O

However O
, O
De O
Kempenaar B-MISC
was O
satisfied O
with O
this O
test O
in O
view O
of O
the O
Tour B-MISC
of I-MISC
France I-MISC
, O
which O
is O
so O
much O
more O
important O
to O
him O
. O

" O
As O
far O
as O
I O
know O
, O
there O
are O
regular O
riders O
who O
work O
on O
their O
program O
. O

Van B-PER
de I-PER
Wouwer I-PER
had O
early O
realized O
that O
Elli B-PER
would O
become O
the O
knocking O
man O
. O

section O

I O
do O
n't O
panic O
yet O
, O
but O
there O
will O
no O
longer O
be O
any O
new O
obstacles O
to O
my O
preparation O
. O

" O
At O
least O
a O
lot O
less O
than O
expected O
. O

After O
117 O
km O
he O
stopped O
. O

One O
thing O
may O
be O
clear O
about O
all O
this O
: O
the O
end O
of O
the'Vandenbroucke B-MISC
- I-MISC
story I-MISC
' O
is O
far O
from O
being O
in O
sight O
. O

15 O

A O
few O
more O
races O
were O
needed O
for O
the O
World B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
before O
the O
dèclic O
announced O
itself O
. O

Frank B-PER
Vandenbroucke I-PER
gives O
up O
in O
GP B-MISC
Wallonie I-MISC
: O
' O
I O
'm O
not O
doing O
well O
' O

Simply O
because O
there O
is O
more O
recovery O
time O
between O
the O
first O
combination O
. O

Belgians B-MISC
who O
are O
already O
there O
, O
are O
Dave B-PER
Bruylants I-PER
, O
second O
yesterday O
, O
and O
Kurt B-PER
Van I-PER
de I-PER
Wauwer I-PER
, O
third O
. O

Ief B-PER
Stomming I-PER

Before O
the O
start O
of O
the O
race O
he O
had O
called O
reaching O
the O
top O
condition O
a O
matter O
of O
days O
, O
but O
barely O
two O
slopes O
further O
he O
cycled O
in O
the O
back O
of O
the O
peloton O
. O

The O
following O
task O
therefore O
surprised O
no O
one O
. O

page O

Meanwhile O
, O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
has O
also O
understood O
that O
he O
is O
currently O
not O
in O
a O
position O
to O
make O
demands O
in O
connection O
with O
his O
preparation O
programme O
for O
the O
Tour B-MISC
. O

edition O

' O

" O
The O
condition O
is O
good O
, O
but O
not O
super O
. O

Then O
I O
was O
regularly O
driven O
in O
15 O
minutes O
. O

author O

Yesterday O
he O
gave O
up O
in O
the O
only O
Belgian B-MISC
games O
he O
would O
ride O
on O
Belgian B-MISC
soil O
. O

While O
Alberto B-PER
Elli I-PER
from O
the O
Telekom B-MISC
team I-MISC
of O
Walter B-PER
Godefroot I-PER
wrote O
the O
GP B-MISC
of I-MISC
Wallonia I-MISC
( O
1.2 O
) O
, O
a O
freshly O
washed O
and O
dressed O
Frank B-PER
Vandenbroucke I-PER
had O
long O
been O
thinking O
about O
how O
to O
proceed O
with O
him O
in O
the O
company O
of O
his O
Italian B-MISC
friend O
Sara B-PER
. O

However O
, O
I O
will O
now O
have O
to O
accept O
the O
arrangement O
proposed O
by O
the O
team O
management O
. O

Names B-LOC

Vandenbroucke B-PER
: O
' O
I O
do O
n't O
panic O
yet O
, O
but O
there O
will O
be O
no O
more O
obstacles O
to O
my O
Tour B-MISC
preparation I-MISC
' O

Not O
that O
I O
'm O
sick O
, O
but O
I O
just O
do O
n't O
have O
an O
acceleration O
in O
the O
legs O
. O

Bruylants B-PER
, O
only O
14 O
days O
of O
racing O
again O
, O
had O
to O
pay O
his O
attempt O
to O
retrieve O
Elli B-PER
with O
cramps O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Nieuw O
are O
director O
Patrice B-PER
Toye I-PER
( O
of O
the O
award O
- O
winning O
film O
Rosie B-MISC
) O
and O
Marion B-PER
Oprel I-PER
, O
friend O
of O
Marianne'De B-MISC
Mol I-MISC
) O
Dupont B-PER
. O

Short O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Agalev B-ORG
says O
he O
wants O
to O
make O
Antwerp B-LOC
an O
open O
, O
vibrant O
metropolis O
again O
. O

edition O

A O
few O
twenty O
- O
somethings O
have O
come O
forward O
and O
are O
placed O
on O
the O
drawn O
- O
up O
lists O
which O
are O
later O
announced O
. O

On O
8 O
October O
the O
senior O
party O
Wachtig B-ORG
Oudeorden I-ORG
( O
WOW B-ORG
) O
participates O
in O
the O
municipal O
, O
district O
and O
provincial O
elections O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
. O

WOW B-ORG
participates O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC

Journal B-MISC

A O
little O
doubt O
had O
arisen O
about O
this O
when O
a O
city O
council O
member O
switched O
to O
the O
VLD B-ORG
and O
passed O
his O
colleague O
in O
the O
provincial O
council O
to O
the O
Vlaams B-ORG
Blok I-ORG
. O

Singer O
, O
showman O
and O
presenter O
Marcel B-PER
Vanthilt I-PER
will O
be O
on O
the O
list O
of O
Agalev B-ORG
in O
the O
next O
municipal O
elections O
in O
Antwerp O
. O

page O

' O

He O
gets O
the O
31st O
place O
and O
is O
part O
of O
the O
so O
- O
called O
cordon O
culturel O
on O
the O
green O
list O
. O

Number O
one O
on O
the O
list O
for O
the O
province O
is O
Frans B-PER
Verbergt I-PER
, O
who O
has O
been O
a O
provincial O
council O
member O
for O
ten O
years O
before O
the O
VLD B-ORG
. O

The O
list O
for O
the O
municipality O
is O
headed O
by O
André B-PER
Crahay I-PER
, O
a O
former O
bank O
clerk O
who O
is O
relatively O
new O
in O
politics O
. O

' O
We O
are O
the O
alternative O
' O
, O
reads O
the O
slogan O
with O
which O
WOW B-ORG
draws O
to O
the O
elections O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
. O

Vanthilt B-PER
is O
by O
no O
means O
the O
only O
BV B-MISC
on O
the O
Antwerp B-MISC
Agalev B-MISC
list I-MISC
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Actress O
Jeanine B-PER
Bishops I-PER
and O
author O
Tom B-PER
Lanoye I-PER
had O
already O
promised O
. O

" O
That O
does O
n't O
come O
with O
scaremakers O
and O
black O
eyes O
, O
" O
says O
the O
party O
, O
" O
we O
have O
it O
more O
for O
green O
, O
the O
color O
of O
hope O
. O

author O

section O

General O

At O
municipal O
level O
, O
the O
party O
wants O
to O
exercise O
general O
voting O
rights O
and O
in O
the O
district O
of O
Antwerp B-LOC
the O
Greens B-MISC
hope O
to O
become O
the O
largest O
party O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

In O
addition O
, O
Agalev B-MISC
- I-MISC
Antwerp I-MISC
unpacks O
with O
a O
list O
of O
Flemish B-MISC
people I-MISC
who O
support O
the O
party O
program O
, O
but O
are O
not O
on O
the O
list O
. O

According O
to O
Cahay B-PER
, O
his O
party O
is O
profiling O
itself O
as O
a O
link O
between O
the O
ages O
, O
which O
means O
that O
young O
people O
also O
get O
a O
chance O
. O

Artists O
for O
Agalev B-ORG

publication O

Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

The O
actresses O
Sarah B-PER
de I-PER
Bosschere I-PER
, O
Veerle B-PER
Dobbelaere I-PER
and O
Patricia B-PER
Goemaere I-PER
, O
writer O
Kristien B-PER
Hemmerechts I-PER
, O
musician O
and O
concert O
organizer O
Paul B-PER
Ambach I-PER
, O
actor O
Pol B-PER
Goossen I-PER
, O
authors O
Paul B-PER
Mennes I-PER
, O
Bart B-PER
Moeyaert I-PER
and O
Jeroen B-PER
Olyslaeghers I-PER
, O
and O
actor O
Carl B-PER
Ridders I-PER
signed O
for O
the O
program O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
" O
Let O
's O
leave O
that O
to O
the O
mediators O
, O
" O
that O
's O
what O
it O
was O
called O
yesterday O
-- O

First O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
have O
to O
leave O
, O
but O
in O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
they O
have O
no O
ears O
for O
that O
. O

' O

Foreign B-MISC

However O
, O
observers O
say O
that O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
have O
been O
withdrawn O
from O
the O
two O
western O
cities O
of O
Barentu B-LOC
and O
Tessenay B-LOC
, O
which O
were O
captured O
during O
the O
latest O
offensive O
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
wants O
to O
comply O
with O
the O
Four O
Point O
Plan O
of O
the O
Organisation B-ORG
of I-ORG
African I-ORG
Unity I-ORG
. O

This O
includes O
sending O
international O
observers O
to O
the O
disputed O
border O
area O
. O

Asmara B-LOC
does O
not O
want O
to O
hear O
from O
a O
truce O
until O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
are O
withdrawn O
. O

" O
We O
would O
like O
to O
go O
back O
to O
our O
positions O
of O
6 O
May O
1998 O
( O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
war O
, O
MR B-PER
) O
" O
, O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
Minister O
said O
. O

Ethiopia B-LOC
did O
it O
after O
it O
had O
taken O
back O
all O
the O
territory O
that O
was O
lost O
after O
the O
Eritrean B-MISC
invasion O
in O
' O
98 O
. O

section O

What O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
now O
wants O
guarantees O
for O
it O
will O
withdraw O
its O
troops O
, O
which O
are O
deeply O
pervaded O
in O
Eritrea B-LOC
. O

Opposite O
visions O
of O
when O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
should O
withdraw O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

date O
of O
publication O

Eritrea B-LOC
, O
says O
the O
BBC B-MISC
correspondent I-MISC
in O
Asmara B-LOC
, O
is O
very O
humiliated O
by O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
ruling O
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
and O
Ethiopia O
disagree O
on O
stock O

Moreover O
, O
the O
current O
situation O
is O
generally O
interpreted O
as O
one O
in O
which O
Ethiopia B-LOC
can O
dictate O
the O
laws O
because O
of O
its O
recent O
military O
successes O
, O
and O
that O
is O
unacceptable O
to O
Asmara B-LOC
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
called O
the O
whole O
thing O
curious O
. O

But O
according O
to O
the O
BCC B-ORG
, O
the O
Eritrean B-MISC
city O
of O
Zenefe B-LOC
remains O
occupied O
by O
Ethiopian B-MISC
soldiers O
. O

General O

" O
But O
then O
we O
want O
to O
make O
sure O
Eritrea B-LOC
does O
n't O
repeat O
the O
madness O
to O
just O
invade O
a O
neighbouring O
country O
. O

From O
the O
press O
agencies O

According O
to O
Ethiopia O
, O
the O
gun O
clatter O
is O
over O
, O
but O
Eritrea B-LOC
does O
not O
share O
that O
view O
. O

And O
right O
there O
, O
the O
shoe O
wrings O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

page O

edition O

publication O

What O
guarantees O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
wants O
was O
not O
immediately O
clear O
. O

It O
is O
a O
bit O
like O
one O
- O
handed O
blow O
: O
Ethiopia O
and O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
who O
have O
been O
at O
war O
for O
two O
years O
, O
are O
sitting O
in O
Algiers B-LOC
around O
the O
negotiating O
table O
. O

Algiers B-LOC

Ouyahia B-PER
mentioned O
the O
statement O
by O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
Foreign B-ORG
Minister O
Seyoum B-PER
Mesfin I-PER
that O
the O
war O
was O
over O
" O
an O
encouraging O
case O
. O
" O

In O
addition O
, O
cartographers O
should O
redesign O
the O
border O
, O
financial O
compensation O
should O
be O
provided O
for O
losses O
on O
both O
sides O
and O
an O
in O
- O
depth O
investigation O
of O
the O
causes O
of O
the O
conflict O
is O
also O
desirable O
. O

The O
Algerian B-MISC
Justice O
Minister O
Ahmed B-PER
Ouyahia I-PER
has O
been O
trying O
to O
mediate O
since O
Tuesday O
in O
the O
two O
- O
year O
- O
old O
conflict O
between O
Ethiopia O
and O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
which O
has O
flared O
up O
again O
in O
the O
last O
three O
weeks O
when O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
army O
crossed O
the O
border O
. O

Maarten B-PER
Rabaey I-PER

" O
How O
can O
they O
say O
the O
war O
is O
over O
? O

author O

We O
will O
not O
close O
a O
truce O
as O
long O
as O
Ethiopian B-MISC
soldiers O
are O
not O
much O
more O
than O
100 O
km O
from O
Asmara B-LOC
, O
" O
said O
Eritrean O
presidential O
advisor O
Yemane B-PER
Gebremeskel I-PER
. O

And O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
does O
n't O
want O
that O
until O
there O
are O
international O
guarantees O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Belga B-ORG
/ O
Own O
reporting O

General O

A O
tax O
reform O
should O
also O
eliminate O
discrimination O
between O
married O
and O
cohabitants O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

ACW B-MISC
president I-MISC
Theo B-PER
Rombouts I-PER
wants O
the O
forthcoming O
tax O
reform O
to O
benefit O
mainly O
low O
- O
income O
people O
. O

Wages O
have O
fallen O
below O
half O
of O
national O
income O
, O
which O
is O
no O
longer O
acceptable O
. O

page O

date O
of O
publication O

Journal B-MISC

Some O
must O
certainly O
go O
to O
social O
security O
and O
some O
must O
be O
spared O
. O

In O
his O
speech O
in O
Mechelen B-LOC
, O
Cortebeeck B-PER
stated O
that O
in O
addition O
to O
social O
benefits O
, O
wages O
also O
fell O
behind O
. O

Therefore O
, O
in O
the O
next O
intersectoral O
negotiations O
, O
the O
Christian O
trade O
union O
will O
work O
towards O
gradual O
wage O
increases O
as O
the O
best O
and O
most O
tried O
way O
to O
share O
the O
fruits O
of O
growth O
. O

According O
to O
Cortebeeck B-PER
, O
financial O
participation O
can O
not O
close O
the O
pay O
gap O
. O

The O
Christian O
trade O
union O
is O
in O
favour O
of O
a O
gradual O
increase O
in O
wages O
and O
social O
benefits O
, O
said O
ACV B-MISC
Chairman I-MISC
Luc B-PER
Cortebeeck I-PER
in O
his O
Rerum B-MISC
Novarum I-MISC
speech I-MISC
. O

Mechelen B-LOC
/ O
Brussels B-LOC

This O
should O
be O
accompanied O
by O
an O
increase O
in O
the O
net O
income O
of O
lowincome O
earners O
and O
families O
with O
dependent O
children O
. O

author O

" O
We O
have O
not O
surrendered O
for O
years O
to O
put O
the O
money O
for O
pensions O
and O
health O
care O
now O
in O
the O
hands O
of O
the O
private O
sector O
, O
" O
said O
the O
ACV B-MISC
President I-MISC
. O

He O
swore O
that O
the O
government O
would O
not O
simply O
enrich O
the O
private O
companies O
in O
the O
insurance O
sector O
by O
entrusting O
them O
with O
the O
fruits O
of O
the O
phasing O
- O
out O
of O
public O
debt O
. O

section O

According O
to O
Cortebeeck B-PER
, O
not O
all O
new O
government O
revenues O
should O
be O
reserved O
for O
ageing O
populations O
. O

In O
the O
case O
of O
profit O
participation O
, O
part O
of O
the O
employee O
income O
is O
made O
dependent O
on O
too O
many O
arbitrary O
decisions O
. O

For O
this O
reason O
, O
the O
ACW B-ORG
defends O
an O
increase O
in O
deductible O
occupational O
costs O
for O
wage O
and O
wage O
earners O
and O
a O
higher O
first O
untaxable O
income O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

In O
his O
speech O
in O
Wemmel O
, O
ACW B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Theo B-PER
Rombouts I-PER
also O
advocated O
a O
tax O
reduction O
which O
should O
primarily O
focus O
on O
income O
from O
work O
and O
, O
above O
all O
, O
on O
longer O
incomes O
. O

The O
resources O
available O
can O
be O
better O
used O
to O
strengthen O
the O
foundations O
of O
society O
, O
such O
as O
education O
and O
care O
, O
public O
transport O
and O
roads O
, O
food O
safety O
etc O
. O
Improvements O
to O
low O
incomes O
can O
only O
be O
achieved O
through O
an O
increase O
in O
the O
minimum O
standard O
of O
living O
, O
guaranteed O
income O
and O
social O
benefits O
. O

Profit O
- O
sharing O
presupposes O
power O
- O
sharing O
, O
but O
it O
is O
not O
granted O
to O
us O
, O
said O
Cortebeeck B-PER
, O
because O
employers O
do O
not O
want O
to O
know O
of O
a O
prior O
negotiated O
collective O
agreement O
in O
this O
area O
. O

ACV B-ORG
prefers O
wage O
increase O
over O
profit O
participation O

The O
trade O
union O
leader O
stated O
that O
the O
active O
welfare O
state O
also O
has O
shadowy O
sides O
. O

Finally O
, O
Rombouts B-PER
asked O
for O
fiscal O
incentives O
to O
live O
more O
environmentally O
friendlyly O
. O

The O
self O
- O
employed O
have O
already O
been O
served O
with O
FF O
1.5 O
billion O
, O
but O
the O
social O
welfare O
workers O
as O
disabled O
persons O
, O
disabled O
persons O
and O
the O
unemployed O
in O
financial O
need O
are O
not O
getting O
anything O
and O
are O
becoming O
more O
and O
more O
disadvantaged O
. O

Rerum B-MISC
Novarum I-MISC
speeches I-MISC
point O
to O
the O
shadow O
side O
of O
active O
welfare O
state O

edition O

publication O

A O
catching O
- O
up O
of O
wages O
and O
benefits O
is O
, O
according O
to O
the O
trade O
union O
leader O
, O
preferable O
to O
allowing O
workers O
to O
participate O
in O
their O
company O
's O
profits O
. O

Cortebeeck B-PER
looks O
forward O
to O
a O
tax O
reform O
, O
but O
is O
opposed O
to O
a O
general O
tax O
reduction O
. O

In O
any O
case O
, O
that O
formula O
requires O
participation O
in O
the O
determination O
of O
profits O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Sunday O
during O
the O
day O
builds O
up O
a O
back O
of O
high O
pressure O
from O
the O
southwest O
, O
gradually O
stabilizing O
the O
atmosphere O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

A O
few O
of O
them O
could O
grow O
into O
a O
loose O
mood O
in O
the O
west O
by O
the O
evening O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

section O

As O
a O
third O
factor O
, O
there O
is O
a O
cold O
front O
approaching O
from O
the O
west O
. O

Furthermore O
, O
the O
thermal O
vore O
will O
lie O
in O
our O
environment O
. O

By O
the O
way O
, O
it O
's O
been O
getting O
less O
hot O
since O
Sunday O
. O

Eddy B-PER
De I-PER
Mey I-PER

This O
morning O
, O
it O
's O
sunny O
. O

page O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

This O
morning O
, O
it O
's O
sunny O
. O

The O
pressure O
of O
the O
colder O
air O
causes O
strong O
rising O
movements O
to O
begin O
in O
the O
course O
of O
the O
day O
. O

Summer O
warm O
. O

Tomorrow O
increasing O
likelihood O
of O
rain O
and O
thunderstorms O
, O
followed O
by O
cooling O
. O

May O
was O
warmer O
than O
usual O
. O

The O
wind O
is O
generally O
weak O
and O
mainly O
blows O
from O
directions O
between O
south O
and O
southwest O
. O

Temperatures O
of O
25 O
degrees O
and O
more O
can O
be O
reached O
this O
afternoon O
. O

edition O

Tomorrow O
thunderstorms O

So O
the O
sun O
is O
pronounced O
master O
of O
the O
situation O
and O
the O
mercury O
goes O
on O
adventure O
. O

There O
is O
virtually O
no O
cloud O
in O
this O
. O

In O
many O
places O
the O
mercury O
does O
not O
drop O
below O
20 O
degrees O
before O
midnight O
. O

After O
the O
weekend O
the O
weather O
does O
n't O
look O
bad O
but O
also O
not O
quite O
steadfast O
. O

86 O
liters O
of O
precipitation O
fell O
in O
20 O
days O
against O
normal O
62 O
liters O
in O
15 O
days O
. O

19.1 O
( O
standard O
17.2 O
. O

At O
the O
flank O
of O
a O
more O
or O
less O
stationary O
ridge O
above O
Central B-LOC
and O
Eastern B-LOC
Europe I-LOC
, O
warm O
and O
initially O
stable O
air O
from O
France B-LOC
is O
being O
landed O
today O
with O
a O
southern O
current O
. O

The O
current O
that O
is O
anticyclonaally O
tinted O
today O
will O
become O
cyclonaal O
tomorrow O
. O

Min O
. O
11.3 O
( O
standard O
8.3 O
) O
. O

Max B-PER
. O

General O

A O
single O
shower O
can O
have O
hail O
on O
board O
and O
discharge O
locally O
so O
much O
water O
that O
causes O
nuisance O
. O

On O
the O
night O
of O
Saturday O
on O
Sunday O
, O
the O
cold O
front O
travels O
through O
the O
country O
. O

This O
afternoon O
we O
also O
have O
pile O
clouds O
. O

Later O
also O
pile O
clouds O
and O
tonight O
a O
small O
chance O
of O
a O
shower O
. O

The O
sun O
shone O
little O
( O
less O
than O
159 O
hours O
) O
against O
normal O
199 O
hours O
. O

publication O

Tonight O
it O
stays O
warm O
for O
a O
long O
time O
and O
in O
other O
words O
it O
is O
ideal O
garden O
or O
terrace O
weather O
. O

As O
a O
result O
, O
the O
chance O
of O
thunderstorms O
increases O
, O
as O
the O
afternoon O
and O
evening O
progresses O
. O

author O

Upon O
approaching O
a O
thermal O
vore O
, O
now O
still O
above O
the O
west O
of O
France B-LOC
, O
the O
atmosphere O
becomes O
somewhat O
unstable O
in O
the O
afternoon O
, O
creating O
a O
number O
of O
pile O
clouds O
. O

In B-MISC
the I-MISC
meantime I-MISC

Tomorrow O
increasing O
likelihood O
of O
rain O
and O
thunderstorms O
, O
followed O
by O
cooling O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Is O
that O
health O
standard O
often O
exceeded O
? O

More O
interesting O
is O
the O
new O
Dutch B-MISC
initiative O
of O
toll O
gates O
and O
billing O
around O
the O
big O
Dutch B-MISC
cities O
. O

Two O
Brussels B-MISC
environmental O
movements O
, O
Bral B-ORG
and O
Inter B-ORG
- I-ORG
Environment I-ORG
... O

Because O
studies O
show O
that O
car O
traffic O
is O
responsible O
for O
more O
than O
70 O
% O
of O
the O
high O
levels O
of O
ozone O
. O

The O
neighbouring O
countries O
have O
been O
working O
on O
such O
measures O
for O
some O
time O
, O
but O
Belgium B-LOC
is O
lagging O
behind O
. O

page O

It O
is O
not O
so O
much O
different O
from O
the O
old O
ozone O
plan O
announced O
in O
1996 O
. O

French B-MISC
cities O
such O
as O
Paris B-LOC
work O
with O
alternating O
driving O
bans O
, O
whereby O
even O
or O
odd O
number O
plates O
are O
not O
allowed O
to O
drive O
during O
ozone O
peaks O
. O

author O

" O
A O
number O
of O
German B-MISC
Länder O
are O
already O
introducing O
temporary O
speed O
limits O
. O

That O
's O
too O
bad O
. O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

For O
Brussels B-LOC
, O
these O
measures O
could O
be O
combined O
with O
the O
rapid O
development O
of O
a O
real O
Brussels B-MISC
suburban O
network O
with O
large O
parking O
spaces O
. O

" O
Last O
year O
it O
was O
exceeded O
in O
Brussels B-LOC
on O
27 O
days O
. O

If O
you O
're O
evened O
out O
, O
what O
are O
you O
going O
to O
do O
with O
the O
money O
in O
the O
event O
of O
an O
overrun O
? O

During O
days O
with O
high O
ozone O
peaks O
, O
population O
groups O
at O
risk O
are O
asked O
to O
remain O
indoors O
until O
the O
danger O
has O
passed O
. O

publication O

What O
measures O
are O
in O
force O
abroad O
? O

This O
means O
that O
older O
people O
, O
children O
or O
persons O
with O
asthma O
problems O
were O
always O
at O
serious O
health O
risks O
. O

Opinion B-MISC

' O

This O
is O
a O
considerable O
amount O
of O
money O
, O
just O
to O
force O
policy O
to O
take O
structural O
measures O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
. O

If O
we O
do O
receive O
money O
, O
we O
will O
transfer O
it O
to O
a O
fund O
that O
will O
help O
me O
finance O
the O
Brussels B-MISC
suburban O
network O
, O
for O
example O
. O

However O
, O
it O
was O
announced O
that O
the O
maximum O
speed O
would O
be O
limited O
. O

There O
they O
want O
to O
make O
the O
rates O
high O
enough O
to O
keep O
a O
large O
number O
of O
cars O
off O
the O
road O
. O

edition O

' O

' O
The O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
disappoints O
us O
greatly O
' O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

This O
also O
clashes O
with O
the O
Constitutional O
Article O
23 O
which O
guarantees O
' O
human O
dignity O
' O
to O
everyone O
. O

Given O
the O
number O
of O
overruns O
in O
1999 O
you O
can O
quickly O
become O
rich O
. O

Another O
study O
showed O
that O
1,200 O
people O
died O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
during O
the O
1994 O
heat O
wave O
due O
to O
high O
ozone O
concentrations O
during O
that O
period O
. O

The O
federal O
government O
just O
announced O
its O
ozone O
plan O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Ceustemans B-PER
: O
" O
At O
a O
time O
when O
the O
so O
- O
called O
European B-MISC
health O
standard O
of O
120 O
micrograms O
ozone O
per O
cubic O
metre O
is O
exceeded O
in O
Brussels B-LOC
for O
at O
least O
eight O
hours O
, O
we O
ask O
for O
compensation O
of O
50 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
. O

' O

" O
The O
paper O
disappoints O
us O
. O

General O

' O

' O

" O
We O
're O
not O
interested O
in O
the O
money O
, O
let O
's O
be O
clear O
about O
that O
. O

The O
case O
will O
be O
brought O
before O
the O
Court O
of O
First O
Instance O
on O
9 O
June O
. O

Are O
you O
satisfied O
with O
the O
work O
of O
the O
two O
green O
ministers O
, O
Magda B-PER
Aelvoet I-PER
and O
Isabelle B-PER
Durant I-PER
? O

The O
focus O
is O
on O
information O
and O
awareness O
raising O
, O
while O
there O
are O
few O
measures O
to O
limit O
car O
traffic O
during O
the O
summer O
months O
. O

It O
is O
unacceptable O
that O
the O
public O
authorities O
do O
not O
want O
to O
intervene O
with O
this O
knowledge O
, O
or O
hardly O
do O
so O
. O

The O
green O
ministers O
have O
not O
( O
yet O
) O
got O
that O
through O
. O

section O

What O
exactly O
is O
your O
demand O
? O

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

date O
of O
publication O

-DOCSTART O
edition O

page O

In O
total O
, O
he O
said O
he O
made O
some O
fifteen O
calls O
, O
including O
to O
the O
offices O
and O
departments O
of O
Transport B-ORG
, O
Economic B-ORG
Affairs I-ORG
and O
Finance B-ORG
. O

My O
mission O
was O
to O
identify O
any O
political O
problems O
. O

" O
According O
to O
Gantman B-PER
, O
a O
change O
in O
corporate O
tax O
law O
on O
the O
tax O
regime O
of O
capital O
gains O
was O
abnormally O
slow O
, O
" O
said O
Larmuseau B-PER
. O

Larmuseau B-PER
replied O
that O
he O
did O
not O
find O
Gantman B-PER
's O
question O
unjustified O
and O
credible O
. O

publication O

" O
It O
's O
been O
so O
long O
, O
I O
do O
n't O
remember O
anything O
about O
that O
. O

Hendrik B-PER
Larmuseau I-PER
, O
former O
advisor O
to O
the O
socio O
- O
economic O
cabinet O
of O
Prime O
Minister O
Jean O
- O
Luc B-PER
Dehaene I-PER
( O
CVP B-ORG
) O
, O
stated O
on O
Wednesday O
before O
the O
Committee O
of O
Inquiry O
into O
Ship O
Credits O
that O
Antwerp B-MISC
's I-MISC
lawyer O
André B-PER
Gantman I-PER
was O
also O
active O
in O
the O
Prime O
Minister O
's O
cabinet O
as O
a O
lobbyist O
of O
owner O
Rosenfeld B-PER
. O

section O

According O
to O
him O
, O
he O
did O
n't O
hear O
from O
the O
Treasury O
. O

' O

' O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

' O

' O

General O

Larmuseau B-PER
had O
two O
other O
meetings O
with O
Gantman B-PER
in O
the O
spring O
of O
1994 O
and O
, O
as O
a O
result O
of O
his O
investigation O
, O
was O
able O
to O
inform O
the O
lawyer O
that O
the O
legislative O
amendment O
was O
in O
accordance O
with O
normal O
procedures O
. O

" O
In O
such O
a O
cabinet O
you O
are O
constantly O
addressed O
by O
all O
kinds O
of O
people O
who O
need O
something O
. O

Gantman B-PER
lobbied O
Prime O
Minister O
Dehaene B-PER

Karel B-PER
De I-PER
Gucht I-PER
: O
" O
Did O
you O
do O
this O
for O
every O
stranger O
? O
" O

" O
He O
complained O
about O
this O
. O

" O
Did O
you O
do O
this O
for O
every O
stranger O
? O
" O
he O
asked O
the O
witness O
. O

But O
Larmuseau B-PER
could O
hardly O
remember O
anything O
about O
that O
working O
group O
. O

According O
to O
Larmuseau B-PER
, O
Gantman B-PER
first O
appeared O
in O
his O
office O
in O
April O
1994 O
without O
making O
an O
appointment O
in O
advance O
. O

Brussels B-LOC

" O
It O
seemed O
like O
an O
important O
problem O
, O
I O
decided O
it O
was O
my O
duty O
to O
check O
this O
out O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

I O
did O
not O
participate O
in O
negotiations O
on O
the O
tax O
problem O
. O

He O
also O
personally O
informed O
Prime O
Minister O
Dehaene B-PER
of O
the O
problem O
raised O
by O
Gantman B-PER
. O

author O

The O
Prime O
Minister O
's O
cabinet O
advisor O
immediately O
took O
action O
. O

" O
I O
have O
only O
experienced O
one O
or O
two O
meetings O
passively O
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O

Then O
Minister O
of O
Finance B-ORG
Philippe B-PER
Maystadt I-PER
( O
PSC B-ORG
) O
blocked O
the O
file O
, O
so O
Gantman B-PER
seemed O
to O
insinuate O
. O

Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

Commissioner O
Karel B-PER
De I-PER
Gucht I-PER
( O
VLD B-ORG
) O
was O
surprised O
by O
such O
diligence O
. O

( O
GT B-PER
) O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Journal B-MISC

Own O
Message O

During O
the O
same O
period O
, O
Larmuseau B-PER
was O
also O
a O
member O
of O
the O
interkabinets O
group O
around O
ABC B-ORG
Containerline I-ORG
, O
which O
was O
specifically O
set O
up O
to O
solve O
the O
tax O
problems O
that O
emerged O
in O
the O
context O
of O
the O
predefined O
takeover O
of O
the O
shipping O
company O
by O
the O
American B-MISC
swindler O
Gary B-PER
Blonder I-PER
. O

-DOCSTART- O
17 O

The O
International B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
must O
listen O
more O
to O
the O
people O
and O
impose O
less O
on O
countries O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
often O
tends O
to O
exhort O
countries O
, O
but O
one O
of O
the O
lessons O
of O
the O
financial O
crises O
in O
Asia B-LOC
is O
that O
it O
needs O
to O
listen O
better O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
itself O
must O
be O
the O
driving O
force O
behind O
such O
changes O
. O

Köhler B-PER
also O
said O
that O
he O
would O
like O
to O
talk O
about O
an O
Asian B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
, O
a O
plan O
on O
which O
the O
large O
industrialized O
countries O
and O
those O
responsible O
within O
the O
IMF B-ORG
have O
long O
been O
working O
. O

This O
led O
to O
the O
call O
for O
policy O
changes O
within O
the O
Fund O
. O

People B-MISC

The O
Prime O
Minister O
of O
Thailand B-LOC
, O
Chuan B-PER
Leekpai I-PER
, O
asked O
Köhler B-PER
to O
learn O
from O
" O
what O
happened O
in O
our O
country O
. O
" O

There O
is O
a O
monetary O
union O
in O
Europe B-LOC
and O
there O
is O
nothing O
against O
such O
unions O
anymore O
, O
the O
IMF B-MISC
top I-MISC
man I-MISC
said O
. O

John B-PER
Vandaele I-PER

publication O

page O

It O
called O
on O
the O
board O
to O
draw O
up O
a O
clear O
vision O
of O
the O
IMF B-ORG
's O
future O
role O
in O
the O
coming O
months O
. O

edition O

In O
Thailand B-LOC
, O
the O
financial O
crisis O
started O
in O
July O
1997 O
, O
followed O
by O
a O
number O
of O
Asian B-MISC
countries O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

According O
to O
the O
Thai B-MISC
Prime O
Minister O
, O
it O
is O
much O
more O
expensive O
to O
cope O
with O
the O
consequences O
of O
a O
crisis O
than O
to O
avoid O
a O
crisis O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
has O
received O
a O
lot O
of O
criticism O
that O
it O
did O
not O
see O
the O
problems O
in O
Asia B-LOC
coming O
in O
time O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Horst B-PER
Köhler I-PER

This O
is O
what O
Horst B-PER
Köhler I-PER
, O
the O
IMF B-ORG
leader O
in O
May O
, O
said O
yesterday O
in O
Bangkok B-LOC
, O
made O
a O
tour O
of O
Asia B-LOC
. O

It O
is O
up O
to O
the O
Asian B-MISC
countries O
themselves O
to O
decide O
on O
their O
own O
monetary O
fund O
, O
according O
to O
Köhler B-PER
. O

The O
administration O
must O
take O
the O
lead O
and O
not O
be O
dictated O
by O
, O
for O
example O
, O
the O
US B-MISC
Congress B-ORG
, O
Köhler B-PER
believes O
. O

Director O
IMF B-ORG

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Listen O
more O

section O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Tomorrow I-MISC

General O

AFP B-ORG

author O

-DOCSTART- O
date O
of O
publication O

But O
no O
one O
who O
can O
or O
wants O
to O
intervene O
. O

publication O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

page O

Koekelberg B-LOC
, O
Ganshoren B-LOC
, O
Jette B-LOC
and O
Sint B-LOC
- I-LOC
Agatha I-LOC
- O
Berchem O
, O
each O
with O
a O
piece O
of O
the O
infamous O
basilica O
on O
their O
territory O
, O
will O
not O
be O
able O
to O
make O
any O
extra O
money O
available O
for O
the O
necessary O
renovation O
and O
stabilisation O
works O
in O
the O
following O
years O
. O

However O
, O
it O
is O
not O
clear O
which O
ministry O
or O
department O
that O
should O
be O
. O

Simonet B-PER
transferred O
the O
concerns O
to O
Minister O
for O
the O
Interior B-ORG
Antoine B-PER
Duquesne I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
. O

Simonet B-PER
promised O
to O
study O
the O
problem O
of O
the O
basilica O
at O
federal O
level O
. O

The O
four O
Brussels B-MISC
municipalities O
that O
are O
now O
paying O
for O
the O
maintenance O
costs O
of O
the O
Basilica B-LOC
of I-LOC
Koekelberg I-LOC
have O
yet O
another O
cry O
for O
help O
. O

The O
basilica O
thus O
threatens O
to O
become O
a O
second O
Atomium B-LOC
. O

The O
four O
mayors O
ask O
that O
the O
federal O
government O
finally O
come O
up O
with O
money O
for O
the O
needy O
national O
monument O
. O

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

General O

Basilica B-LOC
of I-LOC
Koekelberg I-LOC
threatens O
to O
become O
second O
Atomium B-LOC

Life B-MISC

section O

The O
four O
mayors O
discussed O
their O
resentment O
with O
the O
Brussels B-MISC
Prime O
Minister O
Jacques B-PER
Simonet I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
during O
his O
round O
along O
the O
nineteen O
Brussels B-MISC
municipalities O
. O

edition O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

The O
Basilica O
appears O
not O
to O
belong O
to O
the O
Government O
of O
the B-MISC
Buildings I-MISC
as O
a O
national O
sanctuary O
, O
nor O
can O
the O
Ministry O
of O
Justice B-ORG
( O
which O
finances O
the O
recognized O
religions O
) O
intervene O
because O
the O
Basilica O
is O
not O
officially O
a O
church O
or O
cathedral O
. O

For O
years O
there O
have O
been O
cracks O
visible O
and O
occasional O
debris O
coming O
down O
. O

author O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

-DOCSTART- O
' O

" O
The O
system O
stopped O
in O
1990 O
because O
its O
administration O
cost O
a O
lot O
and O
it O
became O
increasingly O
difficult O
to O
distinguish O
between O
speculative O
and O
real O
transactions O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

publication O

I O
am O
not O
a O
priori O
opposed O
to O
a O
modest O
tax O
on O
the O
condition O
that O
it O
is O
done O
at O
a O
global O
level O
. O

' O

It O
sees O
more O
targeted O
actions O
: O
national O
states O
taking O
action O
against O
short O
- O
term O
money O
flows O
. O

page O

They O
believe O
that O
a O
global O
tax O
on O
currency O
exchange O
can O
prevent O
not O
only O
socially O
disruptive O
monetary O
crises O
but O
also O
money O
to O
contribute O
to O
development O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
the O
Senate B-ORG
's O
Finance I-ORG
Committee O
aims O
to O
gain O
a O
better O
understanding O
of O
the O
feasibility O
and O
desirability O
of O
the O
levy O
through O
hearings O
with O
experts O
and O
stakeholders O
. O

Hearing O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

However O
, O
he O
doubts O
whether O
the O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
is O
the O
best O
way O
to O
achieve O
it O
. O

section O

Internationally O
grew O
a O
whole O
movement O
around O
the O
levy O
named O
after O
the O
American B-MISC
economist O
James B-PER
Tobin I-PER
. O

Because O
a O
lot O
of O
Belgian B-MISC
representatives O
see O
something O
in O
the O
idea O
, O
Minister O
of O
Finance B-ORG
Didier B-PER
Reynders I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
decided O
to O
have O
its O
feasibility O
examined O
. O

General O

Governor O
Quaden B-PER
not O
a O
priori O
against O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC

author O

Banking O
sector O
calls O
taxation O
on O
speculative O
profits O
' O
undemocratic O
and O
inefficient O
' O

Quaden B-PER
was O
perfectly O
identified O
as O
a O
central O
banker O
in O
the O
two O
objectives O
of O
the O
levy O
: O
monetary O
stability O
and O
contributing O
to O
development O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

1 O

John B-PER
Vandaele I-PER

Committee B-ORG
on I-ORG
Finance I-ORG

This O
levy O
is O
the O
basis O
of O
the O
Flemish B-ORG
network I-ORG
against I-ORG
financial I-ORG
speculation I-ORG
, O
which O
consists O
of O
the O
two O
major O
trade O
unions O
and O
some O
NGOs O
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Tomorrow I-MISC

' O
Personally O
, O
I O
do O
n't O
see O
why O
you O
should O
n't O
tax O
all O
the O
exchange O
transactions O
. O

JVD B-PER

The O
words O
come O
from O
Governor O
Guy B-PER
Quaden I-PER
of O
the O
National B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
, O
and O
they O
were O
pronounced O
at O
the O
first O
hearing O
in O
the O
Senate B-ORG
on O
the O
so O
- O
called O
Tobin B-MISC
levy I-MISC
on O
Wednesday O
. O

Since O
you O
can O
no O
longer O
make O
that O
distinction O
, O
you O
have O
to O
tax O
all O
transactions O
as O
proposed O
by O
Tobin B-PER
. O

Director O
Georges B-PER
Martin I-PER
called O
the O
levy O
inefficient O
, O
undemocratic O
and O
unjust O
because O
no O
distinction O
is O
made O
between O
speculative O
and O
non O
- O
speculative O
capital O
movements O
. O

The O
Tobin B-MISC
levy I-MISC
was O
much O
less O
sympathetic O
to O
the O
Belgian B-ORG
Banking I-ORG
Association I-ORG
. O

edition O

Quaden B-PER
pointed O
out O
that O
with O
the O
so O
- O
called O
dual O
exchange O
market O
until O
1990 O
Belgium B-LOC
had O
the O
equivalent O
of O
a O
very O
sophisticated O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
. O

-DOCSTART O
- O
Brussels B-LOC

' O

President O
Francis B-PER
Vermeiren I-PER
of O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
( O
also O
VLD B-MISC
mayor I-MISC
of O
Zaventem B-LOC
) O
stresses O
that O
the O
participation O
has O
already O
produced O
a O
lot O
for O
the O
municipalities O
, O
partly O
due O
to O
the O
two O
privatisation O
rounds O
of O
recent O
years O
. O

date O
of O
publication O

Ships O
of O
Finance B-ORG
Hugo B-PER
Schiltz I-PER
( O
VU B-ORG
) O
had O
sent O
a O
letter O
to O
all O
his O
colleagues O
a O
few O
days O
before O
the O
general O
meeting O
explaining O
his O
vision O
. O

Nevertheless O
, O
Antwerp B-LOC
's O
concerns O
were O
not O
reflected O
. O

The O
municipalities O
and O
provinces O
have O
placed O
their O
participation O
in O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

On O
Wednesday O
, O
Antwerp B-LOC
voted O
against O
the O
measures O
which O
give O
the O
municipalities O
greater O
freedom O
in O
managing O
their O
Dexia B-MISC
participation I-MISC
. O

In O
a O
number O
of O
large O
cities O
, O
there O
is O
a O
desire O
to O
be O
able O
to O
decide O
on O
the O
future O
of O
their O
Dexia B-MISC
shares I-MISC
. O

These O
would O
function O
as O
forums O
in O
which O
municipalities O
could O
discuss O
a O
number O
of O
financial O
policy O
choices O
. O

It O
was O
agreed O
at O
the O
General O
Assembly O
to O
set O
up O
a O
series O
of O
working O
groups O
. O

Under O
certain O
conditions O
, O
the O
documents O
can O
also O
be O
sold O
on O
the O
stock O
exchange O
. O

This O
includes O
the O
pension O
file O
, O
the O
liberalisation O
of O
electricity O
traffic O
and O
the O
Geographical B-MISC
Information I-MISC
System I-MISC
( O
GIS B-MISC
) O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

Antwerp B-LOC
was O
one O
of O
the O
few O
votes O
against O
when O
the O
final O
proposal O
was O
put O
to O
the O
vote O
. O

This O
has O
become O
possible O
to O
a O
limited O
extent O
by O
Wednesday O
's O
decision O
to O
certify O
the O
shares O
. O

General O

This O
participation O
is O
now O
worth O
more O
than O
6 O
billion O
. O

Mayor O
Bob B-PER
Van I-PER
Hooland I-PER
( O
VU B-ORG
) O
of O
Sint B-LOC
- I-LOC
Martens I-LOC
- O
Latem O
, O
who O
also O
intervened O
at O
the O
General O
Assembly O
, O
feels O
the O
same O
way O
. O

It O
believes O
that O
the O
marketability O
of O
the O
effects O
between O
municipalities O
( O
the'internal O
market O
' O
) O
can O
already O
partly O
meet O
the O
wishes O
of O
the O
large O
cities O
. O

The O
city O
, O
which O
suffers O
from O
a O
large O
debt O
, O
would O
prefer O
to O
have O
more O
freedom O
to O
finance O
Dexia B-MISC
participation I-MISC
. O

Not O
only O
to O
sell O
, O
but O
also O
to O
buy O
. O

' O

This O
means O
that O
the O
participation O
in O
Dexia B-ORG
is O
watered O
down O
to O
about O
18.5 O
% O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
believes O
that O
these O
conditions O
are O
too O
strict O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
breaks O
Dexia B-MISC
unity I-MISC

This O
may O
be O
a O
way O
to O
increase O
the O
return O
on O
urban O
reserves O
. O

For O
example O
, O
Antwerp B-LOC
has O
already O
received O
about O
4.5 O
billion O
and O
a O
municipality O
like O
Schaerbeek B-LOC
2.3 O
billion O
. O

The O
Belgian B-MISC
municipalities O
and O
provinces O
had O
to O
make O
an O
important O
decision O
on O
Wednesday O
about O
their O
participation O
in O
the O
Dexia B-ORG
banking O
group O
. O

" O
I O
have O
the O
impression O
that O
many O
mayors O
do O
. O

The O
proposal O
was O
finally O
adopted O
by O
about O
87 O
% O
of O
the O
votes O
. O

He O
wants O
to O
professionalise O
the O
board O
, O
which O
is O
now O
politically O
constituted O
. O

author O

We O
should O
not O
try O
to O
cash O
out O
the O
shares O
as O
soon O
as O
possible O
. O

publication O

However O
, O
Van B-PER
Hooland I-PER
believes O
that O
the O
functioning O
of O
the O
municipal O
holding O
company O
can O
be O
improved O
. O

This O
operation O
separates O
the O
dividend O
right O
from O
the O
right O
to O
vote O
, O
making O
it O
possible O
for O
the O
municipalities O
to O
market O
some O
of O
their O
securities O
among O
themselves O
. O

This O
totals O
80 O
billion O
francs O
. O

Ruben B-PER
Mooijman I-PER

page O

Schiltz B-PER
: O
' O
The O
role O
of O
municipalities O
has O
changed O
' O

The O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
will O
subscribe O
to O
Dexia B-ORG
's O
current O
capital O
increase O
for O
4 O
billion O
francs O
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Tomorrow I-MISC

The O
local O
authorities O
, O
formerly O
the O
majority O
shareholder O
of O
the O
Community B-ORG
credit I-ORG
, O
own O
around O
22 O
percent O
of O
the O
Dexia B-MISC
group I-MISC
, O
in O
which O
the O
Community B-ORG
credit I-ORG
was O
absorbed O
. O

17 O

They O
want O
to O
sell O
all O
or O
part O
of O
their O
shares O
. O

section O

edition O

" O
The O
role O
of O
the O
municipalities O
has O
changed O
. O

The O
convergent O
interests O
of O
the O
group O
and O
of O
the O
Municipal B-ORG
Holding I-ORG
are O
no O
longer O
clear O
and O
become O
increasingly O
unclear O
, O
" O
said O
Schiltz B-PER
at O
the O
General O
Assembly O
. O

" O
I O
feel O
called O
to O
support O
the O
holding O
company O
. O

Ruben B-PER
Mooijman I-PER

The O
largest O
Flemish B-MISC
city O
did O
not O
consider O
the O
proposals O
to O
go O
far O
enough O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
According O
to O
local O
police O
officers O
, O
the O
motive O
for O
the O
hostage O
situation O
is O
obvious O
. O

The O
law O
enforcement O
services O
therefore O
tried O
to O
force O
a O
breakthrough O
through O
negotiation O
. O

author O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

edition O

But O
yesterday O
the O
unconfirmed O
rumor O
also O
came O
around O
that O
he O
would O
have O
beaten O
his O
wife O
and O
children O
in O
the O
old O
days O
. O

The O
man O
admitted O
that O
he O
" O
was O
having O
a O
hard O
time O
" O
and O
went O
to O
a O
psychiatrist O
. O

He O
did O
n't O
get O
any O
visitation O
rights O
from O
the O
judge O
either O
. O

There O
was O
confusion O
about O
his O
origins O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

The O
chance O
that O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
would O
also O
use O
effective O
force O
was O
considered O
very O
small O
all O
the O
time O
. O

Hostage O
owner O
could O
n't O
get O
divorce O

The O
children O
who O
were O
released O
slowly O
told O
the O
psychologists O
that O
the O
man O
was O
nice O
to O
them O
and O
told O
all O
the O
time O
about O
his O
own O
children O
. O

section O

Laundry B-LOC

That O
reassured O
him O
. O

From O
our O
on O
- O
the O
- O
spot O
reporter O

page O

publication O

About O
hostage O
taker O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
circulated O
a O
lot O
of O
stories O
yesterday O
. O

He O
was O
quite O
concerned O
that O
the O
police O
described O
him O
as O
insane O
. O

The O
spokeswoman O
of O
the O
Wasserbillig B-LOC
police O
André B-PER
Colas I-PER
could O
only O
confirm O
that O
he O
is O
a O
39 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
man O
of O
Tunisian B-MISC
descent O
with O
Luxembourg B-MISC
nationality O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

date O
of O
publication O

It O
was O
first O
stated O
that O
it O
was O
an O
Algerian B-MISC
who O
was O
mentally O
disturbed O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
1 O
& O
3 O
) O

General O

Crazy O
he O
was O
n't O
at O
all O
, O
just O
a O
bit O
' O
bitter O
' O
. O

Four O
years O
ago O
, O
his O
wife O
left O
him O
and O
the O
judge O
entrusted O
his O
two O
children O
, O
an O
11 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
girl O
and O
a O
5 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
boy O
, O
to O
the O
mother O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Until O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
on O
Wednesday O
night O
himself O
called O
the O
local O
radio O
station O
with O
the O
announcement O
that O
he O
is O
not O
from O
Algeria B-LOC
but O
from O
Tunisia B-LOC
and O
also O
from O
Luxembourg B-MISC
since O
1982 O
. O

The O
hostage O
taker O
is O
described O
as O
a O
sweet O
but O
very O
impulsive O
man O
. O

( O
CG B-PER
) O

He O
tried O
to O
talk O
to O
him O
on O
Wednesday O
and O
Thursday O
all O
the O
time O
, O
supported O
by O
a O
police O
psychologist O
. O

The O
children O
were O
reported O
to O
have O
both O
been O
in O
the O
day O
care O
center O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
" O

' O
Women O
of O
all O
cities O
: O
conquer O
the O
street O
during O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
' O

Or O
other O
special O
events O
for O
women O
. O

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

When O
I O
get O
back O
to O
the O
country O
, O
hopefully O
the O
whole O
fuss O
will O
be O
over O
. O

" O
We O
also O
invite O
them O
to O
the O
streets O
, O
" O
concludes O
Vandamme B-PER
. O

Moreover O
, O
it O
is O
long O
past O
not O
to O
do O
the O
sport O
, O
but O
to O
do O
the O
commerce O
. O

" O
I O
leave O
on O
vacation O
abroad O
. O

It O
does O
n't O
matter O
. O

page O

President O
Leen B-PER
Vandamme I-PER
of O
the O
VOC B-ORG
has O
nothing O
against O
" O
the O
game O
of O
football O
" O
in O
itself O
, O
but O
thinks O
that O
the O
event O
has O
already O
been O
preceded O
by O
the O
" O
excessive O
attention O
" O
in O
the O
media O
. O

" O
If O
football O
is O
so O
important O
to O
men O
that O
it O
makes O
a O
link O
, O
women O
also O
want O
a O
link O
from O
that O
site O
that O
announces O
the O
Women O
's B-MISC
Day I-MISC
of O
November O
11th O
. O

As O
long O
as O
women O
do O
not O
have O
to O
undergo O
football O
in O
the O
seat O
, O
two O
beside O
their O
partner O
for O
the O
tube O
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

date O
of O
publication O

Yeah O
, O
but O
not O
for O
the O
women O
who O
are O
stuck O
with O
a O
soccer O
crazy O
man O
at O
home O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

edition O

Of O
course O
, O
there O
are O
also O
women O
who O
are O
as O
crazy O
as O
their O
male O
partners O
, O
Vandamme B-PER
admits O
, O
who O
describes O
the O
VOC B-MISC
- I-MISC
refreshings I-MISC
about O
football O
as O
" O
ludicrous O
" O
. O

Dancing O
, O
theatre O
, O
film O
, O
café O
... O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

section O

This O
at O
least O
states O
the O
Women B-ORG
's I-ORG
Consultative I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
( O
VOC B-ORG
) O
which O
calls O
on O
Belgian B-MISC
women O
to O
enter O
the O
streets O
in O
mass O
during O
the O
upcoming O
European O
Football B-MISC
Championship I-MISC
and O
to O
go O
out O
of O
the O
game O
collectively O
. O

publication O

On O
the O
other O
hand O
, O
there O
are O
also O
many O
men O
who O
are O
already O
more O
than O
tired O
of O
the O
whole O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
thing O
. O

Life B-MISC

The O
VOC B-ORG
is O
also O
annoyed O
by O
the O
federal O
website O
that O
has O
recorded O
a O
link O
about O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
. O

Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
a O
party O
. O

' O

author O

General O

Vandamme B-PER
itself O
will O
not O
travel O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
streets O
in O
the O
coming O
weeks O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
You O
do O
n't O
usually O
hold O
on O
to O
something O
like O
that O
. O

The O
last O
time O
was O
in O
' O
98 O
against O
the O
Chicago B-ORG
Bulls I-ORG
, O
but O
Michael B-PER
Jordan I-PER
led O
his O
team O
in O
the O
Game B-MISC
Seven I-MISC
to O
the O
finals O
. O

We O
need O
to O
impose O
our O
way O
of O
playing O
. O

edition O

Sports B-MISC

section O

page O

With O
us O
that O
was O
a O
lot O
less O
. O

The O
LA B-ORG
Lakers I-ORG
of O
success O
coach O
Phil B-PER
Jackson I-PER
have O
lost O
the O
chance O
to O
turn O
the O
home O
advantage O
into O
a O
belching O
4 O
- O
2 O
win O
. O

Best B-PER
also O
played O
his O
part O
in O
the O
offensive O
, O
because O
he O
was O
good O
for O
24 O
points O
, O
of O
which O
15 O
in O
the O
last O
quarter O
, O
so O
that O
the O
Pacers B-ORG
can O
now O
look O
for O
a O
final O
place O
in O
Madison B-LOC
Square I-LOC
Garden I-LOC
. O

" O
He O
's O
an O
unadulterated O
fighter O
, O
" O
Blaizers B-MISC
- I-MISC
coach I-MISC
told O
Mike B-PER
Dunleavy I-PER
after O
the O
victory O
of O
hope O
. O

' O

' O

The O
Pacers B-ORG
were O
played O
out O
completely O
by O
the O
Knicks B-ORG
in O
the O
first O
quarter O
. O

' O

We O
can O
and O
then O
the O
road O
to O
the O
finals O
is O
open O
. O

He O
was O
pretty O
close O
to O
Sabonis B-PER
. O

Friday O
, O
2 O
June O
2000 O

date O
of O
publication O

" O
You O
win O
or O
lose O
a O
match O
with O
jumpshots O
, O
" O
found O
O'Neal B-PER
. O

" O
They O
get O
a O
chance O
that O
few O
NBA B-ORG
players O
are O
offered O
. O

Brussels B-LOC

That O
's O
what O
Mark B-PER
Jackson I-PER
agrees O
with O
. O

" O
Only O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
kept O
throwing O
in O
just O
about O
everything O
. O
