-DOCSTART- O
The O
text O
of O
the O
arrest O
is O
not O
yet O
available O
in O
writing O
, O
but O
the O
message O
was O
already O
made O
public O
by O
a O
communications O
firm O
that O
hired O
Floralux B-ORG
. O

In O
' O
81 O
, O
the O
then O
- O
French B-MISC
government O
regulated O
the O
situation O
with O
a O
BPA B-MISC
that O
allowed O
the O
company O
to O
set O
up O
on O
its O
own O
. O

publication O
. O

So O
today O
, O
Floralux B-ORG
is O
okay O
with O
all O
the O
licenses O
, O
but O
the O
BPA B-MISC
with O
which O
they O
could O
be O
obtained O
was O
contested O
because O
case O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
had O
her O
shell O
company O
from O
... O

In O
the O
first O
instance O
, O
Vandenbussche B-PER
was O
convicted O
in O
the O
early O
' O
90s O
of O
misconduct O
, O
but O
was O
later O
acquitted O
by O
the O
court O
of O
appeals O
in O
Ghent B-LOC
. O

SP B-ORG
is O
hard O
-- O
( O
Eric B-PER
, O
sd O
) O
Derycke B-PER
wants O
to O
approve O
BPA B-MISC
on O
condition O
that O
BPA B-MISC
" O
The B-MISC
Altitude I-MISC
" O
is O
accepted O
( O
Mayor O
of O
Moorslede B-LOC
Walter B-PER
Ghekiere I-PER
will O
make O
a O
proposal O
) O

It O
's O
not O
enough O
to O
say O
a O
harsh O
sentence O
, O
it O
says O
. O

Now O
, O
this O
court O
does O
not O
hold O
her O
to O
be O
guilty O
of O
any O
crime O
whatsoever O
. O

And O
it O
's O
rapidly O
growing O
into O
a O
hot O
garden O
center O
. O

page O
. O

There O
's O
a O
lot O
more O
being O
sold O
than O
you O
would O
expect O
in O
a O
plant O
farm O
. O

This O
is O
evident O
from O
a O
fax O
sent O
to O
her O
by O
her O
then O
- O
attorney O
- O
at O
- O
law O
, O
and O
taken O
during O
a O
house O
search O
. O

The O
case O
goes O
back O
to O
the O
late O
' O
80s O
. O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

It O
would O
have O
misused O
Space B-ORG
Order I-ORG
to O
get O
the O
BPA B-MISC
. O

The O
only O
evidence O
that O
survived O
to O
convict O
Vandenbussche B-PER
of O
involvement O
was O
her O
attendance O
at O
the O
Naval O
College O
when O
the O
Florida B-MISC
case I-MISC
was O
brought O
. O

At O
the O
end O
of O
' O
98 O
, O
the O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
made O
this O
regulation O
definitive O
by O
amending O
the O
zoning O
plan O
. O

guilt O
but O
not O
punishment O
. O

" O

He O
even O
did O
this O
as O
a O
joke O
and O
a O
monkey O
out O
of O
a O
block O
of O
chalk O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Five O
years O
after O
Easter O
, O
that O
's O
what O
the O
court O
of O
appeal O
seems O
to O
have O
thought O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
/ O
Brussels B-LOC

Locally O
, O
it O
's O
been O
suspected O
that O
Floralux B-ORG
funded O
Luc B-PER
Martens I-PER
' O
election O
campaigns O
, O
which O
, O
within O
the O
previous O
government O
, O
was O
still O
paying O
attention O
. O

The B-MISC
Life I-MISC

And O
Vandbussche B-PER
himself O
decided O
that O
the O
court O
wanted O
to O
try O
the O
" O
political O
evils O
of O
the O
past O
. O
" O

" O

The O
Court B-ORG
of I-ORG
Cassation I-ORG
overturned O
the O
arrest O
so O
that O
it O
had O
to O
be O
turned O
over O
to O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
of O
Antwerp B-LOC
. O

That O
's O
the O
essence O
of O
the O
arrest O
warrant O
issued O
by O
the O
Court O
of O
Appeal O
in O
Antwerp B-MISC
on O
Wednesday O
in O
the O
case O
of O
the O
controversial O
Floralux B-ORG
gardening O
center O
in O
Moorslede B-LOC
- I-LOC
Dadizele I-LOC
. O

Case O
manager O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
is O
convicted O
of O
conflict O
of O
interest O
, O
but O
she O
does O
n't O
get O
a O
punishment O
because O
a O
punishment O
would O
not O
make O
sense O
after O
all O
those O
years O
. O

It O
's O
already O
the O
interpretation O
given O
in O
the O
context O
of O
Floralux B-ORG
to O
the O
arrest O
-- O
see O
page O
one O
-- O
that O
a O
new O
political O
culture O
has O
begun O
, O
and O
the O
old O
political O
seeds O
that O
were O
disgusting O
may O
no O
longer O
have O
to O
be O
replaced O
by O
the O
closure O
of O
a O
case O
. O

What O
went O
on O
for O
years O
as O
a O
contentious O
CVP B-MISC
file I-MISC
is O
now O
being O
ridiculed O
by O
the O
courts O
for O
being O
the O
equivalent O
of O
an O
old O
cow O
. O

In O
order O
to O
survive O
, O
Floralux B-ORG
wants O
the O
agricultural O
land O
to O
be O
converted O
into O
a O
kmo O
zone O
. O

" O
Court B-ORG
condemned O
political O
acts O
of O
the O
time O
. O
" O

The O
lawyer O
writes O
, O
" O
... O
it O
's O
clear O
then O
that O
it O
was O
only O
for O
private O
purposes O
, O
that O
is O
, O
for O
your O
company O
, O
that O
it O
was O
realized O
, O
and O
the O
shipbuilding O
college O
acts O
as O
the O
gateway O
to O
that O
. O
" O

Nonetheless O
, O
she O
told O
VRT B-MISC
radio I-MISC
that O
she O
had O
nothing O
wrong O
. O

author O

Furthermore O
, O
it O
turns O
out O
that O
discussions O
were O
held O
with O
the O
Liberal O
Party O
-- O
then O
PVV B-ORG
-- O
one O
with O
the O
SP B-ORG
: O
" O
Waltniel B-PER
is O
in O
favour O
. O

And O
Delcroix B-PER
decided O
, O
" O
I O
'll O
get O
through O
it O
. O

publishing O
date O

And O
that O
context O
has O
allowed O
the O
dossier O
to O
always O
be O
bathed O
in O
an O
atmosphere O
of O
partisan O
funding O
in O
exchange O
for O
regularization O
. O

General O
. O

Files O
associated O
with O
partisan O
funding O
in O
exchange O
for O
regularization O

Floralux B-ORG
gets O
a O
license O
to O
set O
up O
a O
plant O
farm O
. O

" O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

The O
court O
in B-MISC
Antwerp I-MISC
denied O
the O
document O
as O
evidence O
, O
but O
read O
it O
during O
the O
hearing O
. O

What O
those O
political O
deeds O
were O
, O
can O
be O
traced O
back O
to O
the O
Atoma B-MISC
manuscripts I-MISC
that O
Leo B-PER
Delcroix I-PER
kept O
as O
secretary B-MISC
of O
the O
CVP O
. O

sect O
. O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

Lawyer O
Floralux B-ORG
: O
Nothing O
wrong O
with O
her O

About O
Floralux B-ORG
, O
it O
said O
, O
" O
They O
want O
regulation O
. O

editing O

-DOCSTART- O
Verberckmoes B-PER
is O
a O
committed O
Catholic O
dissident O
who O
, O
at O
the O
founding O
of O
the O
PVV B-ORG
, O
as O
a O
candidate O
for O
re O
- O
election O
, O
brought O
the O
liberal O
ranks O
up O
and O
almost O
immediately O
made O
him O
a O
representative O
of O
the O
people O
. O

Liberal O
Justice B-ORG
Minister O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
is O
not O
a O
candidate O
on O
the O
local O
LDC B-MISC
list I-MISC
for O
the O
upcoming O
municipal O
elections O
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
. O

A O
member O
of O
Inzet B-ORG
's O
council O
said O
, O
" O
The O
idea O
was O
that O
we O
would O
form O
a O
cartel O
as O
a O
group O
to O
then O
ask O
the O
voters O
for O
a O
new O
mandate O
. O

Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
admits O
that O
there O
may O
have O
been O
other O
motives O
for O
this O
as O
well O
. O

Willy B-PER
Van I-PER
Damme I-PER

" O
He O
does O
n't O
want O
to O
deceive O
voters O
and O
be O
a O
candidate O
to O
get O
elected O
to O
the O
city O
council O
. O

It O
's O
now O
defining O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

Within O
the O
LD B-ORG
, O
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
, O
there O
's O
great O
success O
. O

The O
proposal O
had O
grown O
quite O
spontaneously O
to O
a O
far O
- O
fetched O
majority O
, O
led O
by O
mayor O
Norbert B-PER
De I-PER
Batselier I-PER
( O
SP B-ORG
) O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

According O
to O
local O
LDP B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
, O
his O
decision O
is O
unforgettable O
. O

He O
's O
against O
the O
accumulation O
of O
mandates O
, O
" O
says O
De B-PER
Brandt I-PER
. O

So O
there O
was O
a O
proposal O
for O
a O
joint O
list O
with O
Inzet B-ORG
, O
where O
the O
LDP B-ORG
in O
Dendermonde B-LOC
forms O
the O
majority O
, O
and O
it O
's O
made O
up O
of O
SP B-MISC
's I-MISC
, O
NGO B-MISC
's I-MISC
and O
some O
independents O
. O

Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
: O
No O
candidate O
for O
Dendermonde B-LOC

For O
them O
, O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
is O
the O
future O
of O
the O
LDP B-ORG
, O
and O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
is O
the O
old O
political O
culture O
they O
corrupted O
. O

Willy B-PER
Van I-PER
Damme I-PER

Wilderness B-PER
can O
not O
persuade O
local O
LDCs B-ORG
to O
form O
a O
cartel O
with O
the B-PER
Batselier I-PER
's O
Playlist O

author O

" O

" O
This O
is O
the O
PVV B-ORG
of O
the O
past O
, O
or O
even O
worse O
, O
" O
said O
an O
NGO B-MISC
from O
Verwilghen B-PER
. O

For O
the O
LDC B-ORG
, O
which O
now O
has O
only O
four O
seats O
in O
the O
city O
council O
, O
there O
's O
a O
risk O
of O
a O
debacle O
. O

That O
official O
reason O
was O
given O
by O
Verwilghen B-PER
himself O
last O
night O
in O
a O
press O
release O
. O

Thunderbird B-LOC

It O
also O
, O
according O
to O
various O
sources O
, O
had O
the O
support O
of O
the O
top O
of O
the O
national O
LDC B-ORG
, O
and O
within O
the O
Dendermond B-MISC
LDC B-ORG
, O
it O
was O
led O
mainly O
by O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
. O

Now O
Hilde B-PER
Dierickx I-PER
and O
ships O
for O
Finance B-ORG
Marcel B-PER
Borms I-PER
are O
going O
to O
be O
on O
the O
list O
. O

The B-MISC
Life I-MISC

page O
. O

Some O
of O
you O
may O
be O
able O
to O
tear O
it O
off O
right O
now O
. O

General O
. O

He O
left O
active O
politics O
a O
few O
years O
ago O
, O
but O
remains O
an O
influential O
figure O
within O
the O
local O
liberal O
party O
, O
including O
through O
his O
son O
, O
Kristian B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
, O
who O
is O
a O
member O
of O
the O
city O
council O
. O

The O
majority O
in O
the O
local O
department O
, O
however O
, O
designed O
the O
vest O
. O

Some O
liberals O
have O
already O
taken O
steps O
towards O
engagement B-ORG
, O
or O
are O
planning O
to O
take O
steps O
towards O
engagement O
. O

That O
's O
-- O
according O
to O
circles O
within O
and O
outside O
the O
LDC B-ORG
-- O
it O
was O
initiated O
primarily O
by O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
, O
the O
old B-MISC
LDC I-MISC
representative I-MISC
for O
Dendermonde B-LOC
. O

" O

publishing O
date O

This O
is O
from O
our O
employee O
. O

editing O

Robert B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
, O
Marc B-PER
's O
father O
, O
grabbed O
a O
chair O
. O

And O
insiders O
say O
that O
the O
old O
dispute O
between O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
and O
his O
predecessor O
, O
Frans B-PER
Verberckmoes I-PER
, O
plays O
a O
big O
role O
in O
this O
. O

Rudy B-PER
De I-PER
Brandt I-PER
: O
Indeed O
, O
some O
people O
had O
not O
run O
for O
mayoral O
elections O
in O
anticipation O
of O
what O
Marc B-PER
Verwilghen I-PER
was O
going O
to O
do O
. O

sect O
. O

publication O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Parents O
who O
are O
lucky O
enough O
to O
have O
their O
child O
released O
are O
allowed O
to O
go O
home O
under O
police O
escort O
. O

Thank O
God B-PER
. O

" O
On O
Wednesday O
, O
she O
was O
a O
little O
sick O
. O

Sick O
parents O
powerlessly O
await O
release O
from O
procrastinating O
drama O

The O
child O
is O
barely O
three O
. O

In O
this O
little O
village O
of O
just O
2,300 O
people O
, O
we O
know O
who O
we O
are O
. O

" O
Dads O
do O
n't O
hurt O
babies O
, O
" O
they O
say O
. O

Dads O
do O
n't O
hurt O
kids O
, O
they O
say O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

Every O
year O
, O
the O
village O
is O
flooded O
with O
all O
kinds O
of O
people O
, O
mostly O
tourists O
, O
who O
come O
for O
walks O
and O
bikes O
in O
the O
wonderful O
surroundings O
. O

The O
parents O
are O
also O
visited O
by O
the O
Portuguese B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
ambassador O
and O
a O
representative O
of O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
government O
. O

publication O
. O

Colas B-PER
: O
A O
kid O
of O
that O
age O
does O
n't O
really O
realize O
what O
's O
going O
on O
. O

" O
The O
neighbor O
's O
daughter O
is O
there O
. O

publishing O
date O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

The O
kids O
, O
according O
to O
the O
law O
enforcement O
, O
are O
doing O
fine O
. O

But O
hostages O
they O
've O
never O
had O
before O
. O

My O
daughter O
kept O
her O
at O
home O
. O

General O
. O

" O

Shortly O
after O
seven O
hours O
, O
all O
of O
a O
sudden O
, O
salvation O
came O
. O

sect O
. O

Every O
now O
and O
then O
there O
's O
an O
applause O
at O
the O
cultural O
center O
. O

They O
've O
slept O
well O
, O
and O
they O
've O
had O
time O
to O
eat O
. O

Now O
, O
who O
's O
doing O
this O
? O

But O
nobody O
knows O
what O
's O
going O
to O
happen O
. O

" O
The O
worst O
thing O
is O
when O
they O
come O
in O
and O
they O
say O
children O
have O
been O
released O
and O
then O
they O
hear O
that O
your O
child O
's O
not O
there O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

And O
then O
you O
just O
die O
. O

" O
We O
hold O
ourselves O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
man O
in O
question O
is O
the O
father O
himself O
. O

The O
whole O
neighborhood O
around O
the O
crèche O
is O
hermetically O
closed O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

And O
as O
the O
afternoon O
goes O
by O
, O
the O
atmosphere O
gets O
darker O
. O

because O
it O
's O
a O
melting O
pot O
where O
Portuguese B-MISC
, O
Italian B-MISC
, O
Polish B-MISC
, O
German B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
immigrants O
-- O
who O
'd O
come O
here O
to O
work O
in O
the O
steel O
and O
tape O
industry O
-- O
live O
side O
by O
side O
in O
peace O
. O

The O
inhabitants O
of O
Wasserbillig B-LOC
, O
a O
small O
idyllic O
village O
in O
Luxembourg B-MISC
, O
smashed O
into O
the O
German B-MISC
border O
, O
reacted O
shocked O
. O

After O
a O
few O
shots O
, O
the O
silence O
went O
away O
. O

Every O
now O
and O
then O
, O
they O
'll O
also O
see O
a O
circus O
or O
a O
guy O
, O
just O
like O
in O
the O
past O
few O
days O
. O

The O
municipal O
daycare O
center O
in O
Rue B-LOC
du I-LOC
Bocksberg I-LOC
is O
completely O
surrounded O
by O
special O
intervention O
calls O
from O
the O
Luxembourg B-MISC
, O
German B-MISC
and O
French B-MISC
police O
. O

" O

editing O

" O
Many O
frustrated O
looking O
faces O
. O

Everybody O
gets O
ready O
for O
a O
second O
night O
of O
fear O
. O

And O
the O
old O
lady O
looks O
up O
in O
dismay O
at O
the O
white O
building O
in O
the O
distance O
. O

" O

Some O
parents O
panic O
and O
fear O
the O
worst O
, O
others O
try O
to O
hold O
back O
the O
courage O
. O

Let O
's O
hope O
they O
're O
right O
. O

He O
describes O
the O
atmosphere O
in O
the O
cultural O
center O
as O
dramatic O
. O

These O
are O
relentless O
toddlers O
and O
toddlers O
. O

" O

page O
. O

author O

" O

The O
industry O
left O
a O
few O
decades O
ago O
, O
the O
immigrants O
stayed O
. O

The O
big O
walls O
beneath O
his O
eyes O
conceal O
that O
he O
's O
been O
sitting O
there O
a O
sleepless O
night O
. O

And O
even O
worse O
, O
when O
you O
get O
the O
message O
that O
the O
hostage O
has O
brought O
food O
and O
drink O
for O
three O
days O
, O

" O
I O
was O
listening O
to O
my O
radio O
. O

They O
're O
sad O
because O
their O
kid O
's O
niece O
or O
boyfriend O
is O
there O
. O

" O

" O
My O
little O
daughter O
has O
escaped O
death O
, O
" O
said O
the O
woman O
. O

The O
young O
man O
sucks O
deep O
. O

From O
our O
local O
reporter O

" O

Waterproof B-LOC
. O

Outside O
, O
there O
are O
50 O
villagers O
who O
want O
to O
support O
the O
affected O
parents O
. O

The O
route B-LOC
du I-LOC
Luxembourg I-LOC
, O
the O
street O
in O
front O
of O
the O
city O
hall O
, O
was O
rebuilt O
yesterday O
to O
a O
boulevard O
, O
where O
hundreds O
of O
disaster O
spectators O
lined O
up O
, O
looking O
at O
cars O
( O
more O
than O
20 O
) O
and O
press O
( O
more O
than O
a O
hundred O
) O
instead O
of O
pedestrians O
. O

The O
parents O
of O
the O
stranded O
little O
ones O
are O
taken O
hundreds O
of O
meters O
away O
to O
the O
cultural O
center O
. O

It O
's O
a O
phantom O
on O
what O
could O
have O
been O
a O
beautiful O
summer O
vacation O
day O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
one O
and O
three O
) O

The O
waiter O
starts O
to O
get O
nervous O
because O
his O
demands O
are O
n't O
being O
met O
quickly O
enough O
. O

Fortunately O
for O
them O
, O
their O
child O
is O
not O
among O
the O
trapped O
. O

Through O
psychologists O
, O
parents O
are O
informed O
. O

Ramotti B-PER
is O
one O
of O
the O
few O
parents O
ever O
to O
want O
to O
lose O
something O
. O

And O
also O
, O
tiredness O
is O
starting O
to O
take O
its O
toll O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
General O

And O
that O
can O
only O
happen O
in O
a O
democracy O
or O
... O

The O
rare O
occasions O
when O
Belgian B-MISC
ancestors O
betrayed O
themselves O
occurred O
when O
they O
saw O
their O
own O
position O
in O
jeopardy O
: O
during O
the O
King O
's O
Crusade O
, O
the O
independence O
of O
Congo B-LOC
, O
or O
state O
reform O
. O

Not O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
not O
in O
Laeken B-LOC
. O

page O
. O

He O
can O
not O
have O
his O
own O
opinion O
, O
and O
all O
of O
his O
actions O
are O
prosecuted O
by O
the O
government O
, O
which O
in O
turn O
is O
accountable O
to O
the O
people O
's O
representatives O
. O

" O
My O
kingdom O
for O
purple O
... O
" O

Some O
point O
to O
the O
growing O
influence O
of O
the O
French B-MISC
liberals O
in O
the O
courtroom O
. O

Karl B-PER
van I-PER
den I-PER
Broeck I-PER

It O
's O
a O
simple O
solution O
, O
but O
the O
legitimacy O
of O
the O
exercise O
of O
power O
is O
not O
terribly O
great O
. O

That O
's O
why O
democracy O
is O
the O
least O
evil O
form O
of O
government O
: O
the O
transfer O
of O
power O
is O
peaceful O
, O
and O
the O
people O
in O
power O
have O
legitimacy O
to O
which O
they O
can O
not O
be O
returned O
. O

Officially O
, O
though O
, O
it O
's O
very O
simple O
: O
the O
king O
is O
an O
empty O
box O
. O

That O
's O
why O
it O
's O
such O
a O
valuable O
feature O
of O
a O
civilized O
society O
that O
the O
transfer O
of O
power O
happens O
in O
a O
peaceful O
way O
. O

In O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
that O
was O
still O
often O
one O
segment O
of O
the O
majority O
: O
the O
Christian O
- O
democratic O
segment O
. O

In O
a O
monarchy O
, O
the O
question O
of O
who O
has O
the O
right O
to O
exercise O
power O
is O
left O
to O
fate O
: O
who O
is O
born O
into O
the O
king O
's O
seed O
will O
later O
become O
king O
himself O
. O

editing O

publication O
. O

And O
what O
the O
polls O
are O
pointing O
out O
is O
that O
something O
fundamental O
has O
changed O
in O
this O
country O
since O
the O
establishment O
of O
the O
purple O
- O
green O
coalition O
. O

publishing O
date O

Maybe O
it O
's O
all O
much O
simpler O
. O

The O
natural O
ally O
of O
the O
court O
, O
the O
Christian O
oath O
, O
has O
been O
turned O
into O
opposition O
, O
and O
the O
country O
is O
governed O
by O
a O
Republican O
coalition O
. O

Opinion B-MISC
. O

In O
a O
modern O
democracy O
, O
a O
king O
can O
only O
behave O
if O
he O
does O
not O
upset O
the O
majority O
. O

Whoever O
has O
to O
stay O
out O
of O
power O
gets O
into O
a O
fight O
. O

Prince O
Laurent B-PER
's O
crypto O
- O
masons O
training O
would O
be O
a O
striking O
example O
of O
that O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

author O

In O
that O
way O
, O
the O
king O
was O
reduced O
to O
a O
spokesperson O
for O
the O
majority O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

Belgium B-LOC
, O
of O
course O
, O
was O
in O
trouble O
when O
in O
1830 O
it O
elected O
a O
constitutional O
monarchy O
. O

That O
's O
the O
case O
in O
Britain B-LOC
, O
that O
's O
the O
case O
in O
the O
Netherlands B-LOC
-- O
that O
was O
invented O
by O
Queen O
Beatrix B-PER
-- O
and O
, O
of O
course O
, O
that O
's O
the O
case O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
. O

The O
issue O
of O
abortion O
confronted O
the O
preacher O
again O
and O
again O
with O
the O
dark O
side O
of O
his O
political O
neutrality O
: O
that O
his O
religious O
beliefs O
were O
also O
undermined O
, O
and O
that O
was O
unacceptable O
to O
the O
deep O
- O
seated O
preacher O
. O

sect O
. O

The O
CVP B-ORG
reacts O
cautiously O
and O
accuses O
the O
king O
of O
partisanship O
. O

He O
knows O
that O
if O
he O
does O
n't O
sign O
the O
euthanasia O
bill O
next O
year O
, O
he O
'll O
sign O
his O
death O
wish O
. O

The O
king O
, O
from O
the O
very O
beginning O
, O
was O
in O
a O
difficult O
position O
: O
he O
had O
to O
remain O
in O
the O
public O
good O
in O
order O
to O
preserve O
his O
power O
, O
and O
he O
had O
to O
take O
refuge O
in O
canopy O
politics O
and O
shadowy O
areas O
and O
lobbying O
in O
order O
to O
exercise O
any O
power O
at O
all O
. O

in O
a O
monarchy O
. O

Whoever O
has O
power O
wants O
to O
retain O
power O
. O

The O
fact O
that O
King O
Albert B-PER
and O
his O
children O
are O
becoming O
increasingly O
purple O
reminds O
the O
CVP B-ORG
that O
they O
no O
longer O
share O
bed O
sheets O
. O

And O
king O
Albert B-PER
? O

The O
nineteen O
- O
year O
- O
old O
grabbed O
his O
gun O
and O
shot O
him O
. O

And O
when O
he O
stood O
up O
, O
he O
did O
n't O
resist O
. O

sect O
. O

author O

The O
room O
and O
the O
hallway O
in O
which O
the O
facts O
were O
played O
were O
refurbished O
in O
anticipation O
of O
the O
possible O
departure O
of O
the O
Charleroi B-LOC
department O
. O

The B-MISC
Life I-MISC

Four O
teams O
from O
the O
Charleroi B-LOC
County O
Sheriff O
's O
Department O
raided O
the O
sanctuary O
shortly O
after O
the O
incident O
because O
it O
was O
believed O
that O
the O
director O
of O
the O
sanctuary O
was O
dead O
. O

The O
other O
inhabitants O
of O
the O
house O
were O
picked O
up O
by O
a O
team O
of O
psychologists O
. O

A O
94 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
in O
an O
orphanage O
in O
Aiseau B-LOC
- I-LOC
Presles I-LOC
yesterday O
morning O
chased O
a O
bullet O
through O
the O
head O
of O
the O
homeowner O
's O
shop O
from O
a O
short O
distance O
. O

And O
then O
the O
man O
went O
into O
his O
room O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

According O
to O
the O
sheriff O
's O
office O
, O
the O
elderly O
could O
not O
explain O
his O
actions O
. O

publication O
. O

The O
perpetrator O
could O
eventually O
be O
transferred O
to O
the O
sheriff O
's O
office O
. O

( O
KDM B-PER
) O

The O
man O
was O
taking O
care O
of O
the O
shooter O
when O
it O
came O
to O
a O
high O
- O
profile O
argument O
. O

editing O

An O
elderly O
man O
shoots O
down O
a O
retirement O
home O
director O

page O
. O

General O
. O

The O
victim O
was O
hit O
by O
a O
bullet O
in O
the O
head O
and O
was O
taken O
to O
the O
Fabio B-ORG
's I-ORG
Hospital I-ORG
in O
Auvelais B-LOC
. O

The O
shooter O
was O
no O
longer O
in O
critical O
condition O
after O
the O
shooting O
. O

The O
old O
man O
was O
spotted O
in O
an O
intersection O
as O
he O
moved O
from O
the O
room O
he O
was O
moving O
out O
into O
the O
hallway O
. O

Kristof B-PER
Demagogic I-PER

He O
does O
n't O
even O
seem O
to O
be O
aware O
of O
his O
behavior O
, O
or O
the O
seriousness O
of O
the O
facts O
. O

publishing O
date O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

-DOCSTART- O
That O
Baan B-ORG
would O
be O
taken O
over O
was O
almost O
certain O
. O

So O
Invensys B-ORG
already O
has O
a O
10.8 O
percent O
stake O
. O

There O
must O
be O
a O
thousand O
people O
away O
from O
Baan B-ORG
. O

" O
We O
think O
Invensys B-ORG
is O
the O
right O
company O
to O
restructure O
Baan B-ORG
. O

publication O
. O

The O
cost O
of O
reorganizing O
would O
be O
at O
the O
heart O
of O
that O
. O

By O
the O
way O
, O
Invensys B-ORG
itself O
is O
n't O
doing O
too O
well O
either O
. O

That O
company O
was O
formed O
by O
the O
merger O
of O
Siebe B-ORG
and O
BTR B-ORG
. O

editing O

Invensys B-ORG
is O
able O
to O
leverage O
Baan B-ORG
's O
software O
as O
a O
complement O
to O
its O
control O
systems O
for O
factories O
and O
installations O
. O

Seventeen O
. O

Invensys B-ORG
offers O
858 O
million O
Euros O
to O
Baan B-ORG
, O
or O
2.85 O
Euros O
per O
share O
in O
accounts O
. O

The O
hope O
is O
that O
next O
year O
, O
the O
losers O
will O
be O
remembered O
as O
the O
past O
. O

Baan B-ORG
in O
British B-MISC
hands O

General O
. O

sect O
. O

The O
chartered O
business O
bank O
Lazard B-ORG
Frères I-ORG
has O
been O
leasing O
the O
software O
company O
since O
January O
. O

publishing O
date O

It O
just O
did O
n't O
seem O
like O
anybody O
wanted O
to O
have O
the O
sparkling O
enterprise O
. O

Take O
over O
. O

Baan B-ORG
's O
share O
rose O
13 O
percent O
on O
Wednesday O
to O
2.97 O
euros O
, O
while O
Invensys B-ORG
had O
to O
raise O
13 O
percent O
to O
230 O
pence O
. O

That O
's O
8.8 O
percent O
more O
than O
Tuesday O
's O
lottery O
. O

The O
founders O
of O
the O
company O
, O
the O
brothers O
Jan B-PER
and O
Paul B-PER
Baan I-PER
, O
have O
pledged O
to O
sell O
their O
shares O
in O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

At O
the O
time O
of O
Baan B-ORG
's O
acquisition O
, O
the O
British B-MISC
company O
reported O
a O
loss O
of O
238 O
million O
pounds O
, O
more O
than O
double O
the O
year O
before O
. O

Baan B-ORG
was O
once O
one O
of O
the O
best O
performing O
stocks O
in O
Europe B-LOC
, O
but O
in O
two O
years O
lost O
90 O
percent O
of O
its O
value O
to O
sustained O
losses O
and O
management O
problems O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

There O
are O
other O
groups O
within O
the O
company O
that O
are O
doing O
this O
as O
well O
. O

Invensys B-ORG
wants O
to O
completely O
reorganize O
the O
company O
, O
and O
it O
's O
raising O
400 O
million O
dollars O
to O
do O
that O
. O

The O
idea O
is O
to O
keep O
the O
name O
Baan B-ORG
, O
but O
as O
part O
of O
Invensys B-ORG
Software I-ORG
and I-ORG
Systems I-ORG
. O

Bloomberg B-ORG

The O
Dutch B-MISC
software O
maker O
Baan B-ORG
is O
bought O
by O
the O
British B-MISC
company O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

page O
. O

We O
want O
to O
do O
it O
soon O
, O
" O
said O
Allen B-PER
Yurko I-PER
, O
CEO O
of O
Invensys B-ORG
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Morning I-MISC

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

author O

-DOCSTART O
: O
Back O
to O
Cuba B-LOC
, O
Elian O
, O
step O
closer O

General O
. O

In O
the O
former O
Yugoslav B-MISC
Republic O
of O
Serbia B-LOC
, O
several O
high O
- O
ranking O
officials O
and O
criminals O
have O
been O
killed O
recently O
, O
but O
it O
's O
the O
first O
time O
that O
something O
like O
this O
has O
happened O
in O
Montenegro B-LOC
, O
the O
other O
republic O
of O
the O
former O
Yugoslav B-LOC
Federation I-LOC
. O

editing O

The O
return O
of O
Cuban B-MISC
boat O
refugee O
Elián B-PER
González I-PER
from O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
to O
his O
homeland O
came O
a O
step O
closer O
yesterday O
. O

So O
here O
's O
the O
short O
story O
. O

The O
family O
is O
now O
appealing O
to O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
. O

The O
Hammersmith B-LOC
Bridge I-LOC
in O
western O
London B-LOC
was O
damaged O
yesterday O
by O
a O
bomb O
blast O
. O

Tree O
explodes O
under O
London B-MISC
's I-MISC
bridge O

Abroad B-MISC
. O

Western O
Montenegro B-LOC
is O
trying O
to O
take O
an O
independent O
path O
from O
Slobodan B-PER
Milosevic I-PER
's O
Serbia O
. O

There O
were O
no O
casualties O
, O
but O
there O
was O
a O
huge O
traffic O
jam O
. O

The O
police O
discovered O
a O
small O
explosive O
that O
was O
attached O
to O
a O
support O
bar O
of O
the O
bridge O
that O
connects O
the O
two O
banks O
of O
the O
Theems B-LOC
River O
. O

The O
Northern B-MISC
Irish I-MISC
unionists O
point O
the O
finger O
at O
Republican O
splinter O
movements O
, O
because O
the O
Irish B-ORG
Republican I-ORG
Leger I-ORG
( O
IRA B-ORG
) O
had O
already O
carried O
out O
a O
failed O
attack O
on O
the O
bridge O
in O
1996 O
. O

There O
is O
considerable O
tension O
between O
the O
two O
republics O
. O

The O
judge O
's O
ruling O
was O
the O
latest O
development O
in O
the O
lawsuit O
filed O
by O
Elijah B-MISC
's I-MISC
family O
in O
Miami B-LOC
to O
keep O
the O
child O
in O
the O
United O
States B-LOC
, O
where O
it O
was O
taken O
after O
his O
dramatic O
shipwreck O
. O

According O
to O
the O
court O
, O
only O
his O
father O
can O
do O
that O
for O
him O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

A O
court O
of O
appeal O
in O
Atlanta B-LOC
ruled O
that O
the O
six O
- O
year O
- O
old O
boy O
was O
not O
eligible O
to O
apply O
for O
asylum O
in O
the O
United O
States B-LOC
on O
his O
own O
. O

The O
security O
adviser O
of O
President O
Djukanovic B-PER
of O
Montenegro B-LOC
has O
been O
killed O
by O
unknowns O
in O
the O
capital O
city O
of O
Podgorica B-LOC
. O

publication O
. O

page O
. O

Until O
that O
case O
is O
settled O
, O
the O
boy O
has O
to O
stay O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
. O

The O
police O
found O
Goran B-PER
Zugic I-PER
's O
body O
in O
the O
garden O
next O
to O
his O
home O
, O
after O
a O
neighbor O
had O
heard O
gunfire O
. O

publishing O
date O

Montenegro B-LOC
's O
president O
kills O
co O
- O
worker O

The O
police O
are O
investigating O
whether O
the O
failed O
attack O
is O
the O
work O
of O
dissident O
paramilitaries O
in O
Northern B-LOC
Ireland I-LOC
who O
are O
opposing O
the O
self O
- O
government O
that O
was O
handed O
back O
to O
the O
province O
this O
week O
. O

author O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

sect O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
In O
the O
evening O
, O
he O
let O
go O
of O
17 O
children O
and O
two O
tutors O
. O

Waterproof B-LOC
. O

From O
our O
local O
reporter O

In O
addition O
to O
five O
French B-MISC
girls O
, O
three O
German B-MISC
girls O
and O
an O
Italian B-MISC
girl O
, O
there O
was O
also O
an O
eight O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Belgian B-MISC
girl O
who O
was O
detained O
. O

On O
Thursday O
morning O
, O
at O
midnight O
, O
the O
ultimatum O
was O
that O
Bejui B-PER
was O
going O
to O
get O
a O
minibus O
to O
the O
airport O
and O
get O
an O
airplane O
to O
Libya B-LOC
. O

The O
police O
intervened O
because O
the O
kidnapper O
was O
planning O
to O
take O
a O
number O
of O
children O
with O
him O
if O
he O
wanted O
to O
flee O
. O

The O
man O
was O
holding O
the O
children O
and O
their O
caregivers O
in O
a O
day O
care O
center O
in O
Waterbillig B-LOC
, O
a O
place O
in O
the O
Grand O
Duchy O
of B-LOC
Luxembourg I-LOC
. O

page O
. O

The O
siege O
of O
twenty O
- O
five O
children O
and O
two O
facilitators O
in O
Luxembourgish B-MISC
last O
night O
ended O
well O
over O
seven O
hours O
for O
the O
facilitators O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

editing O

Thirteen O
of O
the O
children O
are O
of O
Portuguese B-MISC
descent O
. O

Page O
three O
. O

The O
police O
's O
actions O
were O
initially O
undermined O
by O
the O
fact O
that O
the O
kidnapper O
was O
closely O
following O
the O
news O
on O
television O
and O
radio O
. O

Yesterday O
, O
the O
kidnapper O
left O
four O
more O
children O
to O
go O
in O
the O
course O
of O
the O
day O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
one O
and O
three O
) O

Gunshotgun O
ends O
drowning O
in O
Waterville B-LOC

An B-PER
Bruyninckx I-PER

According O
to O
the O
latest O
reports O
, O
the O
man O
had O
two O
gunshots O
in O
his O
head O
and O
his O
life O
was O
in O
danger O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

publishing O
date O

sect O
. O

publication O
. O

author O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

He O
would O
have O
asked O
for O
60 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
. O

The O
drowning O
began O
at O
around O
midnight O
on O
Wednesday O
afternoon O
when O
the O
man O
, O
armed O
with O
a O
knife O
, O
a O
gun O
and O
a O
grenade O
, O
entered O
the O
day O
care O
center O
. O

General O
. O

The O
hostage O
, O
39 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
, O
was O
shot O
by O
a O
sniper O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
In O
April O
last O
year O
, O
there O
was O
a O
controversy O
over O
the O
file O
when O
Steve B-PER
Stevaert I-PER
, O
then O
Minister O
of O
Housing B-ORG
, O
consciously O
broke O
into O
the O
BPA B-MISC
after O
the O
auditor O
at O
the O
State B-ORG
Council I-ORG
advised O
him O
to O
destroy O
it O
. O

According O
to O
Floralux B-ORG
's O
board O
of O
directors O
, O
the O
appeals O
court O
did O
not O
issue O
sanctions O
because O
that O
would O
not O
make O
sense O
after O
all O
those O
years O
. O

Page O
seven O
. O

The O
Floralux B-MISC
case I-MISC
has O
been O
dragging O
on O
for O
years O
, O
and O
it O
's O
about O
a O
change O
of O
destination O
that O
was O
made O
to O
the O
company O
's O
specifications O
, O
and O
allowed O
the O
plant O
king O
to O
develop O
into O
a O
supermarket O
- O
sized O
garden O
center O
in O
what O
was O
originally O
an O
agricultural O
area O
. O

So O
Floralux B-ORG
should O
n't O
shrink O
or O
pay O
damages O
to O
Dadiflor B-ORG
. O

A O
fax O
taken O
by O
the O
High B-ORG
Commissioner I-ORG
of I-ORG
Surveillance I-ORG
from O
her O
lawyer O
to O
his O
client O
leaves O
no O
doubt O
about O
the O
role O
of O
the O
Shipping O
College O
in O
this O
. O

And O
in O
the O
process O
, O
case O
leader O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
was O
suspected O
to O
have O
become O
a O
member O
of O
the O
CVP B-MISC
's I-MISC
Marine I-MISC
Corps O
to O
realize O
the O
involvement O
of O
the O
BPA B-MISC
Kezelberg I-MISC
itself O
. O

publishing O
date O

Difference O
of O
interests O
remains O
unpunished O

The O
case O
got O
bigger O
because O
there O
was O
a O
lot O
of O
political O
lobbying O
going O
on O
. O

publication O
. O

But O
that O
was O
more O
of O
a O
symbolic O
decision O
, O
because O
the O
heavier O
- O
than O
- O
life O
planting O
plan O
had O
already O
been O
modified O
at O
the O
time O
, O
and O
so O
the O
case O
was O
definitively O
regulated O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
one O
and O
three O
) O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

sect O
. O

Also O
, O
all O
the O
civil O
proceedings O
of O
the O
opposition O
, O
rival O
Dadiflor B-ORG
, O
have O
been O
dismissed O
. O

author O

General O
. O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

The O
court O
of O
appeals O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
found O
that O
in O
the O
case O
of O
the O
controversial O
Floralux B-ORG
gardening O
center O
in O
the O
West B-MISC
German I-MISC
Dadizele B-LOC
, O
there O
had O
been O
a O
conflict O
of O
interest O
, O
but O
it O
did O
not O
find O
it O
necessary O
to O
punish O
the O
storyteller O
Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
for O
that O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
/ O
Dadizele B-LOC

By O
condemning O
Floralux B-ORG
, O
of O
course O
, O
for O
" O
interest O
- O
sharing O
, O
" O
the O
court O
wanted O
to O
put O
a O
stop O
to O
the O
political O
lobbying O
. O

But O
just O
like O
the O
appeals O
court O
in O
Ghent O
also O
ruled O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
that O
the O
fax O
had O
to O
be O
removed O
from O
the O
file O
because O
it O
falls O
under O
the O
professional O
secrecy O
of O
lawyers O
. O

editing O

Sybille B-PER
Decoo I-PER

That O
's O
how O
the O
case O
went O
into O
Leo B-PER
Delcroix I-PER
's O
famous O
Atoma O
manuscripts O
. O

Appeals O
court O
clears O
Floralux B-ORG
gardening O
center O
executive O
from O
jail O

Divergence O
of O
interests O
in O
a O
criminal O
sense O
would O
not O
be O
proven O
. O

page O
. O

Self O
- O
reporting O

Concurrent O
Dadiflor B-ORG
braved O
the O
arrest O
by O
seeing O
in O
the O
sentencing O
a O
further O
argument O
for O
the O
destruction O
of O
the O
regime O
change O
by O
the O
State B-ORG
Council I-ORG
. O

In O
fact O
, O
the O
Gen. O
Frank B-PER
Schins I-PER
, O
the O
prosecutor O
in O
Ghent O
, O
ruled O
that O
there O
was O
over O
lobbying O
in O
this O
case O
. O

Christiane B-PER
Vandenbussche I-PER
decides O
that O
the O
court O
has O
condemned O
the O
political O
acts O
of O
the O
day O
, O
but O
she O
still O
believes O
that O
she O
did O
nothing O
wrong O
. O

Last O
year O
, O
then O
- O
CVP B-MISC
minister I-MISC
Luc B-PER
Martens I-PER
admitted O
that O
he O
had O
asked O
the O
Flemish B-MISC
government O
to O
pay O
attention O
to O
the O
case O
. O

One O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
For O
the O
first O
time O
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
, O
the O
leader O
came O
in O
very O
quickly O
yesterday O
. O

On O
Abetone B-LOC
, O
Casagrande B-PER
had O
performed O
on O
Monday O
last O
week O
, O
and O
also O
in O
the O
Dolomites B-LOC
, O
the O
leader O
had O
not O
given O
up O
. O

He O
hit O
, O
in O
the O
wheel O
, O
followed O
by O
Tonkov B-PER
, O
again O
by O
Garzelli B-PER
and O
Co. O
, O
and O
sprinted O
up O
to O
third O
place O
. O

The O
difference O
between O
the O
leader O
and O
Garzelli B-PER
is O
only O
25 O
seconds O
. O

sect O
. O

On O
the O
contrary O
, O
Stefano B-PER
Garzelli I-PER
and O
Gilberto B-PER
Simoni I-PER
have O
made O
it O
clear O
that O
they O
can O
make O
Casagrande B-PER
, O
today O
and O
tomorrow O
, O
the O
acid O
of O
life O
. O

Later O
that O
was O
the O
case O
with O
Ivan B-PER
Gotti I-PER
. O

Pratone B-LOC
wool O

to O
win O
. O

" O
I O
'm O
not O
afraid O
of O
anyone O
, O
and O
I O
'm O
not O
going O
to O
attack O
, O
" O
he O
announced O
. O

He O
's O
just O
really O
feeling O
Stefano B-PER
Garzelli I-PER
's O
hot O
breath O
in O
his O
neck O
. O

There O
's O
a O
lot O
of O
interest O
in O
looking O
at O
today O
's O
King O
's O
Run O
, O
with O
the O
climbs O
of O
the O
Col O
d'Agnelli B-LOC
( O
2748 O
meters O
) O
and O
the O
Izoard B-LOC
( O
2361 O
meters O
) O
and O
tomorrow O
's O
timeline O
of O
the O
Montgenèvre B-LOC
and O
Sestrière B-LOC
. O

page O
. O

Thanks O
to O
the O
support O
of O
Buenahora B-PER
, O
Casagrande B-PER
actually O
solved O
the O
problem O
a O
little O
bit O
later O
. O

For O
Di B-PER
Luca I-PER
, O
Wednesday O
became O
too O
much O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Casagrande B-PER
: O
The O
warm O
breath O
of O
Garzelli B-PER

The O
tastemaker O
, O
in O
the O
first O
two O
weeks O
, O
went O
down O
with O
tendinitis O
. O

Here O
's O
where O
I O
want O
to O
make O
the O
difference O
. O

and O
say O
that O
Casagrande B-PER
spoke O
optimistic O
language O
on O
the O
eve O
of O
the O
trip O
to O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
. O

To O
the O
extent O
that O
both O
of O
them O
were O
still O
pursuing O
profit O
- O
making O
ambitions O
, O
they O
should O
now O
be O
allowed O
to O
hold O
onto O
those O
ambitions O
by O
definition O
. O

" O

And O
that O
might O
be O
possible O
. O

Self O
- O
reporting O

I O
'll O
be O
back O
next O
year O
. O

We O
're O
going O
to O
get O
more O
clarity O
today O
and O
tomorrow O
in O
the O
two O
most O
painful O
Alpine B-MISC
rides I-MISC
. O

Not O
Garzelli B-PER
and O
Piepoli B-PER
. O

And O
he O
's O
also O
enjoying O
the O
fact O
that O
he O
's O
the O
best O
time O
traveler O
among O
his O
favorites O
, O
which O
makes O
him O
really O
think O
about O
winning O
the O
race O
. O

Win O
the O
race B-MISC
. O

author O

" O
But O
I O
've O
learned O
a O
lot O
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
. O

Rozetruidrager O
: O
Giro B-MISC
's O
not O
won O
yet O

Gonzales B-PER
the I-PER
Galdean I-PER
, O
who O
is O
known O
as O
a O
better O
time O
traveler O
, O
made O
it O
between O
Genoa B-LOC
and O
Brescia B-LOC
into O
a O
true O
time O
traveler O
. O

( O
TL B-PER
) O

Sport B-MISC

Francesco B-PER
Casagrande I-PER
is O
going O
to O
be O
a O
lot O
less O
relieved O
after O
yesterday O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

publication O
. O

" O

Prior O
to O
the O
solid O
climbing O
of O
the O
Italian B-MISC
, O
everyone O
was O
increasingly O
convinced O
that O
Casagrande B-PER
, O
who O
had O
set O
the O
Italian B-MISC
Round O
as O
his O
main O
goal O
and O
made O
a O
lot O
of O
sacrifices O
for O
it O
, O
would O
achieve O
his O
goal O
. O

Under O
the O
bruising O
accelerations O
of O
Gilberto B-PER
Simoni I-PER
on O
the O
steepest O
parts O
of O
the O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
, O
Casagrande B-PER
had O
to O
pass O
. O

General O
. O

" O
This O
ride O
is O
more O
important O
to O
me O
than O
the O
next O
two O
. O

" O
I O
'm O
winning O
today O
, O
" O
he O
wrote O
on O
the O
checklist O
in O
the O
morning O
. O

Because O
no O
matter O
how O
hard O
the O
sprinters O
pushed O
in O
the O
group O
behind O
the O
Spaniard B-MISC
, O
he O
still O
had O
nearly O
half O
a O
minute O
to O
finish O
. O

But O
do O
we O
have O
to O
assume O
that O
it O
was O
just O
a O
matter O
of O
taking O
off O
the O
lightbulbs O
and O
continuing O
to O
have O
them O
on O
the O
wall O
? O

Halfway O
through O
, O
after O
110 O
miles O
, O
he O
walked O
out O
of O
the O
peloton O
on O
his O
own O
, O
walked O
for O
seven O
minutes O
, O
and O
stood O
back O
in O
a O
beautiful O
way O
as O
the O
peloton O
returned O
. O

Especially O
for O
Garzelli B-PER
, O
the O
rush O
hour O
has O
to O
be O
a O
blast O
. O

editing O

And O
the O
Spanishman B-MISC
from O
the O
Vitalicio B-MISC
Regiment I-MISC
spoke O
. O

On O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
, O
Dario B-PER
Frigo I-PER
was O
in O
trouble O
early O
on O
. O

It O
promises O
to O
be O
exciting O
end O
days O
in O
the O
Italian B-MISC
Round I-MISC
. O

Marco B-PER
Pantani I-PER
's O
crew O
, O
and O
the O
head O
of O
Mercatone B-ORG
Uno I-ORG
in O
this O
Giro B-MISC
, O
yesterday O
left O
all O
of O
his O
competitors O
behind O
on O
the O
Pratonevoso B-LOC
and O
ran O
away O
thanks O
to O
the O
bonification O
closer O
to O
Casagrande B-PER
. O

publishing O
date O

" O
The O
pain O
was O
n't O
too O
much O
anymore O
, O
" O
said O
the O
young O
Di B-PER
Luca I-PER
. O

Fifteen O
. O

But O
the O
Toscan B-MISC
once O
said O
that O
a O
big O
round O
would O
take O
too O
long O
for O
him O
. O

On O
Wednesday O
, O
Alvaro B-PER
Gonzales I-PER
made O
the O
Galdeano B-PER
his O
day O
. O

So O
it O
did O
n't O
work O
out O
that O
way O
. O

Tony B-PER
Landuyt I-PER

Of O
those O
favorites O
, O
two O
were O
picked O
overboard O
yesterday O
. O

And O
they O
quickly O
got O
onto O
Simoni B-PER
's O
path O
. O

-DOCSTART O
-- O
release O
date O
. O

But O
the O
more O
Chernow B-PER
wrote O
, O
the O
more O
mind O
- O
wandering O
they O
became O
. O

Both O
of O
them O
did O
n't O
initially O
see O
Chernow B-MISC
's I-MISC
plan O
because O
they O
felt O
too O
young O
and O
healthy O
to O
write O
a O
biography O
. O

The O
first O
edition O
of O
the O
500 O
- O
page O
book O
Christo B-PER
and O
Jeanne B-PER
- I-PER
Claude I-PER
-- O
a O
biography O
has O
just O
been O
published O
in O
German B-MISC
. O

Christo B-PER
's O
biography O
revealed O

General O
. O

Culture B-MISC
. O

The O
Bulgarian B-MISC
- I-MISC
American I-MISC
artist O
couple O
Christo B-PER
( O
Javacheff B-PER
) O
and O
Jeanne B-PER
- I-PER
Claude I-PER
, O
earlier O
this O
week O
in O
Cologne B-LOC
, O
presented O
at O
the O
Keipenheuer B-ORG
Witsch I-ORG
published O
biography O
appeared O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

page O
. O

The O
author O
Burt B-PER
Chernow I-PER
, O
a O
friend O
of O
the O
Christ B-PER
's I-PER
Crusaders O
, O
wrote O
the O
biography O
of O
the O
couple O
: O
Bulgarian B-LOC
- O
born O
Christo B-PER
Javacheff I-PER
and O
his O
great O
love O
Jeanne O
- O
Claude B-PER
de I-PER
Guillebon I-PER
. O

publication O
. O

They O
got O
a O
lot O
of O
attention O
in O
1995 O
, O
when O
they O
took O
over O
the O
German B-MISC
Reichstag B-LOC
in O
Berlin B-LOC
. O

editing O

sect O
. O

author O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

" O
Germany B-LOC
has O
a O
special O
place O
in O
our O
hearts O
, O
" O
both O
artists O
said O
during O
the O
presentation O
. O

The O
artistic O
couple O
has O
been O
involved O
in O
the O
art O
of O
wrapping O
up O
since O
the O
1960s O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
General O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

" O
The O
government O
has O
been O
raising O
awareness O
for O
over O
20 O
years O
. O

Also O
, O
Brussels B-MISC
Minister O
of O
the O
Environment B-ORG
Didier B-PER
Gosuin I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
/ I-ORG
FDF I-ORG
) O
is O
outraged O
at O
the O
" O
greater O
" O
content O
of O
the O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
. O

In O
excess O
of O
the O
European B-MISC
health O
standards O
, O
120 O
micrograms O
of O
ozone O
per O
cubic O
meter O
for O
at O
least O
eight O
hours O
, O
they O
require O
the O
Belgian B-MISC
state O
, O
the O
Brussels B-LOC
Gewest I-LOC
and O
the O
nineteen O
Brussels B-MISC
municipalities O
to O
spend O
50 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
. O

Air O
pollution O
deserves O
a O
lot O
more O
than O
that O
, O
" O
says O
Gosuin B-PER
, O
who O
himself O
proposes O
structural O
measures O
. O

The O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
suffers O
from O
severe O
inadequacy O
from O
the O
environmental O
movement O
. O

Environmental O
movement O
focuses O
on O
ozone O
processes O

page O
. O

Two O
Brussels B-MISC
- I-MISC
based I-MISC
associations O
, O
Bral B-ORG
and O
Inter B-ORG
- I-ORG
Environnement I-ORG
, O
are O
the O
government O
's O
mouthpiece O
, O
and O
they O
're O
going O
to O
court O
shortly O
. O

Pages O
two O
and O
seven O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

publication O
. O

The O
two O
unions O
are O
asking O
for O
concrete O
action O
by O
the O
summer O
to O
reduce O
road O
traffic O
. O

The O
cabinet O
of O
the O
Minister O
of O
Health B-ORG
, O
Magda B-PER
Aelvoet I-PER
, O
yesterday O
did O
n't O
want O
to O
respond O
to O
the O
battle O
yet O
. O

editing O

publishing O
date O

General B-MISC
( O
one O
and O
three O
) O

author O

One O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

sect O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Di B-PER
Biase I-PER
-- O
11 O
. O

Zabel B-PER
( O
Door B-LOC
) O
3:15:58 O
-- O
2 O
. O

Buenahora B-PER
[ O
unclear B-LOC
] O
08 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Desert B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
/ O
Festina B-ORG
) O
the O
102.6 O
kilometers O
in O
2:28:10 O
-- O
2 O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Plaza B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
31:08:55 O
-- O
2 O
. O

Leoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
four O
. O

Simoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
53 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Simoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
three O
. O

Kadlec B-PER
-- O
... O

Frigo B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
4:34 O
-- O
10 O
. O

43 O
. O

Finot B-PER
( O
Fra B-LOC
) O
so O
- O
called O
-- O
seven O
. O

Zabel B-PER
( O
Dow B-LOC
) O
-- O
five O
. O

Blanco B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
4:39 O
-- O
11 O
. O

Ullrich B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:33 O
-- O
10 O
. O

Forconi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
2:18 O
-- O
18 O
. O

Merckx B-PER
all O
over O
the O
place O
. O

Sport B-MISC

Tonkov B-PER
( O
Russian B-LOC
) O
2:41 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Bridge B-PER
-- O
17 O
. O

Rebellin B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
10:21 O
. O

Broke B-PER
everyone O
's O
seatbelt O
. O

Hruska B-PER
-- O
... O

Guidi B-PER
-- O
10 O
. O

Bruyland B-PER
's O
0:23 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Pantani B-PER
-- O
-- O

Fornaciari B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
13 O
years O
. O

Garzelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
at O
25 O
-- O
three O
. O

Casero B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
1:42 O
-- O
5 O
. O

McRae B-PER
( O
USA B-LOC
) O
19:00 O
-- O
19 O
. O

Koerts B-PER
-- O
Ned B-LOC
-- O
three O
. O

McRae B-PER
: O
1:47 O
-- O
14 O
. O

sect O
. O

White B-PER
-- O
10 O
. O

Garzelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
/ O
Mercatone B-ORG
Uno I-ORG
) O
the O
173 O
kilometers O
in O
4:42:32 O
-- O
two O
. O

Lanfranchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
12:51 O
-- O
15 O
. O

Seventh O
rush O
: O
one O
. O

Plaza B-PER
, O
the O
35.7 O
kilometers O
in O
42:53 O
-- O
2 O
. O

56 O
. O

General O
. O

Beikirch B-PER
-- O
... O

Boscardin B-PER
( O
Zwi B-LOC
) O
44 O
-- O
four O
. O

Rous B-PER
( O
Fra B-LOC
) O
at O
0:09 O
-- O
3 O
. O

From B-PER
the I-PER
Wouver I-PER
0:13 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Petersen B-PER
, O
everybody O
likes O
that O
. O

17th O
round O
of B-MISC
Italy I-MISC
: O
1 O
. O

Grand B-ORG
Prize I-ORG
of I-ORG
Wallonia I-ORG
( O
category O
1.2 O
): O

Hruska B-PER
( O
Tsj B-LOC
) O
13:14 O
-- O
16 O
. O

Rubiera B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
4:45 O
-- O
12 O
. O

Pena B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
16:59 O
-- O
18 O
. O

One O
. O

Sixteen O
. O

Savoldelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
19:08 O
-- O
20 O
. O

Leoni B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
five O
. O

" O
Holy B-PER
" O
2:12 O
-- O
10 O
. O

author O

End O
line O
: O
one O
. O

Gotti B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:54 O
-- O
17 O
. O

publication O
. O

Around B-MISC
Italy I-MISC
: O

Klöden B-PER
at O
0:42 O
-- O
3 O
. O

Piepoli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
on O
02 O
-- O
5 O
. O

31 O
. O

Gerosa B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
14 O
years O
. O

Fifteen O
. O

Casero B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
1:40 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Rittsel B-PER
( O
Sweden B-LOC
) O
2:34 O
. O

Gonzalez B-PER
the I-PER
Galdeo I-PER
... O

Sevilla B-LOC
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
15:24 O
-- O
17 O
. O

Pharaoh B-PER
1 O
: O
58 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Usov B-PER
-- O
7 O
. O

Merckx B-PER
7:32 O
-- O
... O

Baguet B-PER
-- O
18 O
. O

Savoldelli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
8:23 O
-- O
48 O
. O

Rubiera B-PER
49 O
-- O
11 O
. O

Earlier B-PER
, O
2:06 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Heppner B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:06 O
-- O
... O

Piepoli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
6:13 O
-- O
14 O
. O

Liese B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:11 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Status O
: O
1 O
. O

Thirteen O
. O

17th O
lap O
: O
1 O
. O

Increase B-PER
2:02 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Blaudzun B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
1:44 O
-- O
7 O
. O

Lafis B-PER
-- O
15 O
years O
old O
. O

Bölts B-PER
( O
Dow B-LOC
) O
1:41 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Frigo B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
2:38 O
-- O
20 O
. O

Christians B-PER
, O
it O
's O
like O
-- O

34 O
. O

Petersen B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
-- O
six O
. O

Blaudzun B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
1:46 O
-- O
6 O
. O

Martinello B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
six O
. O

Around B-MISC
Germany I-MISC
: O

Ullrich B-PER
18:04 O
. O

Ullrich B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
and O
everybody O
else O
. O

Beikirch B-PER
-- O
three O
. O

18th O
lap O
: O
1 O
. O

Belli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
seven O
. O

Gonzalez B-PER
the I-PER
Galdeano I-PER
[ O
Spa B-LOC
/ O
Vitalicio B-ORG
] O
the O
236 O
kilometers O
in O
5:23:02 O
[ O
time O
: O
43,834 O
km O
/ O
h O
] O
-- O
2 O
. O

Boogerd B-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
is O
... O

Petacchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
five O
. O

Baranowski B-PER
-- O
13 O
years O
old O
. O

Castelblanco B-PER
( O
col B-LOC
) O
2:24 O
-- O
19 O
. O

Belli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:11 O
-- O
5 O
. O

Usov B-PER
-- O
6 O
. O

Casagrande B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
four O
. O

Noè B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
3:39 O
-- O
7 O
. O

Konyshev B-PER
( O
Russian B-LOC
) O
-- O
four O
. O

Braikia B-PER
( O
Den B-LOC
) O
-- O
nine O
. O

Bölts B-PER
( O
Dow B-LOC
) O
1:26 O
-- O
4 O
. O

Buenahora B-PER
( O
Col B-LOC
) O
3:43 O
-- O
8 O
. O

Rows B-LOC
at O
40 O
-- O
three O
. O

Desert B-PER
( O
Dow B-LOC
) O
-- O
four O
. O

Heppner B-PER
( O
Dui B-LOC
) O
2:21 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Casagrande B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
/ O
Vini B-ORG
Caldirola I-ORG
) O
87:11:09 O
-- O
2 O
. O

publishing O
date O

Mattan B-PER
-- O
19 O
. O

editing O

The B-PER
Jongh I-PER
( O
Ned B-LOC
) O
-- O
eight O
. O

Elli B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
at O
4:42:05 O
-- O
2 O
miles O
per O
hour O
. O

Noè B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
12 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Run O
six O
: O
one O
. O

Mancebo B-PER
( O
Spa B-LOC
) O
20:36 O

Lanfranchi B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
1:12 O
-- O
12 O
. O

page O
. O

Mancebo B-PER
-- O
16 O
years O
old O
. O

Tonkov B-PER
-- O
six O
. O

The B-PER
Clercq I-PER
-- O
20 O
. O

Conte B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
12 O
years O
. O

Gotti B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
4:25 O
-- O
9 O
. O

Pieri B-PER
( O
Ita B-LOC
) O
-- O
seven O
. O

Honchar B-PER
( O
Look B-LOC
) O
1:51 O
-- O
15 O
. O

Seventy O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

Swords B-PER
on O
24 O
-- O
three O
. O

Honchar B-PER
( O
Look B-LOC
) O
5:45 O
-- O
13 O
. O

Eighth O
move O
: O
one O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
Last O
year O
, O
by O
the O
way O
, O
I O
had O
the O
same O
problem O
when O
I O
rejoined O
the O
competition O
in O
the O
World B-MISC
Wrestling I-MISC
Championships O
. O

publishing O
date O

Question O
marks O
: O
Water B-PER
holes O
getting O
bigger O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

General O
. O

publication O
. O

Are O
they O
wrong O
? O

" O

I O
just O
hope O
that O
the O
same O
thing O
will O
happen O
over O
the O
next O
few O
days O
, O
although O
I O
have O
to O
admit O
that O
I O
'm O
not O
at O
all O
comfortable O
with O
it O
. O

The O
Tour B-MISC
is O
coming O
soon O
. O

Wheelchair O
racing O

" O

There O
are O
even O
people O
who O
are O
now O
betting O
that O
on O
July O
1 O
in O
Futuroscope B-LOC
, O
he O
's O
not O
going O
to O
be O
on O
the O
Tour B-MISC
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

" O
I O
do O
n't O
understand O
why O
there O
's O
so O
much O
mess O
going O
on O
around O
there O
, O
" O
says O
a O
curious O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
. O

Sport B-MISC

Ief B-PER
Vertommen I-PER

" O
I O
'm O
not O
doing O
well O
, O
" O
one O
, O
by O
the O
way O
, O
calm O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
said O
. O

Self O
- O
reporting O

So O
what O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
wanted O
to O
do O
as O
a O
direct O
preparation O
for O
the O
Tour B-MISC
was O
to O
go O
the O
Dauphiné B-MISC
( O
4 O
- O
11 O
June O
) O
and O
the O
Route B-MISC
du I-MISC
Sud I-MISC
( O
17 O
- O
20 O
June O
) O
instead O
of O
the O
round O
of B-MISC
Luxembourg I-MISC
( O
8 O
- O
11 O
June O
) O
and O
the O
round O
of B-MISC
Switzerland I-MISC
( O
13 O
- O
22 O
June O
) O
. O

The O
camper B-MISC
, O
however O
, O
was O
very O
happy O
with O
this O
test O
, O
because O
he O
was O
looking O
at O
the O
Round B-MISC
of I-MISC
France I-MISC
, O
which O
is O
so O
much O
more O
important O
to O
him O
. O

" O
As O
far O
as O
I O
know O
, O
there O
are O
regular O
runners O
who O
tune O
into O
their O
program O
. O

Van B-PER
the I-PER
Wouver I-PER
had O
already O
announced O
that O
Elli B-PER
would O
become O
the O
right O
man O
. O

sect O
. O

I O
have O
n't O
done O
panic O
attacks O
yet O
, O
but O
there O
wo O
n't O
be O
any O
new O
obstacles O
on O
my O
way O
to O
preparing O
. O

" O
In O
any O
case O
, O
a O
lot O
less O
than O
expected O
. O

And O
after O
117 O
kilometers O
, O
he O
kept O
his O
eyes O
on O
it O
. O

One O
thing O
that O
can O
be O
very O
clear O
about O
all O
of O
this O
is O
that O
the O
end O
of O
the O
story B-MISC
of I-MISC
Vandenbroucke I-MISC
is O
not O
for O
very O
long O
in O
sight O
. O

Fifteen O
. O

It O
took O
a O
few O
more O
World B-MISC
Cup I-MISC
matches O
before O
the O
record O
was O
announced O
. O

Frank B-PER
Vandenbroucke I-PER
: O
I O
'm O
not O
doing O
well O
at O
GP B-MISC
Wallonie I-MISC

Simply O
because O
there O
's O
more O
recovery O
time O
between O
those O
two O
combinations O
. O

The O
Belgians B-MISC
who O
are O
already O
there O
are O
Dave B-PER
Bruylants I-PER
, O
who O
was O
second O
yesterday O
, O
and O
Kurt B-PER
Van I-PER
the I-PER
Wauwer I-PER
, O
who O
is O
third O
. O

Ief B-PER
Vertommen I-PER

Before O
the O
start O
of O
the O
race O
, O
he O
had O
called O
it O
a O
matter O
of O
days O
before O
he O
reached O
the O
top O
, O
but O
as O
he O
cycled O
just O
two O
cliffs O
away O
, O
he O
ended O
up O
in O
the O
back O
of O
the O
field O
. O

So O
nobody O
was O
really O
surprised O
by O
the O
next O
task O
. O

page O
. O

Meanwhile O
, O
Vandenbroucke B-PER
has O
also O
understood O
that O
he O
's O
not O
in O
a O
position O
right O
now O
to O
make O
demands O
about O
his O
preparations O
for O
the O
Tour B-MISC
. O

editing O

" O

" O
The O
condition O
is O
good O
, O
but O
not O
great O
. O

And O
then O
I O
was O
regularly O
driven O
to O
a O
quarter O
mile O
. O

author O

Yesterday O
, O
he O
gave O
up O
in O
the O
only O
Belgian B-MISC
competition O
that O
he O
would O
run O
on O
Belgian B-MISC
soil O
. O

While O
Alberto B-PER
Elli I-PER
of O
Walter B-PER
Godefroot I-PER
's O
Telekom O
team O
wrote O
the O
Walloon B-MISC
GP I-MISC
( O
1.2 O
) O
on O
his O
name O
, O
a O
fresh O
- O
grown O
and O
well O
- O
dressed O
Frank B-PER
Vandenbroucke I-PER
sat O
in O
the O
company O
of O
his O
Italian B-MISC
friend O
Sara B-PER
longing O
to O
know O
what O
to O
do O
next O
with O
him O
. O

But O
I O
'm O
going O
to O
have O
to O
stick O
with O
the O
arrangement O
now O
, O
as O
originally O
proposed O
by O
the O
crew O
. O

Names B-LOC
. O

" O
I O
have O
n't O
done O
panic O
yet O
, O
but O
there O
wo O
n't O
be O
any O
new O
obstacles O
in O
my O
preparation B-MISC
for I-MISC
the I-MISC
Tour I-MISC
. O
" O

It O
's O
not O
that O
I O
'm O
sick O
, O
but O
I O
just O
do O
n't O
have O
acceleration O
in O
my O
legs O
. O

Bride O
- O
to O
- O
bride B-PER
, O
still O
14 O
days O
on O
the O
run O
, O
had O
to O
pay O
for O
his O
attempt O
to O
get O
Elli B-PER
back O
with O
convulsions O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
New O
directors O
Patrice B-PER
Toye I-PER
( O
from O
the O
award O
- O
winning O
film O
Rosie B-MISC
) O
and O
Marion B-PER
Oprel I-PER
, O
girlfriend O
of O
Marianne B-PER
' O
The B-MISC
Mol I-MISC
) O
Dupont B-PER
. O

So O
here O
's O
the O
short O
story O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Agalev B-ORG
says O
he O
wants O
to O
make O
Antwerp B-LOC
again O
an O
open O
, O
brimming O
metropolis O
. O

editing O

There O
are O
now O
a O
couple O
of O
20 O
- O
somethings O
who O
have O
signed O
up O
, O
and O
they O
're O
getting O
a O
place O
on O
the O
lists O
that O
are O
coming O
out O
later O
. O

The O
senior O
citizens O
' O
party O
, O
WOW B-ORG
, O
is O
running O
in O
the O
municipal O
, O
district O
and O
provincial O
council O
elections O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
on O
October O
8th O
. O

WOW B-ORG
joins O
Antwerp B-LOC

Journalism B-MISC

There O
was O
a O
little O
bit O
of O
controversy O
about O
this O
when O
a O
city O
council O
member O
moved O
to O
the O
LDP B-ORG
and O
his O
provincial O
council O
colleague O
moved O
to O
the O
Flemish B-ORG
Bloc I-ORG
. O

Singer O
, O
comedian O
and O
presenter O
Marcel B-PER
Vanthilt I-PER
will O
be O
on O
Agalev B-ORG
's O
list O
for O
the O
upcoming O
municipal O
elections O
in O
Antwerp O
. O

page O
. O

" O

He O
gets O
to O
the O
31st O
place O
and O
is O
part O
of O
what O
's O
called O
the O
cultural O
cordon O
on O
the O
green O
list O
. O

Number O
one O
on O
the O
list O
for O
the O
province O
is O
Frans B-PER
Verbergt I-PER
, O
who O
's O
been O
on O
the O
provincial O
council O
for O
10 O
years O
for O
the O
VLD B-ORG
. O

The O
list O
for O
the O
municipality O
is O
led O
by O
André B-PER
Crahay I-PER
, O
a O
prominent O
banker O
who O
's O
relatively O
new O
to O
politics O
. O

" O
We O
are O
the O
alternative O
, O
" O
is O
the O
slogan O
that O
drove O
WOW B-ORG
to O
the O
elections O
in O
Antwerp B-LOC
. O

Vanthilt B-PER
is O
by O
no O
means O
the O
only O
BV B-MISC
on O
the O
Antwerp B-MISC
Agalev B-MISC
list I-MISC
. O

publishing O
date O

Actress O
Jeanine B-PER
Bisschops I-PER
and O
author O
Tom B-PER
Lanoye I-PER
had O
already O
admitted O
. O

" O
That O
does O
n't O
happen O
with O
bullies O
and O
blackmailers O
, O
" O
the O
party O
argues O
, O
" O
we O
prefer O
green O
, O
the O
color O
of O
hope O
. O
" O

author O

sect O
. O

General O
. O

On O
the O
municipal O
level O
, O
the O
party O
wants O
to O
have O
universal O
suffrage O
, O
and O
in O
the O
district O
of O
Antwerp B-LOC
, O
the O
Greens B-MISC
hope O
to O
become O
the O
largest O
party O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

In O
addition O
, O
Agalev B-MISC
- I-MISC
Antwerp I-MISC
puts O
out O
a O
list O
of O
known B-MISC
disasters I-MISC
that O
sign O
the O
party O
program O
, O
but O
are O
not O
on O
the O
list O
. O

According O
to O
Cahaye B-PER
, O
his O
party O
profile O
is O
a O
bias O
between O
the O
ages O
, O
which O
means O
that O
young O
people O
get O
a O
chance O
as O
well O
. O

Artists O
for O
Agalev B-ORG

publication O
. O

Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

The O
actresses O
Sarah B-PER
de I-PER
Bosschere I-PER
, O
Veerle B-PER
Dobbelaere I-PER
and O
Patricia B-PER
Goemaere I-PER
, O
writer O
Kristien B-PER
Hemmerechts I-PER
, O
musician O
and O
concert O
organizer O
Paul B-PER
Ambach I-PER
, O
actor O
Pol B-PER
Goossen I-PER
, O
authors O
Paul B-PER
Mennes I-PER
, O
Bart B-PER
Moeyaert I-PER
and O
Jeroen B-PER
Olyslaeghers I-PER
, O
and O
actor O
Carl B-PER
Ridders I-PER
drew O
for O
the O
show O
. O

DOCSTART O
: O
" O
Let O
's O
leave O
that O
up O
to O
the O
mediators O
, O
" O
it O
was O
called O
yesterday O
. O

First O
, O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
have O
to O
leave O
, O
but O
then O
they O
do O
n't O
have O
the O
ears O
in O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
. O

" O

Abroad B-MISC
. O

Well O
, O
what O
observers O
say O
is O
that O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
have O
withdrawn O
from O
the O
two O
western O
cities O
of O
Barentu B-LOC
and O
Tessenay B-LOC
, O
which O
had O
been O
occupied O
openly O
during O
the O
last O
decade O
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
wants O
to O
stick O
to O
the O
Organization B-ORG
of I-ORG
African I-ORG
Unity I-ORG
four O
- O
point O
plan O
. O

This O
includes O
, O
among O
other O
things O
, O
sending O
international O
observers O
to O
the O
disputed O
border O
zone O
. O

Asmara B-LOC
only O
wants O
to O
hear O
from O
a O
file O
when O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
are O
withdrawn O
. O

" O
We O
'd O
better O
go O
back O
to O
our O
positions O
of O
May O
6 O
, O
1998 O
( O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
war O
, O
MR B-PER
) O
, O
" O
said O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
minister O
. O

Ethiopia B-LOC
did O
that O
after O
it O
had O
regained O
all O
of O
the O
territory O
that O
had O
been O
lost O
after O
the O
invasion O
of O
Eritrea B-MISC
in O
' O
98 O
. O

sect O
. O

And O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
now O
wants O
guarantees O
that O
its O
troops O
, O
who O
have O
flown O
deep O
into O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
will O
be O
withdrawn O
. O

Proposed O
visions O
for O
when O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
should O
withdraw O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

publishing O
date O

Eritrea B-LOC
, O
according O
to O
a O
BBC B-MISC
correspondent I-MISC
in O
Asmara B-LOC
, O
is O
deeply O
humiliated O
by O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
statement O
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
and O
Ethiopia O
disagree O
on O
file O

Moreover O
, O
the O
current O
situation O
is O
generally O
interpreted O
as O
one O
in O
which O
Ethiopia B-LOC
, O
due O
to O
its O
recent O
military O
successes O
, O
can O
dictate O
the O
laws O
, O
and O
that O
is O
unacceptable O
to O
Asmara B-LOC
. O

Eritrea B-LOC
called O
the O
whole O
thing O
strange O
. O

But O
according O
to O
the O
BCC B-ORG
, O
the O
Eritrean B-MISC
city O
of O
Zenefe B-LOC
remains O
occupied O
by O
Ethiopian B-MISC
soldiers O
. O

General O
. O

" O
But O
then O
we O
want O
to O
make O
sure O
that O
Eritrea B-LOC
does O
n't O
repeat O
the O
madness O
of O
just O
entering O
a O
neighboring O
country O
. O

From O
the O
press O
agencies O
. O

Ethiopia O
believes O
the O
coup O
d'état O
is O
over O
, O
but O
Eritrea B-LOC
does O
n't O
share O
that O
view O
. O

And O
that O
's O
where O
the O
shoe O
is O
wrapped O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

page O
. O

editing O

publication O
. O

What O
kind O
of O
guarantees O
does O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
want O
, O
it O
was O
not O
immediately O
clear O
. O

It O
's O
a O
little O
bit O
like O
clapping O
with O
one O
hand O
: O
Ethiopia O
and O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
which O
have O
been O
waging O
war O
for O
two O
years O
, O
are O
sitting O
at O
the O
negotiating O
table O
in O
Algiers B-LOC
. O

Algeria B-LOC

Ouyahia B-PER
called O
the O
statement O
by O
Ethiopian B-MISC
Foreign B-ORG
Minister O
Seyoum B-PER
Mesfin I-PER
that O
the O
war O
was O
over O
" O
an O
encouraging O
thing O
. O
" O

In O
addition O
, O
cartography O
would O
have O
to O
cross O
the O
border O
, O
there O
would O
have O
to O
be O
financial O
compensation O
for O
the O
losses O
on O
both O
sides O
, O
and O
finally O
, O
a O
profound O
investigation O
of O
the O
causes O
of O
the O
conflict O
would O
be O
desirable O
. O

Algeria B-MISC
's I-MISC
Justice O
Minister O
Ahmed B-PER
Ouyahia I-PER
has O
been O
trying O
since O
Tuesday O
to O
mediate O
the O
two O
- O
year O
- O
old O
conflict O
between O
Ethiopia O
and O
Eritrea B-LOC
, O
which O
restarted O
in O
the O
last O
three O
weeks O
when O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
army O
crossed O
the O
border O
. O

Maarten B-PER
Rabaey I-PER

" O
How O
can O
they O
say O
that O
the O
war O
is O
over O
? O

author O

We O
will O
not O
close O
the O
database O
as O
long O
as O
the O
Ethiopian B-MISC
troops O
are O
no O
more O
than O
100 O
kilometers O
from O
Asmara B-LOC
, O
" O
said O
Eritrean O
presidential O
adviser O
Yemane B-PER
Gebremeskel I-PER
. O

And O
that O
's O
what O
Addis B-LOC
Ababa I-LOC
only O
wants O
when O
there O
are O
international O
guarantees O
. O

-DOCSTART O
- O
Belgium B-ORG
/ O
Own O
Reporting O

General O
. O

Tax O
reform O
also O
has O
to O
end O
discrimination O
between O
married O
and O
non O
- O
married O
people O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

ACW B-MISC
President I-MISC
Theo B-PER
Rombouts I-PER
wants O
the O
next O
tax O
reform O
to O
benefit O
primarily O
low O
- O
income O
people O
. O

Wages O
have O
fallen O
below O
half O
of O
national O
income O
, O
and O
that O
's O
unacceptable O
. O

page O
. O

publishing O
date O

Journalism B-MISC

Part O
of O
it O
has O
to O
go O
to O
social O
security O
, O
and O
part O
of O
it O
has O
to O
be O
saved O
. O

In O
his O
speech O
in O
Mechelen B-LOC
, O
Cortebeeck B-PER
argued O
that O
in O
addition O
to O
social O
expenditures O
, O
wages O
have O
also O
gone O
up O
. O

In O
the O
next O
intersectoral O
negotiations O
, O
the O
Christian O
trade O
union O
will O
also O
push O
for O
a O
gradual O
wage O
increase O
as O
the O
best O
and O
most O
tried O
and O
tested O
way O
to O
share O
the O
fruits O
of O
growth O
. O

Financial O
participation O
ca O
n't O
close O
the O
pay O
gap O
, O
says O
Cortebeeck B-PER
. O

The O
Christian O
trade O
union O
is O
in O
favor O
of O
a O
gradual O
increase O
in O
wages O
and O
social O
benefits O
, O
ACV B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Luc B-PER
Cortebeeck I-PER
said O
in O
his O
Rerum B-MISC
Novarum I-MISC
speech I-MISC
. O

Mechelen B-LOC
/ O
Brussels B-LOC

And O
that O
has O
to O
be O
coupled O
with O
an O
increase O
in O
net O
incomes O
for O
low O
- O
income O
earners O
and O
families O
with O
children O
for O
children O
. O

author O

" O
We O
have O
n't O
spent O
years O
putting O
pensions O
and O
health O
care O
money O
in O
the O
hands O
of O
the O
private O
sector O
now O
, O
" O
says O
the O
ACV B-MISC
president I-MISC
. O

He O
suggested O
that O
the O
government O
should O
not O
simply O
enrich O
private O
companies O
in O
the O
insurance O
sector O
by O
relying O
on O
them O
to O
reap O
the O
benefits O
of O
deleveraging O
. O

sect O
. O

According O
to O
Cortebeeck B-PER
, O
not O
all O
new O
government O
revenues O
should O
be O
reserved O
for O
aging O
. O

In O
the O
case O
of O
profit O
- O
sharing O
, O
some O
of O
the O
workers O
' O
income O
is O
dependent O
on O
too O
many O
arbitrary O
decisions O
. O

That O
's O
why O
the O
ACW B-ORG
is O
advocating O
an O
increase O
in O
the O
deductible O
labor O
costs O
for O
wage O
earners O
and O
for O
widows O
and O
an O
increase O
in O
the O
first O
unencumbered O
balance O
of O
labor O
income O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

ACW B-MISC
chairman I-MISC
Theo B-PER
Rombouts I-PER
, O
in O
his O
speech O
at O
Wemmel B-LOC
, O
argued O
that O
tax O
cuts O
should O
be O
targeted O
primarily O
at O
labor O
incomes O
and O
, O
in O
particular O
, O
longer O
- O
term O
incomes O
. O

The O
resources O
available O
can O
be O
better O
used O
to O
strengthen O
the O
foundations O
of O
society O
, O
such O
as O
education O
and O
health O
care O
, O
public O
transportation O
and O
roads O
, O
food O
security O
, O
etc O
. O
Improving O
low O
incomes O
can O
only O
come O
through O
increasing O
the O
minimum O
wage O
, O
guaranteed O
income O
and O
social O
benefits O
. O

Winning O
presupposes O
power O
- O
sharing O
, O
but O
that O
's O
not O
being O
respected O
, O
said O
Cortebeeck B-PER
, O
because O
employers O
do O
n't O
want O
to O
know O
about O
a O
previously O
negotiated O
CAO B-MISC
third O
party O
. O

ACV B-ORG
: O
Raising O
wages O
over O
profit O
sharing O

The O
trade O
union O
leader O
said O
that O
the O
active O
welfare O
state O
also O
has O
its O
downsides O
. O

And O
finally O
, O
Rombout B-PER
asked O
for O
fiscal O
incentives O
to O
lead O
a O
more O
environmentally O
friendly O
life O
. O

The O
self O
- O
employed O
have O
already O
benefited O
from O
1.5 O
billion O
francs O
, O
but O
the O
social O
workers O
, O
such O
as O
the O
disabled O
, O
the O
disabled O
and O
the O
unemployed O
, O
who O
are O
in O
financial O
distress O
, O
are O
losing O
out O
and O
becoming O
increasingly O
impoverished O
. O

Rerum B-MISC
Novarum I-MISC
talks I-MISC
reveal O
the O
shadow O
of O
an O
active O
welfare O
state O

editing O

publication O
. O

A O
payroll O
movement O
, O
according O
to O
the O
union O
leader O
, O
is O
one O
that O
favors O
the O
participation O
of O
employees O
in O
the O
profits O
of O
their O
company O
over O
the O
non O
- O
participation O
of O
employees O
. O

Well O
, O
Cortebeeck B-PER
argues O
that O
tax O
reform O
works O
, O
but O
he O
's O
opposed O
to O
a O
general O
reduction O
in O
taxes O
. O

In O
any O
case O
, O
that O
formula O
requires O
sharing O
of O
profitability O
. O

-DOCSTART O
: O
On O
a O
sunny O
day O
, O
a O
back O
of O
high O
pressure O
builds O
up O
from O
the O
southwest O
, O
stabilizes O
the O
atmosphere O
gradually O
. O

publishing O
date O

Some O
of O
them O
could O
grow O
very O
local O
to O
a O
loose O
bush O
at O
night O
in O
the O
west O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

sect O
. O

And O
thirdly O
, O
there O
's O
a O
cold O
front O
coming O
in O
from O
the O
west O
. O

First O
, O
the O
thermal O
front O
is O
going O
to O
be O
in O
our O
environment O
. O

By O
the O
way O
, O
from O
Sunday O
it O
gets O
a O
little O
warmer O
. O

Eddy B-PER
De I-PER
Mei I-PER

Sunny O
this O
morning O
. O

page O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

Sunny O
this O
morning O
. O

It O
's O
the O
penetration O
of O
the O
cooler O
air O
that O
causes O
strong O
upward O
movements O
to O
take O
place O
over O
the O
day O
. O

It O
's O
so O
hot O
. O

Tomorrow O
, O
increasing O
chance O
of O
rain O
and O
thunderstorms O
, O
followed O
by O
cooling O
. O

May O
was O
warmer O
than O
normal O
. O

The O
wind O
is O
generally O
weak O
, O
and O
it O
mostly O
blows O
in O
directions O
between O
south O
and O
southwest O
. O

In O
the O
afternoon O
, O
temperatures O
are O
25 O
degrees O
and O
above O
. O

editing O

Tomorrow O
's O
rain O
. O

So O
the O
sun O
becomes O
the O
spoken O
- O
word O
master O
of O
the O
situation O
, O
and O
the O
knight O
goes O
on O
an O
adventure O
. O

There O
's O
virtually O
no O
cloud O
in O
this O
. O

In O
many O
places O
, O
the O
peak O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
night O
is O
less O
than O
20 O
degrees O
below O
zero O
Fahrenheit O
. O

After O
the O
weekend O
, O
the O
weather O
does O
n't O
look O
bad O
, O
but O
it O
's O
also O
not O
completely O
stable O
. O

There O
was O
86 O
liters O
of O
precipitation O
in O
20 O
days O
versus O
a O
normal O
62 O
liters O
in O
15 O
days O
. O

19.1 O
( O
Normal O
17.2 O
) O
. O

On O
the O
flank O
of O
a O
more O
or O
less O
stationary O
altitude O
ridge O
over O
Central B-LOC
and O
Eastern B-LOC
Europe I-LOC
, O
warm O
, O
initially O
stable O
air O
is O
now O
being O
flown O
in O
from O
France B-LOC
with O
a O
southern O
current O
. O

The O
current O
painted O
as O
an O
anticyclone O
today O
becomes O
a O
cyclone O
tomorrow O
. O

Min O
. O
11.3 O
. O

Max B-PER
. O

General O
. O

A O
single O
buoy O
can O
carry O
a O
shark O
on O
board O
and O
locally O
release O
so O
much O
water O
that O
it O
creates O
overload O
. O

On O
the O
night O
of O
Saturday O
to O
Sunday O
, O
the O
cold O
front O
stretches O
across O
the O
country O
. O

And O
in O
the O
afternoon O
, O
it O
's O
cloudy O
. O

And O
then O
clouds O
, O
and O
then O
later O
tonight O
a O
little O
chance O
of O
a O
shower O
. O

The O
sun O
shines O
very O
little O
, O
less O
than O
159 O
hours O
, O
compared O
to O
normal O
199 O
hours O
. O

publication O
. O

And O
tonight O
, O
it O
's O
going O
to O
be O
very O
, O
very O
warm O
, O
and O
it O
's O
going O
to O
be O
, O
among O
other O
things O
, O
ideal O
for O
a O
garden O
or O
a O
patio O
. O

And O
the O
consequence O
of O
that O
is O
that O
the O
chance O
of O
getting O
shots O
goes O
up O
as O
the O
afternoon O
and O
the O
evening O
gets O
warmer O
. O

author O

As O
we O
get O
closer O
to O
a O
thermal O
frontier O
, O
which O
is O
now O
above O
the O
west O
of O
France B-LOC
, O
the O
atmosphere O
becomes O
slightly O
unstable O
in O
the O
afternoon O
, O
causing O
a O
series O
of O
cloud O
formations O
. O

Meanwhile B-MISC
, O

Tomorrow O
, O
increasing O
chance O
of O
rain O
and O
thunderstorms O
, O
followed O
by O
cooling O
. O

DOCSTART O
: O
Is O
that O
standard O
of O
health O
often O
exceeded O
? O

What O
's O
more O
interesting O
is O
the O
new O
Dutch B-MISC
initiative O
of O
toll O
booths O
and O
toll O
booths O
around O
the O
big O
Dutch B-MISC
cities O
. O

Two O
Brussels B-MISC
environmental O
movements O
, O
Bral B-ORG
and O
Inter B-ORG
- I-ORG
Environment I-ORG
... O

Because O
studies O
show O
that O
more O
than O
70 O
percent O
of O
road O
traffic O
is O
responsible O
for O
the O
high O
concentrations O
of O
ozone O
. O

The O
countries O
around O
us O
are O
already O
doing O
a O
lot O
of O
this O
, O
but O
Belgium B-LOC
is O
still O
behind O
. O

page O
. O

It O
's O
not O
that O
different O
from O
the O
old O
ozone O
plan O
that O
was O
announced O
in O
1996 O
. O

French B-MISC
cities O
like O
Paris B-LOC
, O
for O
example O
, O
are O
working O
on O
changing O
the O
driving O
bans O
, O
where O
you O
're O
not O
allowed O
to O
drive O
at O
roughly O
equal O
speeds O
on O
ozone O
depletion O
peaks O
. O

author O

" O
Some O
parts O
of O
Germany B-MISC
are O
already O
introducing O
temporary O
speed O
limits O
. O

That O
's O
unfortunate O
. O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

For O
Brussels B-LOC
, O
those O
measures O
could O
be O
combined O
with O
the O
rapid O
deployment O
of O
a O
real O
Brussels B-MISC
suburban O
grid O
with O
large O
transit O
corridors O
. O

" O
Last O
year O
, O
in O
Brussels B-LOC
, O
we O
exceeded O
it O
by O
27 O
days O
. O

If O
you O
're O
right O
, O
what O
are O
you O
going O
to O
do O
with O
the O
money O
if O
you O
overshoot O
? O

On O
high O
- O
ozone O
days O
, O
populations O
at O
risk O
are O
asked O
to O
stay O
inside O
until O
the O
danger O
is O
identified O
. O

publication O
. O

What O
measures O
are O
being O
taken O
abroad O
? O

That O
means O
that O
older O
people O
, O
children O
or O
people O
with O
asthma O
problems O
were O
always O
running O
high O
health O
risks O
. O

Opinion B-MISC
. O

" O

That O
's O
a O
substantial O
amount O
, O
just O
to O
force O
the O
policy O
to O
take O
structural O
action O
as O
quickly O
as O
possible O
. O

If O
we O
do O
get O
money O
, O
we O
're O
going O
to O
collapse O
it O
into O
a O
fund O
that O
can O
help O
me O
finance O
, O
for O
example O
, O
the O
Brussels B-MISC
suburban O
grid O
. O

And O
yet O
, O
it O
was O
announced O
that O
the O
maximum O
speed O
would O
be O
reduced O
. O

That O
's O
where O
they O
want O
to O
make O
the O
charges O
high O
enough O
to O
keep O
a O
lot O
of O
cars O
out O
of O
the O
way O
. O

editing O

" O

" O
The O
federal O
ozone O
plan O
is O
deeply O
disappointing O
. O
" O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

It O
also O
runs O
counter O
to O
Article O
23 O
of O
the O
Constitution O
, O
which O
guarantees O
everyone O
" O
human O
dignity O
. O
" O

Given O
the O
number O
of O
violations O
in O
1999 O
, O
you O
can O
get O
rich O
very O
quickly O
. O

Another O
study O
found O
that O
during O
the O
1994 O
heat O
wave O
, O
1,200 O
people O
died O
in O
Belgium B-LOC
as O
a O
result O
of O
the O
high O
concentrations O
of O
ozone O
in O
that O
period O
. O

The O
federal O
government O
has O
just O
announced O
its O
ozone O
plan O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

Ceustermans B-PER
: O
Every O
time O
the O
so O
- O
called O
European B-MISC
health O
standard O
of O
120 O
micrograms O
of O
ozone O
per O
cubic O
meter O
is O
exceeded O
in O
Brussels B-LOC
for O
at O
least O
eight O
hours O
, O
we O
ask O
for O
a O
compensation O
of O
50 O
million O
Belgian B-MISC
francs O
. O

" O

" O
The O
piece O
delights O
us O
. O

General O
. O

" O

" O

" O
It O
's O
not O
about O
the O
money O
, O
let O
's O
be O
clear O
. O

The O
case O
comes O
up O
for O
trial O
on O
June O
9th O
in O
the O
first O
instance O
court O
briefly O
. O

Are O
you O
happy O
with O
the O
work O
of O
the O
two O
green O
ministers O
, O
Magda B-PER
Aelvoet I-PER
and O
Isabelle B-PER
Durant I-PER
? O

The O
emphasis O
is O
on O
information O
and O
awareness O
, O
while O
there O
are O
few O
measures O
taken O
to O
curb O
road O
traffic O
during O
the O
summer O
months O
. O

It O
's O
unacceptable O
that O
the O
government O
with O
that O
knowledge O
does O
n't O
want O
to O
intervene O
, O
or O
even O
tries O
to O
do O
so O
. O

That O
's O
what O
the O
green O
ministers O
have O
n't O
been O
able O
to O
do O
yet O
. O

sect O
. O

What O
exactly O
is O
your O
request O
? O

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

publishing O
date O

-DOCSTART O
edit O

page O
. O

In O
total O
, O
he O
personally O
made O
15 O
telephone O
calls O
, O
including O
to O
the O
departments O
and O
offices O
of O
Transportation B-ORG
, O
Economics B-ORG
and O
Finance B-ORG
. O

My O
mandate O
was O
limited O
to O
reporting O
on O
any O
political O
issues O
. O

" O
According O
to O
Gantman B-PER
, O
an O
amendment O
to O
the O
corporate O
tax O
law O
on O
the O
tax O
regime O
of O
overvalued O
securities O
came O
about O
abnormally O
slowly O
, O
" O
Larmuseau B-PER
said O
. O

Larmuseau B-PER
replied O
that O
he O
did O
n't O
find O
Gantman B-PER
's O
question O
unfair O
or O
credible O
. O

publication O
. O

" O
It O
's O
been O
so O
long O
, O
I O
can O
hardly O
remember O
anything O
about O
it O
. O

Hendrik B-PER
Larmuseau I-PER
, O
former O
advisor O
to O
Prime O
Minister O
Jean O
- O
Luc B-PER
Dehaene I-PER
's O
( O
CVP B-ORG
) O
cabinet O
on O
social O
and O
economic O
affairs O
, O
told O
the O
Committee O
of O
Inquiry O
into O
Ship O
Loans O
on O
Wednesday O
that O
the O
Antwerp B-MISC
lawyer O
André B-PER
Gantman I-PER
, O
who O
was O
a O
lobbyist O
for O
Red O
Rosenfeld B-PER
, O
was O
also O
active O
in O
the O
prime O
minister O
's O
cabinet O
. O

sect O
. O

He O
said O
he O
did O
n't O
get O
a O
hearing O
from O
the O
Treasury B-ORG
. O

" O

" O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

" O

" O

General O
. O

Larmuseau B-PER
had O
two O
more O
meetings O
with O
Gantman B-PER
in O
the O
spring O
of O
1994 O
, O
and O
he O
was O
able O
to O
report O
to O
the O
attorney O
, O
as O
a O
result O
of O
his O
investigation O
, O
that O
the O
change O
to O
the O
law O
had O
occurred O
in O
accordance O
with O
the O
normal O
procedures O
. O

" O
Because O
in O
a O
cabinet O
like O
this O
, O
you O
're O
constantly O
being O
called O
by O
all O
sorts O
of O
people O
who O
need O
something O
. O

Gantman B-PER
: O
How O
to O
lobby O
Prime O
Minister O
Dehaene B-PER

Karel B-PER
De I-PER
Gucht I-PER
: O
" O
Did O
you O
do O
this O
to O
any O
stranger O
? O
" O

" O
He O
complained O
about O
this O
. O

" O
Did O
you O
do O
this O
to O
every O
unknown O
person O
? O
" O
he O
asked O
the O
witness O
. O

But O
Larmuseau B-PER
could O
hardly O
remember O
anything O
else O
about O
that O
group O
. O

According O
to O
Larmuseau B-PER
, O
Gantman B-PER
first O
appeared O
in O
his O
office O
in O
April O
1994 O
, O
without O
making O
an O
appointment O
on O
the O
phone O
. O

Brussels B-LOC
. O

" O
It O
seemed O
like O
a O
big O
problem O
, O
and O
I O
felt O
it O
was O
my O
duty O
to O
control O
it O
. O

publishing O
date O

I O
did O
n't O
participate O
in O
the O
negotiations O
on O
the O
fiscal O
issue O
. O

He O
also O
personally O
briefed O
Prime O
Minister O
Dehaene B-PER
on O
the O
issue O
raised O
by O
Gantman B-PER
. O

author O

The O
prime O
minister O
's O
adviser O
to O
the O
cabinet O
immediately O
took O
action O
. O

" O
I O
've O
probably O
had O
one O
or O
two O
meetings O
passively O
, O
" O
he O
said O
. O

Former O
Finance B-ORG
Minister O
Philippe B-PER
Maystadt I-PER
blocked O
the O
file O
, O
as O
Gantman B-PER
seemed O
to O
suggest O
. O

Georges B-PER
Timmerman I-PER

Commissioner O
Karel B-PER
De I-PER
Gucht I-PER
( O
VLD B-ORG
) O
was O
amazed O
by O
the O
sheer O
ice O
. O

( O
GT B-PER
) O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

Journalism B-MISC

Self O
- O
reporting O

At O
the O
same O
time O
, O
Larmuseau B-PER
was O
also O
a O
member O
of O
the O
inter O
- O
agency O
group O
around O
ABC B-ORG
Containerline I-ORG
, O
which O
was O
specifically O
set O
up O
to O
deal O
with O
the O
fiscal O
problems O
that O
arose O
as O
a O
result O
of O
the O
mirrored O
takeover O
of O
jurisdiction O
by O
the O
U.S. B-MISC
taxpayer O
Gary B-PER
Blonder I-PER
. O

-DOCSTART- O
17 O

The O
International B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
needs O
to O
listen O
more O
to O
the O
people O
and O
less O
to O
the O
willingness O
of O
countries O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
is O
often O
inclined O
to O
speak O
out O
to O
countries O
, O
but O
one O
of O
the O
lessons O
from O
the O
financial O
crises O
in O
Asia B-LOC
is O
that O
it O
needs O
to O
listen O
better O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
itself O
must O
be O
the O
driving O
force O
behind O
these O
kinds O
of O
changes O
. O

Köhler B-PER
went O
on O
to O
say O
that O
he O
'd O
like O
to O
talk O
about O
an O
Asian B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
, O
a O
plan O
that O
the O
big O
industrialized O
countries O
and O
the O
IMF B-ORG
officials O
have O
been O
working O
on O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O

And O
that O
led O
to O
a O
call O
within O
the O
foundation O
for O
policy O
changes O
. O

Human B-MISC
beings I-MISC

The O
Prime O
Minister O
of O
Thailand B-LOC
, O
Chuan B-PER
Leekpai I-PER
, O
asked O
Köhler B-PER
to O
draw O
lessons O
from O
what O
happened O
in O
our O
country O
. O

There O
's O
a O
monetary O
union O
in O
Europe B-LOC
, O
and O
there O
's O
nothing O
against O
monetary O
unions O
anymore O
, O
the O
IMF B-MISC
chief I-MISC
said O
. O

John B-PER
Vandaele I-PER

publication O
. O

page O
. O

He O
has O
called O
on O
the O
board O
to O
come O
up O
with O
a O
clear O
vision O
for O
the O
future O
role O
of O
the O
IMF B-ORG
in O
the O
coming O
months O
. O

editing O

In O
Thailand B-LOC
, O
in O
July O
1997 O
, O
the O
financial O
crisis O
broke O
out O
, O
which O
then O
devastated O
a O
number O
of O
Asian B-MISC
countries O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

According O
to O
the O
Thai B-MISC
Prime O
Minister O
, O
it O
's O
much O
more O
expensive O
to O
recover O
from O
a O
crisis O
than O
it O
is O
to O
prevent O
a O
crisis O
. O

The O
IMF B-ORG
has O
received O
a O
lot O
of O
criticism O
that O
it O
did O
n't O
see O
the O
problems O
in O
Asia B-LOC
in O
time O
. O

publishing O
date O

Horst B-PER
Köhler I-PER

This O
is O
what O
Horst B-PER
Köhler I-PER
, O
the O
IMF B-ORG
's O
top O
man O
emerging O
in O
May O
, O
said O
yesterday O
in O
Bangkok B-LOC
, O
from O
which O
he O
's O
making O
a O
tour O
of O
Asia B-LOC
. O

It O
's O
up O
to O
the O
Asian B-MISC
countries O
themselves O
to O
decide O
on O
their O
own O
monetary O
funds O
, O
Köhler B-PER
said O
. O

The O
government O
has O
to O
take O
the O
lead O
and O
not O
be O
dictated O
by O
, O
say O
, O
the O
U.S. B-MISC
Congress B-ORG
, O
Köhler B-PER
says O
. O

IMF B-ORG
director O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

Listen O
more O
. O

sect O
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Morning I-MISC

General O
. O

AFP B-ORG

author O

-DOCSTART O
-- O
release O
date O
. O

But O
nobody O
can O
or O
will O
intervene O
. O

publication O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

page O
. O

Koekelberg B-LOC
, O
Ganshoren B-LOC
, O
Jette B-LOC
and O
Sint B-LOC
- I-LOC
Agatha I-LOC
- O
Berchem O
, O
which O
each O
have O
a O
piece O
of O
the O
famous O
basilica O
on O
their O
territory O
, O
ca O
n't O
release O
any O
extra O
money O
in O
the O
next O
few O
years O
for O
the O
necessary O
renovation O
and O
stabilization O
work O
. O

It O
's O
also O
not O
clear O
which O
ministry O
or O
department O
that O
should O
be O
. O

Simonet B-PER
actually O
passed O
on O
the O
concerns O
to O
Home B-ORG
Affairs I-ORG
Minister O
Antoine B-PER
Duquesne I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
. O

that O
Simonet B-PER
has O
promised O
to O
study O
the O
problem O
of O
the O
basilica O
at O
the O
federal O
level O
. O

The O
four O
Brussels B-MISC
municipalities O
that O
are O
now O
repaying O
for O
the O
cost O
of O
maintaining O
the O
Koekelberg B-LOC
Basilica I-LOC
are O
in O
such O
a O
state O
of O
emergency O
. O

The O
basilica O
threatens O
to O
become O
a O
second O
atom B-LOC
. O

The O
four O
mayors O
are O
asking O
that O
the O
federal O
government O
finally O
agree O
to O
put O
money O
across O
the O
bridge O
for O
the O
critically O
needed O
national O
monument O
. O

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

General O
. O

Basil B-LOC
Koekelberg I-LOC
: O
The O
danger O
of O
becoming O
the O
second O
atom B-LOC

The B-MISC
Life I-MISC

sect O
. O

The O
four O
mayors O
discussed O
their O
outrage O
with O
Brussels B-MISC
Prime O
Minister O
Jacques B-PER
Simonet I-PER
( O
PRL B-ORG
) O
during O
his O
tour O
of O
the O
nineteen O
Brussels B-MISC
municipalities O
. O

editing O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

It O
turns O
out O
that O
the O
basilica O
, O
as O
a O
national O
sanctuary O
, O
does O
not O
belong O
to O
the O
Order B-MISC
of I-MISC
the O
Built O
, O
and O
neither O
can O
the O
Ministry O
of O
Justice B-ORG
, O
which O
funds O
the O
recognized O
religions O
, O
because O
the O
basilica O
is O
not O
officially O
a O
church O
or O
a O
cathedral O
. O

For O
years O
, O
you O
've O
seen O
cracks O
and O
occasional O
fractures O
coming O
down O
. O

author O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

" O
DOCSTART O
. O
" O

" O
The O
system O
was O
discontinued O
in O
1990 O
because O
the O
administration O
of O
the O
system O
cost O
a O
lot O
of O
money O
and O
because O
it O
became O
increasingly O
difficult O
to O
distinguish O
between O
speculative O
and O
real O
transactions O
. O

publishing O
date O

publication O
. O

I O
'm O
not O
a O
priori O
opposed O
to O
a O
small O
fee O
on O
the O
condition O
that O
it O
's O
done O
globally O
. O

" O

It O
's O
more O
about O
targeted O
action O
: O
national O
governments O
taking O
action O
against O
short O
- O
term O
money O
flows O
. O

page O
. O

They O
believe O
that O
a O
global O
levy O
on O
currency O
exchange O
can O
not O
only O
prevent O
socially O
destructive O
monetary O
crises O
, O
but O
it O
can O
also O
delay O
money O
from O
contributing O
to O
development O
. O

In O
addition O
, O
the O
Senate B-ORG
Finance I-ORG
Committee O
wants O
to O
get O
a O
better O
look O
at O
the O
feasibility O
and O
desirability O
of O
taxation O
through O
hearings O
with O
experts O
and O
stakeholders O
. O

Cooling O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Well O
, O
he O
's O
questioning O
whether O
the O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
is O
the O
best O
way O
to O
achieve O
that O
. O

sect O
. O

And O
internationally O
, O
there O
's O
been O
a O
whole O
movement O
around O
taxation O
that O
's O
been O
named O
after O
the O
American B-MISC
economist O
James B-PER
Tobin I-PER
. O

And O
because O
quite O
a O
few O
Belgian B-MISC
representatives O
saw O
something O
in O
the O
idea O
, O
the O
Minister O
of O
Finance B-ORG
, O
Didier B-PER
Reynders I-PER
, O
decided O
to O
have O
the O
feasibility O
study O
done O
. O

General O
. O

Governor O
Quad B-PER
does O
n't O
a O
priori O
oppose O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC

author O

Banking O
: O
Taxing O
speculative O
profits O
is O
undemocratic O
and O
inefficient O

Quaden B-PER
could O
perfectly O
identify O
as O
a O
central O
banker O
with O
the O
two O
goals O
of O
taxation O
: O
monetary O
stability O
and O
development O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

One O
. O

John B-PER
Vandaele I-PER

Commission B-ORG
on I-ORG
Finance I-ORG
. O

That O
fee O
forms O
the O
core O
of O
the O
Flemish B-ORG
network I-ORG
against I-ORG
financial I-ORG
speculation I-ORG
, O
which O
consists O
of O
the O
two O
major O
trade O
unions O
and O
some O
NGOs O
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Morning I-MISC

" O
Personally O
, O
I O
do O
n't O
see O
why O
you O
should O
n't O
be O
taxing O
all O
exchange O
transactions O
. O

JVD B-PER

The O
words O
come O
from O
Governor O
Guy B-PER
Quaden I-PER
of O
the O
National B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
, O
and O
they O
were O
spoken O
on O
Wednesday O
during O
the O
first O
hearing O
in O
the O
Senate B-ORG
on O
the O
so O
- O
called O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
. O

Because O
you O
ca O
n't O
make O
that O
distinction O
anymore O
, O
you O
have O
to O
tax O
all O
transactions O
like O
Tobin B-PER
proposed O
. O

Director O
Georges B-PER
Martin I-PER
called O
it O
inefficient O
, O
undemocratic O
and O
unfair O
because O
there O
is O
no O
distinction O
to O
be O
made O
between O
speculative O
and O
non O
- O
speculative O
capital O
traffic O
. O

The O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
had O
a O
little O
less O
sympathy O
with O
the O
Belgian B-ORG
Banking I-ORG
Association I-ORG
. O

editing O

Quaden B-PER
pointed O
out O
that O
Belgium B-LOC
, O
with O
its O
so O
- O
called O
double O
- O
digit O
exchange O
rate O
until O
1990 O
, O
had O
the O
equivalent O
of O
a O
very O
sophisticated O
Tobin B-MISC
tax I-MISC
. O

-DOCSTART O
Brussels B-LOC

" O

The O
founder O
of O
the O
municipal B-ORG
corporation I-ORG
, O
Francis O
Vermeiren O
, O
who O
is O
also O
the B-MISC
mayor I-MISC
of O
the O
city O
of O
Zaventem B-LOC
, O
emphasized O
that O
the O
participation O
of O
the O
municipalities O
has O
already O
delivered O
a O
lot O
, O
both O
through O
the O
two O
privatization O
cycles O
of O
the O
last O
few O
years O
. O

publishing O
date O

Ships O
of O
Finance B-ORG
Hugo B-PER
Schiltz I-PER
( O
V.U. B-ORG
) O
had O
sent O
a O
letter O
to O
all O
his O
colleagues O
a O
few O
days O
before O
the O
general O
meeting O
outlining O
his O
vision O
. O

And O
yet O
, O
Antwerp B-LOC
's O
ideas O
did O
n't O
make O
much O
sense O
. O

The O
municipalities O
and O
the O
provinces O
have O
got O
involved O
in O
the O
municipal B-ORG
corporation I-ORG
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Antwerp B-LOC
on O
Wednesday O
voted O
against O
measures O
that O
would O
give O
municipalities O
more O
freedom O
in O
managing O
their O
Dexia B-MISC
participation I-MISC
. O

And O
in O
some O
of O
the O
big O
cities O
, O
there O
's O
a O
desire O
to O
be O
able O
to O
decide O
for O
themselves O
the O
future O
of O
their O
Dexia B-MISC
shares I-MISC
. O

which O
would O
function O
as O
forums O
where O
municipalities O
could O
discuss O
some O
of O
the O
financial O
policy O
choices O
. O

And O
in O
the O
general O
meeting O
, O
it O
was O
agreed O
to O
set O
up O
a O
series O
of O
working O
groups O
. O

Under O
certain O
conditions O
, O
the O
pieces O
can O
also O
be O
sold O
on O
the O
stock O
exchange O
. O

Increasingly B-PER
, O
it O
's O
thinking O
about O
the O
retirement O
package O
, O
it O
's O
thinking O
about O
the O
liberalization O
of O
electricity O
and O
it O
's O
thinking O
about O
the O
Geographic B-MISC
Information I-MISC
System I-MISC
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

Antwerp B-LOC
was O
one O
of O
the O
few O
to O
vote O
against O
when O
the O
final O
draft O
was O
put O
to O
the O
vote O
. O

And O
that O
's O
made O
possible O
to O
a O
very O
limited O
extent O
by O
Wednesday O
's O
decision O
to O
certify O
the O
stocks O
. O

General O
. O

That O
participation O
is O
now O
worth O
over O
six O
billion O
. O

And O
the O
mayor O
of O
Sint B-LOC
- I-LOC
Martens I-LOC
- O
Latem O
, O
Bob O
Van O
Hooland O
, O
who O
also O
spoke O
at O
the O
general O
meeting O
, O
thinks O
of O
it O
this O
way O
. O

Vermeiren B-PER
thinks O
that O
the O
negotiability O
of O
the O
effects O
between O
the O
municipalities O
-- O
the O
internal O
market O
-- O
can O
already O
meet O
some O
of O
the O
aspirations O
of O
the O
big O
cities O
. O

The O
city O
, O
which O
is O
struggling O
with O
a O
lot O
of O
debt O
, O
would O
rather O
have O
more O
freedom O
to O
fund O
Dexia B-MISC
's I-MISC
participation I-MISC
. O

Not O
just O
to O
sell O
, O
but O
to O
buy O
. O

" O

That O
means O
that O
participation O
in O
Dexia B-ORG
drops O
to O
about O
18.5 O
percent O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
considers O
these O
conditions O
too O
stringent O
. O

Antwerp B-LOC
breaks O
Dexia B-MISC
common I-MISC
sense I-MISC

That O
could O
be O
a O
way O
to O
increase O
the O
yields O
of O
urban O
reserves O
. O

So O
Antwerp B-LOC
has O
already O
committed O
about O
four O
and O
a O
half O
billion O
, O
and O
a O
city O
like O
Schaarbeek B-LOC
has O
committed O
2.3 O
billion O
. O

The O
Belgian B-MISC
municipalities O
and O
provinces O
had O
to O
make O
a O
major O
decision O
on O
Wednesday O
about O
their O
participation O
in O
the O
banking O
group O
Dexia B-ORG
. O

" O
I O
have O
the O
impression O
that O
a O
lot O
of O
mayors O
feel O
that O
way O
. O

The O
bill O
was O
finally O
passed O
with O
about O
87 O
percent O
of O
the O
votes O
. O

He O
wants O
to O
professionalize O
the O
board O
, O
which O
is O
now O
politically O
assembled O
. O

author O

We O
should O
n't O
try O
to O
invent O
participation O
as O
quickly O
as O
possible O
. O

publication O
. O

Well O
, O
Van B-PER
Hooland I-PER
believes O
that O
the O
functioning O
of O
municipal O
government O
can O
be O
improved O
. O

That O
operation O
separates O
dividend O
rights O
from O
voting O
rights O
, O
allowing O
municipalities O
to O
negotiate O
some O
of O
their O
effects O
amongst O
themselves O
. O

That O
's O
something O
on O
the O
order O
of O
80 O
billion O
francs O
. O

Ruben B-PER
Mooijman I-PER

page O
. O

Schiltz B-PER
: O
The O
role O
of O
cities O
has O
changed O

The O
municipal B-ORG
holding I-ORG
company O
, O
for O
four O
billion O
francs O
, O
is O
going O
to O
sign O
the O
current O
capital O
increase O
for O
Dexia B-ORG
. O

The B-MISC
Financial I-MISC
Morning I-MISC

The O
local O
government O
, O
which O
used O
to O
be O
the O
majority O
owner O
of O
the O
municipal B-ORG
loan I-ORG
, O
now O
owns O
about O
22 O
percent O
of O
the O
Dexia B-MISC
group I-MISC
, O
which O
is O
where O
the O
municipal B-ORG
loan I-ORG
went O
into O
. O

Seventeen O
. O

They O
want O
to O
sell O
their O
shares O
in O
wholesale O
or O
in O
part O
. O

sect O
. O

editing O

" O
The O
role O
of O
the O
municipalities O
has O
changed O
. O

The O
converging O
interests O
of O
the O
group O
and O
those O
of O
the O
municipal B-ORG
corporation I-ORG
are O
no O
longer O
clear O
and O
increasingly O
ambiguous O
, O
" O
said O
Schiltz B-PER
at O
the O
general O
meeting O
. O

" O
I O
feel O
compelled O
to O
support O
the O
holding O
. O

Ruben B-PER
Mooijman I-PER

The O
biggest O
city O
in O
Germany B-MISC
did O
n't O
find O
the O
ideas O
far O
enough O
. O

-DOCSTART- O
According O
to O
only O
local O
police O
officers O
, O
the O
reason O
for O
the O
drowning O
is O
obvious O
. O

So O
the O
law O
enforcement O
agencies O
were O
trying O
to O
force O
a O
breakthrough O
through O
negotiations O
. O

author O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

editing O

But O
yesterday O
, O
he O
also O
made O
the O
unconfirmed O
rumor O
that O
he O
would O
have O
beaten O
his O
wife O
and O
children O
in O
the O
past O
. O

The O
man O
admitted O
to O
having O
a O
little O
bit O
of O
a O
hard O
time O
, O
and O
went O
to O
see O
a O
psychiatrist O
. O

He O
did O
n't O
get O
a O
right O
of O
visitation O
from O
the O
judge O
either O
. O

For O
a O
long O
time O
, O
there O
was O
confusion O
about O
his O
origins O
. O

The O
likelihood O
that O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
would O
use O
force O
effectively O
was O
very O
low O
all O
the O
time O
. O

Gambler O
could O
n't O
conceal O
separation O
. O

The O
children O
who O
were O
released O
with O
open O
mouths O
told O
the O
psychologists O
that O
the O
man O
was O
nice O
to O
them O
and O
talked O
about O
his O
own O
children O
all O
the O
time O
. O

sect O
. O

Waterproof B-LOC
. O

And O
that O
reassures O
him O
. O

From O
our O
local O
reporter O

page O
. O

publication O
. O

About O
mystery O
teller O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
, O
a O
lot O
of O
stories O
circled O
yesterday O
. O

He O
was O
also O
very O
concerned O
that O
the O
police O
described O
him O
as O
insane O
. O

The O
spokesman O
for O
the O
Waterloo B-LOC
police O
, O
André B-PER
Colas I-PER
, O
could O
only O
confirm O
that O
it O
was O
a O
39 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
man O
of O
Tunisian B-MISC
descent O
with O
Luxembourgian B-MISC
nationality O
. O

Cathy B-PER
Galle I-PER

publishing O
date O

It O
was O
first O
explained O
that O
it O
was O
an O
Algerian B-MISC
who O
was O
mentally O
ill O
. O

General B-MISC
( O
one O
and O
three O
) O

General O
. O

He O
was O
n't O
quite O
so O
self O
- O
righteous O
, O
he O
was O
just O
kind O
of O
" O
bittered O
. O
" O

Four O
years O
ago O
, O
his O
wife O
left O
him O
, O
and O
the O
judge O
entrusted O
his O
two O
children O
, O
an O
11 O
- O
year O
- O
old O
girl O
and O
a O
five O
- O
year O
- O
old O
boy O
, O
to O
his O
mother O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

Until O
Negi B-PER
Bejoui I-PER
himself O
called O
the O
local O
radio O
station O
on O
Wednesday O
night O
and O
announced O
that O
he O
was O
not O
from O
Algeria B-LOC
but O
from O
Tunisia B-LOC
and O
had O
Luxembourgish B-MISC
nationality O
since O
1982 O
. O

The O
hostage O
- O
taker O
is O
described O
as O
a O
kind O
but O
very O
impulsive O
man O
. O

( O
CG B-PER
) O

He O
tried O
to O
talk O
to O
him O
on O
Wednesdays O
and O
Thursdays O
all O
the O
time O
, O
supported O
by O
a O
police O
psychologist O
. O

The O
children O
would O
have O
gone O
to O
hide O
and O
taken O
the O
two O
of O
them O
to O
day O
care O
. O

" O
DOCSTART O
. O
" O

" O
Women O
of O
all O
cities O
: O
take O
the O
streets O
during O
Euro B-MISC
2000 I-MISC
" O

Or O
other O
special O
events O
for O
women O
. O

( O
PJB B-PER
) O

When O
I O
get O
back O
to O
the O
country O
, O
the O
whole O
heisa O
is O
hopefully O
behind O
me O
. O

" O
We O
also O
invite O
them O
to O
the O
streets O
, O
" O
says O
Vandamme B-PER
. O

Moreover O
, O
it O
's O
not O
about O
sport O
anymore O
, O
it O
's O
about O
commerce O
. O

" O
I O
'm O
going O
abroad O
on O
vacation O
. O

it O
does O
n't O
matter O
. O

page O
. O

Leen B-PER
Vandamme I-PER
of O
the O
VOC B-ORG
does O
n't O
have O
anything O
to O
do O
with O
" O
the O
game O
of O
football O
, O
" O
but O
he O
thinks O
it O
's O
already O
been O
catapulted O
by O
the O
" O
exaggerated O
attention O
" O
in O
the O
media O
. O

" O
If O
football O
is O
so O
important O
to O
men O
that O
it O
creates O
a O
link O
, O
then O
the O
women O
also O
want O
a O
link O
from O
that O
site O
that O
mentions O
, O
for O
example O
, O
November O
11th O
as O
Women B-MISC
's I-MISC
Day I-MISC
. O

As O
long O
as O
women O
are O
not O
in O
the O
seat O
, O
kneeling O
down O
next O
to O
their O
partner O
in O
front O
of O
the O
tube O
, O
they O
're O
going O
to O
go O
into O
soccer O
. O

Friday O
, O
June O
2nd O
, O
2000 O

publishing O
date O

Yes O
, O
but O
not O
for O
the O
women O
who O
are O
caught O
at O
home O
with O
a O
soccer O
- O
loving O
man O
. O

The B-ORG
Morning I-ORG

editing O

Of O
course O
, O
there O
are O
also O
women O
who O
are O
as O
passionate O
about O
football O
as O
their O
male O
partners O
, O
according O
to O
Vandamme B-PER
, O
who O
calls O
the O
VOC B-MISC
campaigns I-MISC
about O
football O
" O
ridiculous O
. O
" O

Dance O
, O
theater O
, O
film O
, O
coffee O
... O

Peter O
- O
Jan B-PER
Bogaert I-PER

sect O
. O
